<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Amnesty_International">
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Amnesty International (AI) (Amnistie internationale au Canada francophone) est une ONG qui défend les droits humains et le respect de la Déclaration universelle des droits de l'homme. Cette organisation milite notamment pour la libération des prisonniers d'opinion, l'abolition de la peine de mort et de la torture et l'arrêt des crimes politiques, mais aussi pour le respect de l'ensemble des droits civils, politiques, économiques, sociaux et culturels.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Amnesty_International"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Non-ProfitOrganisation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Amnesty International är en internationell frivilligorganisation och NGO som verkar för mänskliga rättigheter. Arbetet bygger på FN:s allmänna förklaring om de mänskliga rättigheterna från 10 december 1948, samt konventioner gällande mänskliga rättigheter. Den 28 maj 2011 firade Amnesty 50 år, eftersom det den dagen år 1961 publicerades en artikel i The Observer som var startskottet för kampen för mänskliga rättigeter. Amnestys mål är en värld där varje människa åtnjuter alla de rättigheter som ingår i förklaringen. Tidigare arbetade Amnesty enbart med politiska och medborgerliga rättigheter, men åtagandet har successivt utvidgats till att idag också omfatta grova kränkningar av ekonomiska, sociala och kulturella rättigheter. Amnesty är partipolitiskt och religiöst oberoende.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Prison-relatedOrganizations"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.globalpolicy.org/ngos/credib/2003/1306interview.htm"/>
    <dbpprop:location xml:lang="en">Global</dbpprop:location>
    <dbpprop:organizationName xml:lang="en">Amnesty International</dbpprop:organizationName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Amnesty International (commonly known as Amnesty and AI) is a non-governmental organisation focused on human rights with over 3 million members and supporters around the world. The objective of the organisation is "to conduct research and generate action to prevent and end grave abuses of human rights, and to demand justice for those whose rights have been violated.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Amnesty_International"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://shorts.nthword.com/2010/06/ad-of-week-amnesty-international-death.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Amnistía Internacional, comúnmente conocida como Amnistía o AI (en el original inglés Amnesty International) es una organización no gubernamental internacional que trabaja para que los derechos humanos reconocidos en la Declaración Universal de los Derechos Humanos aprobada en 1948 y en otros tratados internacionales como los Pactos Internacionales de Derechos Humanos, sean reconocidos y respetados. Amnistía cuenta con más de 3 millones de miembros y simpatizantes en todo el mundo.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">アムネスティ・インターナショナル（Amnesty International）は、国際連合との協議資格をもつ、国際的影響力の大きい非政府組織（NGO）である。国際法に則って、死刑の廃止、人権擁護、難民救済など良心の囚人を救済、支援する活動を行っている。和名は「国際人権救援機構」。 資金の調達のために、アーティストたちにボランティアで描いてもらったアートカードや便箋などのグッズや活動の内容を紹介する書籍、ビデオなどの販売を行っている。団体名「amnesty」は “恩赦” の意。中国の諺「暗闇を呪うより一本の蝋燭に火を点せ」にちなみ、有刺鉄線の絡んだ、灯りの点る蝋燭がシンボルマーク。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/OrganizationsEstablishedIn1961"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Amnistía_Internacional"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Anistia_Internacional"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Amnesty International is een vereniging die de naleving van de mensenrechten, zoals vastgelegd in de Universele Verklaring van de Rechten van de Mens en de standaard minimumregels voor de behandeling van gevangenen, op 10 december 1948 door de Verenigde Naties ondertekend, beoogt. In het bijzonder beijvert zij zich voor de volgende punten: Vrijlating van gewetensgevangenen.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Amnesty_International"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Peter_Benenson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Ân xá Quốc tế là một tổ chức phi chính phủ quốc tế, đặt ra mục đích thúc đẩy tất cả quyền con người đã được trịnh trọng nêu ra trong bản Tuyên ngôn Quốc tế Nhân quyền và các chuẩn mực quốc tế khác. Đặc biệt, Ân xá Quốc tế hoạt động nhằm giải thoát tất cả tù nhân lương tâm; nhằm bảo đảm các tù chính trị được xử công bằng và công khai; nhằm bãi bỏ án tử hình, tra tấn, và các hình thức đối xử khác với tù nhân mà họ cho là tàn bạo; nhằm chấm dứt các vụ ám sát chính trị và mất tích cưỡng bức; và chống lại mọi sự vi phạm nhân quyền, bất kể là do chính phủ hay tổ chức khác.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amnesty_International"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Amnesty International ist eine nichtstaatliche (NGO) und Non-Profit-Organisation, die sich weltweit für Menschenrechte einsetzt. Grundlage ihrer Arbeit sind die Allgemeine Erklärung der Menschenrechte und andere Menschenrechtsdokumente, wie beispielsweise der Internationale Pakt über bürgerliche und politische Rechte oder der Internationale Pakt über wirtschaftliche, soziale und kulturelle Rechte. Die Organisation recherchiert Menschenrechtsverletzungen, betreibt Öffentlichkeits- und Lobbyarbeit und organisiert u.  a. Brief- und Unterschriftenaktionen in Fällen von Folter oder drohender Todesstrafe.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Amnistia Internacional (AI) és una associació internacional que treballa per la defensa dels drets humans arreu del món. El 1977 va ser guardonada amb el Premi Nobel de la Pau per la seva ferma lluita contra la tortura arreu del món.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">國際特赦組織（或稱“大赦國際”，英语：Amnesty International，簡稱AI），是一個人權監察的國際性非政府組織，於1961年創立，由世界各國民間人士組成，監察國際上違反人權的事件。現時在全世界已經有超過200萬名會員，是全球最大的人權組織。根據組織的簡介，“我們奉行並推廣《世界人權宣言》及其他國際法的人權法則，主要的工作為預防及終止肆意侵犯身體以至精神方面的健全、表達良心的自由以及免受歧視的自由。”該組織於1977年獲頒諾貝爾和平獎 ，1978年獲頒聯合國人權獎。</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Διεθνής_Αμνηστία"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">«Міжнаро́дна амні́стія» — всесвітня неурядова та некомерційна організація з захисту прав людини. Має 2,2 міліонів членів і представництва в 43 країнах світу. Штаб-квартира секретаріату знаходиться в Лондоні. Організація отримала Нобелівську премію Миру в 1977. Одна із найбільш шанованих міжнародних правозахисних організацій.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Amnesty International</foaf:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Olof_Palme_Prize_laureates"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">A Anistia Internacional ou Amnistia Internacional é uma organização não governamental que defende os direitos humanos.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Dubious"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Organizations_established_in_1961"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Amnesty International är en internationell frivilligorganisation och NGO som verkar för mänskliga rättigheter. Arbetet bygger på FN:s allmänna förklaring om de mänskliga rättigheterna från 10 december 1948, samt konventioner gällande mänskliga rättigheter. Den 28 maj 2011 firade Amnesty 50 år, eftersom det den dagen år 1961 publicerades en artikel i The Observer som var startskottet för kampen för mänskliga rättigeter.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Amnesty International (commonly known as Amnesty and AI) is a non-governmental organisation focused on human rights with over 3 million members and supporters around the world. The objective of the organisation is "to conduct research and generate action to prevent and end grave abuses of human rights, and to demand justice for those whose rights have been violated. " Amnesty International was founded in London in 1961, following the publication of the article "The Forgotten Prisoners" in The Observer 28 May 1961, by the lawyer Peter Benenson. Amnesty draws attention to human rights abuses and campaigns for compliance with international laws and standards. It works to mobilise public opinion to put pressure on governments that let abuse take place. The organisation was awarded the 1977 Nobel Peace Prize for its "campaign against torture", and the United Nations Prize in the Field of Human Rights in 1978. In the field of international human rights organisations, Amnesty has the longest history and broadest name recognition, and "is believed by many to set standards for the movement as a whole."</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Amnesty International is een vereniging die de naleving van de mensenrechten, zoals vastgelegd in de Universele Verklaring van de Rechten van de Mens en de standaard minimumregels voor de behandeling van gevangenen, op 10 december 1948 door de Verenigde Naties ondertekend, beoogt. In het bijzonder beijvert zij zich voor de volgende punten: Vrijlating van gewetensgevangenen. Dit zijn gevangenen, die omwille van hun politieke, religieuze, sociale of seksuele overtuiging en/of geaardheid vervolgd worden, en gevangengezet zijn, en die geen geweld hebben gebruikt; Een eerlijk proces binnen een redelijke termijn voor de overige gevangenen; Afschaffing van martelingen en andere mishandelingen van gevangenen; Afschaffing van de doodstraf in alle omstandigheden en buitengerechtelijke executies. Stopzetting van zware schendingen, zoals buitensporig geweld door overheidsdiensten, of gijzelneming van en aanvallen op burgers in oorlogsgebieden. Tegenwoordig ziet Amnesty International ook toe op gedragingen van gewapende verzetsbewegingen en richt de organisatie zich op schendingen in de “privé-sfeer” zoals huiselijk geweld. Sinds 2001 houdt de organisatie zich ook bezig met schendingen van sociaal-economische rechten.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Amnesty International ble stiftet i 1961 av den engelske advokaten Peter Benenson på bakgrunn av en artikkel han skrev i avisen The Observer om to portugisiske samvittighetsfanger. Artikkelen fikk stor oppmerksomhet og førte til en brevskrivningskampanje for løslatelse av samvittighetsfanger i mange land. Amnesty International er en verdensomspennende og medlemsstyrt organisasjon som jobber for at de grunnleggende menneskerettighetene skal være oppfylt for alle.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:International_human_rights_organizations"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Prison-related_organizations"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Ân xá Quốc tế</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:services xml:lang="en">Protecting human rights</dbpprop:services>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Amnesty International ble stiftet i 1961 av den engelske advokaten Peter Benenson på bakgrunn av en artikkel han skrev i avisen The Observer om to portugisiske samvittighetsfanger. Artikkelen fikk stor oppmerksomhet og førte til en brevskrivningskampanje for løslatelse av samvittighetsfanger i mange land. Amnesty International er en verdensomspennende og medlemsstyrt organisasjon som jobber for at de grunnleggende menneskerettighetene skal være oppfylt for alle. Som følge av at de verken er politisk avhengige eller mottar noen form for statlig støtte står de fritt til å slå ned på menneskerettighetsbrudd uansett hvor de finner sted. Måten Amnesty jobber på er blant annet ved å aksjonere og få folk til å underskrive på appeller. Ved å få mennesker fra hele verden til å sette søkelyset på overgrep som finner sted, håper Amnestys at man får stoppet overgrepene. I dag har organisasjonen nærmere 3 millioner medlemmer, støttespillere og abonnenter i mer enn 150 land. Ved Amnesty Internationals internasjonale sekreteriat i London arbeider over 400 personer. I 1977 ble organisasjonen hedret med Nobels fredspris for arbeidet med å forsvare menneskerettigheter over hele verden.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundingYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1961-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:foundingYear>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Amnesty International</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:organizationLogo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">100</dbpprop:organizationLogo>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Міжнародна амністія</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Free_Your_Mind_Award_winners"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.012l0"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Amnistia Internacional (AI) és una associació internacional que treballa per la defensa dels drets humans arreu del món. El 1977 va ser guardonada amb el Premi Nobel de la Pau per la seva ferma lluita contra la tortura arreu del món.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Ân xá Quốc tế là một tổ chức phi chính phủ quốc tế, đặt ra mục đích thúc đẩy tất cả quyền con người đã được trịnh trọng nêu ra trong bản Tuyên ngôn Quốc tế Nhân quyền và các chuẩn mực quốc tế khác.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Amnesty International ist eine nichtstaatliche (NGO) und Non-Profit-Organisation, die sich weltweit für Menschenrechte einsetzt. Grundlage ihrer Arbeit sind die Allgemeine Erklärung der Menschenrechte und andere Menschenrechtsdokumente, wie beispielsweise der Internationale Pakt über bürgerliche und politische Rechte oder der Internationale Pakt über wirtschaftliche, soziale und kulturelle Rechte.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/NonProfitOrganization"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">«Международная амнистия» (известная также как Amnesty, AI, Amnesty International, МА, «Эмнести») — международная неправительственная организация, которая ставит своей целью «предпринимать исследования и действия, направленные на предупреждение и прекращение нарушений прав на физическую и психологическую неприкосновенность, на свободу совести и самовыражения, на свободу от дискриминации в контексте своей работы по продвижению прав человека». AI основана в Великобритании в 1961 году.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:founded xml:lang="en">July 1961 by Peter Benenson in Britain</dbpprop:founded>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Amnesty_International"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Amnistia Internacional</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:reason xml:lang="en">www.amnesty-volunteer.org is not an official site, it's managed by members. It's unclear whether this represents AI policies accurately. A better source would help</dbpprop:reason>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Amnesty International (známá také jako Amnesty či AI) je celosvětové hnutí, které monitoruje porušování lidských práv a iniciuje kampaně proti jejich porušování.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Amnesty International (lyhenne AI, epävirallisesti Amnesty) on kansainvälinen järjestö, jonka päämääränä on edistää ihmisoikeuksien noudattamista koko maailmassa Yhdistyneiden kansakuntien ihmisoikeusjulistuksen hengessä. Järjestö perustettiin vuonna 1961 lakimies Peter Benensonin aloitteesta. Amnesty International sai Nobelin rauhanpalkinnon vuonna 1977. Järjestön kahdeksantena pääsihteerinä toimii 1. heinäkuuta 2010 alkaen intialainen Salil Shetty. Amnesty Internationalin huolenaiheena ovat olleet erityisesti mielipidevangit, poliittiset vangit, kuolemanrangaistus, kidutus, poliittiset murhat, katoamiset ja mitkä tahansa muut hallitusten, organisaatioiden tai henkilöiden tekemät ihmisoikeusloukkaukset. Järjestön puolueettomuuden turvaamiseksi Amnesty International ei ota vastaan taloudellista tukea valtioilta ja myös yritysrahoitukselle ollaan kriittisiä. Vastaavista syistä Amnestyn jäsenet eivät kampanjoi omassa maassaan tapahtuneiden yksittäisten ihmisoikeusloukkausten uhrien puolesta, joskin tätä sääntöä on lievennetty kahden viimeisimmän pääsihteerin aikana. Amnestyn tutkimusraportit, joiden tiedot pyritään varmistamaan toisistaan riippumattomista lähteistä, ovatkin saavuttaneet mainetta yleensä luotettavana tietolähteenä ihmisoikeusloukkauksista. Amnestyn päätoimisto eli kansainvälinen sihteeristö sijaitsee Lontoossa. Vuonna 2007 järjestö ilmoitti toimintaansa osallistuvan tai tukevan yhteensä yli kolme miljoonaa ihmistä yli 150 maassa. Suomen osastolla on noin 42 000 jäsentä ja säännöllistä lahjoittajaa. Amnestyn suurimmat osastot ovat Yhdysvallat, Iso-Britannia ja Hollanti.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Az Amnesty International (AI) karitatív nemzetközi szervezet, amely az emberi jogok elismertetéséért küzd. A szervezet az emberi jogok megsértése ellen folytatott kutatómunkájához és kampányaihoz kormányoktól nem kér és nem fogad el pénzt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">«Международная амнистия» (известная также как Amnesty, AI, Amnesty International, МА, «Эмнести») — международная неправительственная организация, которая ставит своей целью «предпринимать исследования и действия, направленные на предупреждение и прекращение нарушений прав на физическую и психологическую неприкосновенность, на свободу совести и самовыражения, на свободу от дискриминации в контексте своей работы по продвижению прав человека». AI основана в Великобритании в 1961 году. Организация привлекает внимание к нарушениям прав человека и выступает за соблюдение международных стандартов. В её задачи входит мобилизация общественности в целях оказания давления на лиц, нарушающих права человека. За свою работу Amnesty International удостоена Нобелевской премии мира,, а также премии ООН в области прав человека. Вместе с тем, в её адрес высказывалась критика за предполагаемую предвзятость, а именно за антизападный и прозападный настрой.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Amnesty_International"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">アムネスティ・インターナショナル（Amnesty International）は、国際連合との協議資格をもつ、国際的影響力の大きい非政府組織（NGO）である。国際法に則って、死刑の廃止、人権擁護、難民救済など良心の囚人を救済、支援する活動を行っている。和名は「国際人権救援機構」。 資金の調達のために、アーティストたちにボランティアで描いてもらったアートカードや便箋などのグッズや活動の内容を紹介する書籍、ビデオなどの販売を行っている。団体名「amnesty」は “恩赦” の意。中国の諺「暗闇を呪うより一本の蝋燭に火を点せ」にちなみ、有刺鉄線の絡んだ、灯りの点る蝋燭がシンボルマーク。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Amnesty International (lyhenne AI, epävirallisesti Amnesty) on kansainvälinen järjestö, jonka päämääränä on edistää ihmisoikeuksien noudattamista koko maailmassa Yhdistyneiden kansakuntien ihmisoikeusjulistuksen hengessä. Järjestö perustettiin vuonna 1961 lakimies Peter Benensonin aloitteesta. Amnesty International sai Nobelin rauhanpalkinnon vuonna 1977. Järjestön kahdeksantena pääsihteerinä toimii 1. heinäkuuta 2010 alkaen intialainen Salil Shetty.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">국제사면위원회 또는 국제 앰네스티(Amnesty International, AI)는 국제 비정부 기구로 "중대한 인권 학대를 종식 및 예방하며 권리를 침해받는 사람들의 편에 서서 정의를 요구하고자 행동하고 연구를 수행하는 것"을 그 목적으로 삼고 있다. 영국사람인 페터 베넨슨변호사가 설립하였다. 엠네스티의 로고는 철조망에 둘러싸인 촛불모양이다. 이것은 1961년 6월에 지역그룹 회원인 Diana Redhouse에 의해 도안 되었으며, 이 상징적 의미는 억압 속에서도 꺼지지 않는 인류연대의 희망을 나타낸다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">It is better to light a candle than to curse the darkness.</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Organizations_awarded_Nobel_Prizes"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amnesty_International?oldid=495137390"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Amnesty International – międzynarodowa organizacja pozarządowa, której celem jest zapobieganie naruszeniom fundamentalnych praw człowieka poprzez wszelkie pokojowe akcje obywatelskie – od organizowania pisania listów do rządów krajów łamiących te prawa, poprzez publiczne rozgłaszanie informacji o takich naruszeniach, po realną pomoc finansową i prawną poszkodowanym osobom. Organizacja jest laureatem Pokojowej Nagrody Nobla z 1977 roku za "wkład w umacnianie podstaw wolności, sprawiedliwości, a tym samym pokoju na całym świecie". Amnesty International finansuje swoją działalność głównie ze składek członkowskich i datków od indywidualnych osób. Amnesty nie przyjmuje jakiejkolwiek pomocy rządowej, a przyjmowanie datków od przedsiębiorstw i innych organizacji podlega licznym obostrzeniom. Zasadami działania Amnesty International są: pełna niezależność polityczna i finansowa oraz maksymalny obiektywizm. Mimo to jest ona często w wielu krajach (głównie tych, które często represjonują swoich obywateli) oskarżana o wspieranie Zachodu i propagowanie jego idei. Przeczą temu jednak akcje wymierzone w obronę przed rządami wielu krajów zachodnich, takie jak protesty przeciwko torturom i pozasądowemu przetrzymywaniu ludzi przez USA w Guantanamo. Amnesty International liczy obecnie 2 mln 200 tys. członków w 150 krajach świata. Centrala AI – tzw. międzynarodowy sekretariat – znajduje się w Londynie. Do końca 2009 Sekretarz Generalną AI była Irene Khan, jej następcą jest Salil Shetty. Oficjalnym hymnem organizacji jest piosenka "One" zespołu U2.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpprop:location xml:lang="en">General secretariat in London</dbpprop:location>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Amnesty International (AI) (Amnistie internationale au Canada francophone) est une ONG qui défend les droits humains et le respect de la Déclaration universelle des droits de l'homme. Cette organisation milite notamment pour la libération des prisonniers d'opinion, l'abolition de la peine de mort et de la torture et l'arrêt des crimes politiques, mais aussi pour le respect de l'ensemble des droits civils, politiques, économiques, sociaux et culturels. Enregistrée comme organisation internationale à caractère non gouvernemental, Amnesty International entretient des sections dans plus de 50 pays et se voit reconnaître le caractère d'organisme à voix consultative auprès de l'ONU — auprès, notamment, de son Conseil économique et social —, de l'UNESCO, de l'Europe et de l'Organisation des États américains. Elle jouit également d'un statut d'observateur auprès de l'Union africaine. Amnesty International tire la presque totalité des fonds dont elle dispose des collectes réalisées par ses membres. Elle regroupe plus de trois millions d'adhérents et de donateurs dans plus de 150 pays et territoires. Afin de s'assurer de l'exacte observation des règles de droit international par les tribunaux qui ont à juger d'affaires politiques, afin d'enquêter sur les conditions d'internement et les allégations de torture, Amnesty International entreprend chaque année de nombreuses missions : ses envoyés sont présents comme observateurs lors de procès dont l'issue est présumée critique. Ils établissent des rapports sur ces procès et recueillent sur place des informations concernant les personnes emprisonnées pour leurs opinions. De telles missions sont habituellement composées de juristes faisant figure d'experts distingués, de diplomates ayant quitté leurs fonctions ou de spécialistes reconnus. Amnesty International publie chaque année un rapport rendant compte de la situation des droits de l'homme et de leurs violations dans l'ensemble des pays du monde. Elle publie également un certain nombre de rapports importants et documentés dénonçant les incarcérations politiques pratiquées par les gouvernements de pays aussi différents que l'Indonésie, la Turquie, la Tchécoslovaquie, l'Union soviétique, le Paraguay, les Philippines, l'Iran, l'Espagne, la Corée du Nord, le Brésil, etc. Ces différents rapports fournissent à l'opinion mondiale des renseignements chiffrés, des références aux textes et aux juridictions d'exception utilisés par les gouvernements et révèlent l'emplacement des prisons, des camps de travail, etc. Depuis la fondation d'Amnesty International, des dizaines de milliers de prisonniers ont été libérés à la suite de son intervention . Même lorsque les efforts déployés par l'organisation ne permettent pas d'atteindre un tel résultat, l'intervention engagée en faveur d'un prisonnier rappelle à celui-ci qu'il n'est pas seul et renforce la pression internationale pour le respect des droits humains.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rwRA2DpwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Amnesty International è un'organizzazione non governativa sovranazionale impegnata nella difesa dei diritti umani. Lo scopo di Amnesty International è quello di promuovere, in maniera indipendente e imparziale, il rispetto dei diritti umani sanciti nella Dichiarazione universale dei diritti umani e quello di prevenirne specifici abusi. Fondata il 28 maggio 1961 dall'avvocato inglese Peter Benenson, l'organizzazione conta oggi oltre due milioni di sostenitori, che risiedono in più di 150 nazioni. Il suo simbolo è una candela nel filo spinato. Ha ricevuto il Premio Nobel per la pace nel 1977 per l'attività di "difesa della dignità umana contro la tortura, la violenza e la degradazione". L'anno seguente è stata insignita del Premio delle Nazioni Unite per i diritti umani. L'inno ufficiale dell'organizzazione è la canzone dei The Wailers e di Bob Marley http://www. youtube. com/watch?v=n6z0OjBSbhU&amp;feature=fvst Get Up Stand Up.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nobel_Peace_Prize_laureates"/>
    <dbpprop:keyPeople xml:lang="en">Salil Shetty</dbpprop:keyPeople>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">«Міжнаро́дна амні́стія» — всесвітня неурядова та некомерційна організація з захисту прав людини. Має 2,2 міліонів членів і представництва в 43 країнах світу. Штаб-квартира секретаріату знаходиться в Лондоні. Організація отримала Нобелівську премію Миру в 1977. Одна із найбільш шанованих міжнародних правозахисних організацій.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/ee/Amnesty_International_logo.svg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">A Anistia Internacional ou Amnistia Internacional é uma organização não governamental que defende os direitos humanos.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/アムネスティ・インターナショナル"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Amnesty International – międzynarodowa organizacja pozarządowa, której celem jest zapobieganie naruszeniom fundamentalnych praw człowieka poprzez wszelkie pokojowe akcje obywatelskie – od organizowania pisania listów do rządów krajów łamiących te prawa, poprzez publiczne rozgłaszanie informacji o takich naruszeniach, po realną pomoc finansową i prawną poszkodowanym osobom.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_non-profit"/>
    <dbpprop:organizationType rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Non-governmental_organization"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="https://www.amnesty.org/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.democracynow.org/2009/10/16/amnesty_international_head_irene_khan_on"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">국제사면위원회 또는 국제 앰네스티(Amnesty International, AI)는 국제 비정부 기구로 "중대한 인권 학대를 종식 및 예방하며 권리를 침해받는 사람들의 편에 서서 정의를 요구하고자 행동하고 연구를 수행하는 것"을 그 목적으로 삼고 있다. 영국사람인 페터 베넨슨변호사가 설립하였다. 엠네스티의 로고는 철조망에 둘러싸인 촛불모양이다. 이것은 1961년 6월에 지역그룹 회원인 Diana Redhouse에 의해 도안 되었으며, 이 상징적 의미는 억압 속에서도 꺼지지 않는 인류연대의 희망을 나타낸다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">國際特赦組織（或稱“大赦國際”，英语：Amnesty International，簡稱AI），是一個人權監察的國際性非政府組織，於1961年創立，由世界各國民間人士組成，監察國際上違反人權的事件。現時在全世界已經有超過200萬名會員，是全球最大的人權組織。根據組織的簡介，“我們奉行並推廣《世界人權宣言》及其他國際法的人權法則，主要的工作為預防及終止肆意侵犯身體以至精神方面的健全、表達良心的自由以及免受歧視的自由。”該組織於1977年獲頒諾貝爾和平獎 ，1978年獲頒聯合國人權獎。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Erasmus_Prize_winners"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/국제사면위원회"/>
    <dbpprop:organizationMotto xml:lang="en">It is better to light a candle than to curse the darkness.</dbpprop:organizationMotto>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/InternationalHumanRightsOrganizations"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Amnistía Internacional, comúnmente conocida como Amnistía o AI (en el original inglés Amnesty International) es una organización no gubernamental internacional que trabaja para que los derechos humanos reconocidos en la Declaración Universal de los Derechos Humanos aprobada en 1948 y en otros tratados internacionales como los Pactos Internacionales de Derechos Humanos, sean reconocidos y respetados. Amnistía cuenta con más de 3 millones de miembros y simpatizantes en todo el mundo. El objetivo de la organización es «realizar labores de investigación y emprender acciones para impedir y poner fin a los abusos graves contra los derechos civiles, políticos, sociales, culturales y económicos» y pedir justicia para aquellos cuyos derechos han sido violados. Amnistía Internacional fue fundada en Londres en 1961, tras la publicación del artículo «The Forgotten Prisoners» en The Observer el 28 de mayo de 1961, escrito por el abogado Peter Benenson. Amnistía trabaja para llamar la atención de la sociedad sobre los abusos contra los derechos humanos, y hace campaña por el cumplimiento de las leyes internacionales. Intenta movilizar a la opinión pública para presionar a los gobiernos que dejan que dichos abusos sucedan. La labor de AI fue reconocida con el Premio Nobel de la Paz en 1977 por su «campaña contra la tortura» y con el Premio de Derechos Humanos de las Naciones Unidas en 1978. En el campo de las organizaciones internacionales de derechos humanos, Amnistía es la que tiene el mayor reconocimiento, y «según muchos es la que crea los estándares para el campo en general».</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:organizationType xml:lang="en">Non-profit</dbpprop:organizationType>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Amnesty International</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Imprisonment_and_detention"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:keyPerson rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Salil_Shetty"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Amnesty_International"/>
    <dbpprop:fields xml:lang="en">Media attention, direct-appeal campaigns, research, lobbying</dbpprop:fields>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Amnesty International</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Международная_амнистия"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1961_establishments_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="https://www.amnesty.org/"/>
    <dbpprop:numMembers rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/second">1.8E8</dbpprop:numMembers>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Amnesty_International"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Amnesty International (známá také jako Amnesty či AI) je celosvětové hnutí, které monitoruje porušování lidských práv a iniciuje kampaně proti jejich porušování.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://thoughtstrategy.co.uk/2011/07/06/justice/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Az Amnesty International (AI) karitatív nemzetközi szervezet, amely az emberi jogok elismertetéséért küzd. A szervezet az emberi jogok megsértése ellen folytatott kutatómunkájához és kampányaihoz kormányoktól nem kér és nem fogad el pénzt.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ee/Amnesty_International_logo.svg/200px-Amnesty_International_logo.svg.png"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Amnesty International è un'organizzazione non governativa sovranazionale impegnata nella difesa dei diritti umani. Lo scopo di Amnesty International è quello di promuovere, in maniera indipendente e imparziale, il rispetto dei diritti umani sanciti nella Dichiarazione universale dei diritti umani e quello di prevenirne specifici abusi.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:date xml:lang="en">July 2011</dbpprop:date>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">國際特赦組織</rdfs:label>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
