<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mulkerrin_Brothers">
    <dbpedia-owl:hometown rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
    <dbpprop:origin rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://data.nytimes.com/N6663995922629365341">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Breand%C3%A1n_%C3%93_hEithir">
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands">
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aran_Islands"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Le Isole Aran (Oileáin Árann in gaelico) sono un gruppo di tre isole situato all'imbocco della baia di Galway, nella Repubblica d'Irlanda. Sebbene siano più vicine e simili come paesaggio al Clare, fanno parte amministrativamente della contea di Galway. Sono in ordine di grandezza o, se si preferisce, da ovest verso est: Inis Mór o Aran (Árainn) Inis Meáin Inis Oírr</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Острова́ А́ран — группа из трёх островов, расположенных у западного побережья Ирландии. С востока омываются водами залива Голуэй. Входят в графство Голуэй. Население — 1225 человек.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Aran_Islands"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.pobail.ie/en/Islands/InhabitedOffshoreIslands/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.lookaroundireland.com/mapofaranislands.htm"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Arany, Wyspy Aran – grupa trzech wapiennych wysp u zachodnich wybrzeży Irlandii w Zatoce Galway. Należą do nich: Inishmore (irl. Inis Mór), pow. 3092 ha, liczba miesz. : 826 os. (2006 r. ), Inishmaan (irl. Inis Meáin), pow. 912 ha, liczba miesz. : 187 os. (2002 r. ), Inisheer (irl. Inis Oírr lub Inis Oirtheach), pow. 567 ha, liczba miesz. : 262 os. (2002 r.). Główną osadą jest port Kilronan (Cill Rónáin) na wyspie Inishmore, zamieszkany przez 270 osób.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Gaeltacht_places_in_County_Galway"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Aransaaret on kolmen saaren ryhmä Irlannin länsirannikolla. Se kuuluu Galwayn kreivikuntaan. Saaret ovat Inis Mór, Inis Meáin ja Inis Óirr. Englanninkieliset nimet ovat Inishmore, Inishmaan ja Inisheer. Suurin saari on Inishmore ja sillä sijaitseva Kilronanin kylä on Aransaarien suurin asutuskeksus. Aransaaret ovat iirinkielistä aluetta. Niiden yhteen laskettu asukasluku on 1 218.</rdfs:comment>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-9.7</geo:long>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://aranislands.galway-ireland.ie/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ImportantBirdAreasOfTheRepuBlicOfIreland"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Islas_Aran"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Aranøyene er en øygruppe ved munningen av Galwaybukten på vestkysten av Irland. Den største øya i øygruppen er Inishmore, . Inis Mór på gælisk betyr «Store øya». Árainn (Aran) er navnet som lokalt brukes om den største øya, men da den britiske oppmålingsmyndigheten kartla Irlands vestkyst, mente de dette var uryddig og valgte alternativet Inishmore (Inis Mór). Dette «offisielle» navnet har likevel kommet i relativt vanlig bruk. Den nest største av de tre øyene er Inishmaan (Inis Meáin / Inis Meadhóin). Den minste og østligste øya er Inisheer (Inis Thiar or Inis Oírr / Inis Oirthir). På kartene står de gæliske navnene ved siden av den engelske formen av navnet. Siden gælisk er det vanligste språket på øyene blir likevel de gæliske formene svært ofte brukt for navn på øyene, tettsteder og for andre stedsnavn.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/42/Aran_Islands.PNG/200px-Aran_Islands.PNG"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.aranislands.com/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/GeoclassIslands"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Arany, Wyspy Aran – grupa trzech wapiennych wysp u zachodnich wybrzeży Irlandii w Zatoce Galway. Należą do nich: Inishmore (irl. Inis Mór), pow. 3092 ha, liczba miesz. : 826 os. (2006 r. ), Inishmaan (irl. Inis Meáin), pow. 912 ha, liczba miesz. : 187 os. (2002 r. ), Inisheer (irl. Inis Oírr lub Inis Oirtheach), pow. 567 ha, liczba miesz. : 262 os. (2002 r.). Główną osadą jest port Kilronan (Cill Rónáin) na wyspie Inishmore, zamieszkany przez 270 osób. Na wyspy można się dostać połączeniami promowymi: z Rossaveal lub z Doolin. Połączenie lotnicze wszystkich wysp obsługiwane są przez lokalne linie lotnicze Aer Arann. Obecnym źródłem utrzymania mieszkańców wysp jest obsługa ruchu turystycznego, rękodzieło, rybołówstwo, rolnictwo. Najwcześniejsze ślady osadnictwa na wyspach pochodzą z epoki brązu (ok. 700 lat p.n.e. ) i żelaza, m. in. kamienne forty Dún Aengus (Dún Aonghasa) i Dún Dúchathair na wyspie Inishmore. Z późniejszego okresu zachowały się pozostałości budowli obronnych i wczesnochrześcijańskich kościołów. W średniowieczu, w związku z rozwojem portu w Galway wyspy nabrały pewnego znaczenia strategicznego, stąd toczyły się o nie walki lokalnych klanów. W 1565 r. królowa Elżbieta I przekazała wyspy w ręce angielskie, pod warunkiem ochrony interesów Korony. Utrata pozycji ekonomicznej w XVII w. i zainteresowania ze strony Anglii spowodowała zapanowanie biedy na wyspach. Sytuację pogarszały wysokie czynsze dzierżawcze nakładane przez właścicieli na użytkowników tych skalistych i nieurodzajnych ziem. Mimo powiązań z ruchem oporu przeciwko Anglikom w Irlandii, mieszkańcy wysp żyli w głębokiej izolacji. W związku z renesansem kultury celtyckiej od końca XIX w. datuje się szersze zainteresowanie życiem i kulturą wyspiarzy z powodu zachowanego bogatego folkloru i tradycji oraz przetrwania języka irlandzkiego w codziennym użyciu (to na Aranach jedne z najsłynniejszych pisarzy irlandzkich, J. M. Synge, osadził akcje kilku ze swych dramatów. Ilustracją ciężkiego życia na przekór naturze jest również film dokumentalny Roberta O'Flaherty'ego "Man of Aran". Obecnie coraz większą rolę w gospodarce odgrywa turystyka, wyspy przyciągają turystów niezwykłymi krajobrazami klifowego wybrzeża, unikalną atmosferą, jak również licznymi obiektami zabytkowymi.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Les îles d’Aran, en irlandais Oileáin Árann, en anglais Aran Islands, forment un archipel d'Irlande située à 18 kilomètres des côtes occidentales du pays, à la sortie de la baie de Galway. Géologiquement parlant, ces îles sont le prolongement de l’ensemble karstique des Burren dans le comté de Clare.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Le Isole Aran (Oileáin Árann in gaelico) sono un gruppo di tre isole situato all'imbocco della baia di Galway, nella Repubblica d'Irlanda. Sebbene siano più vicine e simili come paesaggio al Clare, fanno parte amministrativamente della contea di Galway. Sono in ordine di grandezza o, se si preferisce, da ovest verso est: Inis Mór o Aran (Árainn) Inis Meáin Inis Oírr</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Arany"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Aran Islands</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">De Araneilanden zijn drie eilanden in de monding van de Baai van Galway in county Galway in Ierland. De inwoners op de drie eilanden leven van oudsher van de visserij, maar ook zomertoerisme is heden ten dage een belangrijke bron van inkomsten. De eilanden vallen binnen de Gaeltacht, het gebied waar de omgangstaal het Iers is. De bewoners spreken allen echter ook Engels.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Baronies_of_County_Galway"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://araseanna.ie/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=866617008502543100&amp;q=Man+of+Aran&amp;total=34&amp;start=0&amp;num=10&amp;so=0&amp;type=search&amp;plindex=0"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">アラン諸島（英: Aran Islands、愛: oileáin Árann）は、アイルランド島の西、ゴールウェイ湾に浮かぶ島々。アラン島と呼ばれることも多い。アラン諸島は3つの島からなり、西側から、イニシュモア（英: Inishmore、愛: Inis Mór）、イニシュマーン（英: Inishmaan、愛: Inis Meáin）、イニシィア（英: Inisheer、愛: Inis Oírr）と呼ばれる。アイルランド語でÁrannの意味は「長い山々」の意味で、現在の島の名前にあるInisは「島」の意味である。また、Mór、Meáin、Oírrはそれぞれ「大きな」「真ん中」「東」の意味がある。これらのアラン諸島は石灰質の岩盤だけで出来た島群である。 主要産業はジャガイモなどの農業と漁業。 岩盤で出来たこの島での農業は、土が風で飛ばされないように畑を石垣で囲み、岩盤を槌で砕き海藻と粘土を敷き詰めて土をつくることから始まった。 手編みのアランセーター（フィッシャーマンセーター）も有名。 交通手段としては、ダブリンからバスもしくは鉄道でゴールウェイまで行き、さらにバスと船を乗り継いで行く。又島内には貸自転車と馬車がある。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Aran redirecta aquí. Para la protagonista de Metroid, véase Samus Aran. Las islas Aran son un grupo de tres islas situadas en la desembocadura de la Bahía de Galway. La mayor de las islas se llama Inishmore, la mediana se llama Inishmaan (Inis Meáin) y la menor, situada al este Inisheer (Inis Oírr, o Inis Oirtheach).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Die Aran-Inseln sind eine Inselgruppe vor der Westküste Irlands in der Galway Bay. Die zum County Galway gehörenden Inseln heißen Inishmore (anglisiert, irisch Árainn oder Inis Mór), Inishmaan (Inis Meáin) und Inisheer (Inis Oírr oder Inis Oirtheach).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-9.7 53.1167)</geo:geometry>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/아란_제도"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Isole_Aran"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Les illes Aran en gaèlic irlandès: Oileáin Árann i en anglès Aran islands és un grup de tres illes situades a la sortida de la Badia Galway a la costa occidental d’Irlanda, a uns 18 km de l'illa d'Irlanda. Ocupen una superfície de 51 km2. Les illes del grup, d’oest a est, són: Inishmore (Árainn Mhór/Inis Mór) que és la més grossa; Inishmaan (Inis Meáin/Inis Meadhóin) la segona en extensió i Inisheer (Inis Thiar/Inis Oírr/Inis Oirthir) l’illa més petita. Culturalment conserven amb força l’ús de l’idioma celta gaèlic que en canvi ha anat davallant a la resta d’Irlanda. Les illes es diferencien geològicament de les zones adjacents granítiques de l'illa d'Irlanda pel fet de ser calcàries càrstiques Sobre aquestes illes es va fer una cèlebre pel•lícula documental de 1934 anomenada Man of Aran.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Aranøyene er en øygruppe ved munningen av Galwaybukten på vestkysten av Irland. Den største øya i øygruppen er Inishmore, . Inis Mór på gælisk betyr «Store øya». Árainn (Aran) er navnet som lokalt brukes om den største øya, men da den britiske oppmålingsmyndigheten kartla Irlands vestkyst, mente de dette var uryddig og valgte alternativet Inishmore (Inis Mór). Dette «offisielle» navnet har likevel kommet i relativt vanlig bruk.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">아란 제도는 아일랜드의 서쪽 골웨이 만에 위치한 3개의 섬을 일컫는다. 그중 가장 큰 섬은 이니슈모아이고, 두 번째로 큰 섬은 이니슈만이며 중간에 위치해 있다. 오른쪽에는 이중 가장 작은 섬인 이니슈어가 있다. 3개의 섬 모두에서 아일랜드어가 쓰인다. 아일랜드어로 Árann은 "긴 산맥"이다. 각 섬 이름에 있는 Inis는 섬이라는 뜻이며, Mór, Meáin, Oírr는 각각 '큰', '중간', '동쪽'이라는 의미를 담고 있다.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">アラン諸島（英: Aran Islands、愛: oileáin Árann）は、アイルランド島の西、ゴールウェイ湾に浮かぶ島々。アラン島と呼ばれることも多い。アラン諸島は3つの島からなり、西側から、イニシュモア（英: Inishmore、愛: Inis Mór）、イニシュマーン（英: Inishmaan、愛: Inis Meáin）、イニシィア（英: Inisheer、愛: Inis Oírr）と呼ばれる。アイルランド語でÁrannの意味は「長い山々」の意味で、現在の島の名前にあるInisは「島」の意味である。また、Mór、Meáin、Oírrはそれぞれ「大きな」「真ん中」「東」の意味がある。これらのアラン諸島は石灰質の岩盤だけで出来た島群である。 主要産業はジャガイモなどの農業と漁業。 岩盤で出来たこの島での農業は、土が風で飛ばされないように畑を石垣で囲み、岩盤を槌で砕き海藻と粘土を敷き詰めて土をつくることから始まった。 手編みのアランセーター（フィッシャーマンセーター）も有名。 交通手段としては、ダブリンからバスもしくは鉄道でゴールウェイまで行き、さらにバスと船を乗り継いで行く。又島内には貸自転車と馬車がある。</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.aranislands.com/"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">53.11666666666667 -9.7</grs:point>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Les îles d’Aran, en irlandais Oileáin Árann, en anglais Aran Islands, forment un archipel d'Irlande située à 18 kilomètres des côtes occidentales du pays, à la sortie de la baie de Galway. Géologiquement parlant, ces îles sont le prolongement de l’ensemble karstique des Burren dans le comté de Clare.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.aranisland.info/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Az Aran-szigetek egy három szigetből álló szigetcsoport Írország nyugati partjainál, a Galway-öbölben. A legnagyobb sziget Inishmore (ír nyelven Árainn vagy Inis Mór), a középső, és nagyságban a második Inishmaan (Inis Meáin / Inis Meadhóin), a legkeletibb és legkisebb pedig Inisheer (Inis Thiar vagy Inis Oírr / Inis Oirthir). A szigetek Írország azon kevés részéhez tartoznak, ahol még élő az ír nyelv. Ezt jelzik szigetek-, illetve a szigeteken található falvak és helynevek ír elnevezései is. Közigazgatásilag Galway megyéhez tartozik.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Aran_Islands"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">De Araneilanden zijn drie eilanden in de monding van de Baai van Galway in county Galway in Ierland. De inwoners op de drie eilanden leven van oudsher van de visserij, maar ook zomertoerisme is heden ten dage een belangrijke bron van inkomsten. De eilanden vallen binnen de Gaeltacht, het gebied waar de omgangstaal het Iers is. De bewoners spreken allen echter ook Engels.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">As ilhas de Aran são um arquipélago formado por três ilhas na confluência da Baía de Galway. A maior das três ilhas chama-se Inishmore, a ilha de tamanho médio chama-se Inishmaan (Inis Meáin) e a mais pequena, situada a este, tem o nome de Inisheer (Inis Oírr, o Inis Oirtheach).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/GaeltachtPlacesInCountyGalway"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/IslandsOfCountyGalway"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.guardian.co.uk/departments/travel/story/0,,2077834,00.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.aranislandferries.com"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Die Aran-Inseln sind eine Inselgruppe vor der Westküste Irlands in der Galway Bay. Die zum County Galway gehörenden Inseln heißen Inishmore (anglisiert, irisch Árainn oder Inis Mór), Inishmaan (Inis Meáin) und Inisheer (Inis Oírr oder Inis Oirtheach).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.marinetimes.ie/aran.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The Aran Islands or The Arans are a group of three islands located at the mouth of Galway Bay, on the west coast of Ireland. They constitute the barony of Aran in County Galway, Ireland. From west to east they are: Inishmore, the largest; Inishmaan, the second-largest; and Inisheer, the smallest. Irish is the main spoken language on all three islands, and is the language used naming the islands and their villages and townlands.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Îles_d'Aran"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Ilhas_de_Aran"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/2966947/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Аран_(острова)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">阿倫群島 是一個位於愛爾蘭西岸戈尔韦湾口，由三個島嶼組成的島群。该群岛地理上属于爱尔兰语区，行政上归戈尔韦郡管辖，有航班连接爱尔兰本岛。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">아란 제도는 아일랜드의 서쪽 골웨이 만에 위치한 3개의 섬을 일컫는다. 그중 가장 큰 섬은 이니슈모아이고, 두 번째로 큰 섬은 이니슈만이며 중간에 위치해 있다. 오른쪽에는 이중 가장 작은 섬인 이니슈어가 있다. 3개의 섬 모두에서 아일랜드어가 쓰인다. 아일랜드어로 Árann은 "긴 산맥"이다. 각 섬 이름에 있는 Inis는 섬이라는 뜻이며, Mór, Meáin, Oírr는 각각 '큰', '중간', '동쪽'이라는 의미를 담고 있다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Aran redirecta aquí. Para la protagonista de Metroid, véase Samus Aran. Las islas Aran son un grupo de tres islas situadas en la desembocadura de la Bahía de Galway. La mayor de las islas se llama Inishmore, la mediana se llama Inishmaan (Inis Meáin) y la menor, situada al este Inisheer (Inis Oírr, o Inis Oirtheach).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.wisc.edu/wisconsinpress/books/2147.htm"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Острова́ А́ран — группа из трёх островов, расположенных у западного побережья Ирландии. С востока омываются водами залива Голуэй. Входят в графство Голуэй. Население — 1225 человек.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.017n86"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Islands_of_County_Galway"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Les illes Aran en gaèlic irlandès: Oileáin Árann i en anglès Aran islands és un grup de tres illes situades a la sortida de la Badia Galway a la costa occidental d’Irlanda, a uns 18 km de l'illa d'Irlanda. Ocupen una superfície de 51 km2. Les illes del grup, d’oest a est, són: Inishmore (Árainn Mhór/Inis Mór) que és la més grossa; Inishmaan (Inis Meáin/Inis Meadhóin) la segona en extensió i Inisheer (Inis Thiar/Inis Oírr/Inis Oirthir) l’illa més petita.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">As ilhas de Aran são um arquipélago formado por três ilhas na confluência da Baía de Galway. A maior das três ilhas chama-se Inishmore, a ilha de tamanho médio chama-se Inishmaan (Inis Meáin) e a mais pequena, situada a este, tem o nome de Inisheer (Inis Oírr, o Inis Oirtheach).</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Aran-Inseln"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Aransaaret on kolmen saaren ryhmä Irlannin länsirannikolla. Se kuuluu Galwayn kreivikuntaan. Saaret ovat Inis Mór, Inis Meáin ja Inis Óirr. Englanninkieliset nimet ovat Inishmore, Inishmaan ja Inisheer. Suurin saari on Inishmore ja sillä sijaitseva Kilronanin kylä on Aransaarien suurin asutuskeksus. Aransaaret ovat iirinkielistä aluetta. Niiden yhteen laskettu asukasluku on 1 218.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">阿倫群島</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.overlander.tv/2008/aran-islands-irish-travel-video-guide/"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Aran-Inseln</rdfs:label>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/42/Aran_Islands.PNG"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Aranöarna, tre öar nära Irlands västkust, sydväst om Galway: Inis Mór, Inis Meáin och Inis Oírr. De tre öarna har totalt en yta på 47 km² och 800 inv (2001). Denna ögrupps befolkning har lyckats hålla liv i iriskan, som ännu idag är vardagsspråket. Öarna ingår i grevskapet Galway. John Millington Synges irländska klassiker The Aran Islands (1907), utkom på svenska med titeln Aranöarna 1996. Boken är en skildring av författarens fyra långa besök på öarna och mötet med dess säregna öbor. Synge bodde på Inis Meáin under flera somrar och hämtade inspiration till många av sina verk där.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AranIslands"/>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">53.1167</geo:lat>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The Aran Islands or The Arans are a group of three islands located at the mouth of Galway Bay, on the west coast of Ireland. They constitute the barony of Aran in County Galway, Ireland. From west to east they are: Inishmore, the largest; Inishmaan, the second-largest; and Inisheer, the smallest. Irish is the main spoken language on all three islands, and is the language used naming the islands and their villages and townlands.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Illes Aran</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/アラン諸島"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Az Aran-szigetek egy három szigetből álló szigetcsoport Írország nyugati partjainál, a Galway-öbölben. A legnagyobb sziget Inishmore (ír nyelven Árainn vagy Inis Mór), a középső, és nagyságban a második Inishmaan (Inis Meáin / Inis Meadhóin), a legkeletibb és legkisebb pedig Inisheer (Inis Thiar vagy Inis Oírr / Inis Oirthir). A szigetek Írország azon kevés részéhez tartoznak, ahol még élő az ír nyelv. Ezt jelzik szigetek-, illetve a szigeteken található falvak és helynevek ír elnevezései is.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Important_Bird_Areas_of_the_Republic_of_Ireland"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aran_Islands?oldid=494793188"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">阿倫群島 是一個位於愛爾蘭西岸戈尔韦湾口，由三個島嶼組成的島群。该群岛地理上属于爱尔兰语区，行政上归戈尔韦郡管辖，有航班连接爱尔兰本岛。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Aranöarna, tre öar nära Irlands västkust, sydväst om Galway: Inis Mór, Inis Meáin och Inis Oírr. De tre öarna har totalt en yta på 47 km² och 800 inv (2001). Denna ögrupps befolkning har lyckats hålla liv i iriskan, som ännu idag är vardagsspråket. Öarna ingår i grevskapet Galway. John Millington Synges irländska klassiker The Aran Islands (1907), utkom på svenska med titeln Aranöarna 1996. Boken är en skildring av författarens fyra långa besök på öarna och mötet med dess säregna öbor.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/%C3%81rainn">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Isles_of_Arran">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageDisambiguates rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Isles">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Muireann_Nic_Amhlaoibh">
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aran_Islands">
    <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://data.nytimes.com/3410130115886465941">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ted_Fest">
    <dbpprop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Oile%C3%A1in_%C3%81rann">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Island">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageDisambiguates rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/Aran_Islands">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_islands_bibliography">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Mor">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands_bibliography">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands_Bibliography">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_All_Ireland_Talent_Show_(series_1)">
    <dbpprop:winnerOrigin rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Aran_Islands"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
