<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC">
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">A British Broadcasting Corporation ("Corporação Britânica de Radiodifusão", mais conhecida pelo acrônimo BBC), é uma emissora pública de rádio e televisão do Reino Unido fundada em 1922. Possui uma boa reputação nacional e internacional (sendo vista por alguns críticos como parcial, tendenciando o liberalismo). Por vezes é chamada afectuosamente pelos ingleses como Beeb, The Corporation ou Auntie. Durante muitos anos foi o único fornecedor de rádio e depois de televisão do Reino Unido.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:services rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Online"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">La British Broadcasting Corporation (Corporació Britànica de Difusió), més coneguda com a BBC, és la primera empresa de televisió i ràdio del Regne Unit. A més, és la més gran de transmissió de notícies d'arreu del món. Produeix serveis de programes i informació, transmetent a la televisió, a la ràdio i a Internet; sent una de les cadenes de notícies més respectades del món. És independent de controls comercials i polítics operant sota un estatut real que li garanteix la independència. Té una plantilla de 25.500 empleats i un pressupost anual de 4 bilions de £. L'any 2004 fou guardonat amb el Premi Antonio Asensio de Periodisme.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) is a British public service broadcaster headquartered at Broadcasting House in the City of Westminster, London. It is the largest broadcaster in the world, with about 23,000 staff. Its main responsibility is to provide impartial public service broadcasting in the United Kingdom, Channel Islands and Isle of Man.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:revenue rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/poundSterling">4.741</dbpedia-owl:revenue>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/eb/BBC.svg"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Publicly_funded_broadcasters"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/annualreport/pdf/bbc_exec_sopps_2009_10.pdf"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/CompaniesBasedInLondon"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBC"/>
    <dbpprop:predecessor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Broadcasting_Company"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/BBC"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">British Broadcasting Corporation, mest kjent under forkortelsen BBC, er en britisk radio- og TV-kringkaster. I Storbritannia blir organisasjonen ofte kalt The Beeb eller Auntie ('tante', fordi den tidligere var kjent for å ha en oppdragende stil i mange av sine programmer). Selskapet har omfattende egenproduksjon av programmer. BBC blir av mange oppfattet som et av de mest seriøse medieselskapene i verden, med en nøytral og selvstendig synsvinkel. BBC påtar seg rollen som allmennkringkaster i Storbritannia, og det norske NRK, i likhet med de fleste andre eldre fjernsynskanaler i Europa, sammenligner seg derfor ofte med BBC. 2. november 1936 begynte BBC de første regulære TV-sendingene i verden. Før ITV ble opprettet i 1955 hadde BBC monopol på radio- og TV-sendinger i Storbritannia. BBC blir, på samme måte som NRK, finansiert med lisensmidler. Riktignok blir enkelte deler av BBCs programtilbud betalt av andre; for eksempel World Service, som blir betalt av det britiske utenriksdepartementet. Dessuten har BBC i de senere år tjent endel på sin kommersielle del, som har solgt DVD-kopier av deres store antall programmer. BBC blir, særlig etter opphevingen av monopolet, til stadighet kritisert for å ikke ha en nøytral innstilling. Særlig er det vanlig at det britiske regjeringspartiet klager på at de favoriserer opposisjonen; dette skjer uansett hvilket parti det er som sitter ved makten. Til tider har det kommet klager fra begge sider på ett og samme innslag, noe BBCs ledelse har tolket dithen at nøytralitetskravet er oppfylt enten man fornærmer begge sider eller gleder begge sider. I 2004 ble BBCs ry for nøytralitet skadet av Hutton-rapporten, som tok for seg skandalen omkring unøyaktige rapporter om masseødeleggelsesvåpen i Irak etter David Kellys selvmord i 2003. Rapporten førte til at styreformannen og generaldirektøren, samt en journalist, måtte si opp sine stillinger. BBC har i stor grad gjenopprettet tilliten, blant annet ved at de ansvarlige måtte gå.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">British Broadcasting Corporation je rozhlasová a televizní společnost plnící funkci veřejnoprávního vysílání ve Velké Británii. Zajišťuje vysílání několika britských rozhlasových a televizních stanic i vysílání do zahraničí. Je všeobecně uznávána pro kvalitu a objektivitu svého zpravodajství. Byla založena pod jménem British Broadcasting Company roku 1922, od roku 1927 nese jméno British Broadcasting Corporation.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) is a British public service broadcaster headquartered at Broadcasting House in the City of Westminster, London. It is the largest broadcaster in the world, with about 23,000 staff. Its main responsibility is to provide impartial public service broadcasting in the United Kingdom, Channel Islands and Isle of Man. The BBC is a semi-autonomous public service broadcaster that operates under a Royal Charter and a Licence and Agreement from the Home Secretary. Within the United Kingdom its work is funded principally by an annual television licence fee, which is charged to all British households, companies and organisations using any type of equipment to record and/or receive live television broadcasts; the level of the fee is set annually by the British Government and agreed by Parliament. Outside the UK, the BBC World Service has provided services by direct broadcasting and re-transmission contracts by sound radio since the inauguration of the BBC Empire Service in December 1932, and more recently by television and online. Though sharing some of the facilities of the domestic services, particularly for news and current affairs output, the World Service has a separate Managing Director, and its operating costs have historically been funded mainly by direct grants from the British government. These grants were determined independently of the domestic licence fee and were usually awarded from the budget of the Foreign and Commonwealth Office. As such, the BBC's international content has traditionally represented – at least in part – an effective foreign policy tool of the British Government. The recent BBC World Service spending review has announced plans for the funding for the world service to be drawn from the domestic licence fee. The Corporation's "guaranteed" income from the licence fee and the World Service grants are supplemented by profits from commercial operations through a wholly owned subsidiary, BBC Worldwide Ltd. The company's activities include programme- and format-sales, magazines including the Radio Times and book publishing. The BBC also earns additional income from selling certain programme-making services through BBC Studios and Post Production Ltd. , formerly BBC Resources Ltd, another wholly owned trading subsidiary of the corporation. The BBC is sometimes referred to as "Auntie" and "the Beeb". The former is also used to refer to the BBC's sister corporation, the Australian Broadcasting Corporation.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:BBC"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:British_brands"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">BBC [laus. engl. ' sanana biːbiːˈsiː] (British Broadcasting Corporation) on Ison-Britannian julkinen, vuonna 1922 perustettu yleisradioyhtiö ja tuotantoyhtiö. Yhtiöllä on useita radio- ja televisiokanavia, ja se on todennäköisesti maailman tunnetuin yleisradioyhtiö. BBC käynnisti säännölliset televisiolähetykset ensimmäisenä maailmassa vuonna 1936 ja BBC:n radio- ja televisioteitse välitettyjä uutislähetyksiä katsotaan ympäri maailmaa. Yritys on alallaan maailman suurin. BBC työllistää pelkästään Isossa-Britanniassa noin 26 000 ihmistä. BBC:n motto on "Nation Shall Speak Peace Unto Nation".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:product rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Web_portal"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:European_Broadcasting_Union_members"/>
    <dbpprop:services rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Television"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/annualreport/pdf/2004-05/bbc_2004_05.pdf"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Public_broadcasting"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:service rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Online"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">A British Broadcasting Corporation, röviden: BBC egy állami tulajdonú, kvázi független brit közszolgálati műsorszolgáltató, egyben a világ legnagyobb műsorszolgáltatója. Csak az Egyesült Királyságban 24 000 alkalmazottat foglalkoztat, költségvetése eléri a 4 milliárd fontot (kb. 1500 milliárd forint). Működési költségeit elsősorban a brit állampolgárok által fizetett televízió üzembentartási díj fedezi. 1922-ben alakult meg British Broadcasting Company Ltd néven, majd 1927-ben került állami tulajdonba. A kísérleti televízióadások 1932-ben kezdődtek meg, majd 1936-tól megindultak a rendszeres adások. A II. világháború alatt 1946-ig az adás szünetelt. 1964-ben indult a BBC 2 adása, és 1967-ben kezdődött meg a színes műsorsugárzás. A BBC ismeretterjesztő és szórakoztató televízió- és rádióműsorokat készít, emellett különböző információs szolgáltatásokat is nyújt az Interneten keresztül. A cég célkitűzése: „informálni, oktatni és szórakoztatni”. A társaságot az ún. Board of governors felügyeli, melynek tagjait a Királynő nevezi ki, a kormány ajánlását figyelembe véve. Ez a rendszer jelenleg átalakítás alatt van, az új felügyelő testület 2007 januárjától a BBC Trust lesz. A BBC jelenleg nagy erőkkel dolgozik a digitális rádió- és televíziótechnológia elterjesztésén és alkalmazásán.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/annualreport/pdf/2002-03/bbcannualreport_200203.pdf"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Би-би-си"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_company"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:service rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Radio"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">BBC</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">British Broadcasting Corporation</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:service rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Television"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/BBC"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Broadcasting_Corporation"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">De British Broadcasting Corporation, afgekort BBC, maar in de gesproken omgangstaal van het eigen land vaak aangeduid met de nickname Beeb, is de publieke omroep van het Verenigd Koninkrijk. De in 1922 opgerichte BBC is een van de oudste zendgemachtigden ter wereld. Programma's worden onder andere aangeboden via de televisiezenders BBC One, BBC Two, BBC Three, BBC Four, BBC Entertainment, BBC News 24 en BBC World, en via een aantal radiozenders waaronder BBC 1 t/m 7.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:British_radio"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">BBC là thông tấn xã quốc gia của Vương quốc Liên hiệp Anh và Bắc Ireland. Sản phẩm của BBC là bao gồm các chương trình và thông tin trên TV, trên đài phát thanh và trên Internet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">BBC [laus. engl. ' sanana biːbiːˈsiː] (British Broadcasting Corporation) on Ison-Britannian julkinen, vuonna 1922 perustettu yleisradioyhtiö ja tuotantoyhtiö. Yhtiöllä on useita radio- ja televisiokanavia, ja se on todennäköisesti maailman tunnetuin yleisradioyhtiö. BBC käynnisti säännölliset televisiolähetykset ensimmäisenä maailmassa vuonna 1936 ja BBC:n radio- ja televisioteitse välitettyjä uutislähetyksiä katsotaan ympäri maailmaa. Yritys on alallaan maailman suurin.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">La British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) fondée en 1922 est un organe de production et de diffusion de programmes de radio-télévision britannique. Ayant son siège au Royaume-Uni, c’est un non-departmental public body en charge des média. La BBC bénéficie d’une réputation d’excellence culturelle, et est parfois affectueusement appelée « The Beeb » ou « Auntie » (langage enfantin pour tante) par les Britanniques. Pendant longtemps, elle est restée la seule société diffusant des programmes de télévision et de radio au Royaume-Uni. Au début du XXI siècle, elle reçoit environ 3,6 milliards par année et, pour la période 2008-2009, ses revenus mondiaux ont été de 1 milliard de dollars. C’est la plus puissante société de diffusion au monde en termes de revenu brut et de téléspectateurs. Avant la venue de ITV (Independent Television) en 1955 et des radios locales privées dans les années 1970, elle détenait le monopole de diffusion.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Broadcasting_Corporation"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1922_introductions"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/BBC"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:owner rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Crown"/>
    <dbpprop:founder rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Villiers,_6th_Earl_of_Clarendon"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">英国广播公司（英语：British Broadcasting Corporation），簡稱BBC，是英国的一家资金主要来自英国国民缴纳的电视牌照费且独立运作的公共媒体，长久以来一直被认为是全球最受尊敬的媒体之一。在相当长的一段时间内，BBC一直垄断着英国的电视、电台。在1955年英国独立电视台和1973年英国独立电台成立之前，BBC一直是全英国唯一的电视、电台广播公司。今天BBC除了是一家在全球拥有高知名度的媒体，还提供其他各种服务，包括书籍出版、报刊、英语教学、交响乐团和互联网新闻服务。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Villiers,_6th_Earl_of_Clarendon"/>
    <dbpprop:keyPeople rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Chris_Patten"/>
    <dbpprop:products xml:lang="en">Broadcasting, radio, web portals</dbpprop:products>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">英国广播公司</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/英国放送協会"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/eb/BBC.svg/200px-BBC.svg.png"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0g5lhl7"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">영국방송협회 또는 BBC(British Broadcasting Corporation)는 영국의 국영 방송국이다. 시사 프로그램을 텔레비전과 라디오 그리고 인터넷을 통해 전 세계에 방영한다. 채널은 BBC1, BBC2, BBC3, BBC4, CBBC, Ceebeebies, BBC News, BBC Parliament로 나누어져있다. BBC는 시청자 수로 따졌을 때 세계 최대의 방송국이다. 영국에 2만 6천 여명의 직원을 고용하고 있다. 1년 예산만 해도 약 40억 영국 파운드이다. BBC의 주력 국내 방영 서비스는 BBC One과 BBC Two, BBC 라디오 1, 2, 3, 4 그리고 5 라이브는 아날로그 주파수로 송신하며 나머지 채널들은 디지털로 송신한다. BBC 의회는 영국의 유일한 정치 전문 채널이다.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">La BBC (acronimo di British Broadcasting Corporation, anche informalmente chiamata dai britannici auntie – zietta, ma molto più spesso Beeb, soprattutto sui quotidiani e sui tabloid britannici), fondata nel 1922, è la più grande e autorevole società radiotelevisiva del Regno Unito con sede a Londra. Offre un servizio regolare di trasmissioni e produce anche propri programmi e servizi di informazione.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">英国广播公司（英语：British Broadcasting Corporation），簡稱BBC，是英国的一家资金主要来自英国国民缴纳的电视牌照费且独立运作的公共媒体，长久以来一直被认为是全球最受尊敬的媒体之一。在相当长的一段时间内，BBC一直垄断着英国的电视、电台。在1955年英国独立电视台和1973年英国独立电台成立之前，BBC一直是全英国唯一的电视、电台广播公司。今天BBC除了是一家在全球拥有高知名度的媒体，还提供其他各种服务，包括书籍出版、报刊、英语教学、交响乐团和互联网新闻服务。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Брита́нская широковеща́тельная корпора́ция, сокр. «Би-би-си́» (англ. &amp;#160;British Broadcasting Corporation, сокр. BBC) — комплекс радио-, интернет- и телевещания Великобритании. Корпорация осуществляет как внутреннее, так и внешнее Интернет-, радио- и телевещание, проводимое Всемирной службой Би-би-си. Корпорация не является государственным СМИ, а представляет собой общественную организацию с контрольным советом, состоящим из 12 попечителей, назначаемых английской королевой.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Reith,_1st_Baron_Reith"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">영국방송협회 또는 BBC(British Broadcasting Corporation)는 영국의 국영 방송국이다. 시사 프로그램을 텔레비전과 라디오 그리고 인터넷을 통해 전 세계에 방영한다. 채널은 BBC1, BBC2, BBC3, BBC4, CBBC, Ceebeebies, BBC News, BBC Parliament로 나누어져있다. BBC는 시청자 수로 따졌을 때 세계 최대의 방송국이다. 영국에 2만 6천 여명의 직원을 고용하고 있다. 1년 예산만 해도 약 40억 영국 파운드이다. BBC의 주력 국내 방영 서비스는 BBC One과 BBC Two, BBC 라디오 1, 2, 3, 4 그리고 5 라이브는 아날로그 주파수로 송신하며 나머지 채널들은 디지털로 송신한다. BBC 의회는 영국의 유일한 정치 전문 채널이다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:owningCompany rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Crown"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/annualreport/pdf/2000-01/bbcannualreport_200001.pdf"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/BBC"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:keyPerson rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Chris_Patten"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:keyPerson rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Director-General_of_the_BBC"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">De British Broadcasting Corporation, afgekort BBC, maar in de gesproken omgangstaal van het eigen land vaak aangeduid met de nickname Beeb, is de publieke omroep van het Verenigd Koninkrijk. De in 1922 opgerichte BBC is een van de oudste zendgemachtigden ter wereld. Programma's worden onder andere aangeboden via de televisiezenders BBC One, BBC Two, BBC Three, BBC Four, BBC Entertainment, BBC News 24 en BBC World, en via een aantal radiozenders waaronder BBC 1 t/m 7. De BBC World Service zendt programma's uit in meer dan 30 verschillende talen en wordt in de westerse wereld in het algemeen beschouwd als een gezaghebbende, objectieve nieuwsbron. De BBC zendt uit via grondstations, via satellieten en via het internet. De omroep wordt in eigen land voornamelijk gefinancierd uit kijk- en luistergeld en de opbrengsten van merchandising, televisie- en formatrechten, maar in het geheel niet uit reclame-inkomsten. In Nederland en België zijn op de meeste kabelnetten de televisiestations BBC One, BBC Two en BBC World te ontvangen; de World Service op de radio wordt ook vaak via de kabel doorgegeven en zendt verder uit via korte golf en satelliet. Tot 2011 was de World Service in het grootste deel van Nederland, België en Noord-Frankrijk ook op de middengolf te ontvangen. BBC Radio 4 is te ontvangen via de lange golf (198 kHz), en BBC Radio Five Live via de middengolf (693 en 909 kHz); verder ook via het internet, satelliet en sommige kabelnetten.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PuBliclyFundedBroadcasters"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Multilingual_broadcasters"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Public_corporations_of_the_United_Kingdom_Government"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) är ett statligt brittiskt public service-företag för TV- och radioverksamhet, i första hand finansierat genom licensintäkter. Företaget stod bakom den första nationella TV-kanalen i världen och den första TV-kanalen med reguljära sändningar utanför USA. BBC brukar kallas Public Service-modern eftersom man myntade uttrycket Public Service vars innebörd är att man har särskilda förpliktelser gentemot allmänheten reglerade i ett avtal med staten. Public service, vilket även innefattar de kommersiella kanalerna ITV, Channel 4 och Channel 5, är en benämning som senare kopierats med varierande innebörd av många länder däribland Sverige där SVT / SR gjort sin egen tolkning av uttrycket.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/bbctrust/assets/files/pdf/regulatory_framework/charter_agreement/bbc_royal_charter.pdf"/>
    <dbpprop:founder xml:lang="en">John Reith</dbpprop:founder>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">British Broadcasting Corporation, mest kjent under forkortelsen BBC, er en britisk radio- og TV-kringkaster. I Storbritannia blir organisasjonen ofte kalt The Beeb eller Auntie ('tante', fordi den tidligere var kjent for å ha en oppdragende stil i mange av sine programmer). Selskapet har omfattende egenproduksjon av programmer. BBC blir av mange oppfattet som et av de mest seriøse medieselskapene i verden, med en nøytral og selvstendig synsvinkel.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">BBC là thông tấn xã quốc gia của Vương quốc Liên hiệp Anh và Bắc Ireland. Sản phẩm của BBC là bao gồm các chương trình và thông tin trên TV, trên đài phát thanh và trên Internet.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">英国放送協会（えいこくほうそうきょうかい、イギリス放送協会、英: The British Broadcasting Corporation, BBC）はイギリスの公共放送局。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/BBC"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Broadcasting_Corporation"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:keyPeople rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mark_Thompson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">La BBC (acronimo di British Broadcasting Corporation, anche informalmente chiamata dai britannici auntie – zietta, ma molto più spesso Beeb, soprattutto sui quotidiani e sui tabloid britannici), fondata nel 1922, è la più grande e autorevole società radiotelevisiva del Regno Unito con sede a Londra. Offre un servizio regolare di trasmissioni e produce anche propri programmi e servizi di informazione. Il motto dell'azienda è "Nation Shall Speak Peace Unto Nation" (La nazione parlerà di pace verso la nazione).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">BBC (skrót od British Broadcasting Corporation, Brytyjska Korporacja Nadawcza) – główny brytyjski publiczny nadawca radiowo-telewizyjny, największa tego rodzaju instytucja na świecie. Powstała w 1922 r. z inicjatywy sześciu firm zajmujących się produkcją sprzętu radiowego, które chciały prowadzić przy jej pomocy eksperymentalne nadawanie. Korporacja utrzymuje się z produkcji własnych programów, abonamentu telewizyjnego (osiem kanałów telewizyjnych) i zysków należących do niej przedsiębiorstw. W Wielkiej Brytanii nie emituje reklam ani płatnych ogłoszeń firm czy instytucji. Jej część, BBC Worldwide, działa na zasadach komercyjnych.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">British Broadcasting Corporation je rozhlasová a televizní společnost plnící funkci veřejnoprávního vysílání ve Velké Británii. Zajišťuje vysílání několika britských rozhlasových a televizních stanic i vysílání do zahraničí. Je všeobecně uznávána pro kvalitu a objektivitu svého zpravodajství. Byla založena pod jménem British Broadcasting Company roku 1922, od roku 1927 nese jméno British Broadcasting Corporation.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundingDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1927-01-01</dbpedia-owl:foundingDate>
    <dbpprop:revenue xml:lang="en">£4.741 bn</dbpprop:revenue>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:logo>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">La British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) fondée en 1922 est un organe de production et de diffusion de programmes de radio-télévision britannique. Ayant son siège au Royaume-Uni, c’est un non-departmental public body en charge des média. La BBC bénéficie d’une réputation d’excellence culturelle, et est parfois affectueusement appelée « The Beeb » ou « Auntie » (langage enfantin pour tante) par les Britanniques.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Брита́нська Телерадіомо́вна Корпора́ція (англ. British Broadcasting Corporation, або просто ВВС — британська телерадіомовна компанія. За кількістю слухачів найбільша телерадіомовна компанія у світі. У штаті корпорації працює більш ніж 26 000 осіб у всьому світі, в тому числі і в Україні. Керуючий орган корпорації — «Бі-бі-сі Траст», однак в її установчих документах зазначено, що компанія незалежна від стороннього впливу й підзвітна тільки перед глядачами й слухачами. Основний девіз компанії — «інформувати, навчати і розважати». Річний бюджет 4 мільярди фунтів.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Business"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Companies_based_in_London"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:product rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Radio"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">British Broadcasting  Corporation (BBC)</foaf:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpprop:locationCountry xml:lang="en">United Kingdom</dbpprop:locationCountry>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">A British Broadcasting Corporation, röviden: BBC egy állami tulajdonú, kvázi független brit közszolgálati műsorszolgáltató, egyben a világ legnagyobb műsorszolgáltatója. Csak az Egyesült Királyságban 24 000 alkalmazottat foglalkoztat, költségvetése eléri a 4 milliárd fontot (kb. 1500 milliárd forint). Működési költségeit elsősorban a brit állampolgárok által fizetett televízió üzembentartási díj fedezi.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:owner xml:lang="en">The Crown</dbpprop:owner>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:BBC_radio"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:keyPerson rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Trust"/>
    <dbpprop:foundation rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1927-01-01</dbpprop:foundation>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Die British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) ist eine britische Rundfunkanstalt, die mehrere Hörfunk- und Fernsehprogramme sowie eine umfangreiche und einflussreiche Website betreibt.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">La British Broadcasting Corporation (Corporació Britànica de Difusió), més coneguda com a BBC, és la primera empresa de televisió i ràdio del Regne Unit. A més, és la més gran de transmissió de notícies d'arreu del món. Produeix serveis de programes i informació, transmetent a la televisió, a la ràdio i a Internet; sent una de les cadenes de notícies més respectades del món. És independent de controls comercials i polítics operant sota un estatut real que li garanteix la independència.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Companies_established_in_1922"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">英国放送協会（えいこくほうそうきょうかい、イギリス放送協会、英: The British Broadcasting Corporation, BBC）はイギリスの公共放送局。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:keyPerson rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mark_Thompson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundingYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1927-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:foundingYear>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">A British Broadcasting Corporation ("Corporação Britânica de Radiodifusão", mais conhecida pelo acrônimo BBC), é uma emissora pública de rádio e televisão do Reino Unido fundada em 1922. Possui uma boa reputação nacional e internacional (sendo vista por alguns críticos como parcial, tendenciando o liberalismo). Por vezes é chamada afectuosamente pelos ingleses como Beeb, The Corporation ou Auntie. Durante muitos anos foi o único fornecedor de rádio e depois de televisão do Reino Unido. O seu lema é "Nation Shall Speak Peace Unto Nation". Antes era chamada de British Broadcasting Company Ltd. , nome que permaneceu até 1927.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">British Broadcasting  Corporation</dbpprop:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1922_establishments_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">BBC</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">BBC</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Public_broadcasting"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/BritishBrands"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BBC?oldid=495263396"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:predecessor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Broadcasting_Company"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Брита́нська Телерадіомо́вна Корпора́ція (англ. British Broadcasting Corporation, або просто ВВС — британська телерадіомовна компанія. За кількістю слухачів найбільша телерадіомовна компанія у світі. У штаті корпорації працює більш ніж 26 000 осіб у всьому світі, в тому числі і в Україні. Керуючий орган корпорації — «Бі-бі-сі Траст», однак в її установчих документах зазначено, що компанія незалежна від стороннього впливу й підзвітна тільки перед глядачами й слухачами.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">BBC (skrót od British Broadcasting Corporation, Brytyjska Korporacja Nadawcza) – główny brytyjski publiczny nadawca radiowo-telewizyjny, największa tego rodzaju instytucja na świecie. Powstała w 1922 r. z inicjatywy sześciu firm zajmujących się produkcją sprzętu radiowego, które chciały prowadzić przy jej pomocy eksperymentalne nadawanie. Korporacja utrzymuje się z produkcji własnych programów, abonamentu telewizyjnego (osiem kanałów telewizyjnych) i zysków należących do niej przedsiębiorstw.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Die British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) ist eine britische Rundfunkanstalt, die mehrere Hörfunk- und Fernsehprogramme sowie eine umfangreiche und einflussreiche Website betreibt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC) är ett statligt brittiskt public service-företag för TV- och radioverksamhet, i första hand finansierat genom licensintäkter. Företaget stod bakom den första nationella TV-kanalen i världen och den första TV-kanalen med reguljära sändningar utanför USA. BBC brukar kallas Public Service-modern eftersom man myntade uttrycket Public Service vars innebörd är att man har särskilda förpliktelser gentemot allmänheten reglerade i ett avtal med staten.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:areaServed xml:lang="en">Worldwide</dbpprop:areaServed>
    <dbpprop:industry xml:lang="en">Mass media</dbpprop:industry>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/annualreport/pdf/2003-04/bbcannualreport_200304.pdf"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Broadcasting_Corporation"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Брита́нская широковеща́тельная корпора́ция, сокр. «Би-би-си́» (англ.  British Broadcasting Corporation, сокр. BBC) — комплекс радио-, интернет- и телевещания Великобритании. Корпорация осуществляет как внутреннее, так и внешнее Интернет-, радио- и телевещание, проводимое Всемирной службой Би-би-си. Корпорация не является государственным СМИ, а представляет собой общественную организацию с контрольным советом, состоящим из 12 попечителей, назначаемых английской королевой.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://downloads.bbc.co.uk/annualreport/pdf/2006-07/bbcexec_eng_200607.pdf"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/mobile/index.html"/>
    <dbpprop:locationCity xml:lang="en">London, England</dbpprop:locationCity>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Television_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpprop:services rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BBC_Radio"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-network-noun-2"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">La British Broadcasting Corporation (Corporación Británica de Radiodifusión), más conocida como BBC, es el servicio público de comunicación del Reino Unido. Tiene su sede en la Broadcasting House en Westminster, Londres. Es el mayor grupo de comunicación del mundo con cerca de 23.000 empleados. Sus funciones son las de retransmitir televisión y radio de forma pública en el Reino Unido, la Isla de Man y las Islas del Canal.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/BBC"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">British Broadcasting Corporation</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">La British Broadcasting Corporation (Corporación Británica de Radiodifusión), más conocida como BBC, es el servicio público de comunicación del Reino Unido. Tiene su sede en la Broadcasting House en Westminster, Londres. Es el mayor grupo de comunicación del mundo con cerca de 23.000 empleados. Sus funciones son las de retransmitir televisión y radio de forma pública en el Reino Unido, la Isla de Man y las Islas del Canal. Es un ente público y autónomo establecido en 1922 por un Decreto Real que garantiza su independencia del control comercial y político. En el Reino Unido se financia mediante una licencia de televisión que paga cada hogar, compañía y organización en donde haya cualquier equipamiento capaz de recibir y/o grabar las emisiones de radio y televisión. El precio de esta licencia es fijado anualmente por el Gobierno británico y acordado en el Parlamento. En 2010 el precio por hogar fue de £145.50. Fuera del Reino Unido opera bajo el indicativo de BBC World Service y su labor es la de retransmitir por radio y televisión todos sus productos y más recientemente, también por internet. A pesar de compartir esctructuras, especialmente el servicio de noticias, el World Service opera independientemente y tiene un Director Ejecutivo propio. Se financia principalmente por fondos públicos del Gobierno británico, independientemente de la financiación proveniente de la licencia de televisión. La otra fuente de financiación de la Corporación son mediante sus filiales comerciales, BBC Worldwide Ltd. (venta de programas y formatos, publicación de revistas y libros) y por el alquiler de sus estudios de televisión, organizados en la filial BBC Studios and Post Production Ltd. (anteriormente BBC Resources Ltd.).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Бі-Бі-Сі</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Company"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
