<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cross_Spikes_Club">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Castle_Koon">
    <dbpprop:testSite rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Escholtz_Islands">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://data.nytimes.com/15797497598777974741">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Island">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_(Marshall_Islands)">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_atoll">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pikinni_Atoll">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bikini_Atoll">
    <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll">
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Бікіні (атол)</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Atoll_de_Bikini"/>
    <dbpprop:longew xml:lang="en">E</dbpprop:longew>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Bikini-Atoll</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:country rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marshall_Islands"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NuClearTestSites"/>
    <dbpprop:mapsize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">180</dbpprop:mapsize>
    <dbpprop:imageMap xml:lang="en">Bikini 2244493428 13643c6505 o.jpg</dbpprop:imageMap>
    <dbpprop:coordinatesType xml:lang="en">region:MH_type:isle</dbpprop:coordinatesType>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Bikini è una municipalità delle Isole Marshall con 13 abitanti. La municipalità è costituita dall'omonimo atollo, costituito da 36 isolette, nella Catena delle Ralik, nell'Oceano Pacifico. L'atollo è costituito da una ampia laguna (594,2 km).</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FormerPopulatedPlacesInOceania"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanNuClearTestSites"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4a/Cercle_rouge_100%25.svg/200px-Cercle_rouge_100%25.svg.png"/>
    <dbpprop:areaLandSqMi rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2</dbpprop:areaLandSqMi>
    <dbpprop:mark xml:lang="en">Cercle rouge 100%.svg</dbpprop:mark>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.01d6s9"/>
    <dbpprop:position xml:lang="en">right</dbpprop:position>
    <dbpprop:otherName xml:lang="en">Pikinni Atoll</dbpprop:otherName>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpprop:longm rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">23</dbpprop:longm>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Bikini (znany również jako Pikinni) – atol w archipelagu Wysp Marshalla. Ma on powierzchnię około 6 km² i składa się z 36 wysepek, które otaczają lagunę o powierzchni 594 km². Pierwszym Europejczykiem, który ujrzał atol (a następnie naniósł go na mapy) był w drugiej dekadzie XIX w. rosyjski podróżnik i żeglarz Otto Kotzebue. Nazwał go atolem Eschscholtza - dla upamiętnienia rosyjskiego przyrodnika Johanna Friedricha von Eschscholtza, który towarzyszył mu w jego pierwszej samodzielnej ekspedycji na wody Pacyfiku. W latach 1946-1958 atol był miejscem prowadzenia przez USA ponad dwudziestu prób z bronią jądrową, w tym detonacji największej amerykańskiej bomby wodorowej. Na czas prób jądrowych mieszkańcy Bikini zostali przeniesieni na atol Rongerik, skąd powrócili na swój rodzimy atol na przełomie lat 1960 i 1970. Potem jednak ponownie ich przesiedlono na wyspę Kili z uwagi na utrzymujące się skażenie gleby promieniotwórczym cezem, który wchłaniany przez palmy kokosowe stał się przyczyną chorób nowotworowych wśród mieszkańców wyspy, dla których orzech kokosowy stanowił podstawę diety. Skażenie pożywienia było także przyczyną większej umieralności wśród niemowląt. Za uszczerbek na zdrowiu Bikińczyków zapłacił rząd USA, któremu sąd wyznaczył karę 100 mln dolarów. Podjęto także operację oczyszczania atolu, podczas której zebrano około 300 000 m³ radioaktywnej gleby. Organizacje ekologiczne nie maja dostępu do dokumentów zawierających dane z informacją dokąd przewieziono radioaktywna glebę. W 1998 roku na wyspie Bikini (największej wyspie atolu) otwarto bazę nurkową, w której jednorazowo może przebywać 12 nurków. Opłaty za korzystanie z bazy wpływają do kasy wyspiarskiego rządu Bikini z siedzibą na wyspie Kili. W wodach laguny spoczywa wiele wraków okrętów z okresu II wojny światowej zatopionych w wyniku prób atomowych w ramach Operacji Crossroads, co stanowi wielką atrakcję dla amatorów nurkowania. W 2010 roku atol Bikini został wpisany na listę światowego dziedzictwa UNESCO.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">El Atolón Bikini es un atolón deshabitado de unos 6 km² de superficie.11°37′N 165°25′E﻿ / ﻿11.617, 165.417Coordenadas: 11°37′N 165°25′E﻿ / ﻿11.617, 165.417. Es uno de los atolones que componen las Islas Marshall. Consta de 36 islas que bordean una laguna de unos 594,2 km². Bikini viene del marchalés "Pik" que significa "superficie" y "Ni" que significa "coco", "Bikini" deriva de esas palabras. Es famoso por las pruebas nucleares que se llevaron a cabo en él.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:areaLand rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#double">5956970.0</dbpedia-owl:areaLand>
    <dbpprop:flagSize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">180</dbpprop:flagSize>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">11.5833</geo:lat>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Bikini Atoll is an atoll, listed as a World Heritage Site, in the Micronesian Islands of the Pacific Ocean, part of Republic of the Marshall Islands. It consists of 23 islands surrounding a deep 229.4-square-mile (594.1 km) central lagoon at the northern end of the Ralik Chain (approximately 87 kilometres northwest of Ailinginae Atoll and 850 kilometres northwest of Majuro), now universally significant to the world as follows: Bikini Atoll has conserved direct tangible evidence ...</rdfs:comment>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">165.383</geo:long>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">O Atol de Bikini é um atol do Oceano Pacífico onde se deu, em julho de 1946, uma explosão atômica experimental. Também conhecido como Atol de Pikini, é um atol desabitado de 6 km² localizado na Micronésia, no Oceano Pacífico, 11° 30' N 165° 25' E. O Atol de Bikini é membro das Ilhas Marshall e é formado por 36 ilhas que rodeiam uma lagoa. O atol foi parte do programa de testes nucleares desenvolvido pelos Estados Unidos da América, após ser invadida durante a 2ª Guerra Mundial. No local foram lançadas mais de 20 bombas de hidrogênio e bombas nucleares, entre julho de 1946 e 1958. Antes da realização dos testes nucleares, a população nativa foi transferida para o Atol de Rongerik. No fim dos anos 1960 e começo dos anos 1970, alguns dos antigos moradores do Atol de Bikini retornaram das Ilhas Kili, mas foram novamente transferidos, devido a alta radioatividade. O navegador e explorador Otto von Kotzebue chamou o "Atol Bikini" como Atol Eschscholtz em homenagem ao cientista Johann Friedrich von Eschscholtz. Em testes, vários foguetes Loki e Asp foram lançados em 11° 35' N 165° 20' E.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Bikiniatollen tilhører Marshalløyene. Den dekker omkring 5 km² og hadde i 1988 en befolkning på ti personer. Den er kjent som stedet hvor USA foretok flere atomprøvesprengninger mellom 1946 og 1958. Senere har det vært gjort forsøk på å rehabilitere landområdet. Debatten rundt disse atomprøvesprengningene gav også opphavet til navnet på badedrakten bikini.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Bikini là một đảo san hô vòng có diện tích 6 km² thuộc Quần đảo Marshall, một quốc gia ở Châu Đại Dương. Loại áo tắm Bikini được đặt theo tên theo chính hòn đảo này. Sau khi kết thúc Chiến tranh Thế giới II, Bikini nằm dưới sự kiểm soát của Hoa Kỳ như một phần của Lãnh thổ Ủy thác Quần đảo Thái Bình Dương cho đến khi quần đảo Marshall tuyên bố độc lập năm 1986. Vào thế chiến thứ hai, nước Mỹ quay trở về với việc sản xuất bom hạt nhân, và bờ biển của đảo san hô vòng Bikini là nơi để Mỹ thử nghiệm việc này. Trong thời gian sản xuất và thử nghiệm bom hạt nhân tại đây, Mỹ đã thả xuống khu vực Quần đảo Marshall 67 quả bom. Vào ngày 1 tháng 3 năm 1954, lần đầu tiên, Mỹ bắt đầu chuỗi thử nghiệm "Lâu đài Hoạt Động". Quả bom "Castle Bravo" là một trong những quả bom được thử nghiệm nổi tiếng. Chính quả bom này đã làm cho tàu đánh cá Nhật Bản Daigo Fukuryū Maru bị nhiễm xạ. Cũng chính tại đây, Mỹ đã sản xuất ra 2 quả bom "Fat Man" và "Little Boy", 2 quả bom mà sau này được thả xuống Hiroshima và Nagasaki. Chúng đã gây ra nhiều tổn thất rất lớn, làm không ít người chết. Số người chết nhiều nhất ở đây là thường dân. Bức ảnh nhà máy sản xuất bom hạt nhân http://whc. unesco. org/include/tool_image. cfm?src=/uploads/sites/gallery/full/site_1339_0004. jpg Vào ngày 1 tháng 8 năm 2010, UNESCO đã công nhận Khu thử nghiệm hạt nhân trên Đảo san hô vòng Bikini là di sản thế giới cùng với 20 di sản khác.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Bikini Atoll</foaf:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">L' Atol de Bikini és un atol, declarat Patrimoni de la Humanitat, a les illes de la Micronèsia de l'Oceà Pacífic, formen part de la República de les Illes Marshall. Es compon de 23 illes que envolten una profunda llacuna central de 594,1 Km en l'extrem nord de la cadena Ralik (aproximadament a 87 Km al nord-oest de l'atol de Ailinginae i al nord-oest de Majuro), ara universalment important per al món de la següent manera: « (anglès) Bikini Atoll has conserved direct tangible evidence ...</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Das Bikini-Atoll liegt im Pazifischen Ozean und gehört mit seinen insgesamt 23 Inseln zu den Marshallinseln . Das Atoll wurde als Schauplatz zahlreicher Kernwaffentests der USA in den 1940er und 1950er Jahren bekannt. Der zweiteilige Bikini-Badeanzug wurde nach ihm benannt. Am 31. Juli 2010 wurde das Atoll zum UNESCO-Welterbe erklärt. Auf marshallesisch wird sie Pikinni genannt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Bikini is een vrijwel onbewoond atol van 2,32 vierkante kilometer in Micronesië in de Grote Oceaan en is te vinden op 11°30' NB en 165°25' OL. Het maakt onderdeel uit van de Marshalleilanden en bestaat uit 36 eilandjes rond een lagune van 594,2 vierkante kilometer. Bikini telt 10 inwoners en behoort tot de Ralik-Eilanden. Tussen 1946 en 1958 experimenteerde de Verenigde Staten er met atoomwapens. Vanaf juli 1946 werden er meer dan 20 waterstof- en atoombommen getest.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Settlement"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Бикини_(атолл)"/>
    <dbpprop:latDir xml:lang="en">N</dbpprop:latDir>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ビキニ環礁"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">A Bikini-atoll (más néven Pikinni-atoll) egy atoll a Marshall-szigeteken, a Csendes-óceánon. 23 szigetből áll, melyek mintegy 594 km²-nyi lagúnát ölelnek körbe. A szárazföld összterülete 8,8 km². A Csendes-óceáni kísérleti terület részeként az USA 23 hidrogénbombát és atombombát robbantott itt fel 1946 és 1958 között. Felfedezője, Otto von Kotzebue a területet Johann Friedrich von Escholtz után Escholtz-atollnak nevezte el, a második világháborúig a nyugati világban ezen a néven volt ismert. A bombarobbantásokat megelőzően lakott terület volt. Lakosait kitelepítették a Kili szigetre. A tesztek 1946 júliusában kezdődtek. Az 1960-as évek végén, 1970-es évek elején pár idevalósi megpróbált visszaköltözni Kili szigetéről, de a túlságosan nagy radioaktivitás miatt meggondolták magukat.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:latm rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">35</dbpprop:latm>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://marshall.csu.edu.au/Marshalls/html/atolls/bikini.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ビキニ環礁（ビキニかんしょう、Bikini Atoll）は、マーシャル諸島共和国に属する環礁。23の島嶼からなり、礁湖の面積は594.1平方キロメートル。 1946年から1958年にかけて、太平洋核実験場としてアメリカ合衆国が23回もの核実験を行ったことで有名である。 2010年、第34回世界遺産委員会において、UNESCOの世界文化遺産に登録された。マーシャル諸島共和国初の世界遺産となった。</rdfs:comment>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(165.333 11.5833)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">비키니 환초(Bikini Atoll/Pikinni Atoll)은 태평양 중앙과 마셜 제도에 위치한 환초로, 랄리크 열도에 속한다. 적도 북쪽에 위치하고 있고 콰잘레인 환초에서 북서쪽으로 360㎞, 에네웨타크 환초에서 동쪽으로 305㎞ 떨어진 곳에 위치한다. 1946년부터 1958년까지 미국의 핵 실험 장소로 쓰였으며 미국은 이 곳을 핵 실험 장소로 쓰려고 이곳에서 살던 주민들을 이웃 산호섬인 롱겔라프 환초로 이주시켰다. 비키니 수영복은 여기서 유래된 이름이다. 2010년 8월 2일 브라질 브라질리아에서 열린 유네스코 제34차 세계유산회의에서 세계유산으로 등재되었다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionType xml:lang="en">Country</dbpprop:subdivisionType>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Bikiniatollen är en atoll bland Raliköarna i norra Stilla havet och tillhör Marshallöarna.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Bikini</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Atoll"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.eh.doe.gov/health/marshall/marshall.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bikiniatoll.com/whatrad.html"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Location_Underspecified"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/PopulatedPlace"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Location of Bikini Atoll in the Pacific Ocean</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Bikiniatollen tilhører Marshalløyene. Den dekker omkring 5 km² og hadde i 1988 en befolkning på ti personer. Den er kjent som stedet hvor USA foretok flere atomprøvesprengninger mellom 1946 og 1958. Senere har det vært gjort forsøk på å rehabilitere landområdet. Debatten rundt disse atomprøvesprengningene gav også opphavet til navnet på badedrakten bikini.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:mapCaption xml:lang="en">Map of the Marshall Islands show Bikini</dbpprop:mapCaption>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionName rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marshall_Islands"/>
    <dbpprop:latMin rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">35</dbpprop:latMin>
    <dbpprop:mapCaption xml:lang="en">Map of Bikini Atoll</dbpprop:mapCaption>
    <dbpprop:officialName xml:lang="en">Bikini Atoll</dbpprop:officialName>
    <dbpprop:lonDeg rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">165</dbpprop:lonDeg>
    <dbpprop:populationTotal xml:lang="en">Uninhabited</dbpprop:populationTotal>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Bikini là một đảo san hô vòng có diện tích 6 km² thuộc Quần đảo Marshall, một quốc gia ở Châu Đại Dương. Loại áo tắm Bikini được đặt theo tên theo chính hòn đảo này. Sau khi kết thúc Chiến tranh Thế giới II, Bikini nằm dưới sự kiểm soát của Hoa Kỳ như một phần của Lãnh thổ Ủy thác Quần đảo Thái Bình Dương cho đến khi quần đảo Marshall tuyên bố độc lập năm 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/4a/Cercle_rouge_100%25.svg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">O Atol de Bikini é um atol do Oceano Pacífico onde se deu, em julho de 1946, uma explosão atômica experimental. Também conhecido como Atol de Pikini, é um atol desabitado de 6 km² localizado na Micronésia, no Oceano Pacífico, 11° 30' N 165° 25' E. O Atol de Bikini é membro das Ilhas Marshall e é formado por 36 ilhas que rodeiam uma lagoa. O atol foi parte do programa de testes nucleares desenvolvido pelos Estados Unidos da América, após ser invadida durante a 2ª Guerra Mundial.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/GeoclassAtoll"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WorldHeritageSites"/>
    <dbpprop:lonDir xml:lang="en">E</dbpprop:lonDir>
    <dbpprop:marksize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">20</dbpprop:marksize>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.oceandots.com/pacific/marshall/bikini.php"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Souřadnice: 11° 35' s. š. , 165° 23' v.d. Atol Bikini Světové dědictví Jaderný výbuch BakerJaderný výbuch Baker Smluvní stát Marshallovy ostrovy Marshallovy ostrovy Typ kulturní dědictví Kritérium iv, vi Odkaz 1339 (anglicky) Zařazení do seznamu Zařazení 2010 Tento článek pojednává o tichomořském atolu. O dvoudílných dámských plavkách pojednává článek bikiny. Atol Bikini je v současnosti neobydlený atol v Tichém oceánu, který je součástí Marshallových ostrovů.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AtollsOfTheMarshallIslands"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bikini_Atoll"/>
    <dbpprop:imageSkyline xml:lang="en">BikiniLigging.PNG</dbpprop:imageSkyline>
    <dbpprop:imageFlag xml:lang="en">Flag of bikini.svg</dbpprop:imageFlag>
    <dbpprop:latns xml:lang="en">N</dbpprop:latns>
    <dbpprop:label xml:lang="en">Bikini</dbpprop:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Bikini Atoll</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Đảo san hô Bikini</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/PopulatedPlace"/>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">165.333</geo:long>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Bikinin atolli (suomeksi myös Bikini, englanniksi Bikini Atoll tai Pikinni Atoll) on asumaton 6,0 neliökilometrin atolli Mikronesian saaristossa Tyynellä valtamerellä. Bikinin atolli kuuluu Marshallinsaarten liittovaltioon. Se koostuu 36 saaresta, jotka ympäröivät 594,2 neliökilometrin laguunia. Vuosina 1946–1958 Yhdysvallat käytti aluetta ydinkoealueena yli 20 vetypommille ja atomipommille. Ennen ydinkokeiden alkamista alkuperäinen väestö siirrettiin Rongerikin atollille.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/비키니_환초"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Bikiniatollen är en atoll bland Raliköarna i norra Stilla havet och tillhör Marshallöarna.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:imageMap xml:lang="en">MH_-map_A.png</dbpprop:imageMap>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bikini_Atoll?oldid=495108332"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Bikini is een vrijwel onbewoond atol van 2,32 vierkante kilometer in Micronesië in de Grote Oceaan en is te vinden op 11°30' NB en 165°25' OL. Het maakt onderdeel uit van de Marshalleilanden en bestaat uit 36 eilandjes rond een lagune van 594,2 vierkante kilometer. Bikini telt 10 inwoners en behoort tot de Ralik-Eilanden. Tussen 1946 en 1958 experimenteerde de Verenigde Staten er met atoomwapens. Vanaf juli 1946 werden er meer dan 20 waterstof- en atoombommen getest. Voorafgaand aan de tests werd de inheemse bevolking verplaatst naar het atol Rongerik. Eind jaren '60, begin jaren '70 keerden sommige van de oorspronkelijke bewoners terug van het eiland Kili, maar ze werden er weer verwijderd omdat er hoge radioactiviteit op het eiland heerste.. Het eiland is in 2010 op de werelderfgoedlijst geplaatst. Dit komt voornamelijk omdat het atol van 1946 tot 1958 gebruikt werd door de Verenigde Staten als testgebied voor (kern)bommen.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Village"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/YagoGeoEntity"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Ато́лл Бики́ни (англ.  Bikini Atoll, ато́лл Эшшо́льца) — атолл в Тихом океане в цепи Ралик.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/2080855/"/>
    <dbpprop:settlementType xml:lang="en">Atoll</dbpprop:settlementType>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Bikini Atoll is an atoll, listed as a World Heritage Site, in the Micronesian Islands of the Pacific Ocean, part of Republic of the Marshall Islands. It consists of 23 islands surrounding a deep 229.4-square-mile (594.1 km) central lagoon at the northern end of the Ralik Chain (approximately 87 kilometres northwest of Ailinginae Atoll and 850 kilometres northwest of Majuro), now universally significant to the world as follows: Bikini Atoll has conserved direct tangible evidence ... conveying the power of ... nuclear tests, i.e. the sunken ships sent to the bottom of the lagoon by the tests in 1946 and the gigantic Bravo crater ... Through its history, the atoll symbolises the dawn of the nuclear age, despite its paradoxical image of peace and of earthly paradise. Within Bikini Atoll, Bikini Island is the northeastern most and largest islet, measuring 4 kilometres (2.5 mi) long. About twelve kilometres to the northwest is the islet of Aomen. As part of the Pacific Proving Grounds it was the site of more than 20 nuclear weapons tests between 1946 and 1958. The first Westerner to see the atoll, in the mid-1820s, was the Russian captain and explorer Otto von Kotzebue, who named the atoll Eschscholtz Atoll after the Russian scientist Johann Friedrich von Eschscholtz. The atoll, however, has always been called Bikini by the native Marshall Islanders, from Marshallese "Pik" meaning "surface" and "Ni" meaning "coconut". The name was popularized in the United States not only by nuclear bomb tests, but because the bikini swimsuit was named after the island in 1946. The two-piece swimsuit was introduced within days of the first nuclear test on the atoll, when the name of the island was in the news. Introduced just weeks after the one-piece "Atome" was widely advertised as the "smallest bathing suit in the world", it was said that the bikini "split the atom".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Bikini_Atoll"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L'atoll de Bikini est un atoll des îles Marshall. Il fut le théâtre d'essais d'armes atomiques menés par les États-Unis, à partir du 1 juillet 1946, date de la première explosion de l'opération Crossroads.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:synonym xml:lang="en">Pikinni Atoll</dbpedia-owl:synonym>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Bikini (znany również jako Pikinni) – atol w archipelagu Wysp Marshalla. Ma on powierzchnię około 6 km² i składa się z 36 wysepek, które otaczają lagunę o powierzchni 594 km². Pierwszym Europejczykiem, który ujrzał atol (a następnie naniósł go na mapy) był w drugiej dekadzie XIX w. rosyjski podróżnik i żeglarz Otto Kotzebue.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">300</dbpprop:width>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Place"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Бікі́ні — невеликий кораловий острів в Тихому океані. Розташований в ланцюжку Ралік Маршаллових островів приблизно за 3400 кілометрів від узбережжя Австралії під 11°35' пн. ш. і 165°25' сх. д. Площа близько 6 км. Населення вивезене.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Souřadnice: 11° 35' s. š. , 165° 23' v.d. Atol Bikini Světové dědictví Jaderný výbuch BakerJaderný výbuch Baker Smluvní stát Marshallovy ostrovy Marshallovy ostrovy Typ kulturní dědictví Kritérium iv, vi Odkaz 1339 (anglicky) Zařazení do seznamu Zařazení 2010 Tento článek pojednává o tichomořském atolu. O dvoudílných dámských plavkách pojednává článek bikiny. Atol Bikini je v současnosti neobydlený atol v Tichém oceánu, který je součástí Marshallových ostrovů. Tvoří ho 36 ostrovů, které obklopují lagunu o ploše 591,1 km. Celková plocha všech ostrovů je 6 km. Ostrov byl znám jako americká jaderná střelnice a byly po něm pojmenovány i dvojdílné plavky – Bikiny. Atol je neobydlený, protože jeho obyvatelé museli být kvůli zamoření radioaktivitou přesídleni. Vzhledem k množství vraků válečných lodí na dně laguny je oblast vyhledávanou potápěčskou lokalitou. V letech 1946–1958 zde bylo provedeno 23 zkušebních jaderných výbuchů. Například zde byl zkoumán vliv jaderných výbuchů na válečné lodě – krycí název byl Operace Crossroads. V prostoru výbuchu bylo soustředěno pět bitevních lodí, čtyři křižníky, dvě letadlové lodě, 12 torpédoborců, osm ponorek, obchodní a výsadkové lodě. První jaderný test – Able, byl odpálen 1. července 1946. Puma byla shozena z bombardéru a vybuchla ve vzduchu. Mnohem ničivější ovšem byl podhladinový výbuch, ke kterému došlo 25. července 1946 při testu Baker. Řada z lodí se po některém z výbuchů potopila na místě a vytvořila lodní pohřebiště, ty které přečkaly, byly často později potopeny jinde. V roce 1954 byla na atolu při testu Castle Bravo odpálena vodíková bomba. Do kontaktu s radioaktivním spadem z tohoto výbuchu přišel také japonský rybářský člun Lucky Dragon No. 5, což zapříčinilo onemocnění členů posádky, jedna osoba nakonec zemřela. To způsobilo silný mezinárodní odpor a znovu podnítilo obavy Japonců týkající se radioaktivity, obzvlášť s ohledem na možnou kontaminaci ryb. V roce 2010 byl atol Bikini zapsán na seznam kulturního dědictví UNESCO.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:lonMin rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">23</dbpprop:lonMin>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">El Atolón Bikini es un atolón deshabitado de unos 6 km² de superficie.11°37′N 165°25′E﻿ / ﻿11.617, 165.417Coordenadas: 11°37′N 165°25′E﻿ / ﻿11.617, 165.417. Es uno de los atolones que componen las Islas Marshall. Consta de 36 islas que bordean una laguna de unos 594,2 km². Bikini viene del marchalés "Pik" que significa "superficie" y "Ni" que significa "coco", "Bikini" deriva de esas palabras. Es famoso por las pruebas nucleares que se llevaron a cabo en él. Como parte de los Territorios de Prueba del Océano Pacífico, fue un sitio donde se probaron más de 20 bombas de hidrógeno y atómicas entre 1946 y 1958. Antes de las pruebas nucleares, la población indígena fue reubicada en el Atolón Rongerik. Dichas pruebas comenzaron en julio de 1946. A finales de los años 60 y principios de los años 70, algunos de los pobladores originales trataron de retornar desde las Islas Kili, pero fueron evacuados por los altos niveles de radiactividad. El 31 de julio de 2010, la Unesco inscribió al atolón de Bikini como el primer Patrimonio de la Humanidad de las Islas Marshall.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:float xml:lang="en">right</dbpprop:float>
    <dbpprop:coordinatesDisplay xml:lang="en">inline,title</dbpprop:coordinatesDisplay>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">A Bikini-atoll (más néven Pikinni-atoll) egy atoll a Marshall-szigeteken, a Csendes-óceánon. 23 szigetből áll, melyek mintegy 594 km²-nyi lagúnát ölelnek körbe. A szárazföld összterülete 8,8 km². A Csendes-óceáni kísérleti terület részeként az USA 23 hidrogénbombát és atombombát robbantott itt fel 1946 és 1958 között. Felfedezője, Otto von Kotzebue a területet Johann Friedrich von Escholtz után Escholtz-atollnak nevezte el, a második világháborúig a nyugati világban ezen a néven volt ismert.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Location_map"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Das Bikini-Atoll liegt im Pazifischen Ozean und gehört mit seinen insgesamt 23 Inseln zu den Marshallinseln . Das Atoll wurde als Schauplatz zahlreicher Kernwaffentests der USA in den 1940er und 1950er Jahren bekannt. Der zweiteilige Bikini-Badeanzug wurde nach ihm benannt. Am 31. Juli 2010 wurde das Atoll zum UNESCO-Welterbe erklärt. Auf marshallesisch wird sie Pikinni genannt.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Atol_de_Bikini"/>
    <dbpprop:imageCaption xml:lang="en">Bikini Atoll, with Bikini Island boxed in the northeast. The crater formed by the Castle Bravo nuclear test can be seen on the northwest cape of the atoll.</dbpprop:imageCaption>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Ато́лл Бики́ни (англ. &amp;#160;Bikini Atoll, ато́лл Эшшо́льца) — атолл в Тихом океане в цепи Ралик.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1339"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_(atol)"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Bikini_Atoll"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_settlement"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">11.583333333333334 165.38333333333333</grs:point>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Atol de Bikini</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Atollo_di_Bikini"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">L'atoll de Bikini est un atoll des îles Marshall. Il fut le théâtre d'essais d'armes atomiques menés par les États-Unis, à partir du 1 juillet 1946, date de la première explosion de l'opération Crossroads.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Bikini è una municipalità delle Isole Marshall con 13 abitanti. La municipalità è costituita dall'omonimo atollo, costituito da 36 isolette, nella Catena delle Ralik, nell'Oceano Pacifico. L'atollo è costituito da una ampia laguna (594,2 km).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Atolón_Bikini"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://japanfocus.org/-Yoichi-Funabashi/1576"/>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(165.383 11.5833)</geo:geometry>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Бікі́ні — невеликий кораловий острів в Тихому океані. Розташований в ланцюжку Ралік Маршаллових островів приблизно за 3400 кілометрів від узбережжя Австралії під 11°35' пн. ш. і 165°25' сх. д. Площа близько 6 км. Населення вивезене.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:longd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">165</dbpprop:longd>
    <dbpprop:latDeg rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">11</dbpprop:latDeg>
    <dbpprop:unitPref xml:lang="en">Imperial</dbpprop:unitPref>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Bikinin atolli (suomeksi myös Bikini, englanniksi Bikini Atoll tai Pikinni Atoll) on asumaton 6,0 neliökilometrin atolli Mikronesian saaristossa Tyynellä valtamerellä. Bikinin atolli kuuluu Marshallinsaarten liittovaltioon. Se koostuu 36 saaresta, jotka ympäröivät 594,2 neliökilometrin laguunia. Vuosina 1946–1958 Yhdysvallat käytti aluetta ydinkoealueena yli 20 vetypommille ja atomipommille. Ennen ydinkokeiden alkamista alkuperäinen väestö siirrettiin Rongerikin atollille. Sieltä heidät siirrettiin vuonna 1948 Kwajaleinille ja lopulta Kilille. Ydinkokeet alkoivat 1. heinäkuuta 1946, jolloin Operaatio Crossroads testasi ydinaseiden vaikutusta käytöstä poistettuihin laivoihin suorittamalla ensimmäisen ydinkokeensa (koodinimi ABLE; viimeinen Operaatio Crossroadsin kahdesta ydinkokeesta, koodinimi BAKER, suoritettiin 25.7.1946). 1960- ja 1970-lukujen vaihteessa osa alkuperäisasukkaista palasi Bikinin atollille Kili-saarelta, mutta heidät karkotettiin korkean radioaktiivisuuden takia. Unesco lisäsi atollin maailmanperintöluetteloon vuonna 2010. Bikinit-uima-asu on saanut nimensä Bikinin atollin mukaan.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini-Atoll"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">11.583333333333334 165.33333333333334</grs:point>
    <dbpprop:latd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">11</dbpprop:latd>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Place"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">L' Atol de Bikini és un atol, declarat Patrimoni de la Humanitat, a les illes de la Micronèsia de l'Oceà Pacífic, formen part de la República de les Illes Marshall. Es compon de 23 illes que envolten una profunda llacuna central de 594,1 Km en l'extrem nord de la cadena Ralik (aproximadament a 87 Km al nord-oest de l'atol de Ailinginae i al nord-oest de Majuro), ara universalment important per al món de la següent manera: « (anglès) Bikini Atoll has conserved direct tangible evidence ... conveying the power of ... nuclear tests, i.e. the sunken ships sent to the bottom of the lagoon by the tests in 1946 and the gigantic Bravo crater ... Through its history, the atoll symbolises the dawn of the nuclear age, despite its paradoxical image of peace and of earthly paradise. (català) a l'Atol de Bikini s'ha conservat l'evidència tangible directe ... transmetent la potència de ... proves nuclears, és a dir, vaixells enfonsats que van enviar al fons de la llacuna les proves del 1946 i el gegantí crater Bravo ... a través de la seva història, l'atol representa les albors l'edat nuclear, malgrat la seva imatge paradoxal de pau i del paradís terrenal. » Dins l'Atol de Bikini, l'Illa Bikini és l'illot del nord-est més gran, fa una mesura de 4 kilòmetres de llarg. A uns dotze kilòmetres al nord-oest està l'illot d'Aomen. Formant part dels sols de prova del Pacífic va ser el lloc de més de 20 proves d'armes nuclears entre 1946 i 1958. El primer occidental en veure l'atol, en el mig de la dècada de 1820, fou el capità i explorador rus Otto von Kotzebue, qui anomenà l'atol atol Eschscholtz en honor del científic rus Johann Friedrich von Eschscholtz. El atol, però, sempre s'ha anomenat Bikini pels nadius de les Illes Marshall, de la llengua de les Illes Marshall on "Pik", significa "superfície" i "Ni", significa "coco". El nom es va popularitzar en tot el món no només pels assajos de bombes nuclears, sinó perquè el vestit de bany bikini portà el nom de l'illa el 1946. El vestit de bany de dues peces es va introduir als pocs dies de la primera prova nuclear a l'atol, quan el nom de la illa sortia a les notícies. Es va presentar tot just unes setmanes després de la prova d'una sola peça "Atòmica" i va ser àmpliament publicitat com el "vestit de bany més petit del món", es va dir que el biquini "dividia l'àtom".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ビキニ環礁（ビキニかんしょう、Bikini Atoll）は、マーシャル諸島共和国に属する環礁。23の島嶼からなり、礁湖の面積は594.1平方キロメートル。 1946年から1958年にかけて、太平洋核実験場としてアメリカ合衆国が23回もの核実験を行ったことで有名である。 2010年、第34回世界遺産委員会において、UNESCOの世界文化遺産に登録された。マーシャル諸島共和国初の世界遺産となった。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">비키니 환초(Bikini Atoll/Pikinni Atoll)은 태평양 중앙과 마셜 제도에 위치한 환초로, 랄리크 열도에 속한다. 적도 북쪽에 위치하고 있고 콰잘레인 환초에서 북서쪽으로 360㎞, 에네웨타크 환초에서 동쪽으로 305㎞ 떨어진 곳에 위치한다. 1946년부터 1958년까지 미국의 핵 실험 장소로 쓰였으며 미국은 이 곳을 핵 실험 장소로 쓰려고 이곳에서 살던 주민들을 이웃 산호섬인 롱겔라프 환초로 이주시켰다. 비키니 수영복은 여기서 유래된 이름이다. 2010년 8월 2일 브라질 브라질리아에서 열린 유네스코 제34차 세계유산회의에서 세계유산으로 등재되었다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bikiniatoll.com/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://alsos.wlu.edu/qsearch.aspx?browse=places/Bikini"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Castle_Union">
    <dbpprop:testSite rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eschscholtz_Atoll">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll_Airport">
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atol">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Castle_Romeo">
    <dbpprop:testSite rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_(disambiguation)">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageDisambiguates rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini,_Marshall_Islands">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll_Nuclear_Test_Site">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Castle_Yankee">
    <dbpprop:testSite rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pikinni">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Castle_Bravo">
    <dbpprop:testSite rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/Bikini_Atoll">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bikini_Atoll"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
