<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan">
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">"Lay Lady Lay", on the country album Nashville Skyline, has been one of Dylan's biggest hits, reaching No.7 in the U.S.A.</dbpprop:description>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">밥 딜런은 미국의 싱어송라이터, 시인, 화가이다. 유대인 집안에서 태어났고, 본명은 로버트 앨런 지머맨 (히브리어 샤브타이 지셀 벤 아브라함)이다. 그의 작품은 1960년대부터 비공식 작자와 저항음악의 대표로서 사랑을 받았다. 한국의 학생운동에도 영향을 준"Blowin' in the Wind"그리고 "The Times They Are a-Changin'"과 같은 노래들은 사회상을 잘 보여주는 저항적 노랫말로 시민권을 대표하는 곡이 되었으며, 베트남 전쟁에 대한 저항의 표상이 되었다. 대중음악 역사상 가장 영향력있는 음악가 중 한명으로 꼽힌다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Minnesota"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanPoets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Traveling_Wilburys"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Johnny_Cash"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_gospel_singers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.expectingrain.com/"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_blues_singers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/MusicalArtist"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.boblinks.com/dates.html"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/LivingPeople"/>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Johnny_Cash"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanCountrySingers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanGospelSingers"/>
    <dbpprop:description rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/second">7074000.0</dbpprop:description>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ボブ・ディラン（Bob Dylan、1941年5月24日 - ）は、アメリカのミュージシャン。出生名はロバート・アレン・ジマーマン（Robert Allen Zimmerman）だが、後に自ら法律上の本名もボブ・ディランに改名している。 「風に吹かれて」、「時代は変る」、「ミスター・タンブリン・マン」、「ライク・ア・ローリング・ストーン」、「見張塔からずっと」、「天国への扉」他多数の楽曲により、1962年のレコードデビュー以来半世紀にわたり多大なる影響を人々に与えてきた。現在でも、「ネヴァー・エンディング・ツアー」と呼ばれる年間100公演ほどのライブ活動を中心にして活躍している。 グラミー賞やアカデミー賞をはじめ数々を受賞し、ロックの殿堂入りも果たしている。詩人としてノーベル文学賞にノミネートされ、2008年には「卓越した詩の力による作詞がポピュラー・ミュージックとアメリカ文化に大きな影響与えた」としてピューリッツァー賞特別賞を受賞した。 「ローリング・ストーンの選ぶ歴史上最も偉大な100人のシンガー」に於いて第7位。</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_folk_singers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mark_Knopfler"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanHarmonicaPlayers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1941_births"/>
    <dbpprop:alternativeNames xml:lang="en">Zimmerman, Robert Allen</dbpprop:alternativeNames>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Blues_rock"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Bob Dylan là một ca sĩ, tác giả, nhà soạn nhạc, nhà thơ và gần đây nhất là một DJ. Một nhân vật có tầm ảnh hưởng lớn tới âm nhạc đại chúng trong năm thập kỉ qua. Rất nhiều thành quả lao động của Dylan được công nhận từ thập niên 1960 khi ông gây nhiều xôn xao trong dư luận Mỹ. Một vài bài hát của ông như "Blowin' in the Wind" và "The Times They Are a-Changin trở thành những bài ca chống chiến tranh và ủng hộ phong trào nhân quyền. Album Studio gần đây nhất của ông Modern Times, phát hành ngày 28 tháng 8, 2006, đã dành vị trí số 1 tại các bảng xếp hạng của Mỹ, giúp ông, ở tuổi 65, trở thành ca sĩ già nhất còn sống dành vị trí cao nhất trong các bảng xếp hạng. Sau đó, album đã được tạp chí Rolling Stone bầu chọn là "Album của năm". Những lời trong các bài hát đầu tiên của Dylan là sự kết hợp tầm ảnh hưởng của chính trị, bình luận xã hội, triết học và văn chương. Thách thức dòng nhạc Pop đương thời và tạo sức hút rộng rãi văn hóa đối lập (counterculture) thời đó. Trong khi phát triển và cá nhân hóa những phong cách âm nhạc, ông đã thể hiện sự tâm huyết với nhiều dòng nhạc truyền thống của Mĩ từ folk và country/blues đến rock and roll và rockabilly, tới nhạc Folk Anh, Scotland, Ireland, thậm chí là jazz, swing, Broadway, rock nặng và gospel. Dylan biểu diễn với guitar, keyboard and harmonica. Được sự giúp đỡ của nhiều nhà soạn nhạc, ông đã thực hiện các tour diễn đều đặn từ cuối thập niên 1980, chính vì vậy mà sau đó họ gọi đó là "Never Ending Tour" (tour diễn không bao giờ kết thúc). Dylan đã biểu diễn cùng nhiều danh ca lớn như The Band, Tom Petty, Joan Baez, George Harrison, The Grateful Dead, Johnny Cash, Willie Nelson, Paul Simon, Eric Clapton, Patti Smith, Emmylou Harris, Bruce Springsteen, U2, The Rolling Stones, Joni Mitchell, Jack White, Merle Haggard, Neil Young, Van Morrison, Ringo Starr và Stevie Nicks. Dù những thành quả với tư cách là ca sĩ và nghệ sĩ thu âm là dấu ấn lớn trung tâm trong sự nghiệp Dylan, nhưng việc sáng tác ca khúc được ghi nhận là đóng góp lớn nhất của ông cho âm nhạc đương đại. Những bản thu âm đã giúp ông giành giải Grammy, Quả Cầu Vàng và nhiều giải thưởng của viện Hàn Lâm. Ông đã được ghi danh tại đại sảnh danh vọng về dòng nhạc Rock&amp;Roll, đại sảnh danh vọng cho các nhà soạn nhạc tại Nashville, và đại sảnh danh vọng dành cho các nhà soạn nhạc. Dylan được tạp chí Time bầu là một trong những nhân vật có tầm ảnh hưởng nhất thế kỉ 20. Năm 2004, Bob Dylan được xếp ở vị trí thứ 2 bên cạnh The Beatles trong danh sách 100 nghệ sĩ xuất sắc nhất mọi thời đại của tạp chí Rolling Stone. Tháng 1 năm 1990, ông được trao huân chương nghệ thuật &amp; văn học (Commandeur des Arts et des Lettres) bởi bộ trưởng văn hóa Pháp Jack Lang. Năm 2000, ông được trao giải Polar Music bởi viện âm nhạc hoàng gia Thụy Điển. Và năm 2007, Dylan được trao giải Prince of Asturias trong lĩnh vực nghệ thuật. Ông cũng đã vài lần được đề cử cho giải Nobel văn học.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:recordLabel rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Columbia_Records"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songwriters_from_Minnesota"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Bob_Dylan_-_Blowin'_in_the_Wind.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Blues_rock"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Traveling_Wilburys"/>
    <dbpprop:pnd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">118528408</dbpprop:pnd>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/PersonWithOccupation"/>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Folk_rock"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanMaleSingers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Singing"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Robert Allen Zimmerman, conegut amb el nom artístic de Bob Dylan, és un compositor i cantant estatunidenc, considerat un dels músics més influents i prolífics del segle XX i proposat diverses vegades pel Premi Nobel de Literatura.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/JewishPeaceActivists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanDJs"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Bob Dylan, właśc. Robert Allen Zimmerman – amerykański piosenkarz, kompozytor, autor tekstów, pisarz i poeta. Jest jedną z najważniejszych postaci muzyki popularnej ostatnich pięciu dekad. Swój indywidualny styl oparł na wielu gatunkach muzycznych, od tradycyjnego amerykańskiego folku i country-bluesa do muzyki gospel, rock and rolla, rockabilly, czy angielskiej, szkockiej i irlandzkiej muzyki folkowej, a także jazzu i swingu.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.01vrncs"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Bob Dylan est un auteur-compositeur-interprète, musicien, peintre, poète américain, une des figures majeures de la musique populaire depuis cinq décennies. Ses œuvres les plus célèbres et les plus influentes datent des années 1960, quand il fut d'abord un chroniqueur informel des troubles américains, par exemple avec Like a Rolling Stone, Ballad of a Thin Man, All Along the Watchtower, Masters of War ou encore Gates of Eden.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Tangled_Up_In_Blue.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tom_Petty_and_the_Heartbreakers"/>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rock_music"/>
    <dbpprop:id rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1168</dbpprop:id>
    <dbpprop:v xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:v>
    <dbpprop:caption rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gMonthDay">--06-26</dbpprop:caption>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Quill_Award_winners"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rv9PVjZwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Country_rock"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Piano"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Country_rock"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Folk_rock"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Musicians_from_Minnesota"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanFolkSingers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_male_singers"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Listen"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Distintosi anche come scrittore, poeta, pittore, attore e conduttore radiofonico, è una delle più importanti figure degli ultimi cinquant'anni nel campo musicale, in quello della cultura popolare e della letteratura. La maggior parte delle sue canzoni più conosciute risale agli anni sessanta, quando l'artista si è posto come figura chiave del movement, il movimento di protesta americano. Canzoni come Blowin' in the Wind e The Times They Are A-Changin' sono diventate gli inni dei movimenti pacifisti e per i diritti civili. I testi delle sue prime canzoni affrontano temi politici, sociali e filosofici, e risentono di influenze letterarie, sfidando le convenzioni della musica pop e appellandosi alla controcultura del tempo. Nel corso degli anni Dylan ha ampliato e personalizzato il suo stile musicale arrivando a toccare molti generi diversi come country/blues, gospel, rock and roll, rockabilly, jazz e swing, ed anche musica popolare inglese, scozzese ed irlandese.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tom_Petty_and_the_Heartbreakers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Bob Dylan, vlastním jménem Robert Allen Zimmerman je americký původně folkový skladatel a zpěvák. Bob Dylan inspiroval svoji unikátní hudbou, v níž je sám interpretem, autorem, kytaristou i hráčem na foukací harmoniku, naprosto ojedinělým zjevem. Zavedl do popové, folkové a rockové hudby zvláštní frázovitý styl „zpěvu nezpěvu“, který nadchl mnoho dalších interpretů a tvůrců. Jedině díky němu se v rockové oblasti fenomenální kytarista Jimi Hendrix rozhodl také zpívat, inspiroval Micka Jaggera v brilatní rockové frázovitosti písní, podobně Madonnu a Michaela Jacksona, ve folkové oblasti Joan Baezovou, čerpá z něho brilantní irská skupina Frames, která dokonce tvrdí, že když začínala, byl to právě Dylan, který jim pomohl nastartovat jejich hudební dráhu. Přitom začínali na předměstí Dublinu v ulicích. Říká se, že Dylan má krákoravý hlas, který však v sobě skrývá nesmírně jemnou básnickou poetiku a vidění světa. Když zpívá, některé fráze ani nedozpívá a už rozbrnkává další a do ní zas další a další, přepíná mezi zpěvem, harmonikou, dalšími instrumenty, dokáže vytěžit maximum i z pouhé řeči, která dovede být tichá, přitom naléhavá. Dylan ovlivnil mnohé autory a interprety, z nichž většina se k jeho vlivu otevřeně hlásí např. John Lennon, Paul McCartney, Pete Townshend, Neil Young, Bruce Springsteen, David Bowie, Bryan Ferry, Nick Cave, Patti Smith, Syd Barrett, Cat Stevens, Joni Mitchell, Tom Waits a mnozí jiní. Ukázalo se, že jeho tiché ševelení nebo broukání má pro rockovou hudbu nebývalý a cenný skrytý náboj, skutečné hudební a poetické charisma.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"Tangled Up in Blue"</dbpprop:title>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Artist"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:recordLabel rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Asylum_Records"/>
    <dbpprop:b xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:b>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Jewish_poets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Grateful_Dead"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan, born Robert Allen Zimmerman on May 24, 1941, is an American singer-songwriter, musician and artist. He has been an influential figure in popular music and culture for five decades. Much of his most celebrated work dates from the 1960s when he was an informal chronicler and a seemingly reluctant figurehead of social unrest. A number of Dylan's early songs, such as "Blowin' in the Wind" and "The Times They Are a-Changin'", became anthems for the US civil rights and anti-war movements. Leaving his initial base in the culture of folk music behind, Dylan's six-minute single "Like a Rolling Stone" has been described as radically altering the parameters of popular music in 1965. However, his recordings employing electric instruments attracted denunciation and criticism from others in the folk movement. Dylan's lyrics incorporated a variety of political, social, philosophical, and literary influences. They defied existing pop music conventions and appealed hugely to the then burgeoning counterculture. Initially inspired by the songs of Woody Guthrie, Robert Johnson, and Hank Williams, as well as the music and performance styles of Buddy Holly and Little Richard, Dylan has both amplified and personalized musical genres. His recording career, spanning fifty years, has explored numerous distinct traditions in American song—from folk, blues and country to gospel, rock and roll, and rockabilly to English, Scottish, and Irish folk music, embracing even jazz and swing. Dylan performs with guitar, keyboards, and harmonica. Backed by a changing line-up of musicians, he has toured steadily since the late 1980s on what has been dubbed the Never Ending Tour. His accomplishments as a recording artist and performer have been central to his career, but his greatest contribution is generally considered to be his songwriting. Since 1994, Dylan has published three books of drawings and paintings, and his work has been exhibited in major art galleries. As a songwriter and musician, Dylan has received numerous awards over the years including Grammy, Golden Globe, and Academy Awards; he has been inducted into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame, Nashville Songwriters Hall of Fame, and Songwriters Hall of Fame. The Pulitzer Prize jury in 2008 awarded him a special citation for "his profound impact on popular music and American culture, marked by lyrical compositions of extraordinary poetic power. " In May 2012, Dylan received the Presidential Medal of Freedom from President Barack Obama.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d5/Bob_Dylan_-_Azkena_Rock_Festival_2010_1.jpg/200px-Bob_Dylan_-_Azkena_Rock_Festival_2010_1.jpg"/>
    <dbpprop:label rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Asylum_Records"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d5/Bob_Dylan_-_Azkena_Rock_Festival_2010_1.jpg"/>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan - Like a Rolling Stone.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan performs The Times they are a Changin at the White House.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/KennedyCenterHonorees"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:IMDb_name"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/1960sSingers"/>
    <dbpprop:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Piano"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Jewish_American_musicians"/>
    <dbpprop:label rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Columbia_Records"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bjorner.com/still.htm"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Bob Dylan er en amerikansk musiker, sanger, låtskriver, poet og forfatter, og i den senere tid også radiovert, som har vært en av de mest innflytelsesrike og viktige personene innen populærmusikken gjennom mer enn 45 år. De siste årene har Dylan hatt en renessanse gjennom plater, memoarbok, dokumentarfilm av Martin Scorsese og sin kontinuerlige konsertvirksomhet, som har bidratt til å befeste en enestående posisjon innen populærkulturen.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:s xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:s>
    <dbpprop:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Guitar"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan, born Robert Allen Zimmerman on May 24, 1941, is an American singer-songwriter, musician and artist. He has been an influential figure in popular music and culture for five decades. Much of his most celebrated work dates from the 1960s when he was an informal chronicler and a seemingly reluctant figurehead of social unrest. A number of Dylan's early songs, such as "Blowin' in the Wind" and "The Times They Are a-Changin'", became anthems for the US civil rights and anti-war movements.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Bob_Dylan"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/MusicGroup"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/밥_딜런"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/2000sSingers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ボブ・ディラン（Bob Dylan、1941年5月24日 - ）は、アメリカのミュージシャン。出生名はロバート・アレン・ジマーマン（Robert Allen Zimmerman）だが、後に自ら法律上の本名もボブ・ディランに改名している。 「風に吹かれて」、「時代は変る」、「ミスター・タンブリン・マン」、「ライク・ア・ローリング・ストーン」、「見張塔からずっと」、「天国への扉」他多数の楽曲により、1962年のレコードデビュー以来半世紀にわたり多大なる影響を人々に与えてきた。現在でも、「ネヴァー・エンディング・ツアー」と呼ばれる年間100公演ほどのライブ活動を中心にして活躍している。 グラミー賞やアカデミー賞をはじめ数々を受賞し、ロックの殿堂入りも果たしている。詩人としてノーベル文学賞にノミネートされ、2008年には「卓越した詩の力による作詞がポピュラー・ミュージックとアメリカ文化に大きな影響与えた」としてピューリッツァー賞特別賞を受賞した。 「ローリング・ストーンの選ぶ歴史上最も偉大な100人のシンガー」に於いて第7位。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_harmonica_players"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Bob Dylan là một ca sĩ, tác giả, nhà soạn nhạc, nhà thơ và gần đây nhất là một DJ. Một nhân vật có tầm ảnh hưởng lớn tới âm nhạc đại chúng trong năm thập kỉ qua. Rất nhiều thành quả lao động của Dylan được công nhận từ thập niên 1960 khi ông gây nhiều xôn xao trong dư luận Mỹ. Một vài bài hát của ông như "Blowin' in the Wind" và "The Times They Are a-Changin trở thành những bài ca chống chiến tranh và ủng hộ phong trào nhân quyền.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Things_Have_Changed.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpprop:birthName xml:lang="en">Robert Allen Zimmerman</dbpprop:birthName>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Joan_Baez"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanBluEsSingers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tom_Petty_and_the_Heartbreakers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Blues"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gospel_music"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Jewish_American_writers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Bob Dylan on yhdysvaltalainen folk- ja rocklaulaja ja -lauluntekijä sekä elokuvanäyttelijä. Häntä pidetään yhtenä kaikkien aikojen merkittävimmistä lauluntekijöistä. Runotutkija Christopher Ricks nostaa hänet merkittävien englanninkielisten sanataitureiden rinnalle ja vertaa häntä William Wordsworthiin, John Donneen ja Alfred Tennysoniin. Dylanin tunnetuimpia kappaleita ovat Blowin' in the Wind, The Times They Are a-Changin', Like a Rolling Stone, Knockin' on Heavens Door ja Mr. Tambourine Man. Musiikkilehti Rolling Stone on rankannut Dylanin kaikkien aikojen parhaiden artistien listalla toiselle sijalle The Beatlesin jälkeen. Varsinkin uransa alkuvaiheissa Dylan otti lauluissaan aktiivisesti kantaa yhteiskunnallisiin ja poliittisiin kysymyksiin. Bob Dylan oli eräs tunnetuimpia henkilöitä 1960-luvun protestiliikkeessä. Suuren osan tunnetuimmista sävellyksistään Dylan lauloi nauhalle yhdellä otolla. Bob Dylanin tuotanto on vaihdellut tyyliltään, sovituksiltaan ja myös tasoltaan valtavasti. Uran alkuvaiheita pidetään merkittävimpinä, erityisesti vuosia 1963-1966. Dylan sai vuonna 2008 ensimmäisenä rock-muusikkona Pulitzer-palkinnon perustavanlaatuisesta vaikutuksestaan populaarimusiikkiin ja amerikkalaiseen kulttuuriin. Vuonna 2012 presidentti Barack Obama myönsi hänelle Vapauden mitalin.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Harmonica_blues_musicians"/>
    <dbpprop:background xml:lang="en">solo_singer</dbpprop:background>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Bob Dylan, nacido como Robert Allen Zimmerman, es un músico, cantante y poeta estadounidense. Ha sido, durante cinco décadas, una de las mayores figuras en la música popular, siendo considerado uno de los compositores y músicos más influyentes y prolíficos del siglo XX. Muchos de los más célebres trabajos de Dylan datan de la década de 1960, en la cual se convirtió en un cronista informal de los conflictos estadounidenses.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"Things Have Changed"</dbpprop:title>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanFolkGuitarists"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Bob Dylan, född Robert Allen Zimmerman den 24 maj 1941 i Duluth, Minnesota, är en amerikansk singer-songwriter, författare, regissör, poet, gitarrist, keyboardist samt munspelare, vid senare tid programledare i radio. Dylan har varit en frontfigur inom populärmusik i närmare femtio år, ofta beskriven som en levande legend inom rockmusiken. Många av Dylans mest prisade låtar kommer från 1960-talet, då han kom att bli en förgrundsfigur i USA och han ansågs av många skildra en hel generation. Några av hans sånger, såsom "Blowin' in the Wind" och "The Times They Are a-Changin'", blev ledmotiv till den amerikanska antikrigs- och medborgarrättsrörelsen. Många av Dylans tidiga texter behandlade politiska frågor, samhällskritik, filosofi och litterära influenser, och trotsade dåvarande konventioner inom popmusiken och vände sig mycket till motkulturen. Medan han utvecklade och personifierade musikstilar, har han visat tillgivenhet till många traditioner inom amerikansk sång, från folkmusik och country/blues till gospel, rock'n'roll och rockabilly, till engelsk, skotsk och irländsk folkmusik, även jazz och swing. Dylan uppträder med sin gitarr, keyboard och sitt munspel. Uppbackad av en varierande sättning av musiker, har han turnerat oavbrutet sedan slutet av 1980-talet, i vilket som har kallats för "Never Ending Tour". Han har även spelat tillsammans med andra stora artister. Dylans första album Bob Dylan släpptes 1962, som följdes sedan av många prisade album som The Freewheelin' Bob Dylan (1963), Highway 61 Revisited (1965), Blonde on Blonde (1966), Blood on the Tracks (1975), Oh Mercy (1989) och Time Out of Mind (1997). Dylan tog medvetet upp arvet efter Woody Guthrie. Han besökte dennes dödsbädd och lovade då att föra Guthries gärning vidare. Folkmusik och arbetarsånger som Joe Hills inspirerade honom tidigt, men också franska poeter som Arthur Rimbaud reflekteras i hans texter. Dylans musik bestod i början mest av politiska och sociala protestsånger, till exempel "A Hard Rain's a-Gonna Fall" och nämnda "The Times They Are a-Changin'". Denna "revolutionära period" följdes av en mer surrealistisk period i mitten av 1960-talet, då hans texter var kryptiska och ironiska. Dylans musik blev senare mer inåtvänd, med delvis religiösa texter. Senare kom Dylan in i två religiösa perioder, först en kristen, sedan en judisk. Bob Dylan erhöll Polarpriset år 2000.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="en">118528408</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Боб Дилан — американский автор-исполнитель песен, поэт, художник, киноактёр. Является культовой фигурой в рок-музыке на протяжении пяти десятилетий. Многие его песни, такие как «Blowin' in the Wind» и «The Times They Are a-Changin'», стали гимнами для движения гражданских прав и антивоенного движения в США. По данным опроса журнала Rolling Stone — является второй по значимости фигурой в истории рок-музыки.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Bob Dylan, é um cantor e compositor norte-americano. Nascido no estado de Minnesota, neto de imigrantes judeus russos, aos dez anos de idade Dylan escreveu seus primeiros poemas e, ainda adolescente, aprendeu piano e guitarra sozinho. Começou cantando em grupos de rock, imitando Little Richard e Buddy Holly, mas quando foi para a Universidade de Minnesota em 1959, voltou-se para a folk music, impressionado com a obra musical do lendário cantor folk Woody Guthrie, a quem foi visitar em Nova York em 1961. Em 2004, Bob Dylan foi escolhido pela revista Rolling Stone, como o 2º melhor artista de todos os tempos, ficando atrás somente dos Beatles, e uma de suas principais canções, "Like a Rolling Stone", foi escolhida como a melhor de todos os tempos. Influenciou diretamente grandes nomes do rock americano e britânico dos anos de 1960 e 1970.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-musician-noun-1"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Duluth,_Minnesota"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Rock_and_Roll_Hall_of_Fame_inductees"/>
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">Dylan said of "The Times They Are a-Changin'": "This was definitely a song with a purpose. I wanted to write a big song, some kind of theme song, with short concise verses that piled up on each other in a hypnotic way. The civil rights movement and the folk music movement were pretty close and allied together at that time."</dbpprop:description>
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">Dylan took five months off at the beginning of 1979 to attend Bible school. His subsequent album Slow Train Coming reached No.3 on the U.S. Billboard 200 chart and included this Grammy-winning song.</dbpprop:description>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Traveling_Wilburys_members"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Living_people"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Robert Allen Zimmerman, conegut amb el nom artístic de Bob Dylan, és un compositor i cantant estatunidenc, considerat un dels músics més influents i prolífics del segle XX i proposat diverses vegades pel Premi Nobel de Literatura. Dylan ha aportat a la música rock una dimensió poètica més rica i adulta, emprant metàfores i figures al·legòriques per a descriure el desordre individual i social, a més d'una inventiva melòdica provinent d'estructures tradicionals com el blues, la balada o les cançons de treball. Al llarg de la seva carrera ha experimentant amb tota mena de ritmes i formes harmòniques, cosa que ha enriquit la seva expressió musical i ha influït en molts altres intèrprets i compositors.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1941-05-24</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_memoirists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Bob Dylan, é um cantor e compositor norte-americano. Nascido no estado de Minnesota, neto de imigrantes judeus russos, aos dez anos de idade Dylan escreveu seus primeiros poemas e, ainda adolescente, aprendeu piano e guitarra sozinho.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Grateful_Dead"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Pseudonymous_musicians"/>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Gotta_Serve_Somebody.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mark_Knopfler"/>
    <dbpprop:origin xml:lang="en">Hibbing, Minnesota, U.S.</dbpprop:origin>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Bob Dylan, vlastním jménem Robert Allen Zimmerman je americký původně folkový skladatel a zpěvák. Bob Dylan inspiroval svoji unikátní hudbou, v níž je sám interpretem, autorem, kytaristou i hráčem na foukací harmoniku, naprosto ojedinělým zjevem. Zavedl do popové, folkové a rockové hudby zvláštní frázovitý styl „zpěvu nezpěvu“, který nadchl mnoho dalších interpretů a tvůrců.</rdfs:comment>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_Dylan?oldid=495254176"/>
    <dbpprop:alias xml:lang="en">Elston Gunnn, Blind Boy Grunt, Bob Landy, Robert Milkwood Thomas, Tedham Porterhouse, Lucky/Boo Wilbury, Jack Frost, Sergei Petrov</dbpprop:alias>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Bob Dylan [ˈdɪlən] ist ein US-amerikanischer Folk- und Rockmusiker, Dichter und Maler. Bob Dylan singt, spielt Gitarre, Mundharmonika und Klavier und gilt als einer der einflussreichsten Musiker des 20. Jahrhunderts. Dylan begann Ende der 1950er-Jahre nach Rock`n`Roll-Jahren in Schülerbands als Folkmusiker und wandte sich Mitte der 1960er-Jahre der Rockmusik zu. Seine Texte waren zu Beginn seines Schaffens von den Inhalten der Folkbewegung und einem ihrer bekanntesten Vertreter, Woody Guthrie, später auch von symbolistischen Dichtern wie Arthur Rimbaud und Charles Baudelaire, aber auch von der Bibel beeinflusst.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Country_music"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Joan_Baez"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Bob Dylan, nacido como Robert Allen Zimmerman, es un músico, cantante y poeta estadounidense. Ha sido, durante cinco décadas, una de las mayores figuras en la música popular, siendo considerado uno de los compositores y músicos más influyentes y prolíficos del siglo XX. Muchos de los más célebres trabajos de Dylan datan de la década de 1960, en la cual se convirtió en un cronista informal de los conflictos estadounidenses. Aunque es bien conocido por revolucionar el concepto de los límites de la música popular en 1965 con el single "Like a Rolling Stone" de seis minutos de duración, algunas de sus primeras canciones, como "Blowin' in the Wind" y "The Times They Are a-Changin'", se convirtieron en himnos antibélicos y de los movimientos civiles de la época. Uno de los últimos álbumes de estudio de Dylan, Modern Times, publicado en 2006, entró directamente en el primer puesto de la lista Billboard 200 y fue nombrado álbum del año por la revista musical Rolling Stone. Las primeras letras de Dylan abordaban temas sociales y filosóficos y delataban una fuerte influencia literaria, desafiando la música pop convencional existente y apelando generalmente a la contracultura de aquel tiempo. Mientras expandía y personalizaba estilos musicales, mostraba una firme devoción por muchas tradiciones de la música americana, desde el folk, el country, el blues, el gospel, el rock and roll y el rockabilly hasta la música folk inglesa, escocesa e irlandesa, pasando por el jazz y el swing. Dylan interpreta mediante guitarra, teclado y armónica. Respaldado por una cambiante alineación de músicos, ha permanecido de gira de forma constante desde finales de la década de 1980, en lo que ha venido a conocerse como el Never Ending Tour (la gira interminable). Sus logros en el estudio de grabación y como artista han sido una de las señas de identidad de su carrera, aunque generalmente se considera que su mayor contribución consiste en la composición y escritura de canciones. A lo largo de su carrera, Dylan ha sido reconocido y honrado por sus composiciones, interpretaciones y grabaciones. Sus discos le han valido varios Grammys, Globos de Oro y premios de la Academia, y su nombre se halla en el Salón de la Fama del Rock and Roll, el Salón de la Fama de Compositores de Nashville y el Salón de la Fama de los Compositores. En enero de 1990, fue investido Caballero de la Orden de las Artes y las Letras por el Ministro de Cultura de Francia Jack Lang. En 1999, fue incluido en la lista de las cien personas más influyentes del siglo XX elaborada por la revista Time. En el año 2000, ganó el Premio de Música Polar de la Real Academia Sueca de Música, y en 2004 alcanzó el segundo puesto en la lista de los 100 mejores artistas de todos los tiempos elaborada por la revista Rolling Stone, después de The Beatles. El 13 de junio de 2007 fue premiado con el Premio Príncipe de Asturias de las Artes, y en 2008 recibió un reconocimiento honorario del Premio Pulitzer por su "profundo impacto en la música popular y en la cultura americana, marcado por sus composiciones líricas de extraordinario poder poético". En este contexto, desde 1996 diversos autores y académicos han nominado a Dylan para la candidatura del .</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:background xml:lang="en">solo_singer</dbpedia-owl:background>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">Rock and folk musician</dc:description>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromGreenwichVillage,NewYork"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_rock_guitarists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Rock_music"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/American_folk_music"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Bob Dylan est un auteur-compositeur-interprète, musicien, peintre, poète américain, une des figures majeures de la musique populaire depuis cinq décennies. Ses œuvres les plus célèbres et les plus influentes datent des années 1960, quand il fut d'abord un chroniqueur informel des troubles américains, par exemple avec Like a Rolling Stone, Ballad of a Thin Man, All Along the Watchtower, Masters of War ou encore Gates of Eden. Certaines de ses chansons comme Blowin' in the Wind et The Times They Are a-Changin' sont devenues des hymnes anti-guerre, en particulier anti-guerre du Vietnam et des mouvements civils de l'époque. L'un de ses derniers albums studio, Modern Times, publié en 2006, est entré directement à la première place dans le classement Billboard 200 et a été nommé Album de l'année par le magazine Rolling Stone. Dans ses premières chansons Dylan a abordé les questions sociales, et trahissait une forte influence philosophique et littéraire défiant les « existants » de la musique pop classique, et il faisait généralement appel à la contre-culture de l'époque. Tout en élargissant et en personnalisant les styles musicaux, il a montré une grande dévotion à de nombreuses traditions de la musique américaine, folk, country, blues, gospel, rock'n'roll et rockabilly, ainsi qu’à la musique folk anglaise, écossaise et irlandaise. Depuis le début de sa carrière, dans les années 1960, Dylan a, par ses textes et par sa recherche de voies nouvelles (allant parfois même à l’encontre de son public), sensiblement marqué la culture musicale contemporaine : en témoignent les nombreux artistes qui se réclament de son influence, ou le vaste répertoire des chansons qu'il a composées, dans lequel puisent des musiciens de tous les horizons et de toutes les générations Les références dont s’inspire Bob Dylan pour faire évoluer son art sont non seulement à rechercher du côté de musiciens américains légendaires, tels Hank Williams, Woody Guthrie et Robert Johnson, mais aussi chez des écrivains de la Beat generation, comme Jack Kerouac ou Allen Ginsberg. Il apprécie également Arthur Rimbaud, à qui il sera souvent comparé, et s’intéresse à des dramaturges, tel Bertolt Brecht. Complexe, en constante évolution (il réinvente régulièrement chacun de ses standards dans différents registres, allant du rock agressif au jazz en passant par les ballades), proche des aspirations sociales et culturelles des époques qu’elle a traversées, l’œuvre de Dylan a, peut-être plus que toute autre, fait évoluer le rôle de la musique populaire en Occident (cf. Analyses). Depuis 1997, Bob Dylan est régulièrement nommé pour l’obtention du Prix Nobel de littérature. Par ailleurs, les textes de ses chansons, qui se situent entre poésie surréaliste et musique traditionnelle américaine, sont étudiés dans les universités américaines.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_country_singers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Bob Dylan</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Band"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Μπομπ_Ντίλαν"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118528408</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/1990sSingers"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Bob Dylan</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"Gotta Serve Somebody"</dbpprop:title>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_awards_received_by_Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Greenwich_Village,_New_York"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Bob Dylan, właśc. Robert Allen Zimmerman – amerykański piosenkarz, kompozytor, autor tekstów, pisarz i poeta. Jest jedną z najważniejszych postaci muzyki popularnej ostatnich pięciu dekad. Swój indywidualny styl oparł na wielu gatunkach muzycznych, od tradycyjnego amerykańskiego folku i country-bluesa do muzyki gospel, rock and rolla, rockabilly, czy angielskiej, szkockiej i irlandzkiej muzyki folkowej, a także jazzu i swingu. Występuje z gitarą akustyczną, elektryczną, keyboardem, harmonijką ustną. Wczesne utwory Boba Dylana zawierające komentarze społeczne, polityczne, filozoficzne i odwołujące się do literatury ignorowały istniejące konwencje muzyki pop wpisując się w nurt ówczesnej kontrkultury. Twórca piosenek uznawanych za hymny pokolenia: Blowin' in the Wind, Like a Rolling Stone i protest songów: The Times They Are a-Changin', Hurricane. Jego twórczość była nagradzana Grammy, Oscarem i Nagrodą Pulitzera. Został kilkakrotnie nominowany do Nagrody Nobla w dziedzinie literatury. W 2009 otrzymał Narodowy Medal Sztuki, a w 2012 – Prezydencki Medal Wolności. W 1994 Dylan wystąpił na koncertach w Krakowie i Sali Kongresowej, a 7 czerwca 2008 roku w warszawskim klubie Stodoła.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1941-05-24</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dbpprop:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Singing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Duluth,_Minnesota"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:alias xml:lang="en">Elston Gunnn, Blind Boy Grunt, Bob Landy, Robert Milkwood Thomas, Tedham Porterhouse, Lucky/Boo Wilbury, Jack Frost, Sergei Petrov</dbpedia-owl:alias>
    <dbpprop:pos xml:lang="en">right</dbpprop:pos>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.bobdylan.com/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">鲍勃·迪伦（英语：Bob Dylan，1941年5月24日－），原名羅伯特·艾倫·齊默曼（Robert Allen Zimmerman），是一位有重要影響力的美國唱作人，民謠歌手，音樂家，詩人。 迪伦成名於1960年代，並被廣泛認為是美國六十年代反叛文化的代言人。他的一些歌曲，例如《答案在風中飄》（Blowing in The Wind）（或譯為《隨風而飄》等），成為在反戰抗議和民權運動中被廣泛傳唱的曲目。直到今天，他仍然是非常具有影響力非常受歡迎的藝人之一。他的歌詞包含了政治抗議、社會評論、哲學和詩歌。除了在音樂上形式的探索以外，他也繼承了美國傳統的民謠、搖滾樂、鄉村和藍調音樂，甚至包括爵士和搖擺樂。</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Grammy_Award_winners"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Guitar"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Harmonica"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">鲍勃·迪伦（英语：Bob Dylan，1941年5月24日－），原名羅伯特·艾倫·齊默曼（Robert Allen Zimmerman），是一位有重要影響力的美國唱作人，民謠歌手，音樂家，詩人。 迪伦成名於1960年代，並被廣泛認為是美國六十年代反叛文化的代言人。他的一些歌曲，例如《答案在風中飄》（Blowing in The Wind）（或譯為《隨風而飄》等），成為在反戰抗議和民權運動中被廣泛傳唱的曲目。直到今天，他仍然是非常具有影響力非常受歡迎的藝人之一。他的歌詞包含了政治抗議、社會評論、哲學和詩歌。除了在音樂上形式的探索以外，他也繼承了美國傳統的民謠、搖滾樂、鄉村和藍調音樂，甚至包括爵士和搖擺樂。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">밥 딜런은 미국의 싱어송라이터, 시인, 화가이다. 유대인 집안에서 태어났고, 본명은 로버트 앨런 지머맨 (히브리어 샤브타이 지셀 벤 아브라함)이다. 그의 작품은 1960년대부터 비공식 작자와 저항음악의 대표로서 사랑을 받았다. 한국의 학생운동에도 영향을 준"Blowin' in the Wind"그리고 "The Times They Are a-Changin'"과 같은 노래들은 사회상을 잘 보여주는 저항적 노랫말로 시민권을 대표하는 곡이 되었으며, 베트남 전쟁에 대한 저항의 표상이 되었다. 대중음악 역사상 가장 영향력있는 음악가 중 한명으로 꼽힌다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">Dylan said of the opening song from Blood on the Tracks: "I was trying to deal with the concept of time, and the way the characters change from the first person to the third person, and you're never sure if the first person is talking or the third person. But as you look at the whole thing it really doesn't matter."</dbpprop:description>
    <dbpedia-owl:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Keyboard_instrument"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/JewishAmericanWriters"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/JewishAmericanComposersAndSongwriters"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Byrds"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Duluth, Minnesota, United States</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Bob Dylan, geboren als Robert Allen Zimmerman is een Amerikaans popmusicus.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Bob Dylan, amerikai énekes, dalszerző, zenész, költő. Munkásságát gyakran hasonlítják Stephen Foster, Irving Berlin, Woody Guthrie és Hank Williams pályafutásához. Dylan legismertebb dalai az 1960-as években születtek, amikor az amerikai nyugtalanság krónikása és visszahúzódó vezéralakja lett. Több dala, például a "Blowin' in the Wind" és a "The Times They Are A-Changin'" a háborúellenes és polgárjogi mozgalmak himnuszává vált.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Converts_to_Christianity"/>
    <dbpprop:wikt xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:wikt>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Joan_Baez"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Authority_control"/>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"Lay Lady Lay"</dbpprop:title>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Columbia_Records_artists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Боб Ді́лан (Bob Dylan) — псевдонім Роберта Аллена Ціммермана (англ. Robert Allen Zimmerman) — американський співак, композитор, поет і гітарист, з лірики якого запозичено багато крилатих фраз, а музика вплинула на величезну кількість композиторів-піснярів.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Dylan, Bob</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"Blowin' in the Wind"</dbpprop:title>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/American_folk_music"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Боб Ді́лан (Bob Dylan) — псевдонім Роберта Аллена Ціммермана (англ. Robert Allen Zimmerman) — американський співак, композитор, поет і гітарист, з лірики якого запозичено багато крилатих фраз, а музика вплинула на величезну кількість композиторів-піснярів.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:University_of_Minnesota_alumni"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/2010sSingers"/>
    <dbpprop:format rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ogg"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:The_Band"/>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"The Times They Are a-Changin'"</dbpprop:title>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Christians_of_Jewish_descent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bobdylan.com/"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:United_States_National_Medal_of_Arts_recipients"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Sony/ATV_Music_Publishing_artists"/>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Musician, singer-songwriter, producer, visual artist, poet, writer, director, screenwriter</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Kennedy_Center_honorees"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">鲍勃·迪伦</rdfs:label>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan</foaf:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_multi-instrumentalists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Artist"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromSt.LouisCounty,Minnesota"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_folk_guitarists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:hometown rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Hibbing,_Minnesota"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Byrds"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MusiciansFromNewYorkCity"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1941-05-24</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Blues"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Боб Ділан</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/1970sSingers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_folk_rock_musicians"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Robert Allen Zimmerman</foaf:givenName>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Johnny_Cash"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ColumbiaRecordsArtists"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Bob Dylan, född Robert Allen Zimmerman den 24 maj 1941 i Duluth, Minnesota, är en amerikansk singer-songwriter, författare, regissör, poet, gitarrist, keyboardist samt munspelare, vid senare tid programledare i radio. Dylan har varit en frontfigur inom populärmusik i närmare femtio år, ofta beskriven som en levande legend inom rockmusiken. Många av Dylans mest prisade låtar kommer från 1960-talet, då han kom att bli en förgrundsfigur i USA och han ansågs av många skildra en hel generation.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_poets"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Best_Song_Academy_Award_winning_songwriters"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Боб_Дилан"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_Jews"/>
    <dbpprop:viaf rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">111894442</dbpprop:viaf>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromDuluth,Minnesota"/>
    <dbpprop:species xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:species>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MusiciansFromMinnesota"/>
    <dbpprop:yearsActive rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1961</dbpprop:yearsActive>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_musical_artist"/>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Bob Dylan performs The Times they are a Changin' at the White House.ogv</dbpprop:filename>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Grammy_Lifetime_Achievement_Award_winners"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1961-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear>
    <dbpprop:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Keyboard_instrument"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Bob Dylan</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace xml:lang="en">Duluth, Minnesota, U.S.</dbpprop:birthPlace>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Distintosi anche come scrittore, poeta, pittore, attore e conduttore radiofonico, è una delle più importanti figure degli ultimi cinquant'anni nel campo musicale, in quello della cultura popolare e della letteratura. La maggior parte delle sue canzoni più conosciute risale agli anni sessanta, quando l'artista si è posto come figura chiave del movement, il movimento di protesta americano.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Country_music"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ConvertsToChristianity"/>
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">Blowin' in the Wind was, according to critic Andy Gill, "the song with which Dylan's name is most inextricably linked, and safeguarded his reputation as a civil libertarian through any number of changes in style and attitude."</dbpprop:description>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Bob Dylan</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Bob Dylan, geboren als Robert Allen Zimmerman is een Amerikaans popmusicus.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Боб Дилан — американский автор-исполнитель песен, поэт, художник, киноактёр. Является культовой фигурой в рок-музыке на протяжении пяти десятилетий. Многие его песни, такие как «Blowin' in the Wind» и «The Times They Are a-Changin'», стали гимнами для движения гражданских прав и антивоенного движения в США. По данным опроса журнала Rolling Stone — является второй по значимости фигурой в истории рок-музыки.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Bob Dylan, amerikai énekes, dalszerző, zenész, költő. Munkásságát gyakran hasonlítják Stephen Foster, Irving Berlin, Woody Guthrie és Hank Williams pályafutásához. Dylan legismertebb dalai az 1960-as években születtek, amikor az amerikai nyugtalanság krónikása és visszahúzódó vezéralakja lett. Több dala, például a "Blowin' in the Wind" és a "The Times They Are A-Changin'" a háborúellenes és polgárjogi mozgalmak himnuszává vált. Dylan ezután is megőrizte befolyását és népszerűségét; "Love and Theft" című albuma az USA-ban 5. , Nagy-Britanniában a 3. lett. Dalszövegeire hatással volt a politika, a szociális kommentár, a filozófia és az irodalom, így sikeresen szállt szembe a korabeli könnyűzene konvencióival és elnyerte az ellenkultúra tetszését. Míg kitágította és magáévá tette a zenei stílusokat, hatással volt rá többek között a folk, a country, a blues, a rock and roll, a kelta ballada és a jazz. Dylan gitáron, billentyűs hangszereken és szájharmonikán játszik. Állandóan változó összetételű zenekarával az 1980-as évek vége óta rendszeresen turnézik. Alkalmanként más zenészekkel is együtt játszott, például Paul Simonnal, Tom Pettyvel és Eric Claptonnal. Bár pályájának középpontjában előadói munkássága és albumai állnak, általában mégis dalszerzői tehetségéért rajonganak.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">Dylan's Oscar winning song was featured in the movie Wonder Boys. The line "sapphire-tinted skies" echoes the verse of Shelley while "forty miles of bad road" echoes Duane Eddy's hit single.</dbpprop:description>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PolarMusicPrizeLaureates"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Sister_project_links"/>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"Like a Rolling Stone"</dbpprop:title>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Band"/>
    <dbpprop:description xml:lang="en">audio only version</dbpprop:description>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gospel_music"/>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Lay_Lady_Lay.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpprop:lccn xml:lang="en">n/50/30190</dbpprop:lccn>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Bob</foaf:givenName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Bob Dylan on yhdysvaltalainen folk- ja rocklaulaja ja -lauluntekijä sekä elokuvanäyttelijä. Häntä pidetään yhtenä kaikkien aikojen merkittävimmistä lauluntekijöistä. Runotutkija Christopher Ricks nostaa hänet merkittävien englanninkielisten sanataitureiden rinnalle ja vertaa häntä William Wordsworthiin, John Donneen ja Alfred Tennysoniin. Dylanin tunnetuimpia kappaleita ovat Blowin' in the Wind, The Times They Are a-Changin', Like a Rolling Stone, Knockin' on Heavens Door ja Mr. Tambourine Man.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Rock and folk musician</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ボブ・ディラン"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/MusicalPerformer"/>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Bob_Dylan_-_The_Times_They_Are_a-Changin'.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Byrds"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_DJs"/>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Traveling_Wilburys"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_Christians"/>
    <dbpprop:description rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gMonthDay">--02-09</dbpprop:description>
    <dbpprop:n xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:n>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanRockGuitarists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/JewishAmericanMusicians"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/1980sSingers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedMusicalArtist rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Band"/>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">"The Times they are a Changin'"</dbpprop:title>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://zitgist.com/music/artist/72c536dc-7137-4477-a521-567eeb840fa8"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Pulitzer_Prize_winners"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/JewishWriters"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Bob Dylan er en amerikansk musiker, sanger, låtskriver, poet og forfatter, og i den senere tid også radiovert, som har vært en av de mest innflytelsesrike og viktige personene innen populærmusikken gjennom mer enn 45 år. De siste årene har Dylan hatt en renessanse gjennom plater, memoarbok, dokumentarfilm av Martin Scorsese og sin kontinuerlige konsertvirksomhet, som har bidratt til å befeste en enestående posisjon innen populærkulturen. Bob Dylan forandret populærmusikken på to viktige punkter: Han økte betydningen av sangteksten,og han gjorde det klart at en pen sangstemme og en effektiv rock'n'roll-stemme ikke nødvendigvis er det samme. Mange av Dylans mest kjente sanger er fra 1960-tallet, da han ofte ble omtalt som «talsmann for en generasjon» og ble en ledende skikkelse i den voksende amerikanske motkulturen. Sanger som «Blowin' In the Wind» og «The Times They Are A-Changin'» ble viktige for borgerrettighetsbevegelsen i USA og krigsmotstandere verden over. Dylan ble først kjent som visesanger. Han opptrer med gitar, piano og munnspill. Dylan møtte både motstand og begeistring da «protestsangene» begynte å nærme seg popmusikkens og rockens formspråk. Samtidig brakte han, som en av de første artistene, intelligente og engasjerende tekster inn i pop og rock. Med sin sammensmelting av folkemusikk og rock til folkrock ga han viktige impulser til den framvoksende motkulturen. Han har utviklet og personliggjort en rekke sjangre, men han har en særlig nærhet til amerikanske sjangre og tradisjoner. Musikken er inspirert av alt fra folk, country og blues til rock and roll og rockabilly og fra engelsk, irsk og skotsk folkemusikk til jazz, gospel, swing og hardrock. Med et bredt utvalg av musikere med seg har Dylan turnert jevnt og trutt siden slutten av 1980-tallet. Han har også opptrådt sammen med en rekke kjente artister: The Band, Tom Petty, Joan Baez, George Harrison, The Grateful Dead, Johnny Cash, Willie Nelson, Paul Simon, Eric Clapton, Patti Smith, Emmylou Harris, Bruce Springsteen, U2, The Rolling Stones, Joni Mitchell, Jack White, Merle Haggard, Neil Young, Van Morrison, Ringo Starr og Stevie Nicks. Selv om opptredenene har hatt stor betydning for Dylans karriere regnes først og fremst prestasjonene som låtskriver som hans viktigste. Gjennom årene har Dylan blitt hedret for sine utgivelser og opptredener mange ganger. Utgivelsene hans har vunnet både Grammy, Golden Globe og Academy Award, og han har blitt tatt opp i Rockens æresgalleri (Rock and Roll Hall of Fame), Nashville Songwriters Hall of Fame og Songwriters Hall of Fame. I 1999 ble Dylan regnet blant de 100 mest innflytelsesrike personene fra det 20. århundre av TIME Magazine. I 2004 ble han listet som nummer to på magasinet Rolling Stone sin kåring «Greatest Artist of All Time», kun slått av The Beatles. Han har blitt nominert til Nobelprisen i litteratur flere ganger. I april 2008 ble han tildelt en «Special Citation» under utdelingen av Pulitzer-prisen, som første rock-musiker. Dylan ble i 2012 tildelt Presidentens frihetsmedalje. Hans nest siste album, Modern Times, kom ut den 29. august 2006 og toppet umiddelbart hitlistene i USA. I en alder av 65 er han den eldste som har toppet disse listene. Magasinet Rolling Stone utropte Modern Times til årets album.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Dylan</foaf:surname>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Bob_Dylan"/>
    <dbpprop:instrument rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Harmonica"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Bob Dylan [ˈdɪlən] ist ein US-amerikanischer Folk- und Rockmusiker, Dichter und Maler. Bob Dylan singt, spielt Gitarre, Mundharmonika und Klavier und gilt als einer der einflussreichsten Musiker des 20. Jahrhunderts. Dylan begann Ende der 1950er-Jahre nach Rock`n`Roll-Jahren in Schülerbands als Folkmusiker und wandte sich Mitte der 1960er-Jahre der Rockmusik zu.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:associatedBand rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Grateful_Dead"/>
    <dbpprop:associatedActs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mark_Knopfler"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Songwriters_Hall_of_Fame_inductees"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Navboxes"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_rock_singer-songwriters"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Musicians_from_New_York_City"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
