<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot">
    <dbpedia-owl:birthName xml:lang="en">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot</dbpedia-owl:birthName>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/브리지트_바르도"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Brigitte Bardot, född 28 september 1934 i Paris, är en fransk skådespelerska, sångerska, modell och djurrättsaktivist. Bardots far var ingenjör och verksam i ett familjeföretag. Hennes mor var 14 år yngre än fadern och de gifte sig 1933. Modern uppmuntrade dottern att ta lektioner i musik och dans. Hon började som fotomodell då hon var 15 år och bilder av henne publicerades redan då i det franska magasinet Elle. Hennes ungdomliga skönhet visade sig när hon fick roller i filmer. Hon debuterade i filmen i Le Trou normand 1952. Samma år gjorde hon ytterligare två filmer och gifte sig med Roger Vadim. De hade då redan känt varandra några år, men föräldrarna hindrade henne att gifta sig innan hon fyllt 18 år. Äktenskapet höll i fem år. 1953 gjorde hon sin första amerikanska film, Un acte d’amour, med Kirk Douglas. Hon fortsatte dock att även göra fransk film. Brigitte Bardot var 1966-1969 gift med Gunter Sachs. Hennes filmer är av varierande kvalitet, men Jean-Luc Godards Föraktet och Henri-Georges Clouzots rättegångsdrama Sanningen, med Bardots gripande porträtt av en misstrodd kvinna, måste räknas som två höjdpunkter. Kändast är hon emellertid för Och Gud skapade kvinnan.... 1965 spelade hon sig själv i den amerikanska filmen Dear Brigitte, i vilken hon spelade mot James Stewart. Innan hon fyllde 40 år slutade hon att medverka i filmer. Hon drog sig tillbaka som artist med den sista filmen Le Historie tres bonne et tres joyeuse de Colionot Trousse-Cehmise. Hon har därefter levt ett tillbakadraget liv för att undvika nyfikna och fotografer. Senare har hon dock var mycket aktiv i olika frågor rörande djurrättigheter och grundade en stiftelse i sitt eget namn i syfte att värna om djurens rättigheter. Hon är vegetarian och skrev tillsammans med ett stort antal organisationer 2009 ett öppet brev till EU:s ordförande om förslaget att instifta en officiell europeisk vegetarisk dag. Hon har också gjort flera politiska uttalanden riktade mot invandrare och särskilt muslimer, vilket har lett till att hon flera gånger fällts i domstol för hets mot folkgrupp. Bardot spelade även in ett flertal skivor under 60-talet. Många av låtarna är skrivna av Serge Gainsbourg, bland annat "Contact", "Harley Davidson", "Bonnie &amp; Clyde" och "Comic Strip".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Bardot</foaf:surname>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FrenchFemaleSingers"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Brigitte Bardot</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ブリジット・バルドー（Brigitte Bardot、1934年9月28日 - ）は、フランス・パリ出身の女優、ファッションモデル、動物保護活動家である。頭文字が B.B. であることから、同じ発音で「赤ん坊」を意味するフランス語 bébéとかけて「BB」が愛称になった。　</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FrenchFemaleModels"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Paris, France</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Actors_from_Paris"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Brigitte Bardotová</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Singer110599806"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:French_activists"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ブリジット・バルドー"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/French-languAgeSingers"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot is a former French fashion model, actress, singer and animal rights activist. She was one of the best-known sex symbols of the 1960s. Starting in 1969, Bardot's features became the official face of Marianne (who had previously been anonymous) to represent the liberty of France. Bardot was an aspiring ballet dancer in early life. She started her acting career in 1952 and, after appearing in 16 films, became world-famous due to her role in her then-husband Roger Vadim's controversial film And God Created Woman. She later starred in Jean-Luc Godard's 1963 cult film Contempt. Bardot was nominated for a BAFTA Award for Best Foreign Actress for her role in Louis Malle's 1965 film Viva Maria!. Bardot caught the attention of French intellectuals. She was the subject of Simone de Beauvoir's 1959 essay, The Lolita Syndrome, which described Bardot as a "locomotive of women's history" and built upon existentialist themes to declare her the first and most liberated woman of post-war France. Bardot retired from the entertainment industry in 1973. During her career in show business, Bardot starred in 47 films, performed in numerous musical shows, and recorded 80 songs. She was awarded the Legion of Honour in 1985, but refused to receive it. After her retirement, Bardot established herself as an animal rights activist. During the 1990s she generated controversy by criticizing immigration, Islamization and Islam in France, and has been fined five times for "inciting racial hatred".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Brigitte Bardot, còn được gọi là BB, là một nữ diễn viên người Pháp nổi tiếng trong thập niên 1950, thập niên 1960 vì thân hình và phong cách diễn xuất gợi cảm. BB sinh ra tại thủ đô Paris, Pháp. Năm 1947, với mong muốn trở thành một vũ công, bà vào học tại trường múa Conservatoire Nationale de Danse. Không lâu sau đó, bà bắt đầu làm người mẫu thời trang và xuất hiện trên bìa tạp chí Elle vào tháng 5 năm 1949. Chính tấm ảnh bìa này đã đem đến cơ hội thử vai đầu tiên cho bà. Bộ phim đầu tay của BB là Le Trou Normand (1952) do Jean Boyer đạo diễn, trong phim này bà đóng chung với danh hài Bourvil. Sự xuất hiện của BB tại Liên hoan phim Cannes 1953 là một bước ngoặt đưa tên tuổi bà trở nên nổi tiếng.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:alias xml:lang="en">BB</dbpedia-owl:alias>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Brigitte Bardot, celým jménem Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot je francouzská herečka, zpěvačka a bojovnice za práva zvířat. Byla sexuálním symbolem 50. a 60. let 20. století. K filmové kariéře jí pomohl první manžel režisér Roger Vadim. Jejím nejúspěšnějším filmem byl A bůh stvořil ženu natočený roku 1956. Je vegetariánka a silná kuřačka. Byla několikrát vdaná. Jejím prvním manželem se stal Roger Vadim, který ji pomoh k filmové kariéře. S Vadimem se rozvedla v roce 1957 a dva roky na to se podruhé provdala, a to za herce Jacquese Charriera, s nímž má své jediné vlastní dítě - syna Nicolase, poté si vzala německého milionáře Gunthera Sachse a jejím nynějším manželem je od roku 1992 francouzský politik Bernard d'Ormale. Brigitte Bardotová se rozhodla ukončit svou filmovou kariéru ve svých 39 letech a svůj další život zasvětila již zmiňovanému boji za práva zvířat, jemuž se věnuje dodnes.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Brigitte Bardot es una actriz y símbolo sexual francesa de mediados del siglo XX. Junto a Sophia Loren, es una de las pocas supervivientes del cine clásico.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Critics_of_Islam"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Brigitte Bardot</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Brigitte Bardot es una actriz y símbolo sexual francesa de mediados del siglo XX. Junto a Sophia Loren, es una de las pocas supervivientes del cine clásico.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:awards rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/David_di_Donatello"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Brigitte Bardot</foaf:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Dopo gli esordi come danzatrice classica, diviene prima attrice e poi, dal 1962, cantante. Dagli anni cinquanta è considerata un'icona sexy.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:French_vegetarians"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:French_female_singers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Brigitte Bardot is een Frans fotomodel, actrice en zangeres. Als ondeugende "stoeipoes" en frivole pin-upgirl maakte ze zeer snel internationaal furore en vooral in Europa vormde ze een icoon van de jaren 50. Als sekssymbool was zij een Frans antwoord op de Amerikaanse Marilyn Monroe (MM). Haar naam werd vaak afgekort als BB, wat vanwege de alliteratie erg voor de hand lag, maar wat nog meer populair werd door een tophit van Dario Moreno (1961), waarin Bardot in het Frans en Portugees wordt bezongen. DOORVERWIJZINGSjabloon:Bron?</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/LivingPeople"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot is a former French fashion model, actress, singer and animal rights activist. She was one of the best-known sex symbols of the 1960s. Starting in 1969, Bardot's features became the official face of Marianne (who had previously been anonymous) to represent the liberty of France. Bardot was an aspiring ballet dancer in early life.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Brigitte Bardot francia színésznő, énekes, állatvédő. Az igazi, tiszta szexepilt ábrázolta egy meglehetősen prűd korszakban. Ruhái, frizurái megszabták az 1960-as évek divatirányzatát. Merész szerepei miatt sokan a bűn megtestesítőjének tekintették akkoriban.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Brigitte Bardot, właściwie Brigitte Anne Marie Bardot – francuska modelka, piosenkarka i aktorka filmowa, symbol seksu w latach 50. i 60. XX wieku, później także działaczka na rzecz ochrony praw zwierząt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Brigitte Bardot, celým jménem Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot je francouzská herečka, zpěvačka a bojovnice za práva zvířat. Byla sexuálním symbolem 50. a 60. let 20. století. K filmové kariéře jí pomohl první manžel režisér Roger Vadim. Jejím nejúspěšnějším filmem byl A bůh stvořil ženu natočený roku 1956. Je vegetariánka a silná kuřačka. Byla několikrát vdaná. Jejím prvním manželem se stal Roger Vadim, který ji pomoh k filmové kariéře.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Brigitte Bardot, właściwie Brigitte Anne Marie Bardot – francuska modelka, piosenkarka i aktorka filmowa, symbol seksu w latach 50. i 60. XX wieku, później także działaczka na rzecz ochrony praw zwierząt.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">브리지트 바르도는 프랑스 파리 시 태생의 배우, 가수, 모델이다. 1950년 ~ 1960년대를 풍미한 섹시 심볼로 알려져 있다. 1970년대 은퇴이후에 동물 권익 보호 운동가로 변신하여 오늘에 이르고 있다. 1990년대에 들어 프랑스사회에서 종종 반이민, 반이슬람, 반동성애 및 인종차별적 언행으로 사회적 논란을 야기시켰다. 르펜이 당수로 있는 극우 정당 국민 전선의 지지자로서 그녀의 남편도 당원이다. 대한민국에서는 개고기 반대로 한국 제품 불매 운동등을 벌인 것으로 유명하다. 2008년, 무슬림을 공개적으로 비난하는 인종차별적 망언으로 인해 재판에 회부되어 벌금 및 집유를 선고받았다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:occupation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot__1"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Bardot, Brigitte</dbpprop:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">브리지트 바르도는 프랑스 파리 시 태생의 배우, 가수, 모델이다. 1950년 ~ 1960년대를 풍미한 섹시 심볼로 알려져 있다. 1970년대 은퇴이후에 동물 권익 보호 운동가로 변신하여 오늘에 이르고 있다. 1990년대에 들어 프랑스사회에서 종종 반이민, 반이슬람, 반동성애 및 인종차별적 언행으로 사회적 논란을 야기시켰다. 르펜이 당수로 있는 극우 정당 국민 전선의 지지자로서 그녀의 남편도 당원이다. 대한민국에서는 개고기 반대로 한국 제품 불매 운동등을 벌인 것으로 유명하다. 2008년, 무슬림을 공개적으로 비난하는 인종차별적 망언으로 인해 재판에 회부되어 벌금 및 집유를 선고받았다.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/78/Brigitte_Bardot.jpg"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_person"/>
    <dbpprop:alternativeNames xml:lang="en">BB</dbpprop:alternativeNames>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Брижи́т Анн-Мари́ Бардо́ — французская певица, киноактриса, фотомодель и защитница животных. Впервые снялась в кино в 1952 году. Завоевала всемирную популярность благодаря роли в фильме «И Бог создал женщину» 1956 года. В 1950-х она была для Европы таким же секс-символом, как Мэрилин Монро для Америки. В течение своей 21-летней карьеры в шоу-бизнесе снялась в 48 фильмах, записала 80 песен, выступила в различных музыкальных шоу. Закончив кинокарьеру в 1973 году, Бардо начала деятельность по защите животных. С 1990-х неоднократно выступала с критикой иммигрантов и ислама во Франции, гомосексуализма и межрасовых браков, в результате чего 5 раз была осуждена «за разжигание межнациональной розни».</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://zitgist.com/music/artist/efbdded5-ab91-4bb7-ba57-f36d7413eb70"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:MGM_Records_artists"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Бріжіт Бардо</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot é uma atriz e cantora francesa. Conhecida mundialmente por suas iniciais, BB, é considerada o grande símbolo sexual dos anos 50 e anos 1960. Tornou-se ativista dos direitos animais, após se retirar do mundo do entretenimento e se afastar da vida pública.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ActorsWhoAttemptedSuicide"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Animal_rights_advocates"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:French_film_actors"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot ist ein ehemaliges französisches Model, frühere Filmschauspielerin, Sängerin und erotische Ikone. Sie wurde nach ihrer Karriere im Jet-Set der 1960er Jahre als Tierschutzaktivistin und zunehmend als Symbolfigur der französischen Rechten bekannt.</rdfs:comment>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brigitte_Bardot?oldid=495083713"/>
    <dbpprop:yearsActive rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1952</dbpprop:yearsActive>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1934-09-28</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <dbpprop:birthName xml:lang="en">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot</dbpprop:birthName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Brigitte Bardot és una actriu francesa nascuda el 28 de setembre de 1934 a París. Coneguda com BB, Bardot és considerada la personificació del mite eròtic dels anys 50.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/78/Brigitte_Bardot.jpg/200px-Brigitte_Bardot.jpg"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">French actress and animal welfare activist</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Brigitte Bardot</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">碧姬·芭杜</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:French_female_models"/>
    <dbpprop:awards rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Legion_of_Honour"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Brigitte Bardot is een Frans fotomodel, actrice en zangeres. Als ondeugende "stoeipoes" en frivole pin-upgirl maakte ze zeer snel internationaal furore en vooral in Europa vormde ze een icoon van de jaren 50. Als sekssymbool was zij een Frans antwoord op de Amerikaanse Marilyn Monroe (MM).</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Bardot in 1968</dbpprop:caption>
    <dbpedia-owl:award rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Legion_of_Honour"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ブリジット・バルドー（Brigitte Bardot、1934年9月28日 - ）は、フランス・パリ出身の女優、ファッションモデル、動物保護活動家である。頭文字が B.B. であることから、同じ発音で「赤ん坊」を意味するフランス語 bébéとかけて「BB」が愛称になった。　</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:L%C3%A9gion_d'honneur_refusals"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paris"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Бардо,_Брижит"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MGMRecordsArtists"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Μπριζίτ_Μπαρντό"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.fondationbrigittebardot.fr/site/homepage.php?Id=2"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118506552</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Brigitte Bardot, född 28 september 1934 i Paris, är en fransk skådespelerska, sångerska, modell och djurrättsaktivist. Bardots far var ingenjör och verksam i ett familjeföretag. Hennes mor var 14 år yngre än fadern och de gifte sig 1933. Modern uppmuntrade dottern att ta lektioner i musik och dans. Hon började som fotomodell då hon var 15 år och bilder av henne publicerades redan då i det franska magasinet Elle. Hennes ungdomliga skönhet visade sig när hon fick roller i filmer.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Breast_cancer_survivors"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Brigitte</foaf:givenName>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Model110324560"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Брижи́т Анн-Мари́ Бардо́ — французская певица, киноактриса, фотомодель и защитница животных. Впервые снялась в кино в 1952 году. Завоевала всемирную популярность благодаря роли в фильме «И Бог создал женщину» 1956 года. В 1950-х она была для Европы таким же секс-символом, как Мэрилин Монро для Америки. В течение своей 21-летней карьеры в шоу-бизнесе снялась в 48 фильмах, записала 80 песен, выступила в различных музыкальных шоу.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Actor"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AnimalRightsAdvocates"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Бріжі́т Анн-Марі́ Бардо́ — французька кіноактриса, фотомодель, співачка, секс-символ 1950-60-х років. Із початку 1970-х — активістка руху за права тварин, засновниця й голова фонду захисту тварин Fondation Brigitte Bardot. У юності Бардо займалася балетом. Розпочавши кінокар'єру в 1952 році, вона здобула статус секс-символу та всесвітню популярність завдяки кінофільму «І Бог створив жінку».</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">碧姬·芭铎（法文：Brigitte Bardot，1934年9月28日－， [bʁiʒit baʁˈdo]）法国电影女明星，昵称“BB”，有时也被称为“性感小猫”。 芭杜出生于巴黎，少女时便以美貌闻名，被时尚杂志ELLE发掘担任模特。1952年，她身着比基尼出演首部电影《穿比基尼的姑娘》，一举奠定自己性感女神的地位，也使得比基尼迅速流行。同年，她开始与罗杰·瓦迪姆同居。1956年，她出演瓦迪姆的电影《上帝創造女人》，大胆暴露的表演使得她在美国的知名度急剧上升，一时与玛丽莲·梦露风头无两，被视为性解放的代表人物之一。之后，她一度前往好莱坞发展，与柯克·道格拉斯等影星有过合作。 1973年，碧姬·芭铎宣布息影，此后成为积极的动物保护主义活动分子。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1934-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:birthYear>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/BreastCancerSurvivors"/>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Actress, model, singer, animal rights activist</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Бріжі́т Анн-Марі́ Бардо́ — французька кіноактриса, фотомодель, співачка, секс-символ 1950-60-х років. Із початку 1970-х — активістка руху за права тварин, засновниця й голова фонду захисту тварин Fondation Brigitte Bardot. У юності Бардо займалася балетом. Розпочавши кінокар'єру в 1952 році, вона здобула статус секс-символу та всесвітню популярність завдяки кінофільму «І Бог створив жінку». Протягом 21-річної кар'єри у шоу-бізнесі знялася в 48 фільмах, виступила в численних музичних програмах і записала 80 пісень; номінувалася на премію Британської Кіноакадемії за роль у фільмі «Віва Марія!». Екранному образу Бардо властиві сексуальність у сполученні з безпосередністю й простодушністю. Як акторка найбільшого успіху досягла в жанрі романтичної комедії, але найвизначнішими фільмами за її участю критики вважають драми «І Бог створив жінку», «Істина» і «Зневага». У 1970 році Бардо першою була обрана моделлю для погруддя Маріанни, офіційного символу Франції. Завершивши кінокар'єру в 1973 році, вона присвятила своє життя боротьбі за права тварин. У 1990-х почала виступати із критикою іммігрантів і мусульман Франції і, як наслідок, була 5 разів засуджена за «збурювання ненависті на расистському ґрунті».</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Brigitte Bardot, née Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot le 28 septembre 1934 à Paris, est une actrice de cinéma et chanteuse française, une militante de la cause animale, ainsi que la fondatrice et présidente de la fondation qui porte son nom. Figure féminine des années 1950 et 1960, elle fut une star mondiale, l'égérie et la muse des plus grands artistes de l'époque. Emblème de l'émancipation des femmes et de la liberté sexuelle, elle passa des rôles de femme enfant à ceux de femme fatale. Elle tourna avec les plus grands réalisateurs incarnant des personnages à l'élégante légèreté et à la sensualité photogénique. Elle devint rapidement un sex-symbol. Avec à son actif 48 films et plus de 80 chansons en 21 ans de carrière, Brigitte Bardot, tout aussi connue sous les initiales de « BB », est une des artistes françaises les plus célèbres. Elle mit un terme à sa carrière d'actrice en 1973 pour se consacrer à la défense des animaux. Par ailleurs, elle fut condamnée pour incitation à la haine raciale à cinq reprises, pour ses critiques envers l'immigration, l'abattage rituel des animaux, le métissage, certains aspects de l'homosexualité ou encore l'islam en France.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">碧姬·芭铎（法文：Brigitte Bardot，1934年9月28日－， [bʁiʒit baʁˈdo]）法国电影女明星，昵称“BB”，有时也被称为“性感小猫”。 芭杜出生于巴黎，少女时便以美貌闻名，被时尚杂志ELLE发掘担任模特。1952年，她身着比基尼出演首部电影《穿比基尼的姑娘》，一举奠定自己性感女神的地位，也使得比基尼迅速流行。同年，她开始与罗杰·瓦迪姆同居。1956年，她出演瓦迪姆的电影《上帝創造女人》，大胆暴露的表演使得她在美国的知名度急剧上升，一时与玛丽莲·梦露风头无两，被视为性解放的代表人物之一。之后，她一度前往好莱坞发展，与柯克·道格拉斯等影星有过合作。 1973年，碧姬·芭铎宣布息影，此后成为积极的动物保护主义活动分子。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:otherNames xml:lang="en">BB</dbpprop:otherNames>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rV-oQhAD8TiKgYROsl_42Iw"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Living_people"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FrenchFilmActors"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FrenchActivists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Brigitte Bardot tai BB on ranskalainen näyttelijä ja laulaja sekä Marilyn Monroen ohella yksi suurista seksisymboleistaMalline:Lähde?. Häntä on nostettu naisliikkeen keulakuvaksi, mutta itse hän on todennut, ettei usko feminismiin, vaan on pikemminkin maskulinisti ("rakastan miehiä").</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Brigitte Bardot, còn được gọi là BB, là một nữ diễn viên người Pháp nổi tiếng trong thập niên 1950, thập niên 1960 vì thân hình và phong cách diễn xuất gợi cảm. BB sinh ra tại thủ đô Paris, Pháp. Năm 1947, với mong muốn trở thành một vũ công, bà vào học tại trường múa Conservatoire Nationale de Danse. Không lâu sau đó, bà bắt đầu làm người mẫu thời trang và xuất hiện trên bìa tạp chí Elle vào tháng 5 năm 1949. Chính tấm ảnh bìa này đã đem đến cơ hội thử vai đầu tiên cho bà.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsEndYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1973-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsEndYear>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Brigitte Bardot tai BB on ranskalainen näyttelijä ja laulaja sekä Marilyn Monroen ohella yksi suurista seksisymboleistaMalline:Lähde?. Häntä on nostettu naisliikkeen keulakuvaksi, mutta itse hän on todennut, ettei usko feminismiin, vaan on pikemminkin maskulinisti ("rakastan miehiä").</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Brigitte Bardot, née Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot le 28 septembre 1934 à Paris, est une actrice de cinéma et chanteuse française, une militante de la cause animale, ainsi que la fondatrice et présidente de la fondation qui porte son nom. Figure féminine des années 1950 et 1960, elle fut une star mondiale, l'égérie et la muse des plus grands artistes de l'époque. Emblème de l'émancipation des femmes et de la liberté sexuelle, elle passa des rôles de femme enfant à ceux de femme fatale.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Individuals_associated_with_animal_welfare"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1934_births"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:award rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/David_di_Donatello"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1952-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Brigitte_Bardotová"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot er en fransk skuespiller. Brigittes far var ingeniør og arbeidet i et familiefirma. Moren var 14 år yngre enn faren, og de giftet seg i 1933. Moren oppmuntret datteren til å ta leksjoner i musikk og dans. Hun begynte som fotomodell da hun var 15, og bilder av henne ble allerede den gang publisert i det franske motemagasinet Elle. Som skuespiller debuterte hun i den franske filmen Le Trou normand i 1952. Samme år spilte hun i ytterligere to filmer, og giftet seg med Roger Vadim. De hadde allerede kjent hverandre i noen år, men foreldrene hadde nektet henne å gifte seg før hun fylte 18. Ekteskapet varte i fem år. I 1953 spilte hun i sin første amerikanske film, Un acte d’amour, med Kirk Douglas. Hun fortsatte også å spille i franske filmer. Filmene var av varierende kvalitet. I 1965 spilte hun seg selv i den amerikanske filmen Dear Brigitte, mot James Stewart. Hun sluttet å medvirke i filmer før hun fylte 40 år. Hun trakk seg tilbake som skuespiller etter filmen: L'Historie très bonne et très joyeuse de Colinot trousse-chemise. Etter dette har hun levd et tilbaketrukket liv for å unngå nysgjerrige fans og fotografer. Hun har vært svært aktiv i arbeid for dyrs rettigheter, og grunnla en stiftelse i sitt eget navn, med formålet å verne om dyrenes rettigheter.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Brigitte Bardot</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:children xml:lang="en">Nicholas-Jacques Charrier</dbpprop:children>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Brigitte Bardot francia színésznő, énekes, állatvédő. Az igazi, tiszta szexepilt ábrázolta egy meglehetősen prűd korszakban. Ruhái, frizurái megszabták az 1960-as évek divatirányzatát. Merész szerepei miatt sokan a bűn megtestesítőjének tekintették akkoriban.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FrenchVegetarians"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">28</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Dopo gli esordi come danzatrice classica, diviene prima attrice e poi, dal 1962, cantante. Dagli anni cinquanta è considerata un'icona sexy.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot é uma atriz e cantora francesa. Conhecida mundialmente por suas iniciais, BB, é considerada o grande símbolo sexual dos anos 50 e anos 1960. Tornou-se ativista dos direitos animais, após se retirar do mundo do entretenimento e se afastar da vida pública.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot er en fransk skuespiller. Brigittes far var ingeniør og arbeidet i et familiefirma. Moren var 14 år yngre enn faren, og de giftet seg i 1933. Moren oppmuntret datteren til å ta leksjoner i musikk og dans. Hun begynte som fotomodell da hun var 15, og bilder av henne ble allerede den gang publisert i det franske motemagasinet Elle. Som skuespiller debuterte hun i den franske filmen Le Trou normand i 1952.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Brigitte Anne-Marie Bardot ist ein ehemaliges französisches Model, frühere Filmschauspielerin, Sängerin und erotische Ikone. Sie wurde nach ihrer Karriere im Jet-Set der 1960er Jahre als Tierschutzaktivistin und zunehmend als Symbolfigur der französischen Rechten bekannt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Paris"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-actor-noun-1"/>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1934-09-28</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:French_Roman_Catholics"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromParis"/>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">French actress and animal welfare activist</dc:description>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Brigitte Bardot és una actriu francesa nascuda el 28 de setembre de 1934 a París. Coneguda com BB, Bardot és considerada la personificació del mite eròtic dels anys 50.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.018hl"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Brigitte_Bardot"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Brigitte Bardot</rdfs:label>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
