<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/British_Council">
    <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/British_Council">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council">
    <dbpprop:foundedDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1934</dbpprop:foundedDate>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://learnenglishkids.britishcouncil.org/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Le British Council est une institution gouvernementale du Royaume-Uni. Son président actuel est Vernon Ellis. Le siège de l'organisation se trouve à Londres, avec des affiliations en 110 pays. Son but est d'établir des relations culturelles entre le Royaume-Uni et d'autres pays ; pour ce but il a, en particulier, pour mission de promouvoir l'apprentissage de la langue anglaise, de participer à sa diffusion et de fortifier sa position dans le monde.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Hội đồng Anh là một tổ chức của Vương quốc Anh chuyên môn trong về lĩnh vực giáo dục và văn hóa quốc tế. Tổ chức này được đăng ký như là tổ chức từ thiện ở Anh Quốc và Xứ Wales, Scotland. Được thành lập vào năm 1934 với tên là Ủy ban Anh quốc về Quan hệ Ngoại Quốc, và được ban cho đặc quyền hoàng gia bởi vua George VI của Anh vào năm 1940, Hội đồng Anh được lấy cảm hứng từ sự công nhận của Ngài Reginald (Rex) Leeper về tầm quan trọng của "tuyên truyền văn hóa" trong việc thúc đẩy lợi ích nước Anh. "Bộ phận tài trợ" trong Chính phủ Vương quốc Anh là Văn phòng Ngoài nước và Khối thịnh vượng chung, mặc dù tổ chức này hoạt động độc lập ngày qua ngày. Martin Davidson là tổng giám đốc điều hành, bổ nhiệm vào tháng 4 năm 2007. Vào ngày 19 tháng 8 năm 2011, những kẻ tấn công tự sát đã xông vào văn phòng Hội đồng Anh ở thủ đô Afghanistan, Kabul, giết ít nhất 12 người - hầu hết trong số đó là người Anh. Trước đó giám đốc Hội đồng Anh tại Kabul xác nhận rằng "những chương trình tiếng Anh quân đội là cốt lõi để Hội đồng Anh làm việc tại Afghanistan."</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Британська рада — неміністерський департамент уряду Великої Британії, що займається поширенням британської культури за межами Великої Британії. Є позавідомчим державним органом, який створений королівською милістю і зареєстрований як благодійна організація в Англії. Заснована 1934 року, 1940 року король Георг VI дарував раді королівську грамоту. Його чинним головою є лорд Ніл Кіннок, колишній лідер британської Лейбористської партії.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.englishonline.org.cn"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://blog.britishcouncil.org/2010/11/teaching-military-english-in-kabul/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://takeielts.britishcouncil.org/"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">British Council</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-south-asia-14585563"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">The British Council er en britisk organisasjon som ble stiftet i 1934. Organisasjonen har kontorer i mange forskjellige land, blant annet i Norge. Organisasjonen jobber med å utvikle forbindelser mellom Storbritannia og andre land. De jobber også en del med å lære bort engelsk til mennesker som ikke kan det. British Council fikk i 2005 Fyrsten av Asturias' pris for kommunikasjon og humaniora sammen med Instituto Camões, Società Dante Alighieri, Alliance Française, Goethe-Institut og Instituto Cervantes for sitt arbeid for menneskeheten innen kommunikasjon.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">British Council – brytyjska agencja ds. współpracy kulturalej oraz oświatowej, z nastawieniem na naukę języka angielskiego. British Council zostało założone w 1934 roku jako "The British Council for Relations with Other Countries" – Brytyjska Rada ds. relacji z innymi krajami. Dwa lata później nazwę skrócono do obecnej formy. Pierwszym zagranicznym biurem tej organizacji był założony w 1938 roku "British Institute in Cairo" – Instytut Brytyjski w Kairze. W tym samym roku powstała polska filia British Council w Warszawie przy ul. Górnośląskiej. Obecnie w Polsce działalność prowadzą dwie placówki British Council - w Warszawie, w al. Jerozolimskich 59; oraz w Krakowie, w Szarej Kamienicy na Rynku Głównym 6. Ich działalność to głównie prowadzenie kursów j. angielskiego na wszystkich poziomach zaawansowania, a także przeprowadzanie egzaminów Cambridge English for Speakers of Other Languages. Testy przygotowywane przez University of Cambridge i przeprowadzane przez oddziały British Council są jednymi z najpopularniejszych ogólnych egzaminów z j. angielskiego.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/InternationalCulturalOrganizations"/>
    <dbpprop:keyPeople xml:lang="en">Martin Davidson</dbpprop:keyPeople>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">British Council on brittiläinen julkinen järjestö, joka edistää kulttuurisuhteita, englannin kielen opiskelua ja oppilasvaihtoa Britannian kanssa. British Councililla on toimintaa 109 maassa. Se on perustettu vuonna 1934. British Councililla oli vielä vuonna 2007 toimistoja 19 Euroopan maassa, mutta järjestön Euroopan toimintojen rahoitusta leikattiin kolmanneksella ja kahdessa vuodessa se vetäytyy kymmenestä Euroopan maasta. Toiminnot siirtyvät pääasiassa Irakiin, Afganistaniin, Egyptiin ja Bangladeshiin, joissa British Councilin rahoitusta on lisätty puolella. British Council kärsi Venäjän ja Britannian huononevista suhteista ja joulukuussa 2007 se ilmoitti että Venäjän ulkoministeriö oli määrännyt sen sulkemaan Moskovan ulkopuoliset toimistonsa Pietarissa ja Jekaterinburgissa. Kiistan uskotaan johtuvan Litvinenkon tapauksesta ja Venäjän kansalaisen Andrei Lugovoin luovutusvaatimuksesta. Suomen British Council avattiin Helsingissä jo vuonna 1945. Se toimii nykyisin Kampissa, mutta ole enää nykyisin avoinna yleisölle. Aiemmin laitos ylläpiti muun muassa laajaa kirjastoa, jonka sulkemisen yhteydessä kokoelma lahjoitettiin Rikhardinkadun kirjastoon. Vuodesta 2008 toiminta keskittyy eurooppalaisten kulttuurisuhteiden edistämiseen yhteistyössä monien erityyppisten organisaatioiden ja verkostojen kanssa.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://takeielts.britishcouncil.org"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Pencxu-SFgY"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:product rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Culture_of_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://bcec.org.hk"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.027jyp"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/britishcouncil4teens"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://maps.google.co.uk/maps/ms?ie=UTF8&amp;hl=en&amp;msa=0&amp;msid=200812294318285167943.00049c6673e031918c091&amp;ll=53.865486,-1.999512&amp;spn=8.792252,26.806641&amp;t=h&amp;z=6"/>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org/"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_non-profit"/>
    <dbpprop:product xml:lang="en">British cultural and language education</dbpprop:product>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Non-ProfitOrganisation"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Британский_совет"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Funding_bodies_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/British_Council?oldid=493790386"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The British Council is a United Kingdom-based organisation specialising in international educational and cultural opportunities. It is registered as a charity both in England and Wales, and in Scotland. Founded in 1934 as the British Committee for Relations with Other Countries, and granted a royal charter by King George VI in 1940, the British Council was inspired by Sir Reginald (Rex) Leeper's recognition of the importance of "cultural propaganda" in promoting British interests.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.chinadaily.com.cn/hkedition/2011-07/14/content_12898594.htm"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e1/BritishCouncil.png"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Il British Council è un'organizzazione culturale britannica presente in 110 paesi in tutto il mondo. Si occupa di diffondere la cultura britannica in Europa e negli altri continenti, sponsorizzando mostre d'arte e spettacoli teatrali, favorendo la diffusione delle scoperte scientifiche britanniche ed europee, istituendo corsi di lingua inglese e stabilendo forti rapporti tra gli inglesi e le altre culture. Il British Council si occupa anche di emigrazione in paesi anglosassoni, offrendo la possibilità di sottoporsi ad esami di lingue e corsi professionali. La fondazione si rifà al Foreign and Commonwealth Office, l'organo amministrativo britannico analogo al nostro ministero degli Esteri.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/britishcouncilmy"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Британська рада</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.youtube.com/user/BritishCouncilJapan#p/u/11/GItXWktm8aM"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Британский совет — неминистерский департамент правительства Великобритании, занимающийся распространением британской культуры за пределами Великобритании. Британский совет функционирует в самой Великобритании и в 215 городах 110 других государств и территорий. Персонал, задействованный по всему миру, превышает 8 тысяч человек. Правительство Великобритании спонсирует совет на одну треть, другая часть идёт с собственных доходов совета (мероприятия, плата за обучение и сдачу экзаменов). В год более миллиона человек проходят тестирование на владение английским языком на различных уровнях при совете. В России работало 15 центров британского совета, но формально из-за неурегулированности его правового статуса, хотя некоторые политики заявляли, что их побудили напряжённые отношения Великобритании и России, к январю 2008 года российскими властями были закрыты все, кроме отделения в Москве. Британский совет специализируется на учебной деятельности и развитии связей стран, где базируется, с Великобританией. Является общественной организацией, созданной в 1934 году королевской хартией. В Англии совет числится, как благотворительная организация. Главой совета и её покровителем является Королева Елизавета Вторая, вице-покровителем — Принц Уэльский, председателем — Лорд Киннок, бывший лидер партии Лейбористов. Финансовый аспект регулируется Форин Офисом (Foreign and Commonwealth Office), при этом в своей деятельности совет независим и самостоятелен. Исполнительный директор — Мартин Дэвидсон (вступил в должность в апреле 2007).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.theaustralian.com.au/higher-education/tenth-court-case-after-inquiry-into-curtin-ielts-scam/story-e6frgcjx-1226184963752"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Hội đồng Anh</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:revenue rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/poundSterling">9.82E8</dbpprop:revenue>
    <dbpprop:nonProfitName xml:lang="en">British Council</dbpprop:nonProfitName>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">De British Council is een internationale organisatie in het Verenigd Koninkrijk die educatieve mogelijkheden en culturele relaties bevordert tussen mensen uit het Verenigd Koninkrijk en de rest van de wereld. In de Nederlandse hoofdstad Amsterdam is er een British Council. Het werk van de British Council omvat vier deelgebieden: Engelse taal en examens; Kunst; Hoger Onderwijs; Onderwijs en Samenleving. In Nederland is de British Council vooral bekend vanwege de organisatie van Cambridge ESOL examens en de IELTS test. Om de toegang tot het leren van de Engelse taal te vereenvoudigen onderhoudt de British Council diverse websites voor docenten en voor lerenden. De meest bekende sites zijn Learn English, Teaching English en Learn English Kids.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">英國文化協會於1934年成立於英國，致力於促進英國文化、教育、國際關係之拓展和交流，於全球109個國家、兩百多座城市設有分部，1943年起在中國大陸、香港及台灣陸續成立辦事處，提供英式英語教學、英國期刊、留學情報以及各領域消息、免費諮詢等服務，並與外交機構建有合作計畫。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">英國文化協會</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:areaServed xml:lang="en">Worldwide</dbpprop:areaServed>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://activitymap.britishcouncil.org/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org/learning-english-gateway"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/BritishCouncilNI"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">British Council</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Il British Council è un'organizzazione culturale britannica presente in 110 paesi in tutto il mondo. Si occupa di diffondere la cultura britannica in Europa e negli altri continenti, sponsorizzando mostre d'arte e spettacoli teatrali, favorendo la diffusione delle scoperte scientifiche britanniche ed europee, istituendo corsi di lingua inglese e stabilendo forti rapporti tra gli inglesi e le altre culture.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">The British Council er en britisk organisasjon som ble stiftet i 1934. Organisasjonen har kontorer i mange forskjellige land, blant annet i Norge. Organisasjonen jobber med å utvikle forbindelser mellom Storbritannia og andre land. De jobber også en del med å lære bort engelsk til mennesker som ikke kan det.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:British_Council"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://tribune.com.pk/story/315761/human-trafficking-fia-to-probe-fake-visa-case-involving-british-council/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/teachingenglishvideo"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.iaeste.org.uk"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Le British Council est une institution gouvernementale du Royaume-Uni. Son président actuel est Vernon Ellis. Le siège de l'organisation se trouve à Londres, avec des affiliations en 110 pays. Son but est d'établir des relations culturelles entre le Royaume-Uni et d'autres pays ; pour ce but il a, en particulier, pour mission de promouvoir l'apprentissage de la langue anglaise, de participer à sa diffusion et de fortifier sa position dans le monde. Un directeur du British Council précise : « Le véritable or noir de la Grande-Bretagne est non point le pétrole de la Mer du Nord, mais la langue anglaise. Le défi que nous affrontons, c’est de l’exploiter pleinement.  » 65 % des frais du British Council sont financés par l'enseignement de l'anglais, le reste étant payé par le Foreign and Commonwealth Office du Royaume-Uni. En 2005 ce reste était de 186 millions de livres.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">British Council</foaf:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">De British Council is een internationale organisatie in het Verenigd Koninkrijk die educatieve mogelijkheden en culturele relaties bevordert tussen mensen uit het Verenigd Koninkrijk en de rest van de wereld. In de Nederlandse hoofdstad Amsterdam is er een British Council. Het werk van de British Council omvat vier deelgebieden: Engelse taal en examens; Kunst; Hoger Onderwijs; Onderwijs en Samenleving.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.youtube.com/user/BritishCouncilIndia"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/commentisfree/2012/apr/15/nick-cohen-china-censorship-writers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:British_culture"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Der British Council ist eine britische gemeinnützige Einrichtung zur Förderung internationaler Beziehungen. Ziel der Einrichtung ist der Aufbau gegenseitiger Beziehungen zwischen Menschen des Vereinigten Königreiches und anderen Staaten. Dies geschieht vor allem in den Bereichen Bildung, Kultur, Wissenschaft und Gesellschaft. Ferner steht der internationale Dialog zu Ideen und Innovationen aus Großbritannien im Mittelpunkt. Vertreten ist die Einrichtung in 109 Ländern. In Deutschland steuert der British Council seine Arbeit von Berlin aus, in Österreich hat er ein Büro in Wien und in der Schweiz in Bern. Die Finanzierung erfolgt zu 65 Prozent durch eigene Mittel, die vor allem durch Angebote in der Sprachausbildung erwirtschaftet werden. Weltweit werden Sprachkurse und Sprachtests angeboten. Ferner führt die Einrichtung Entwicklungshilfeprojekte durch. Auf diese Weise standen 2005/2006 186,2 Millionen Pfund zur Verfügung. Das Foreign and Commonwealth Office (britisches Auswärtiges Amt) gibt eine Beihilfe, die 2005/2006 bei 164 Millionen Pfund lag. Der British Council ist formal unabhängig, arbeitet aber eng mit dem Foreign and Commonwealth Office zusammen. Im Jahr 1934 wurde er als British Committee for Relations with Other Countries gegründet. Die Initiative ging von Sir Reginald ('Rex') Leeper aus, der zu diesem Zeitpunkt die Notwendigkeit für „kulturelle Propaganda“ sah.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:nonProfitLogo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:nonProfitLogo>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:International_cultural_organizations"/>
    <dbpprop:founder rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Government_of_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundingYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1934-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:foundingYear>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">British Council – brytyjska agencja ds. współpracy kulturalej oraz oświatowej, z nastawieniem na naukę języka angielskiego. British Council zostało założone w 1934 roku jako "The British Council for Relations with Other Countries" – Brytyjska Rada ds. relacji z innymi krajami. Dwa lata później nazwę skrócono do obecnej formy. Pierwszym zagranicznym biurem tej organizacji był założony w 1938 roku "British Institute in Cairo" – Instytut Brytyjski w Kairze.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/africaandindianocean/libya/8725024/Libya-Hana-Gaddafi-alive-and-well.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2012/apr/13/london-book-fair-china-censorship"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org/learning-teaching-english-gateway"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://blog.britishcouncil.org/2011/04/afghanistan-graduating-with-flying-colours/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">El Consejo Británico, es un instituto cultural, una institución pública cuya misión es difundir el conocimiento de la lengua inglesa y su cultura mediante la formación y otras actividades educativas. Además, este ente público cumple una función relevante para mejorar las relaciones exteriores del Reino Unido. Su sede principal se encuentra en Mánchester y Londres.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Британский совет — неминистерский департамент правительства Великобритании, занимающийся распространением британской культуры за пределами Великобритании. Британский совет функционирует в самой Великобритании и в 215 городах 110 других государств и территорий. Персонал, задействованный по всему миру, превышает 8 тысяч человек. Правительство Великобритании спонсирует совет на одну треть, другая часть идёт с собственных доходов совета (мероприятия, плата за обучение и сдачу экзаменов).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/britishcouncilhk"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The British Council is a United Kingdom-based organisation specialising in international educational and cultural opportunities. It is registered as a charity both in England and Wales, and in Scotland. Founded in 1934 as the British Committee for Relations with Other Countries, and granted a royal charter by King George VI in 1940, the British Council was inspired by Sir Reginald (Rex) Leeper's recognition of the importance of "cultural propaganda" in promoting British interests. Its "sponsoring department" within the United Kingdom Government is the Foreign and Commonwealth Office, although it has day-to-day operational independence. Martin Davidson is its chief executive, appointed in April 2007. From April 2012 British Council ceased to be the administrator of the FCO's prestigious UK Chevening Scholarships scheme which is now run by a new Chevening Secretariat under the umbrella of the Association of Commonwealth Universities: http://www. fco. gov. uk/en/about-us/what-we-do/scholarships/</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Der British Council ist eine britische gemeinnützige Einrichtung zur Förderung internationaler Beziehungen. Ziel der Einrichtung ist der Aufbau gegenseitiger Beziehungen zwischen Menschen des Vereinigten Königreiches und anderen Staaten. Dies geschieht vor allem in den Bereichen Bildung, Kultur, Wissenschaft und Gesellschaft. Ferner steht der internationale Dialog zu Ideen und Innovationen aus Großbritannien im Mittelpunkt. Vertreten ist die Einrichtung in 109 Ländern.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:revenue rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/poundSterling">9.82E8</dbpedia-owl:revenue>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English-language_education"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">El British Council, es un institut cultural, una institució publica la missió de la qual és difondre el coneixement de la llengua anglesa i la seva cultura mitjançant la formació i altres activitats educatives. A més, aquest ens públic compleix una funció rellevant per a millorar les relacions exteriors del Regne Unit. Fou creat amb el nom de British Committee for Relations with Other Countries el 1934 com a una organització voluntària per a promoure la cultura, educació, ciència i tecnologia britànica. A l'any següent el nom es modificà de Committee a Council, i el 1936 és canvià finalment pel nom actual. Les seves primeres seus s'establiren a Egipte, Portugal, Romania i Polònia el 1938, i la seva seu espanyola s'obrí el 1940. Avui dia està present en més de 110 països, i té la seva seu central a les ciutats de Manchester i Londres. L'any 2005 l'Institut Cervantes, l'Instituto Camões, l'Alliance Française, el British Council, el Goethe-Institut i la Società Dante Alighieri varen ser reconeguts internacionalment per la seva tasca essent guardonats amb el Premi Príncep d'Astúries de Comunicació i Humanitats d'aquell l'any.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">British Council</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/theobserver/2012/apr/22/observer-letters-british-council-china"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">英國文化協會於1934年成立於英國，致力於促進英國文化、教育、國際關係之拓展和交流，於全球109個國家、兩百多座城市設有分部，1943年起在中國大陸、香港及台灣陸續成立辦事處，提供英式英語教學、英國期刊、留學情報以及各領域消息、免費諮詢等服務，並與外交機構建有合作計畫。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/BritishCouncilWales"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e1/BritishCouncil.png/200px-BritishCouncil.png"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/britishcouncilsg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">El British Council, es un institut cultural, una institució publica la missió de la qual és difondre el coneixement de la llengua anglesa i la seva cultura mitjançant la formació i altres activitats educatives. A més, aquest ens públic compleix una funció rellevant per a millorar les relacions exteriors del Regne Unit.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:nonProfitType xml:lang="en">Cultural institution</dbpprop:nonProfitType>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Foreign_and_Commonwealth_Office"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/British_Council"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">British Council on brittiläinen julkinen järjestö, joka edistää kulttuurisuhteita, englannin kielen opiskelua ja oppilasvaihtoa Britannian kanssa. British Councililla on toimintaa 109 maassa. Se on perustettu vuonna 1934. British Councililla oli vielä vuonna 2007 toimistoja 19 Euroopan maassa, mutta järjestön Euroopan toimintojen rahoitusta leikattiin kolmanneksella ja kahdessa vuodessa se vetäytyy kymmenestä Euroopan maasta.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Government_of_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:keyPeople xml:lang="en">Vernon Ellis</dbpprop:keyPeople>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Non-departmental_public_bodies_of_the_United_Kingdom_government"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://uk.youtube.com/user/StudyInTheUK"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/British_Council"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">O British Council (lit. Conselho Britânico) é uma instituição pública do Reino Unido, um instituto cultural cuja missão é difundir o conhecimento da língua inglesa e sua cultura mediante a formação e outras atividades educativas. Além disso, esta entidade pública cumpre uma função relevante para melhorar as relações exteriores do Reino Unido. As suas sedes principais estão localizadas em Manchester e Londres. Foi fundada em 1934 com o nome de British Committee for Relations with Other Countries. Este instituto é equivalente ao Instituto Camões português, ao Instituto Cervantes espanhol, ao Instituto Goethe alemão, à Sociedade Dante Alighieri italiana, à Aliança Francesa e ao Instituto Confúcio da China. Todos eles trabalham para divulgar suas respectivas culturas por todo o mundo, favorecendo deste modo o conhecimento de algumas das principais línguas mundiais. No Brasil, foi um dos responsáveis pela criação do Colégio Técnico da Universidade Federal de Minas Gerais. Internacionalmente, é responsável pelo Sistema de avaliação na língua inglesa internacional, exame de proficiência conhecido como IELTS.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1934_establishments_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">O British Council (lit. Conselho Britânico) é uma instituição pública do Reino Unido, um instituto cultural cuja missão é difundir o conhecimento da língua inglesa e sua cultura mediante a formação e outras atividades educativas. Além disso, esta entidade pública cumpre uma função relevante para melhorar as relações exteriores do Reino Unido. As suas sedes principais estão localizadas em Manchester e Londres.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Британська рада — неміністерський департамент уряду Великої Британії, що займається поширенням британської культури за межами Великої Британії. Є позавідомчим державним органом, який створений королівською милістю і зареєстрований як благодійна організація в Англії. Заснована 1934 року, 1940 року король Георг VI дарував раді королівську грамоту. Його чинним головою є лорд Ніл Кіннок, колишній лідер британської Лейбористської партії. «Спонсуючим департаментом» Британської ради є Міністерство закордонних справ та у справах Співдружності, хоча насправді вона має практично повну незалежність у власних справах та діях. Виконавчим директором є Мартін Девідсон, призначений на свою посаду у квітні 2007.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.dailymail.co.uk/news/article-2048545/Whitehall-departments-leave-London-save-sky-high-office-costs-says-MP.html?ito=feeds-newsxml"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.fco.gov.uk/en/about-us/what-we-do/scholarships/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.britishcouncil.org/learning-ielts"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">El Consejo Británico, es un instituto cultural, una institución pública cuya misión es difundir el conocimiento de la lengua inglesa y su cultura mediante la formación y otras actividades educativas. Además, este ente público cumple una función relevante para mejorar las relaciones exteriores del Reino Unido. Su sede principal se encuentra en Mánchester y Londres. Este instituto es equivalente al Instituto Cervantes español, el Goethe-Institut alemán, la Sociedad Dante Alighieri italiana, la Alliance Française o el Instituto Confucio de la China. Todos ellos trabajan por divulgar sus respectivas culturas por todo el mundo, favoreciendo así el conocimiento de algunas de las principales lenguas europeas, hecho por el que se les ha otorgado el Premio Príncipe de Asturias de Comunicación y Humanidades el año 2005.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/OrganizationsEstablishedIn1934"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Organizations_established_in_1934"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/NonProfitOrganization"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Hội đồng Anh là một tổ chức của Vương quốc Anh chuyên môn trong về lĩnh vực giáo dục và văn hóa quốc tế. Tổ chức này được đăng ký như là tổ chức từ thiện ở Anh Quốc và Xứ Wales, Scotland.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=r3huRoNnq2A&amp;feature=share"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/BC">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageDisambiguates rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Gabor_Fabricius">
    <dbpedia-owl:award rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sri_Chandrasekharendra_Saraswathi_Viswa_Mahavidyalaya">
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_British_Council">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Slim_John">
    <dbpedia-owl:company rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
    <dbpprop:company rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/British_Council"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
