<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Colin_Middleton">
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colin_Middleton"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Colin Middleton</rdfs:label>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Middleton</foaf:surname>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Colin</foaf:givenName>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Colin_Middleton"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Colin Middleton foi um pintor irlandês, conhecido como o mais eclético da Irlanda modernista. A sua obra varia diversas vezes de movimentos artísticos, tendo o artista optado maioritariamente pelo Cubismo, Surrealismo e Expressionismo. Este facto explica-se, sendo que, tal como Picasso, por exemplo, Middleton sempre procurou o "movimento perfeito", ou seja, o movimento artístico com que mais se identificasse.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://whiteimage.com/colin-middleton-rha/archive/127.html"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1983_deaths"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.067yz8"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">29</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Belfast"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Members_of_the_Order_of_the_British_Empire"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Colin Middleton MBE (29 January 1910 – 23 December 1983) was an Irish artist and surrealist. Middleton was born in 1910 in Belfast. He trained at Belfast College of Art, he was heavily influenced by the work of Vincent van Gogh. He regarded himself as the only surrealist working in Ireland in the 1930s. His work first appeared at the Royal Hibernian Academy in 1938. His first solo exhibition was at the Grafton Gallery in 1944. A damask-designer like his father before him, he now devoted himself to full-time painting. More exhibitions followed in Dublin, London and Boston. In 1953, he moved to Bangor where he designed for the New Theatre; he also designed sets for the Circle Theatre and the Lyric Theatre. At around this time he exhibited alongside Daniel O'Neill at the Tooth Galleries in London. In the same year (1954), he started his career as an art teacher at the Belfast College of Art and at Coleraine Technical School, eventually becoming head of art at Friends' School, Lisburn. The 'Dublin Magazine' at this time said of him: 'Apart from the brilliance of his paint, he has one rare quality in his inexhaustible capacity for wonder'. A poet and musician, Middleton also produced murals, mosaics and posters. In 1969, he was awarded an MBE and appointed an associate at the Royal Hibernian Academy, with full membership in 1970. A major retrospective was held in 1976 at The Ulster Museum and the Hugh Lane Municipal Gallery of Modern Art in Dublin. He continued to exhibit at the RHA until his death in 1983 in Dublin. Critical Biography John Hewitt, Colin Middleton (Arts Council/An Chomhairle Ealaíon and the Arts Council of Northern Ireland, 1976)</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Surrealist_artists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Colin Middleton MBE (29 January 1910 – 23 December 1983) was an Irish artist and surrealist. Middleton was born in 1910 in Belfast. He trained at Belfast College of Art, he was heavily influenced by the work of Vincent van Gogh. He regarded himself as the only surrealist working in Ireland in the 1930s. His work first appeared at the Royal Hibernian Academy in 1938. His first solo exhibition was at the Grafton Gallery in 1944.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">23</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Painters_from_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Colin Middleton foi um pintor irlandês, conhecido como o mais eclético da Irlanda modernista. A sua obra varia diversas vezes de movimentos artísticos, tendo o artista optado maioritariamente pelo Cubismo, Surrealismo e Expressionismo. Este facto explica-se, sendo que, tal como Picasso, por exemplo, Middleton sempre procurou o "movimento perfeito", ou seja, o movimento artístico com que mais se identificasse. Trabalhou para uma família burguesa que possuía vários campos de damascos, campos estes geridos por Middleton. Trabalhou aqui até 1947, ano em que foi convidado a leccionar Desenho e Pintura numa universidade de Belas-Artes. Durante toda a sua vida dispôs de uma fértil e rica imaginação. Tal é visível nas suas obras surrealistas, por exemplo. Destas é de destaque A noiva, um óleo sobre tela datado de 1938, leiloada na Christie's em 2006. Hoje em dia, diversas obras suas, sobretudo pinturas e desenhos, encontram-se pertencentes à grande colecção de arte irlandesa de George e Maura McClelland, os quais foram grandes amigos e agentes do pintor.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1910_births"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1983-12-23</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Middleton, Colin</dbpprop:name>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Colin_Middleton?oldid=449041366"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/SurrealistArtists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PaintersFromNorthernIreland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1910-01-29</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Colin Middleton</foaf:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromBelfast"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Colin_Middleton"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
