<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns4="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/PopulatedPlace/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/County_Londonderry">
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">倫敦德里郡</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">O Condado de Derry ou Condado de Londonderry é um dos seis condados da Irlanda do Norte, na província de Ulster. O seu nome deve-se à sua principal cidade - e, mais tarde cidade e centro administrativo - Derry (Londonderry), que se situa no noroeste do condado. O ponto mais alto do condado é a Montanha Sawel (678 m) na fronteira com o Condado de Tyrone. Sawel faz parte das Montanhas Sperrin, que dominam a parte sul do condado. Para o leste e o oeste, a terra cai nos vales dos rios Bann e Foyle, respectivamente, no sudeste do país, o condado atinge as margens do Lago Neagh, que é o maior lago na Irlanda, no norte do condado e é distinguido pelas suas escarpas íngremes, sistemas de dunas e pelas notáveis praias na costa atlântica. O condado tem uma série de importantes edifícios e paisagens, incluindo as bem-conservadas muralhas de Derry, datadas do século XVII, a National Trust Plantação de Springhill; o Templo Musseden com as suas vistas espectaculares sobre o Atlântico, os diques, a orla costeira e a possibilidade de observação de santuários de aves sobre a costa oriental do Estuário de Foyle; e Bellaghy, perto da casa de infância do Nobel Seamus Heaney. No centro do condado situam-se florestas caducifólias antigas em Banagher e Ness Wood, onde o rio Burntollet tem no seu curso, as maiores cataratas da Irlanda do Norte.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">County Londonderry</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Londonderry ist eine der sechs historischen Grafschaften Nordirlands. Von Bewohnern der Republik Irland oder katholischen Nordiren wird aus politischen Gründen der Name Derry verwendet.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Лондондеррі (графство)</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/County_Londonderry"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-location-noun-1"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Ulster"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Londonderry eller Derry är ett grevskap i Nordirland. Den viktigaste staden, som tidigare var administrativ huvudort, är Derry. Sedan 1973 har grevskapet inte längre någon administrativ funktion; för detta ändamål ersattes grevskapet av distrikt. Namnet på staden var från början Derry, men som en gest gentemot gillen från London som deltog i koloniseringen av Ulster, även kallad bosättningen i Ulster, på 1600-talet fick den ett nytt namn. Nordirländska nationalister föredrar det gamla namnet på både byn och grevskapet och i Irland används också formen Derry i officiella sammanhang. Grevskapet är nyare än de andra på ön, efter att ha blivit upprättat när grevskapet Coleraine blev sammanslaget med delar av Antrim, Donegal samt Tyrone. Orsaken till detta är att stadens myndigheter önskat att få kontroll över området.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_settlement"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Le Comté de Londonderry ou Comté de Derry (en gaélique Contae Dhoire ou Doire) est un des six comtés de la province d'Ulster situé en Irlande du Nord. Il est nommé d'après sa ville principale et aussi notamment la ville Coleraine. Le comté est bordé par les comtés de Antrim, Tyrone et Donegal. Sa superficie est de 2 074 km² et sa population est d’environ 230 000 habitants.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:areaTotal rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#double">2074000000.0</dbpedia-owl:areaTotal>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">El comtat de Derry és un dels sis comtats d'Irlanda que formen part d'Irlanda del Nord. Doire vol dir "roure" en gaèlic. El govern britànic, però, ha dividit el territori de l'antic comtat de Londonderry en quatre districtes: Districte de Coleraine Districte de Limavady Districte de Magherafelt</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">County Londonderry or County Derry is one of the six counties of Northern Ireland. Adjoined to the north-west shore of Lough Neagh, the county covers an area of 2,074 km², with a population of approximately 233,550. It is also one of the thirty-two traditional counties of Ireland, lying within the historical province of Ulster.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:isPartOf rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Northern_Ireland"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Counties_of_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">El Condado de Londonderry o Condado de Derry (Doire, cuyo significado es "roble" en irlandés) es uno de los seis condados de Irlanda del Norte, Reino Unido. Lleva el nombre de su ciudad más importante. Derry, después llamada Londonderry. El condado ocupa una superficie de 2.074 kilómetros cuadrados y tiene una población de 213.000 habitantes. El nombre está sujeto a la disputa política. Los nacionalistas irlandeses prefieren Derry, mientras que los unionistas prefieren Londonderry.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/런던데리_주"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/CountiesOfNorthernIreland"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Hrabství_Londonderry"/>
    <dbpprop:seat rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Coleraine"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Comté_de_Londonderry"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">El Condado de Londonderry o Condado de Derry (Doire, cuyo significado es "roble" en irlandés) es uno de los seis condados de Irlanda del Norte, Reino Unido. Lleva el nombre de su ciudad más importante. Derry, después llamada Londonderry. El condado ocupa una superficie de 2.074 kilómetros cuadrados y tiene una población de 213.000 habitantes. El nombre está sujeto a la disputa política. Los nacionalistas irlandeses prefieren Derry, mientras que los unionistas prefieren Londonderry. En la República de Irlanda se utiliza oficialmente el nombre Derry, mientras que las autoridades británicas utilizan Londonderry.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:imageMap xml:lang="en">Island_of_Ireland_location_map_Londonderry.svg</dbpprop:imageMap>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Hrabství Londonderry</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">County Londonderry / County Derry</dbpprop:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">런던데리 주(County Londonderry) 또는 데리 주(County Derry)는 북아일랜드의 주 중 하나이다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionName rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">County Londonderry</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:motto xml:lang="en">Auxilium A Domino</dbpprop:motto>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Location_Underspecified"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/County_Londonderry"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">County Londonderry / County Derry</foaf:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">德里郡 （County Derry；愛爾蘭語：Contae Dhoire），或稱倫敦德里郡 （County Londonderry），是愛爾蘭阿爾斯特省的一個郡，位於北愛爾蘭西北部。面積2,074 km²，郡治倫敦德里。1973年以後被分為四個區。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Лондондеррі — графство на півночі Ірландії.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Лондондерри или Дерри — историческое графство и округ на севере Ирландии. Входит в состав провинции Ольстер на территории Северной Ирландии. Столица и крупнейший город — Лондондерри. Население 213 тыс. человек (5-е место среди графств; данные 2002 г.).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/PopulatedPlace"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Derryn kreivikunta on yksi Pohjois-Irlannin kuudesta kreivikunnasta, ja se sijaitsee Ulsterin provinssissa. Kreivikunta on nimetty suurimman kaupunkinsa, Derryn, mukaan.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">County Derry of County Londonderry is een van de graafschappen van Ierland, en is een van de zes graafschappen van Noord-Ierland. Het ligt in de provincie Ulster. Het is genoemd naar de hoofdstad Derry. De naam van de county (en de stad) is omstreden: Ierse nationalisten gebruiken de vorm Derry en Noord-Ierse unionisten geven de voorkeur aan Londonderry. Het graafschap Derry bestaat uit het voormalig graafschap Coleraine en een deel van de graafschappen Antrim, Donegal en Tyrone.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/95/Lderry_arms.svg/200px-Lderry_arms.svg.png"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Hrabství Londonderry či pouze Derry (anglicky County Londonderry, irsky Contae Dhoire či Doire a skotsky Coontie Lunnonderrie či Derrie) je severoirské hrabství, patřící do bývalé provincie Ulster. Sousedí s hrabstvím Tyrone na jihu, s hrabstvím Antrim na východě a s irským hrabstvím Donegal na západě. Přes Lough Neagh sousedí také s hrabstvím Armagh. Severní pobřeží omývá Atlantský oceán. Hlavním městem hrabství je Coleraine, největším je však Londonderry s 85 016 obyvateli.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Londonderry er et grevskap i Nord-Irland. Den viktigste byen, som tidligere var administrasjonsby, er Londonderry. Siden 1973 har ikke grevskapet hatt noen administrativ funksjon og er i den sammenheng erstattet av distrikter. Navnet på byen og grevskapet var opprinnelig Derry, men på grunn av Londonfirmaers deltagelse i bosetningen i Ulster fikk den nytt navn. Nord-irske nasjonalister foretrekker det gamle navnet både på byen og grevskapet, og i Republikken Irland brukes også formen Derry i offisielle sammenhenger. Grevskapet er nyere enn de andre på øya; det ble opprettet senere ved at Coleraine ble slått sammen med deler av Antrim, Donegal og Tyrone. Årsaken til dette er at byens myndigheter ønsket å få kontroll over omegnen og presset gjennom opprettelsen av en ny administrativ enhet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:country rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionName rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ulster"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Hrabstwo Londonderry, hrabstwo Derry (irl. Contae Dhoire lub Doire - "drewno dębowe") – jedno z sześciu hrabstw położonych na wyspie Irlandii w prowincji Ulster, wchodzących w skład brytyjskiej Irlandii Północnej. Położone w północnej części wyspy. Hrabstwo graniczy z hrabstwem Donegal na zachodzie, Tyrone na południowym zachodzie, Antrim na wschodzie, oraz z Armagh przez Lough Neagh na południu. Stolicą hrabstwa jest miasto Derry. Nazwa hrabstwa jest kwestią sporną, podobnie jak nazwa jego stolicy – nacjonaliści oraz mieszkańcy Republiki Irlandii używają nazwy Derry, z kolei zwolennicy pozostania Irlandii Północnej w Zjednoczonym Królestwie preferują nazwę Londonderry. W mieście używa się obu nazw naprzemiennie.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:populationRank rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6</dbpprop:populationRank>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpprop:motto xml:lang="en">"Help comes from the Lord"</dbpprop:motto>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Лондондерри_(графство)"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Condado_de_Derry"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Village"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Settlement"/>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionType rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_sovereign_states"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/GeoclassRegion"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Condado_de_Londonderry"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Londonderry ist eine der sechs historischen Grafschaften Nordirlands. Von Bewohnern der Republik Irland oder katholischen Nordiren wird aus politischen Gründen der Name Derry verwendet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionName rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Northern_Ireland"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/95/Lderry_arms.svg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">La contea di Londonderry o Derry (Doire in gaelico irlandese, Contae Dhoire esteso; Coonty Lunnonderrie / Coonty Derrie in Ulster Scots) è una delle trentadue contee d'Irlanda e delle sei sotto il controllo britannico. Non ha più valenza politica e amministrativa, ma solo culturale e sportiva.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Londonderry er et grevskap i Nord-Irland. Den viktigste byen, som tidligere var administrasjonsby, er Londonderry. Siden 1973 har ikke grevskapet hatt noen administrativ funksjon og er i den sammenheng erstattet av distrikter. Navnet på byen og grevskapet var opprinnelig Derry, men på grunn av Londonfirmaers deltagelse i bosetningen i Ulster fikk den nytt navn.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">County Derry of County Londonderry is een van de graafschappen van Ierland, en is een van de zes graafschappen van Noord-Ierland. Het ligt in de provincie Ulster. Het is genoemd naar de hoofdstad Derry. De naam van de county (en de stad) is omstreden: Ierse nationalisten gebruiken de vorm Derry en Noord-Ierse unionisten geven de voorkeur aan Londonderry. Het graafschap Derry bestaat uit het voormalig graafschap Coleraine en een deel van de graafschappen Antrim, Donegal en Tyrone. Dit is gebeurd onder druk van bedrijven in Londen die beide oevers en de monding van de rivieren Foyle en Bann wilden beheersen om zo toegang wilden te hebben tot genoeg hout voor de bouw. Sinds 1973 is het graafschap bestuurlijk verdeeld in verschillende districten: Derry (stad), Coleraine, Limavady, en Magherafelt; en deel van het district Cookstown, dat hoofdzakelijk in County Tyrone ligt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">La contea di Londonderry o Derry (Doire in gaelico irlandese, Contae Dhoire esteso; Coonty Lunnonderrie / Coonty Derrie in Ulster Scots) è una delle trentadue contee d'Irlanda e delle sei sotto il controllo britannico. Non ha più valenza politica e amministrativa, ma solo culturale e sportiva. Confina, per quel che riguarda il territorio della sua nazione, partendo da ovest, con Antrim e Tyrone, mentre ad ovest col Donegal che fa parte della Repubblica d'Irlanda; si affaccia, invece, a nord sull'Oceano Atlantico, a nord-ovest sul Lough Foyle a sud-est su una piccola parte del Lough Neagh. Deve il nome alla città di Derry (o Londonderry), compresa nel territorio.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">런던데리 주(County Londonderry) 또는 데리 주(County Derry)는 북아일랜드의 주 중 하나이다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Hrabstwo_Londonderry"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/County_Londonderry?oldid=484941754"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Derryn kreivikunta on yksi Pohjois-Irlannin kuudesta kreivikunnasta, ja se sijaitsee Ulsterin provinssissa. Kreivikunta on nimetty suurimman kaupunkinsa, Derryn, mukaan.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/PopulatedPlace"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">County Londonderry or County Derry is one of the six counties of Northern Ireland. Adjoined to the north-west shore of Lough Neagh, the county covers an area of 2,074 km², with a population of approximately 233,550. It is also one of the thirty-two traditional counties of Ireland, lying within the historical province of Ulster. Since 1981, it has become one of four counties in Northern Ireland that has a Catholic majority (55.56% according to the 2001 Census), with 57% of the Catholic population residing within Derry City Council. The highest point in the county is the summit of Sawel Mountain (678 m) on the border with County Tyrone. Sawel is part of the Sperrin Mountains, which dominate the southern part of the county. To the east and west, the land falls into the valleys of the Bann and Foyle rivers respectively; in the south-east, the county touches the shore of Lough Neagh, which is the largest lake in Ireland; the north of the county is distinguished by the steep cliffs, dune systems, and remarkable beaches of the Atlantic coast. The county is home to a number of important buildings and landscapes, including the well-preserved 17th-century city walls of Derry; the National Trust-owned Plantation estate at Springhill; Mussenden Temple with its spectacular views of the Atlantic; the dikes, artificial coastlines and the noted bird sanctuaries on the eastern shore of Lough Foyle; and the visitor centre at Bellaghy Bawn, close to the childhood home of Nobel laureate Seamus Heaney. In the centre of the county are the old-growth deciduous forests at Banagher and Ness Wood, where the Burntollet River flows over the highest waterfalls in Northern Ireland. The county flower is the Purple Saxifrage. The term Oak Leaf County is the county nickname particularly in relation to the county's teams in Gaelic Athletic Association competitions.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Лондондеррі — графство на півночі Ірландії.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionType rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Countries_of_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0dwdy"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Le Comté de Londonderry ou Comté de Derry (en gaélique Contae Dhoire ou Doire) est un des six comtés de la province d'Ulster situé en Irlande du Nord. Il est nommé d'après sa ville principale et aussi notamment la ville Coleraine. Le comté est bordé par les comtés de Antrim, Tyrone et Donegal. Sa superficie est de 2 074 km² et sa population est d’environ 230 000 habitants.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:isPartOf rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ulster"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Hrabstwo Londonderry, hrabstwo Derry (irl. Contae Dhoire lub Doire - "drewno dębowe") – jedno z sześciu hrabstw położonych na wyspie Irlandii w prowincji Ulster, wchodzących w skład brytyjskiej Irlandii Północnej. Położone w północnej części wyspy. Hrabstwo graniczy z hrabstwem Donegal na zachodzie, Tyrone na południowym zachodzie, Antrim na wschodzie, oraz z Armagh przez Lough Neagh na południu. Stolicą hrabstwa jest miasto Derry.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:population rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">233500</dbpprop:population>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Лондондерри или Дерри — историческое графство и округ на севере Ирландии. Входит в состав провинции Ольстер на территории Северной Ирландии. Столица и крупнейший город — Лондондерри. Население 213 тыс. человек (5-е место среди графств; данные 2002 г.).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">德里郡 （County Derry；愛爾蘭語：Contae Dhoire），或稱倫敦德里郡 （County Londonderry），是愛爾蘭阿爾斯特省的一個郡，位於北愛爾蘭西北部。面積2,074 km²，郡治倫敦德里。1973年以後被分為四個區。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Place"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">O Condado de Derry ou Condado de Londonderry é um dos seis condados da Irlanda do Norte, na província de Ulster. O seu nome deve-se à sua principal cidade - e, mais tarde cidade e centro administrativo - Derry (Londonderry), que se situa no noroeste do condado. O ponto mais alto do condado é a Montanha Sawel (678 m) na fronteira com o Condado de Tyrone. Sawel faz parte das Montanhas Sperrin, que dominam a parte sul do condado.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:populationTotalRanking rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">6</dbpedia-owl:populationTotalRanking>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Hrabství Londonderry či pouze Derry (anglicky County Londonderry, irsky Contae Dhoire či Doire a skotsky Coontie Lunnonderrie či Derrie) je severoirské hrabství, patřící do bývalé provincie Ulster. Sousedí s hrabstvím Tyrone na jihu, s hrabstvím Antrim na východě a s irským hrabstvím Donegal na západě. Přes Lough Neagh sousedí také s hrabstvím Armagh. Severní pobřeží omývá Atlantský oceán. Hlavním městem hrabství je Coleraine, největším je však Londonderry s 85 016 obyvateli. Hrabství má rozlohu 2074 km² a žije v něm 233 500 obyvatel . Hrabstvím protéká řeka Foyle, která tvoří přirozenou hranici s Irskem.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:subdivisionType rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Provinces_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">"Help comes from the Lord"</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">El comtat de Derry és un dels sis comtats d'Irlanda que formen part d'Irlanda del Nord. Doire vol dir "roure" en gaèlic. El govern britànic, però, ha dividit el territori de l'antic comtat de Londonderry en quatre districtes: Districte de Coleraine Districte de Limavady Districte de Magherafelt</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:County_Londonderry"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Londonderry eller Derry är ett grevskap i Nordirland. Den viktigaste staden, som tidigare var administrativ huvudort, är Derry. Sedan 1973 har grevskapet inte längre någon administrativ funktion; för detta ändamål ersattes grevskapet av distrikt. Namnet på staden var från början Derry, men som en gest gentemot gillen från London som deltog i koloniseringen av Ulster, även kallad bosättningen i Ulster, på 1600-talet fick den ett nytt namn.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:areaTotalKm rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2074</dbpprop:areaTotalKm>
    <dbpprop:footnotes xml:lang="en">Contae Dhoire is the Irish name; Coontie Lunnonderrie is its name in Ulster Scots.</dbpprop:footnotes>
    <dbpprop:seatType rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/County_town"/>
    <dbpprop:imageShield xml:lang="en">Lderry arms.svg</dbpprop:imageShield>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Comtat de Derry</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Place"/>
    <dbpprop:areaRank rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">15</dbpprop:areaRank>
    <dbpprop:populationAsOf rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2001</dbpprop:populationAsOf>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Auxilium A Domino(Latin)</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/County_Londonderry"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Londonderry_(contea)"/>
    <ns4:areaTotal rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/squareKilometre">2074.0</ns4:areaTotal>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
