<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eigerwand">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger_north_face">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger">
    <dbpedia-owl:mountainRange rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bernese_Alps"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:firstAscentYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1858-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:firstAscentYear>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">O Eiger é uma montanha de 3970 m de altitude e 1168 m de proeminência topográfica nos Alpes Berneses, na Suíça. Faz parte do conjunto Jungfrau-Aletsch-Bietschhorn declarado Património da Humanidade pela Unesco em 2001. É o pico mais oriental da cadeia que se estende cruzando o Mönch (4099 m) e o Jungfrau (4158 m). O lado norte da montanha ergue-se cerca de 3 km sobre Grindelwald e outros vales habitados do Oberland bernês, e a vertente meridional fica frente à região de Jungfrau-Aletsch, coberta por alguns dos maiores glaciares dos Alpes. O seu cume-pai é o Mönch.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(8.00528 46.5775)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpedia-owl:parentMountainPeak rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/M%C3%B6nch"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Eiger – szczyt w Alpach Berneńskich o wysokości 3970 metrów n.p.m. Jest najbardziej znaną górą w historii alpinizmu ekstremalnego. Wraz z Mönchem i Jungfrau tworzy trio (Dreigestirn) wielkich szczytów w północnej części berneńskiego Oberlandu w Szwajcarii. Jego północna ściana znana jest pod kilkoma nazwami: Eigerwand, Nordwand lub Mordwand (Ściana Śmierci) – to nazwa, jaką zaczęto określać ją po wielu tragicznie zakończonych próbach jej zdobycia. W 1912 roku ukończono budowę kolejki zębatej na przełęcz Jungfraujoch (górna stacja na wysokości 3454 metry n.p.m. ), która biegnie przez kilka kilometrów we wnętrzu Eigeru. W dwóch miejscach zrobiono okna w północnej ścianie, umożliwiając obserwowanie jej z bliska. Pociąg zawsze się zatrzymuje w tych miejscach, aby turyści mogli skorzystać z punktów widokowych. Są to stacje "Eigerwand" i "Eismeer". Północna ściana jest także bardzo dobrze widoczna z przełęczy Kleine Scheidegg, na której znajduje się stacja kolejki na Jungfraujoch oraz hotele i restauracje; a także z wielu innych miejsc leżących u podnóża ściany. Północna ściana ma 1800 metrów wysokości i jest to najwyższa ściana w Alpach i Europie. Tworzy ona wraz z filarem Walkera na Grandes Jorasses i północną ścianą Matterhornu tzw. Tryptyk Alpejski. Pierwsze wejście: Charles Barrington oraz przewodnicy Christian Almer i Peter Bohren. 11 sierpnia 1858 o trzeciej rano wyruszają z Wengernalp. Wspinają się nie dzisiejszą "drogą normalną" lecz prawie ostrzem grani północno-zachodniej i na wierzchołku stają tuż przed południem. Schodzą kuluarem i wzdłuż flanki gdzie dziś prowadzi normalna droga zejścia.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/NaturalPlace"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:nationalTopographicSystemMapNumber xml:lang="en">Swisstopo 1229 Grindelwald</dbpedia-owl:nationalTopographicSystemMapNumber>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.peakware.com/peaks.html?pk=71"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fc/North_face.jpg/200px-North_face.jpg"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MountainsOfSwitzerland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.racingandsports.com.au/sports/rsNewsArt.asp?NID=128312&amp;story=Steck_scales_new_heights_with_Eiger_Award_2008"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/BerneseAlps"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">De Eiger is een 3970 meter hoge berg in de Berner Alpen. De Eiger is weliswaar geen "vierduizender", zoals nabijgelegen toppen als de Jungfrau en de Mönch, maar hij geldt wel als de spectaculairste om te beklimmen. Zijn steile noordwand is een klassieke uitdaging, die bekend staat als de gevaarlijkste klim van Europa. In 1858 is de berg voor het eerst beklommen door Charles Barrington, Christian Almer en metgezellen. Op 24 juni 1938 beklom Anderl Heckmair als eerste met Heinrich Harrer, Fritz Kasparek en Ludwig Vörg deze beruchte Eiger-noordwand, die gold als "een van de laatste problemen in de Alpen". Twee van hen beschikten over stijgijzers met punten aan de voorkant: voor die tijd een nieuwigheid in de klimuitrusting die veel tijdwinst opleverde doordat in ijs en sneeuw niet overal treden hoefden te worden uitgehakt. De als zeer heldhaftig afgeschilderde beklimming, door een onderweg gesloten gelegenheidcoalitie van een Duits en een Oostenrijks duo kort na de Anschluss van Oostenrijk bij Duitsland, werd door de nazi's propagandistisch uitgebuit. Hierdoor werd het ook een politiek beladen sportieve prestatie. Overigens zou een van het viertal later in de Tweede Wereldoorlog sneuvelen als militair bij de Gebirgsjäger, die voor speciale opdrachten ook werden ingezet aan het oostfront. De bijnaam van de noordwand werd de "Mordwand",vanwege het grote aantal omgekomen klimmers. De mislukte en herhaaldelijk na dramatische en fatale ongevallen afgebroken pogingen in de jaren '30 van de 20e eeuw bezorgden de wand een sinistere reputatie, die door sommige vermetele klimmers niet als afschrikwekkend maar juist als een uitdaging werd gezien. Ten tijde van die eerste geslaagde beklimming in 1938 waren naar aanleiding van ongevallen in de voorgaande zomer verdere pogingen zelfs nog door de autoriteiten verboden. De klim is in het bijzonder gevaarlijk vanwege steenval, ijsafzetting en de drie ijsvelden waar de klimmers een makkelijk doelwit voor de vallende stenen zijn. In 1971 beklommen Vincent Dewaele en Renaat Van Malderen als eerste Belgen de Noordwand. In 1969 had deze laatste reeds samen met Tony Peeters als eerste Belgisch team de Walkerpijler op de Grandes Jorasses beklommen. In 1977 beklommen Bas Gresnigt en Ronald Naar als eerste Nederlanders de noordwand. Sindsdien is de bergwand meerder keren door Nederlanders beklommen, onder andere door Gertjan van Leersum, Johan Taks, Gerard van Sprang, Cas van der Gevel, Wilco van Rooijen, Thierry Schmitter en Jan-Willem Jenneskens. Ook zijn er over de duizelingwekkend steile pijlers moderne rotsklimroutes geopend. Michel Piola en Gerard Hopfgartner klommen in 1979 De Geneefse route. Deze route werd door Piola gewaardeerd op ED-A3. In 1988 werd deze route voor de derde maal herhaald door het Nederlandse klimduo van der Werff/Zikel. Op 13 juli 2006 stortte rond acht uur 's avonds 500.000 kubieke meter rotsblokken naar beneden op de Untere Grindelwaldgletscher, waardoor er urenlang een grote stofwolk hing boven de gemeente Grindelwald. De oorzaak ligt mogelijkerwijs in het binnendringen van smeltwater in de rotsen alsook wellicht in de toegenomen instabiliteit vanwege de door de opwarming van de Aarde veroorzaakte inkrimping van de aanwezige gletsjer.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:mapCaption xml:lang="en">Location in Switzerland</dbpprop:mapCaption>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Mountain"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">L'Eiger és una muntanya de 3.970 metres d'altura dels Alps Bernesos de Suïssa. Es localitza a la regió de l'Oberland Bernès, al cantó de Berna. És el pic més oriental de la cadena que inclou també els cims del Mönch (4099 m. ) i la Jungfrau (4158 m.). El costat septentrional de la muntanya s'alça al voltant de 3.000 metres sobre la localitat de Grindelwald. La cara meridional queda enfront de la regió de Jungfrau-Aletsch-Bietschhorn, coberta per algunes de les glaceres més grans dels Alps i declarada Patrimoni de la Humanitat per la Unesco el 2001.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:longEw xml:lang="en">E</dbpprop:longEw>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Bernese_Alps"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpprop:topo xml:lang="en">Swisstopo 1229 Grindelwald</dbpprop:topo>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">De Eiger is een 3970 meter hoge berg in de Berner Alpen. De Eiger is weliswaar geen "vierduizender", zoals nabijgelegen toppen als de Jungfrau en de Mönch, maar hij geldt wel als de spectaculairste om te beklimmen. Zijn steile noordwand is een klassieke uitdaging, die bekend staat als de gevaarlijkste klim van Europa. In 1858 is de berg voor het eerst beklommen door Charles Barrington, Christian Almer en metgezellen.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">El Eiger es una montaña de 3970 m. de altura de los Alpes berneses de Suiza, que forma parte del conjunto Jungfrau-Aletsch-Bietschhorn declarado Patrimonio de la Humanidad por la Unesco en 2001. Es el pico más oriental de la cadena que se extiende cruzando el Mönch (4099 m. ) y la Jungfrau (4158 m.). El lado septentrional de la montaña se alza alrededor de 3 km sobre Grindelwald y otros valles habitados del Oberland bernés, y la cara meridional queda frente a la región del Jungfrau-Aletsch, cubierta por algunos de los glaciares más grandes de los Alpes.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://fksa.org/showthread.php?t=6271"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Eiger är ett 3 970 meter högt berg i Bernalperna i Schweiz. Det är den östligaste i en rad bergstoppar som sträcker sig till Mönch på 4 107 meter, och över Jungfraujochpasset till Jungfrau på 4 158 meter. Toppen omnämns i källor bak till 1200-talet men det finns inga tydliga källor till hur berget fick sitt namn. De tre bergen i krönet brukar kallas ungmön, munken (Mönch) och trollet (Eiger). Namnet har även kopplats till grekiska akros, som betyder "skarp" eller "spetsig", men oftare till tyska eigen, som betyder karakteristisk (egen). Eiger bestegs för första gången av schweiziska guiderna Christian Almer och Peter Bohren tillsammans med irländaren Charles Barrington. De besteg den västra sidan den 11 augusti 1858. Järnvägslinjen Jungfraubahn sträcker sig genom Eiger i en tunnel, och två stationer inne i berget ger möjlighet till utsikt genom utkiksfönster i bergväggen. Järnvägen har sin ändstation vid Jungfraujochpasset, vilken är Europas högst belägna järnvägsstation. I juli 2006 föll en bit av Eiger, motsvarande 700 000 kubikmeter sten, från östra sidan. Stenklumpen landade i ett obebott område, så ingen människa eller byggnad skadades.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:range rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bernese_Alps"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Mountains_of_Switzerland"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Mountain109359803"/>
    <dbpprop:firstAscent rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">11</dbpprop:firstAscent>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Der Eiger ist ein 3'970 m ü.  M. hoher Berg in den Berner Alpen. Er ist dem Hauptkamm der Berner Alpen etwas nördlich vorgelagert und steht vollständig auf dem Territorium des Schweizer Kantons Bern. Zusammen mit Mönch und Jungfrau dominiert der Eiger die Landschaft des zentralen Berner Oberlandes. Die etwa 3000 Meter über dem Tal aufragende Nordwestseite dieser drei Gipfel ist eines der bekanntesten „Dreigestirne“ der Alpen. Die Nordwand des Eigers fasziniert sowohl Bergsteiger als auch Alpin-Laien. Durch dramatische Besteigungsversuche dieser Wand wurde der Eiger weltweit bekannt und immer wieder ins Blickfeld der Öffentlichkeit gerückt – nicht zuletzt, da die gesamte Nordwand von Grindelwald und der Bahnstation Kleine Scheidegg einsehbar ist. Heute ist die Jungfraubahn mit ihrem Tunnel durch den Eigerfels ein Touristenmagnet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/fc/North_face.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The Eiger (3,970 m) is a mountain in the Bernese Alps in Switzerland. It is the easternmost peak of a ridge crest that extends across the Mönch to the Jungfrau at 4,158 m. The northern side of the mountain rises about 3,000 m (9,800 ft) above Grindelwald and other inhabited valleys of the Bernese Oberland, and the southern side faces the deeply glaciated region of the Jungfrau-Aletsch, covered by some of the largest glaciers in the Alps. The first ascent of the Eiger was made by Swiss guides Christian Almer and Peter Bohren and Irishman Charles Barrington, who climbed the west flank on August 11, 1858. The north face, 1,800 m (5,900 ft), was first climbed in 1938 by an Austrian-German expedition and is one of the six great north faces of the Alps. Since 1935, at least sixty-four climbers have died attempting the north face, earning it the German nickname Mordwand, literally "murder(ous) wall" - a pun on its correct title of Nordwand (North Wall). From Kleine Scheidegg a railway tunnel runs inside the Eiger and two internal stations provide easy access to viewing-windows in the mountainside. This railway, the Jungfraubahn rack railway, terminates in the Jungfraujoch, between the Mönch and the Jungfrau, at the highest railway station in Europe. The Eiger is mentioned in records dating back to the 13th century but there is no clear indication of how exactly the peak gained its name. The three mountains of the ridge are commonly referred to as the Virgin, the Monk (Mönch) and the Ogre (Eiger). The name has been linked to the Latin term acer, meaning "sharp" or "pointed," but more commonly to the German eigen, meaning "own".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Eiger – szczyt w Alpach Berneńskich o wysokości 3970 metrów n.p.m. Jest najbardziej znaną górą w historii alpinizmu ekstremalnego. Wraz z Mönchem i Jungfrau tworzy trio (Dreigestirn) wielkich szczytów w północnej części berneńskiego Oberlandu w Szwajcarii. Jego północna ściana znana jest pod kilkoma nazwami: Eigerwand, Nordwand lub Mordwand (Ściana Śmierci) – to nazwa, jaką zaczęto określać ją po wielu tragicznie zakończonych próbach jej zdobycia.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-mountain-noun-1"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Eiger</rdfs:label>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">8.00528</geo:long>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpprop:region xml:lang="en">CH</dbpprop:region>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">46.5775</geo:lat>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Eiger er et fjell på 3970 moh. i Berner Oberland i Bern-Alpene i Sveits. Fjellet ble første gang besteget 1858. Den stupbratte og svært krevende nordveggen ble ikke besteget før i 1938. Eiger er den østligste toppen i et fjellmassiv som fortsetter videre til Mönch på 4 107 m og deretter via Jungfraujoch til Jungfrau på 4158 m. Jungfraubahnen går fra Kleine Scheideg i tunnel gjennom fjellet til Jungfraujoch, den høyest beliggende jernbanestasjonen i Europa. Siden 1903 har det vært en stasjon midt inne i tunnelen der man kan nyte utsikten gjennom åpninger i Eigers nordvegg. Eiger ligger mellom byene Brig og Interlaken. Fjellkjeden med Eiger, Mönch og Jungfrau er godt synlig flere steder nordfra og området der er derfor et yndet turistmål i Bern-alpene. Massivet er nevnt i skriftlige kilder tilbake til 1200-tallet. Toppene kalles ofte «Jetten» (Eiger), «Munken» (Mönch) og «Jomfruen» (Jungfrau). Navnet Eiger kan henge sammen med det greske ordet akros som betyr «skarp» eller «spiss», eller med det tyske eigen, som betyr «egenartet».</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">El Eiger es una montaña de 3970 m. de altura de los Alpes berneses de Suiza, que forma parte del conjunto Jungfrau-Aletsch-Bietschhorn declarado Patrimonio de la Humanidad por la Unesco en 2001. Es el pico más oriental de la cadena que se extiende cruzando el Mönch (4099 m. ) y la Jungfrau (4158 m.).</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">アイガー (Eiger) は、ベルニーズアルプスの一峰でスイスを代表する山。標高は3,975 m。 ユングフラウ、メンヒと並び、いわゆるオーバーランド三山の一つとされる。アイガー北壁は、高さ1800mの岩壁で、グランドジョラスの北壁、マッターホルン北壁とともに、困難な三大ルートの一つとして知られ、三大北壁と呼ばれている。1935年～1958年までに25回の登頂が試され、死者が15名に及んだものの、13回67名が登頂に成功している。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:elevation rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#decimal">3970</dbpedia-owl:elevation>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eiger"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Eiger</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.flickr.com/groups/eiger"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Eiger är ett 3 970 meter högt berg i Bernalperna i Schweiz. Det är den östligaste i en rad bergstoppar som sträcker sig till Mönch på 4 107 meter, och över Jungfraujochpasset till Jungfrau på 4 158 meter. Toppen omnämns i källor bak till 1200-talet men det finns inga tydliga källor till hur berget fick sitt namn. De tre bergen i krönet brukar kallas ungmön, munken (Mönch) och trollet (Eiger).</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">L'Eiger è una montagna svizzera delle Alpi bernesi, situata nella regione montuosa dell'Oberland. È particolarmente famosa per la sua parete nord, che ha costituito uno dei principali problemi alpinistici degli anni trenta.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">L'Eiger è una montagna svizzera delle Alpi bernesi, situata nella regione montuosa dell'Oberland. È particolarmente famosa per la sua parete nord, che ha costituito uno dei principali problemi alpinistici degli anni trenta.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Switzerland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:locatedInArea rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Canton_of_Bern"/>
    <dbpprop:prominenceM rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">356</dbpprop:prominenceM>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.hikr.org/dir/Eiger_1505/"/>
    <dbpprop:latD rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">46</dbpprop:latD>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Айгер — горная вершина в Бернских Альпах высотой 3970 м над уровнем моря. Выступающий из центрального горного хребта Бернских Альп Эйгер целиком находится на территории швейцарского кантона Берн. Вместе с вершинами Юнгфрау и Мёнх он образует знаменитое трио и гордо возвышается над окружающим ландшафтом. Эйгер впервые упоминается в исторических документах в 1252 году.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">アイガー (Eiger) は、ベルニーズアルプスの一峰でスイスを代表する山。標高は3,975 m。 ユングフラウ、メンヒと並び、いわゆるオーバーランド三山の一つとされる。アイガー北壁は、高さ1800mの岩壁で、グランドジョラスの北壁、マッターホルン北壁とともに、困難な三大ルートの一つとして知られ、三大北壁と呼ばれている。1935年～1958年までに25回の登頂が試され、死者が15名に及んだものの、13回67名が登頂に成功している。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Айгер — горная вершина в Бернских Альпах высотой 3970 м над уровнем моря. Выступающий из центрального горного хребта Бернских Альп Эйгер целиком находится на территории швейцарского кантона Берн. Вместе с вершинами Юнгфрау и Мёнх он образует знаменитое трио и гордо возвышается над окружающим ландшафтом. Эйгер впервые упоминается в исторических документах в 1252 году.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpprop:elevationM rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3970</dbpprop:elevationM>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">L’Eiger est un sommet individualisé des Alpes situé entièrement en Suisse dans le massif des Alpes bernoises. Son nom, attesté en 1252, ne signifie pas l'« ogre » contrairement aux idées reçues mais plus probablement « le grand épieu ». La confusion est due à la face nord qui a tué plusieurs personnes. Cette dernière, la plus grande face des Alpes avec 1 600 m de hauteur, presque totalement verticale ou déversante, fut considérée comme un des trois derniers grands problèmes des Alpes, avec les faces Nord du Cervin et des Grandes Jorasses.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpprop:easiestRoute xml:lang="en">basic rock/snow/ice climb</dbpprop:easiestRoute>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">艾格峰（Eiger，3970米），屬瑞士阿爾卑斯山脈部份的山峰。是少女峰（Jungfrau）4,158米及莫希峰（Mönch）4,107米東部延伸的高峰。 艾格峰名稱記錄可追溯到十三世紀，艾格峰被稱為“Mons Egere”，源自德語單詞“hej Ger”（意思是“矛”）在法語區，艾格峰常常被稱為“Ogre”（意為“食人者”）。艾格峰是由愛爾蘭人 Charles Barrington和瑞士導遊Christian Almer，Peter bohren於1858年8月11日從西側翼爬上首次登頂，這條線路至今仍然是標準線路。 少女峰鐵路的隧道段就是建築在艾格峰內，隧道段有兩個站，艾格石壁（Eigerwand）和冰海站（Eismeer），站內有玻璃觀景窗，看出去正是艾格峰冰河的遼闊視野。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">아이거 산은 알프스 산맥의 산으로 스위스에 위치한다. 높이는 3,970 m이다. 아일랜드 출신 찰스 배링턴과 두 명의 그린델발트 가이드가 1858년 8월 11일 가장 쉬운 서릉루트로 초등 하였다. 이후 남서릉, 미텔레기능, 라우퍼 루트 등 수많은 루트가 개척되었으나 북벽만은 등반이 불가능하다고 믿어져 왔다. 융프라우 철도가 아이거 산을 통과해서 지나간다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L’Eiger est un sommet individualisé des Alpes situé entièrement en Suisse dans le massif des Alpes bernoises. Son nom, attesté en 1252, ne signifie pas l'« ogre » contrairement aux idées reçues mais plus probablement « le grand épieu ». La confusion est due à la face nord qui a tué plusieurs personnes.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:prominence rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#decimal">356</dbpedia-owl:prominence>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.independent.co.uk/news/obituaries/anderl-heckmair-484841.html"/>
    <dbpprop:parentPeak rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/M%C3%B6nch"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MountainsOfTheAlps"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Mountains_of_the_Alps"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/アイガー"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">O Eiger é uma montanha de 3970 m de altitude e 1168 m de proeminência topográfica nos Alpes Berneses, na Suíça. Faz parte do conjunto Jungfrau-Aletsch-Bietschhorn declarado Património da Humanidade pela Unesco em 2001. É o pico mais oriental da cadeia que se estende cruzando o Mönch (4099 m) e o Jungfrau (4158 m).</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Eiger er et fjell på 3970 moh. i Berner Oberland i Bern-Alpene i Sveits. Fjellet ble første gang besteget 1858. Den stupbratte og svært krevende nordveggen ble ikke besteget før i 1938. Eiger er den østligste toppen i et fjellmassiv som fortsetter videre til Mönch på 4 107 m og deretter via Jungfraujoch til Jungfrau på 4158 m. Jungfraubahnen går fra Kleine Scheideg i tunnel gjennom fjellet til Jungfraujoch, den høyest beliggende jernbanestasjonen i Europa.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.markseaton.com/stories/eiger.htm"/>
    <dbpprop:longM rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">0</dbpprop:longM>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Eiger</foaf:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">艾格峰</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Mountain"/>
    <dbpprop:longS rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">19</dbpprop:longS>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Mountain"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.summitpost.org/mountains/mountain_link.pl?mountain_id=46"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Eiger"/>
    <dbpprop:longD rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">8</dbpprop:longD>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Eiger</rdfs:label>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eiger?oldid=494342282"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Eiger</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_mountain"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Der Eiger ist ein 3'970 m ü.  M. hoher Berg in den Berner Alpen. Er ist dem Hauptkamm der Berner Alpen etwas nördlich vorgelagert und steht vollständig auf dem Territorium des Schweizer Kantons Bern. Zusammen mit Mönch und Jungfrau dominiert der Eiger die Landschaft des zentralen Berner Oberlandes. Die etwa 3000 Meter über dem Tal aufragende Nordwestseite dieser drei Gipfel ist eines der bekanntesten „Dreigestirne“ der Alpen.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Place"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ranseloke.com/"/>
    <dbpprop:latNs xml:lang="en">N</dbpprop:latNs>
    <dbpprop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Canton_of_Bern"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/아이거_산"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Eiger</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.swisspanorama.com/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">아이거 산은 알프스 산맥의 산으로 스위스에 위치한다. 높이는 3,970 m이다. 아일랜드 출신 찰스 배링턴과 두 명의 그린델발트 가이드가 1858년 8월 11일 가장 쉬운 서릉루트로 초등 하였다. 이후 남서릉, 미텔레기능, 라우퍼 루트 등 수많은 루트가 개척되었으나 북벽만은 등반이 불가능하다고 믿어져 왔다. 융프라우 철도가 아이거 산을 통과해서 지나간다.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">艾格峰（Eiger，3970米），屬瑞士阿爾卑斯山脈部份的山峰。是少女峰（Jungfrau）4,158米及莫希峰（Mönch）4,107米東部延伸的高峰。 艾格峰名稱記錄可追溯到十三世紀，艾格峰被稱為“Mons Egere”，源自德語單詞“hej Ger”（意思是“矛”）在法語區，艾格峰常常被稱為“Ogre”（意為“食人者”）。艾格峰是由愛爾蘭人 Charles Barrington和瑞士導遊Christian Almer，Peter bohren於1858年8月11日從西側翼爬上首次登頂，這條線路至今仍然是標準線路。 少女峰鐵路的隧道段就是建築在艾格峰內，隧道段有兩個站，艾格石壁（Eigerwand）和冰海站（Eismeer），站內有玻璃觀景窗，看出去正是艾格峰冰河的遼闊視野。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:locatedInArea rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Switzerland"/>
    <dbpprop:photo xml:lang="en">North face.jpg</dbpprop:photo>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Eiger (v překladu obr) je nejvýchodnějším vrcholem horského masivu Jungfrau v bernském regionu Švýcarských Alp. Dalšími známými vrcholy tohoto masívu jsou Jungfrau a Mönch.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Eiger (v překladu obr) je nejvýchodnějším vrcholem horského masivu Jungfrau v bernském regionu Švýcarských Alp. Dalšími známými vrcholy tohoto masívu jsou Jungfrau a Mönch.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.023sff"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">46.5775 8.005277777777778</grs:point>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Place"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/2660928/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Eiger on Bernin Alpeilla, Sveitsissä sijaitseva 3 970 metriä korkea vuorenhuippu. Se on Jungfraun (4 158 m) ja Mönchin (4 107 m) kanssa samaan vuoristoalueeseen kuuluvista huipuista itäisin. Eiger on osa Jungfrau-Aletsch-maailmanperintökohdetta. Ensimmäiset huipulle kiivenneet olivat sveitsiläiset oppaat Christian Almer ja Peter Bohren sekä irlantilainen Charles Barrington, jotka nousivat huipulle länsipuolelta 11. elokuuta 1858, mutta vuoren pelätty pohjoisseinämä valloitettiin vasta 1938.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The Eiger (3,970 m) is a mountain in the Bernese Alps in Switzerland. It is the easternmost peak of a ridge crest that extends across the Mönch to the Jungfrau at 4,158 m. The northern side of the mountain rises about 3,000 m (9,800 ft) above Grindelwald and other inhabited valleys of the Bernese Oberland, and the southern side faces the deeply glaciated region of the Jungfrau-Aletsch, covered by some of the largest glaciers in the Alps.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:latS rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">39</dbpprop:latS>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">L'Eiger és una muntanya de 3.970 metres d'altura dels Alps Bernesos de Suïssa. Es localitza a la regió de l'Oberland Bernès, al cantó de Berna. És el pic més oriental de la cadena que inclou també els cims del Mönch (4099 m. ) i la Jungfrau (4158 m.). El costat septentrional de la muntanya s'alça al voltant de 3.000 metres sobre la localitat de Grindelwald.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Эйгер"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Eiger on Bernin Alpeilla, Sveitsissä sijaitseva 3 970 metriä korkea vuorenhuippu. Se on Jungfraun (4 158 m) ja Mönchin (4 107 m) kanssa samaan vuoristoalueeseen kuuluvista huipuista itäisin. Eiger on osa Jungfrau-Aletsch-maailmanperintökohdetta. Ensimmäiset huipulle kiivenneet olivat sveitsiläiset oppaat Christian Almer ja Peter Bohren sekä irlantilainen Charles Barrington, jotka nousivat huipulle länsipuolelta 11. elokuuta 1858, mutta vuoren pelätty pohjoisseinämä valloitettiin vasta 1938. Seinämää on myös kutsuttu Kuolemanseinämäksi, koska rinne oli vienyt jo yhdeksän vuorikiipeilijän hengen. Läheisiä taajamia on 5 kilometrin päässä pohjoisessa sijaitseva Grindelwald ja sen lähellä sijaitseva Interlaken. Jungfraujochille nouseva Jungfraubahn-juna kulkee osan matkastaan Eigerin sisällä tunnelissa. Eigerin eteläpuolella on jäätiköitä.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:latM rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">34</dbpprop:latM>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpprop:map xml:lang="en">Switzerland relief</dbpprop:map>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alpine_Three-thousanders"/>
    <dbpprop:photoCaption xml:lang="en">The north face of the Eiger</dbpprop:photoCaption>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger_(disambiguation)">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageDisambiguates rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger_(Canton_of_Bern)">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eiger">
    <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger_(Canton_Bern)">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Eiger">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/Eiger">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Toni_Kurz">
    <dbpprop:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mount_eiger">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eiger"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
