<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns9="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
   xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Araminta_Star_Matthews">
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson">
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Emily Dickinson Tập tin:Black-white photograph of Emily Dickinson. jpgẢnh của Emily Dickinson. Sinh 12 tháng 10, 1830Amherst, Massachusetts, Hoa KỳMất 15 tháng 5, 1886 (55 tuổi)Amherst, Massachusetts, Hoa KỳCông việc Nhà thơ Emily Elizabeth Dickinson (12 tháng 10 năm 1830 – 15 tháng 5 năm 1886) là một nhà thơ Mỹ. Cùng với Walt Whitman, Emily Dickinson đã trở thành nhà thơ đặc sắc nhất của Mỹ trong thế kỉ 19.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/エミリー・ディキンソン"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1886-05-15</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson (December 10, 1830 – May 15, 1886) was an American poet. Born in Amherst, Massachusetts, to a successful family with strong community ties, she lived a mostly introverted and reclusive life. After she studied at the Amherst Academy for seven years in her youth, she spent a short time at Mount Holyoke Female Seminary before returning to her family's house in Amherst.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_of_the_Victorian_era"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MountHolyokeCollegeAlumni"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson was een Amerikaanse dichteres wier werk tezamen met dat van Walt Whitman een nieuw tijdperk in de Amerikaanse poëzie inluidde: het modernisme.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.poetryfoundation.org/bio/emily-dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Poet</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Gutenberg_author"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson – poetka amerykańska.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/cb/Emily_Dickinson_daguerreotype.jpg/200px-Emily_Dickinson_daguerreotype.jpg"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:19th-century_women_writers"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.01509d"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">艾米莉·迪金森</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">에밀리 엘리자베스 디킨슨은 미국의 여류시인이다. 미국 매사추세츠(Massachusetts)주의 앰허스트(Amherst)에서 태어났다. 그녀는 거의 2000편에 달하는 시를 썼는데 주로 사랑,죽음,이별,영혼,천국 등을 소재로 한 명상시가 대부분이다. 미국에서 가장 천재적인 시인들 중 한 명으로 자주 꼽힌다. 그녀의 시는 당시의 다른 시들과는 많이 달라 생전에는 대중에게 인정받지 못했고 겨우 4편의 시만이 시집에 쓰였다. 에밀리 디킨슨은 생전에는 그녀의 재능을 알아본 소수의 시인과 지식인과 꾸준히 서신으로 시를 주고 받았다. 그녀의 천재성이 널리 인정받은 것은 사후, 여동생 라비니아 노크로스 디킨슨 (Lavinia Nocross Dickinson)이 에밀리의 시를 모아 시집을 낸 후의 일이다. 외출을 극도로 자제하고 은거한 시인으로 알려져 있으나, 젊었을 때는 매일 들판으로 외출하고 동네 아이들을 불러 놀기도 하던 활기찬 소녀였다. 마운트 홀리요크 대학교에 다녔다. 그녀는 시를 쓰다가 55세의 나이로 사망했다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Emily Dickinsonová byla americká básnířka 19. století, avšak povahou poezie a svým osobním apelem byla roku 1930 označena britským básníkem a kritikem za „nejsoučasnější, nejživější z básníků". Celé její dílo s výjimkou 13 básníhttp://www. jarab. cz/index. php?sec=8388623&amp;art=8389050 bylo objeveno a vydáno až po její smrti. Teprve ve 20. století začaly vycházet její básně v původním, neupraveném znění. Narodila se a zemřela v Amherstu ve státě Massachusetts. Přestože její rodina zaujímala významné místo ve společnosti, Emily žila a tvořila v samotě. Po sedmi letech studia na amherstské Akademii (střední škola) pokračovala Dickinsonová v Mount Holyoke Seminary. V dívčím semináři strávila pouhý rok a poté se vrátila zpět do rodného města, které pak už prakticky neopustila. Později dokonce nevycházela ani ze svého pokoje. Obyvatelé Amherstu ji považovali za výstředního blázna kvůli její zálibě v nošení bílých šatů, neochotě vítat hosty apod. Většinu přátelství udržovala pouze písemnou formou. Emily Dickinsonová byla velmi plodná autorka. Její tvorba čítá asi 1800 básní, z nichž téměř všechny byly vydány až po její smrti. Básnířka sama souhlasila se zveřejněním pouze sedmi básní. Všechny byly vydány anonymně a pozměněny nakladately, aby odpovídaly tehdejším básnickým normám. Její básně ignorovaly tehdejší básnické zvyklosti například tím, že používaly poloviční rým, byly krátké a málokdy obsahovaly název. Interpunkce a psaní velkých písmen jsou další znaky jimiž se básně Emily Dickinsonové lišily od ostatních. Hlavními tématy jejích básní jsou smrt a nesmrtelnost, jež také dopodrobna rozebírala ve svých dopisech přátelům. Je s podivem, že básně objevila Emilyina mladší sestra Lavinia až po její smrti v roce 1886. Je totiž velmi pravděpodobné, že mnoho autorčiných známých o jejím psaní vědělo. V roce 1890 vydali její přátelé Thomas Wentworth Higginson a Mabel Loomis Toddová první básnickou sbírku Emily Dickinsonové, která ale také nezůstala beze změn. První kompletní a nejméně pozměněnou sbírku vydal Thomas H. Johnson až v roce 1955. Dílo Emily Dickinsonové zaznamenalo nepříznivou kritiku na přelomu 19. a 20. století. Její přínos byl ale později doceněn a nyní je kritiky považována za přední americkou autorku poezie.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">埃米莉·伊丽莎白·狄更生（英文：Emily Elizabeth Dickinson，又譯艾彌莉‧狄瑾蓀或艾米莉·狄金森，1830年12月10日－1886年5月15日），美國詩人。詩風凝煉，比喻尖新，常置格律以至語法於不顧。生前只发表過10首詩，默默無聞，死後近70年開始得到文學界的認真關注，被現代派詩人追認為先驅。與同時代的惠特曼，一同被奉為美國最偉大詩人，後世對她的詩藝、戀愛生活、性取向多有揣測。 狄更生出生于马萨诸塞州安默斯特颇具影响力的一个显赫家族，性格内向，不爱露面。年轻时，她曾在安默斯特学院学习了七年，此后，又在曼荷莲女子学院度过了一段短暂的时光，最终返回到位于安默斯特的家中。当地人认为她似乎格格不入。大家都知道她偏爱白色衣着，不愿见客，晚年时甚至不愿迈出自己房间一步。因此她与大多数朋友的友情都靠通信维系。 作为一位高产却孤僻的诗人，狄更生的1800多首诗歌作品仅有十几首在她在世时得到出版。这些在她生前出版的作品常常会被出版商大肆修改，以符合当时传统的诗歌规则。在狄更生所处的时代里，她的诗歌是独特的。她的诗歌包含短句，略去标题，韵脚不齐，并且还有反常规的大写字母和标点符号。 她的许多诗歌探讨死亡和永生，这两个主题也反复出现在她寄给朋友的信里。 尽管大多数狄更生的朋友可能都意识到她的写作异于常人，但是直到1886年她去世这年，她的妹妹拉维尼亚发现了她藏匿的作品，狄更生大量的作品才为人所知。她的第一本诗歌作品集在1890年由私人好友托马斯•温特沃斯•希金森和梅布尔•托特出版，他们二人都对作品内容进行了重大修改。直至1955年，学者托马斯•H•约翰逊出版了《埃米莉•狄更生诗集》，这是狄更生作品首度完整出版，几乎没有任何修改。尽管19世纪晚期至20世纪早期这段时间里，有人批评并质疑狄更生的文学功力，当今的评论家却认为狄更生算得上是美国一位重要的诗人。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/gutendata/resource/people/Dickinson_Emily_1830-1886"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Nacque da una famiglia molto in vista, conosciuta per il sostegno fornito alle istituzioni scolastiche locali. Suo nonno, Samuel Fowler Dickinson, era uno dei fondatori dell'Amherst College, mentre il padre ricopriva la funzione di legale e tesoriere dell'Istituto; inoltre, ricopriva importanti incarichi presso il Tribunale Generale del Massachusetts, il Senato dello Stato e la Camera dei Rappresentanti degli Stati Uniti.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson fue una poetisa estadounidense, cuya poesía apasionada ha colocado a su autora en el reducido panteón de poetas fundacionales estadounidenses que hoy comparte con Edgar Allan Poe, Ralph Waldo Emerson y Walt Whitman.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_of_Massachusetts_in_the_American_Civil_War"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">埃米莉·伊丽莎白·狄更生（英文：Emily Elizabeth Dickinson，又譯艾彌莉‧狄瑾蓀或艾米莉·狄金森，1830年12月10日－1886年5月15日），美國詩人。詩風凝煉，比喻尖新，常置格律以至語法於不顧。生前只发表過10首詩，默默無聞，死後近70年開始得到文學界的認真關注，被現代派詩人追認為先驅。與同時代的惠特曼，一同被奉為美國最偉大詩人，後世對她的詩藝、戀愛生活、性取向多有揣測。 狄更生出生于马萨诸塞州安默斯特颇具影响力的一个显赫家族，性格内向，不爱露面。年轻时，她曾在安默斯特学院学习了七年，此后，又在曼荷莲女子学院度过了一段短暂的时光，最终返回到位于安默斯特的家中。当地人认为她似乎格格不入。大家都知道她偏爱白色衣着，不愿见客，晚年时甚至不愿迈出自己房间一步。因此她与大多数朋友的友情都靠通信维系。 作为一位高产却孤僻的诗人，狄更生的1800多首诗歌作品仅有十几首在她在世时得到出版。这些在她生前出版的作品常常会被出版商大肆修改，以符合当时传统的诗歌规则。在狄更生所处的时代里，她的诗歌是独特的。她的诗歌包含短句，略去标题，韵脚不齐，并且还有反常规的大写字母和标点符号。 她的许多诗歌探讨死亡和永生，这两个主题也反复出现在她寄给朋友的信里。 尽管大多数狄更生的朋友可能都意识到她的写作异于常人，但是直到1886年她去世这年，她的妹妹拉维尼亚发现了她藏匿的作品，狄更生大量的作品才为人所知。她的第一本诗歌作品集在1890年由私人好友托马斯•温特沃斯•希金森和梅布尔•托特出版，他们二人都对作品内容进行了重大修改。直至1955年，学者托马斯•H•约翰逊出版了《埃米莉•狄更生诗集》，这是狄更生作品首度完整出版，几乎没有任何修改。尽管19世纪晚期至20世纪早期这段时间里，有人批评并质疑狄更生的文学功力，当今的评论家却认为狄更生算得上是美国一位重要的诗人。</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Дикинсон,_Эмили"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Dickinson</foaf:surname>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Emily Dickinson oli yhdysvaltalainen runoilija. Kuoleman, kärsimyksen ja menetyksen runolijana pidetty Emily Dickinson syntyi Amherstissa, Massachusettsissä varakkaaseen perheeseen. Vuodesta 1840 lähtien hän opiskeli englannin kieltä ja kirjallisuutta Amherstin akatemiassa. Kun Dickinson kuoli munuaistulehdukseen vuonna 1886, vain seitsemän hänen runoistaan oli julkaistu. 1890-luvulla julkaistiin kuitenkin postuumisti kolme hänen runokokoelmaansa, jotka tekivät hänestä tunnetun.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Е́мілі Елі́забет Ді́кінсон — американська поетеса. Дікінсон прожила відлюдником все життя. Хоча вона була плідним поетом, менше дюжини із створених нею майже 1800 творів були опубліковані під час її життя. Опубліковані твори були змінені редакторами для того, щоби відповідати поетичним правилам її часу. Поезії Дікінсон були не типовими для її часу, вони складаються з коротких рядків, не мають назв, часто містять неточні рими та неконвенційну пунктуацію. Темою багатьох її творів є смерть та безсмертя.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/에밀리_디킨슨"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson va ser una poetessa americana. Malgrat ser gairebé desconeguda en vida, Dickinson ha acabat sent considerada, juntament amb Walt Whitman, un dels més importants poetes americans del segle XIX. De fet, la teoria sol acceptar que la poesia nord-americana contemporània amplia dos corrents divergents: un que neix de Whitman i un que neix de Dickinson. Curiosament, aquests dos poetes eren gairebé perfectes opostos en tarannà, prosòdia, intencions i estils poètics. Dickinson va viure una vida introvertida i hermètica, que ha inspirat moltes biografies i voluminoses especulacions (tanmateix, se'n sap ben poc). Malgrat que va escriure, segons el darrer recompte, 1.789 poemes, només alguns d'ells es van publicar en vida de l'autora, tots ells anònims i probablement sense saber-ho ella.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Mount_Holyoke_College_alumni"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Emily Dickinson Tập tin:Black-white photograph of Emily Dickinson. jpgẢnh của Emily Dickinson. Sinh 12 tháng 10, 1830Amherst, Massachusetts, Hoa KỳMất 15 tháng 5, 1886 (55 tuổi)Amherst, Massachusetts, Hoa KỳCông việc Nhà thơ Emily Elizabeth Dickinson (12 tháng 10 năm 1830 – 15 tháng 5 năm 1886) là một nhà thơ Mỹ. Cùng với Walt Whitman, Emily Dickinson đã trở thành nhà thơ đặc sắc nhất của Mỹ trong thế kỉ 19.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson var en amerikansk forfatter. Selv om hun var nærmest ukjent i sin levetid, regnes hun nå som en av USAs viktigste diktere i det nittende århundre. Alt i alt skrev hun snaut 1800 dikt, hvorav de færreste ble publisert mens hun levde.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118525255</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Amherst, Massachusetts, United States</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://onlinebooks.library.upenn.edu/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Emily Dickinson amerikai költőnő. Magábafordulóan és a környezetétől elzárkózottan élt. Az utolsó vizsgálatok szerint 1789 verset írt, de ezek közül csak néhány (kb. 7-10) jelent meg életében, azok is névtelenül, vagy az ő tudta nélkül.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1886-05-15</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.emilydickinsoninternationalsociety.org/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WomenInTheAmericanCivilWar"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Dickinson, Emily</dbpprop:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_in_the_American_Civil_War"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson foi uma poetisa americana, considerada moderna em vários aspectos da sua obra.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <ns9:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emily_Dickinson?oldid=494239822"/>
    <dbpprop:id xml:lang="en">Emily+Dickinson</dbpprop:id>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Emily Dickinsonová</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">エミリー・エリザベス・ディキンソン（Emily Elizabeth Dickinson、1830年12月10日 - 1886年5月15日）はアメリカの詩人。生前は無名であったが、1700篇以上残した作品は世界中で高い評価を受けている。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Emily</foaf:givenName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson, née le 10 décembre 1830 et morte le 15 mai 1886, est une poétesse américaine. Née à Amherst dans le Massachusetts, dans une famille aisée ayant des liens communautaires forts, elle a vécu une vie introvertie et recluse. Après avoir étudié dans sa jeunesse, durant sept ans à l'académie d’Amherst, elle vit un moment au séminaire féminin du mont Holyoke avant de retourner dans la maison familiale à Amherst.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Emily Dickinson</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Emily Dickinson</dbpprop:name>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Emily Dickinson</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Э́мили Эли́забет Ди́кинсон — американская поэтесса. При жизни опубликовала менее десяти стихотворений (большинство источников называют цифры от семи до десяти) из тысячи восьмисот, написанных ей. Даже то, что было опубликовано, подверглось серьёзной редакторской переработке, чтобы привести стихотворения в соответствии с поэтическими нормами того времени. Стихи Дикинсон не имеют аналогов в современной ей поэзии. Их строки коротки, названия, как правило, отсутствуют, и часто встречаются необычная пунктуация и использование заглавных букв. Многие её стихи содержат мотив смерти и бессмертия, эти же сюжеты пронизывают её письма к друзьям. Хотя большинство её знакомых знали о том, что Дикинсон пишет стихи, масштаб её творчества стал известен только после её смерти, когда её младшая сестра Лавиния в 1886 году обнаружила неопубликованные произведения. Первое собрание поэзии Дикинсон было опубликовано в 1890 году и подверглось сильной редакторской правке; полное и почти неотредактированное издание было выпущено в 1955 году Томасом Джонсоном. Хотя публикации вызвали неблагоприятные отзывы критики в конце XIX и начале XX века, в настоящее время Эмили Дикинсон рассматривается критикой как один из величайших американских поэтов.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Э́мили Эли́забет Ди́кинсон — американская поэтесса. При жизни опубликовала менее десяти стихотворений (большинство источников называют цифры от семи до десяти) из тысячи восьмисот, написанных ей. Даже то, что было опубликовано, подверглось серьёзной редакторской переработке, чтобы привести стихотворения в соответствии с поэтическими нормами того времени. Стихи Дикинсон не имеют аналогов в современной ей поэзии.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_women_writers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_poets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson fue una poetisa estadounidense, cuya poesía apasionada ha colocado a su autora en el reducido panteón de poetas fundacionales estadounidenses que hoy comparte con Edgar Allan Poe, Ralph Waldo Emerson y Walt Whitman. Emily Dickinson pasó gran parte de su vida recluida en una habitación de la casa de su padre en Amherst, y, excepto cinco poemas (tres de ellos publicados sin su firma y otro sin que la autora lo supiera), su ingente obra permaneció inédita y oculta hasta después de su muerte.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.emilydickinson.org/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Emily Dickinson oli yhdysvaltalainen runoilija. Kuoleman, kärsimyksen ja menetyksen runolijana pidetty Emily Dickinson syntyi Amherstissa, Massachusettsissä varakkaaseen perheeseen. Vuodesta 1840 lähtien hän opiskeli englannin kieltä ja kirjallisuutta Amherstin akatemiassa. Kun Dickinson kuoli munuaistulehdukseen vuonna 1886, vain seitsemän hänen runoistaan oli julkaistu. 1890-luvulla julkaistiin kuitenkin postuumisti kolme hänen runokokoelmaansa, jotka tekivät hänestä tunnetun.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.emilydickinsonmuseum.org/"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Емілі Дікінсон</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson, gilt als bedeutende US-amerikanische Dichterin. Ihre Gedichte, erstmals 1890 nach ihrem Tod gedruckt, scheinen stilistisch vielfach ins 20. Jahrhundert vorzugreifen.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Е́мілі Елі́забет Ді́кінсон — американська поетеса. Дікінсон прожила відлюдником все життя. Хоча вона була плідним поетом, менше дюжини із створених нею майже 1800 творів були опубліковані під час її життя. Опубліковані твори були змінені редакторами для того, щоби відповідати поетичним правилам її часу. Поезії Дікінсон були не типовими для її часу, вони складаються з коротких рядків, не мають назв, часто містять неточні рими та неконвенційну пунктуацію.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1830_births"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Emily Dickinson</foaf:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson foi uma poetisa americana, considerada moderna em vários aspectos da sua obra.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Emily Dickinson, född 10 december 1830 i Amherst i Massachusetts, död där 15 maj 1886, var en amerikansk poet. Dickinson föddes i en universitetsfamilj på Amerikas östkust nära Amherst College. Hennes far, Edward Dickinson, var en politiskt prominent person i Massachusetts på den tiden. Hon hade en bror, William Austin, och en syster, Lavinia "Vinnie". Emily förde en isolerad och tillbakadragen tillvaro i föräldrahemmet under hela sitt liv.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/cb/Emily_Dickinson_daguerreotype.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson, née le 10 décembre 1830 et morte le 15 mai 1886, est une poétesse américaine. Née à Amherst dans le Massachusetts, dans une famille aisée ayant des liens communautaires forts, elle a vécu une vie introvertie et recluse. Après avoir étudié dans sa jeunesse, durant sept ans à l'académie d’Amherst, elle vit un moment au séminaire féminin du mont Holyoke avant de retourner dans la maison familiale à Amherst. Considérée comme une excentrique par le voisinage, on la connaît pour son penchant pour les vêtements blancs et pour sa répugnance à recevoir des visiteurs voire, plus tard, à sortir de sa chambre. La plupart de ses amitiés seront donc entretenues par correspondance. Bien qu’ayant été un auteur prolifique, moins d’une douzaine de ses presque mille huit cent poèmes ont été publiés de son vivant. Ceux qui furent publiés étaient généralement modifiés par les éditeurs afin de se conformer aux règles poétiques de l’époque. Les poèmes de Dickinson sont uniques pour leur époque, ils sont constitués de vers très courts, n’ont pas de titres et utilisent fréquemment des rimes imparfaites et des majuscules et ponctuations non conventionnelles. Un grand nombre de ses poèmes traitent de la mort et de l’immortalité, des sujets récurrents dans sa correspondance avec ses amis. Même si la plupart de ses connaissances devaient savoir qu’Emily Dickinson écrivait, l’étendue de son œuvre ne fut connue qu’après sa mort, en 1886, quand Lavinia, sa plus jeune sœur, découvre sa cachette de poèmes. Son premier recueil est publié en 1890 par des relations personnelles, Thomas Wentworth Higginson et Mabel Loomis Todd, qui en altèreront fortement le contenu. Ce n’est qu’avec l’édition de Thomas H. Johnson en 1955, Les poèmes d’Emily Dickinson (The Poems of Emily Dickinson), que parait pour la première fois un recueil complet et pratiquement intact de son travail. Malgré des critiques défavorables et un grand scepticisme vis-à-vis de ses performances littéraires de la fin du XIX siècle au début du XX siècle, les critiques considèrent à présent Emily Dickinson comme un poète américain majeur.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Amherst,_Massachusetts"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleOfMassachusettsInTheAmericanCivilWar"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson – poetka amerykańska.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Nacque da una famiglia molto in vista, conosciuta per il sostegno fornito alle istituzioni scolastiche locali. Suo nonno, Samuel Fowler Dickinson, era uno dei fondatori dell'Amherst College, mentre il padre ricopriva la funzione di legale e tesoriere dell'Istituto; inoltre, ricopriva importanti incarichi presso il Tribunale Generale del Massachusetts, il Senato dello Stato e la Camera dei Rappresentanti degli Stati Uniti.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinsonová"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Emily Dickinsonová byla americká básnířka 19. století, avšak povahou poezie a svým osobním apelem byla roku 1930 označena britským básníkem a kritikem za „nejsoučasnější, nejživější z básníků". Celé její dílo s výjimkou 13 básníhttp://www. jarab. cz/index. php?sec=8388623&amp;art=8389050 bylo objeveno a vydáno až po její smrti. Teprve ve 20. století začaly vycházet její básně v původním, neupraveném znění. Narodila se a zemřela v Amherstu ve státě Massachusetts.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Deaths_from_nephritis"/>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">Poet</dc:description>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson was een Amerikaanse dichteres wier werk tezamen met dat van Walt Whitman een nieuw tijdperk in de Amerikaanse poëzie inluidde: het modernisme.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanWomenWriters"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">에밀리 엘리자베스 디킨슨은 미국의 여류시인이다. 미국 매사추세츠(Massachusetts)주의 앰허스트(Amherst)에서 태어났다. 그녀는 거의 2000편에 달하는 시를 썼는데 주로 사랑,죽음,이별,영혼,천국 등을 소재로 한 명상시가 대부분이다. 미국에서 가장 천재적인 시인들 중 한 명으로 자주 꼽힌다. 그녀의 시는 당시의 다른 시들과는 많이 달라 생전에는 대중에게 인정받지 못했고 겨우 4편의 시만이 시집에 쓰였다. 에밀리 디킨슨은 생전에는 그녀의 재능을 알아본 소수의 시인과 지식인과 꾸준히 서신으로 시를 주고 받았다. 그녀의 천재성이 널리 인정받은 것은 사후, 여동생 라비니아 노크로스 디킨슨 (Lavinia Nocross Dickinson)이 에밀리의 시를 모아 시집을 낸 후의 일이다. 외출을 극도로 자제하고 은거한 시인으로 알려져 있으나, 젊었을 때는 매일 들판으로 외출하고 동네 아이들을 불러 놀기도 하던 활기찬 소녀였다. 마운트 홀리요크 대학교에 다녔다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://edl.byu.edu/index.php"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://hcl.harvard.edu/libraries/houghton/"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Writers_from_Massachusetts"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson va ser una poetessa americana. Malgrat ser gairebé desconeguda en vida, Dickinson ha acabat sent considerada, juntament amb Walt Whitman, un dels més importants poetes americans del segle XIX. De fet, la teoria sol acceptar que la poesia nord-americana contemporània amplia dos corrents divergents: un que neix de Whitman i un que neix de Dickinson. Curiosament, aquests dos poetes eren gairebé perfectes opostos en tarannà, prosòdia, intencions i estils poètics.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Emily Dickinson</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromAmherst,Massachusetts"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath xml:lang="en">Amherst, Massachusetts, United States</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvvqsg5wpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://hcl.harvard.edu/libraries/houghton/collections/modern/dickinson.cfm"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1886_deaths"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WomenOfTheVictorianEra"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/gardening/main.jhtml?xml=/gardening/2007/06/29/gemily29.xml"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1830-12-10</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www3.amherst.edu/magazine/issues/06winter/emily/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="https://www.amherst.edu/mm/278804"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.english.illinois.edu/maps/poets/a_f/dickinson/dickinson.htm"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://onlinebooks.library.upenn.edu/webbin/book/search?author=Dickinson%2C+Emily&amp;amode=words&amp;title=&amp;tmode=words"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Emily Dickinson amerikai költőnő. Magábafordulóan és a környezetétől elzárkózottan élt. Az utolsó vizsgálatok szerint 1789 verset írt, de ezek közül csak néhány (kb. 7-10) jelent meg életében, azok is névtelenül, vagy az ő tudta nélkül.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Emily Dickinson</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">エミリー・エリザベス・ディキンソン（Emily Elizabeth Dickinson、1830年12月10日 - 1886年5月15日）はアメリカの詩人。生前は無名であったが、1700篇以上残した作品は世界中で高い評価を受けている。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Emily Dickinson, född 10 december 1830 i Amherst i Massachusetts, död där 15 maj 1886, var en amerikansk poet. Dickinson föddes i en universitetsfamilj på Amerikas östkust nära Amherst College. Hennes far, Edward Dickinson, var en politiskt prominent person i Massachusetts på den tiden. Hon hade en bror, William Austin, och en syster, Lavinia "Vinnie". Emily förde en isolerad och tillbakadragen tillvaro i föräldrahemmet under hela sitt liv. Hon skickade in dikter till en lokal kritiker, som avrådde henne från publicering; han ansåg hennes diktning alltför oren och ojämn. Under sin livstid publicerade hon endast en handfull dikter, men efterlämnade en produktion på sjuttonhundra. Efter Emilys död verkade hennes syster för publiceringen av Emilys dikter och dessa har hyllats av hennes eftervärld som mer eller mindre har romantiserat henne. Dickinson betraktas idag som en av de mest betydande amerikanska lyrikerna inom engelskspråkig poesi och hon har påverkat många efterföljare. Hon var en originell poet, högstämd och liksom konverserande i samma andetag. Hon skrev om konventionella poetiska ämnen såsom naturen, kärleken, döden och Gud. Bland hennes mest omtyckta dikter är "I'm Nobody! Who Are You?", vars första vers lyder: I'm Nobody! Who are you? Are you -- Nobody -- Too? Then there's a pair of us! Don't tell! they'd banish us -- you know! How dreary -- to be -- Somebody! How public -- like a Frog -- To tell one's name -- the livelong day -- To an admiring Bog! Dickinson dog den 15 maj 1886 av nefrit. Hennes sista vilja innan hon dog var att alla hennes dikter skulle brännas, vilket hon inte fick igenom.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson (December 10, 1830 – May 15, 1886) was an American poet. Born in Amherst, Massachusetts, to a successful family with strong community ties, she lived a mostly introverted and reclusive life. After she studied at the Amherst Academy for seven years in her youth, she spent a short time at Mount Holyoke Female Seminary before returning to her family's house in Amherst. Thought of as an eccentric by the locals, she became known for her penchant for white clothing and her reluctance to greet guests or, later in life, even leave her room. Most of her friendships were therefore carried out by correspondence. Although Dickinson was a prolific private poet, fewer than a dozen of her nearly eighteen hundred poems were published during her lifetime. The work that was published during her lifetime was usually altered significantly by the publishers to fit the conventional poetic rules of the time. Dickinson's poems are unique for the era in which she wrote; they contain short lines, typically lack titles, and often use slant rhyme as well as unconventional capitalization and punctuation. Many of her poems deal with themes of death and immortality, two recurring topics in letters to her friends. Although most of her acquaintances were probably aware of Dickinson's writing, it was not until after her death in 1886—when Lavinia, Emily's younger sister, discovered her cache of poems—that the breadth of Dickinson's work became apparent. Her first collection of poetry was published in 1890 by personal acquaintances Thomas Wentworth Higginson and Mabel Loomis Todd, both of whom heavily edited the content. A complete and mostly unaltered collection of her poetry became available for the first time in 1955 when The Poems of Emily Dickinson was published by scholar Thomas H. Johnson. Despite unfavorable reviews and skepticism of her literary prowess during the late 19th and early 20th century, critics now consider Dickinson to be a major American poet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanPoets"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_Christians"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Έμιλι_Ντίκινσον"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson, gilt als bedeutende US-amerikanische Dichterin. Ihre Gedichte, erstmals 1890 nach ihrem Tod gedruckt, scheinen stilistisch vielfach ins 20. Jahrhundert vorzugreifen.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1830-12-10</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <dbpprop:alternativeNames xml:lang="en">Dickinson, Emily Elizabeth</dbpprop:alternativeNames>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WritersFromMassachusetts"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Amherst,_Massachusetts"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Amherst,_Massachusetts"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Emily Elizabeth Dickinson var en amerikansk forfatter. Selv om hun var nærmest ukjent i sin levetid, regnes hun nå som en av USAs viktigste diktere i det nittende århundre. Alt i alt skrev hun snaut 1800 dikt, hvorav de færreste ble publisert mens hun levde.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dickinson_(crater)">
    <dbpprop:eponym rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_dickonson">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Box_(locked)">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Phil_Solomon_(filmmaker)">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Christopher_Benfey">
    <dbpprop:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <skos:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Kay_Ryan">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Elizabeth_Dickinson">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://data.nytimes.com/92132711173033412593">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ted_Hughes">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emily_Dickinson">
    <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ample_Make_This_Bed">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Shannon_Bramer">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageDisambiguates rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_dickinson">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Theodore_Roethke">
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alice_Fulton">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Austin_Gary">
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Susan_Howe">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cherry_bureau">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Richard_Brautigan">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/J._Jill_Robinson">
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emliy_dickenson">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poem_301">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/Emily_Dickinson">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jack_Ketchum">
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Frank_Stanford">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jerome_Charyn">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Style_of_Emily_Dickinson">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Maurice_Sendak">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Raymond_Kennedy">
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickenson">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageRedirects rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Giannina_Braschi">
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mabel_Loomis_Todd">
    <dbpprop:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
    <skos:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Elizabeth_Barrett_Browning">
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Emily_Dickinson"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
