<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvbky55wpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_of_the_Victorian_era"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">George Eliot, pseudonym for Mary Ann (Marian) Evans var en britisk forfatter, journalist og oversetter. Evans var en av de ledende forfatterne av den viktorianske epoken. Hun var forfatter av syv romaner, blant dem var Adam Bede, The Mill on the Floss, Silas Marner, Middlemarch og Daniel Deronda. De fleste av hennes verker er lagt til det provinsielle England og hun er kjent for sin realisme og psykologisk innsikt i hennes litterære verker. Evans publiserte sine bøker under et mannlig pseudonym for å sikre at hennes arbeider ble tatt på alvor. Kvinnelige forfattere utgav ofte bøker under sitt eget navn på denne tiden, men Evans ønsket å unnslippe Stereotypen om at kvinner bare skriver muntre romanser. En ytterligere faktor i hennes bruk av en et psevdonym kan ha vært et ønske om å skjerme hennes private liv fra offentlig ettersyn og sladder.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">George Eliot, pseudonym for Mary Ann (Marian) Evans var en britisk forfatter, journalist og oversetter. Evans var en av de ledende forfatterne av den viktorianske epoken. Hun var forfatter av syv romaner, blant dem var Adam Bede, The Mill on the Floss, Silas Marner, Middlemarch og Daniel Deronda. De fleste av hennes verker er lagt til det provinsielle England og hun er kjent for sin realisme og psykologisk innsikt i hennes litterære verker.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">George Eliot, właśc. Mary Ann Evans (ur. 22 listopada 1819 w South Farm Arbury – angielska pisarka należąca do czołowych twórców epoki wiktoriańskiej. Autorka siedmiu powieści, cechujących się realizmem i przenikliwością psychologiczną; ich akcja rozgrywa się w najczęściej prowincjonalnej Anglii. Pisała także wiersze i inne utwory. W słowniku języka angielskiego Oxford English Dictionary jest najczęściej cytowaną kobietą-pisarką.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Arbury_Hall"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Mary Anne (alternatively Mary Ann or Marian) Evans (22 November 1819 – 22 December 1880), better known by her pen name George Eliot, was an English novelist, journalist and translator, and one of the leading writers of the Victorian era.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.george-eliot.com"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Arbury"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thomas_Mann"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Charlotte_Bront%C3%AB"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableWork rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Silas_Marner"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.skoob.com/seriph/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">George Eliot, de son vrai nom Mary Anne Evans, est une romancière britannique née le 22 novembre 1819 à Nuneaton et morte le 22 décembre 1880 à Londres. Elle est considérée comme un des plus grands écrivains victoriens, tous sexes confondus. Ses romans, qui se situent dans une Angleterre provinciale, sont connus pour leur réalisme et leur profondeur psychologique. Elle prit un nom de plume à consonance masculine afin que son œuvre soit prise au sérieux.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Martin_Amis"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Artist"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">4</dbpprop:deathPlace>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">George Eliot es el seudónimo que empleó la escritora británica Mary Anne Evans.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Writer"/>
    <dbpprop:id xml:lang="en">George_Eliot</dbpprop:id>
    <dbpedia-owl:partner rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Henry_Lewes"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">George Eliot</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:pseudonym xml:lang="en">George Eliot</dbpedia-owl:pseudonym>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Martin_Amis"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Mary Anne Evans, més coneguda pel pseudònim George Eliot, fou una novel·lista, periodista i traductora anglesa. Una de les millors plomes de l'època victoriana, és autora de set novel·les, la majoria situades a l'Anglaterra provinciana i conegudes pel seu realisme i l'anàlisi psicològica.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1880-12-22</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thomas_Mann"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nuneaton"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Mary Ann (Marian) Evansová, v literatuře známá pod pseudonymem George Eliot, byla anglická spisovatelka, novinářka a překladatelka, jedna z nejvýznamnějších autorek viktoriánského období. Ve své době pobouřila veřejnost nelegitimním vztahem se spisovatelem a Goethovým životopiscem Georgem Henry Lewesem. První její prací byly překlady německých filozofů Davida Strausse a Ludwiga Feuerbacha, o kterých se tenkrát velmi diskutovalo. Eliotová procestovala velkou část Evropy.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.princeton.edu/~batke/eliot/jacob/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Джордж Элиот — английская писательница. Ошибка: неверное или отсутствующее изображение В этой статье не хватает ссылок на источники информации. Информация должна быть проверяема, иначе она может быть поставлена под сомнение и удалена. Вы можете отредактировать эту статью, добавив ссылки на авторитетные источники. Эта отметка стоит на статье с 6 октября 2011.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Writer"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Mary Anne Evans</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:period xml:lang="en">Victorian</dbpprop:period>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableWork rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Daniel_Deronda"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_essayists"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_novelists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/VictorianNovelists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromNuneaton"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Victorian_novelists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">조지 엘리엇은 영국의 여류 소설가이다. 본명은 메리 앤 에번스 (Mary Anne Evans)이다. 영국 중부의 워릭셔에서 출생. 부친은 건축가였다가 지주를 위한 토지관리인이 되었다. 부친은 견실한 성격을 가졌고, 엘리엇의 소설인 &lt;아덤 비드&gt;(1859)의 아덤을 위시하여 자주 다른 곳에도 그녀의 부친을 모델로 하는 인물이 등장한다. 소녀 시절의 그녀는 복음주의의 열렬한 신봉자였으나 차차로 당시의 새 사상에 접촉하여 과학주의·실증주의에 입각한 사상을 품게 되어 기독교를 떠난다. 그러나 그녀의 도덕관을 이루는 기저(基底)에는 종교적인 심정이 일생을 일관하고 있다. 1854년 이후에 처자가 있는 조지 루이스와 동거생활을 하게 되어 세상의 비난을 받았으나 조지 엘리엇이란 이름으로 &lt;플로스강(江)의 물레방아&gt;(1860), &lt;미들마치&gt;(1872) 등의 걸작을 내면서 작가로서 그녀의 위치는 부동한 것이 된다. 그녀의 소설은 사실주의의 기법을 따르고 있지만 내용은 사람이 사는 방식에 관하여 그녀만의 독특한 철학을 구체화한 것이다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.poetryfoundation.org/bio/george-eliot"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">4</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Honor%C3%A9_de_Balzac"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:NPG_name"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishWomenWriters"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_women_writers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">George Eliot (oik. Mary Ann Evans) oli englantilainen kirjailija. Hän oli 1800-luvun loppupuolen huomattavimpia kirjailijoita. Eliotin realistiset romaanit, ennen kaikkea Middlemarch, sijoittuvat Englannin maaseudulle. Eliot käytti kirjailijanimeä tullakseen vakavasti otetuksi – naiskirjailijoita pidettiin usein romantiikan kirjoittajina.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Nuneaton"/>
    <dbpprop:id rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1124</dbpprop:id>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WomenNovelists"/>
    <dbpprop:relatives xml:lang="en">Robert Evans and Christiana Pearson ; Christiana, Isaac, Robert, and Fanny</dbpprop:relatives>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Mary Anne (alternatively Mary Ann or Marian) Evans (22 November 1819 – 22 December 1880), better known by her pen name George Eliot, was an English novelist, journalist and translator, and one of the leading writers of the Victorian era. She is the author of seven novels, including Adam Bede (1859), The Mill on the Floss (1860), Silas Marner (1861), Middlemarch (1871–72), and Daniel Deronda (1876), most of them set in provincial England and well known for their realism and psychological insight. She used a male pen name, she said, to ensure her works would be taken seriously. Female authors were published under their own names during Eliot's life, but she wanted to escape the stereotype of women only writing lighthearted romances. An additional factor in her use of a pen name may have been a desire to shield her private life from public scrutiny and to prevent scandals attending her relationship with the married George Henry Lewes, with whom she lived for over 20 years. Her 1872 work, Middlemarch, has been described as the greatest novel in the English language by Martin Amis and by Julian Barnes.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">George Eliot</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Christopher_Hitchens"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jane_Austen"/>
    <dbpprop:pseudonym xml:lang="en">George Eliot</dbpprop:pseudonym>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1880-12-22</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://webscript.princeton.edu/~geliot/eliot-texts/eliot-rationalism.html"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Margaret_Atwood"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Virginia_Woolf"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Norman_Mailer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marcel_Proust"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">瑪麗·安妮·「瑪麗安」或「瑪麗安」艾凡斯（Mary Anne「Mary Ann」Or「Marian」 Evans，1819年11月22日－1880年12月22日），筆名喬治·艾略特（George Eliot），是一位英國小説家。她的作品包括《佛羅斯河畔上的磨坊》（1860年）和《中間進行曲》（1871年－1872年）等。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ジョージ・エリオット"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118529846</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Eliot"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.archive.org/details/essencechristia01eliogoog"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Mary Ann (Marian) Evansová, v literatuře známá pod pseudonymem George Eliot, byla anglická spisovatelka, novinářka a překladatelka, jedna z nejvýznamnějších autorek viktoriánského období. Ve své době pobouřila veřejnost nelegitimním vztahem se spisovatelem a Goethovým životopiscem Georgem Henry Lewesem. První její prací byly překlady německých filozofů Davida Strausse a Ludwiga Feuerbacha, o kterých se tenkrát velmi diskutovalo. Eliotová procestovala velkou část Evropy. V roce 1851 přijala místo kritičky v londýnských novinách Westmister Review. Lewes podporoval její literární tvorbu a přesvědčil ji, aby se pokusila psát beletrii. Její první román obdivoval i Charles Dickens. Tušil, že autorem tohoto románu je žena. Její romány se vyznačují hlubokou prokresleností postav a co do příběhů jsou velmi komplexní a realistické. Mezi její nejvýznamnější a také nejznámější dílo patří obsáhlý román Middlemarch. Tvrdila, že používá jako pseudonym mužské jméno, aby si zajistila, že její díla budou brána vážně. Nechtěla být vnímána jen jako autorka jednoduchých romantických příběhů, se kterými by byla spojována, jak se domnívala, kdyby publikovala pod svým vlastním ženským jménem. Dalším důvodem mohla být také snaha zabránit nežádoucí publicitě a ochránit si své soukromí.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Female_authors_who_wrote_under_male_or_gender-neutral_pseudonyms"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://webscript.princeton.edu/~geliot/eliot-texts/eliot-threemonthsinweimar.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">George Eliot was het pseudoniem van de Engelse schrijfster en dichteres Mary Ann Evans. Ze was ook journalist en vertaler en behoort tot de toonaangevende schrijvers van het Victoriaans tijdperk.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Burials_at_Highgate_Cemetery"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://athenaeum.soi.city.ac.uk/aboutath.html"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WomenOfTheVictorianEra"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.03d_m"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=4MopnRJ-HmMC&amp;pg=PA654&amp;dq=broadview+middlemarch+ruskin+review&amp;hl=en&amp;ei=MA6qTefUI4HZgAf65Y30BQ&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;ct=result&amp;resnum=1&amp;ved=0CC4Q6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;q=ruskin&amp;f=false."/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">George Eliot</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">George Eliot era o pseudônimo de Mary Ann Evans, uma novelista autodidata britânica. O seu primeiro trabalho literário, de 1844, foi a tradução da Vida de Jesus de David Strauss. O tema principal dos seus romances, como em Silas Marner, é a vida das pessoas simples, que retrata com uma sensibilidade reconhecida por várias gerações de leitores. Desenvolveu o método da análise psicológico característico da ficção moderna. Seu Middlemarch (1872) é considerado um dos maiores romances do século XIX.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:alternativeNames xml:lang="en">Eliot, George</dbpprop:alternativeNames>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Gutenberg_author"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Mary Anne Evans, được biết đến phổ biến với bút danh George Eliot, là một nhà văn tiểu thuyết người Anh. Bà là một trong những nhà văn tiên phong của thời đại Victoria. Những tiểu thuyết của bà, phản ánh đời sống trung lưu tại miền nông thôn nước Anh, nổi tiếng với những mô tả hiện thực đơn giản, tình cảm, tâm lí, sự hiểu biết. George Eliot sử dụng bút danh nam cho các tác phẩm, như bà đã từng nói, để đảm bảo rằng tác phẩm của bà được chú trọng.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfRoyalHolloway,UniversityOfLondon"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Norman_Mailer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Mary Anne Evans, được biết đến phổ biến với bút danh George Eliot, là một nhà văn tiểu thuyết người Anh. Bà là một trong những nhà văn tiên phong của thời đại Victoria. Những tiểu thuyết của bà, phản ánh đời sống trung lưu tại miền nông thôn nước Anh, nổi tiếng với những mô tả hiện thực đơn giản, tình cảm, tâm lí, sự hiểu biết. George Eliot sử dụng bút danh nam cho các tác phẩm, như bà đã từng nói, để đảm bảo rằng tác phẩm của bà được chú trọng. Dù những nhà văn nữ có thể xuất bản thoải mái dưới tên của họ, như Eliot muốn đảm bảo rằng mình không bị coi là một nhà văn lãng mạn đơn thuần. Chính yếu tố bổ sung này có thể đã bảo vệ bà khỏi sự xoi mói vào đời sống riêng tư, và bảo vệ bà khỏi những scandal liên quan tới người chồng George Henry Lewes.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Highgate_Cemetery"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">I suoi romanzi sono ambientati prevalentemente nella provincia inglese e sono famosi per il loro stile realista e la loro perspicacia psicologica. Mary Anne usa uno pseudonimo a partire dalla sua prima opera narrativa, "Scenes of Clerical Life"; a differenza di altre scrittrici a lei contemporanee o precedenti (per esempio, le sorelle Bronte), la Evans utilizza un pen-name non tanto per ragioni sociali, quanto per vezzo. Sebbene all'epoca le donne scrittrici non fossero ben viste, Mary Anne Evans proveniva da un rango sociale elevato, era la compagna dell'editore e intellettuale George Henry Lewes e la sua formazione ed esperienza era già ben nota al pubblico e tanto apprezzata da non aver alcun bisogno di nascondersi dietro a un falso nome.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://webscript.princeton.edu/~geliot/eliot-texts/eliot-naturalhistoryofgermanlife.html"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Virginia_Woolf"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_people_of_Welsh_descent"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_Royal_Holloway,_University_of_London"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FemaleAuthorsWhoWroteUnderMaleOrGender-neutralPseuDonyms"/>
    <dbpprop:imagesize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">250</dbpprop:imagesize>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Mary Anne</foaf:givenName>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marcel_Proust"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace xml:lang="en">South Farm, Arbury Hall, Nuneaton, Warwickshire, England</dbpprop:birthPlace>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://nrs.harvard.edu/urn-3:FHCL.HOUGH:5340370"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Honor%C3%A9_de_Balzac"/>
    <dbpprop:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1880-12-22</dbpprop:deathDate>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Aged 30 by the Swiss artist Alexandre Louis François d'Albert Durade</dbpprop:caption>
    <dbpprop:spouse xml:lang="en">John Cross</dbpprop:spouse>
    <dbpprop:notableworks xml:lang="en">The Mill on the Floss , Silas Marner , Middlemarch , Daniel Deronda</dbpprop:notableworks>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">George Eliot was het pseudoniem van de Engelse schrijfster en dichteres Mary Ann Evans. Ze was ook journalist en vertaler en behoort tot de toonaangevende schrijvers van het Victoriaans tijdperk.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">George Eliot (oik. Mary Ann Evans) oli englantilainen kirjailija. Hän oli 1800-luvun loppupuolen huomattavimpia kirjailijoita. Eliotin realistiset romaanit, ennen kaikkea Middlemarch, sijoittuvat Englannin maaseudulle. Eliot käytti kirjailijanimeä tullakseen vakavasti otetuksi – naiskirjailijoita pidettiin usein romantiikan kirjoittajina.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Chelsea,_London"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:19th-century_women_writers"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">George Eliot</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_writer"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/조지_엘리엇"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">瑪麗·安妮·「瑪麗安」或「瑪麗安」艾凡斯（Mary Anne「Mary Ann」Or「Marian」 Evans，1819年11月22日－1880年12月22日），筆名喬治·艾略特（George Eliot），是一位英國小説家。她的作品包括《佛羅斯河畔上的磨坊》（1860年）和《中間進行曲》（1871年－1872年）等。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.litencyc.com/php/speople.php?rec=true&amp;UID=1408"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Victorian_women_writers"/>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">Novelist</dc:description>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1819-11-22</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ジョージ・エリオット（George Eliot 1819年11月22日 - 1880年12月22日）は、イギリスの女流作家のペンネーム。本名はメアリー・アン [メアリ・アン メアリ・アン]（Mary Anne [Mary Ann]）あるいは[マリアン マリアン]・エバンス（[Marian Marian] Evans）。ウォリックシャー出身。代表作は「サイラス・マーナー」、「ミドルマーチ」など。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/81/George_Eliot_at_30_by_François_D'Albert_Durade.jpg/200px-George_Eliot_at_30_by_François_D'Albert_Durade.jpg"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/PersonWithOccupation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">George Eliot, właśc. Mary Ann Evans (ur. 22 listopada 1819 w South Farm Arbury – angielska pisarka należąca do czołowych twórców epoki wiktoriańskiej. Autorka siedmiu powieści, cechujących się realizmem i przenikliwością psychologiczną; ich akcja rozgrywa się w najczęściej prowincjonalnej Anglii. Pisała także wiersze i inne utwory. W słowniku języka angielskiego Oxford English Dictionary jest najczęściej cytowaną kobietą-pisarką. Zaczerpnięto z jej utworów liczne przykłady ilustrujące zastosowanie angielskich słów.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">George Eliot</foaf:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Charlotte_Bront%C3%AB"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.archive.org/details/lifeofjesuscriti02stra"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">South Farm, Arbury, near Nuneaton</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Miguel_de_Cervantes"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Evans, Mary Anne</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.archive.org/details/lifeofjesuscriti01stra"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1819_births"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableWork rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Middlemarch"/>
    <dbpprop:partner rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Henry_Lewes"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Gutenberg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">조지 엘리엇은 영국의 여류 소설가이다. 본명은 메리 앤 에번스 (Mary Anne Evans)이다. 영국 중부의 워릭셔에서 출생. 부친은 건축가였다가 지주를 위한 토지관리인이 되었다. 부친은 견실한 성격을 가졌고, 엘리엇의 소설인 &lt;아덤 비드&gt;(1859)의 아덤을 위시하여 자주 다른 곳에도 그녀의 부친을 모델로 하는 인물이 등장한다. 소녀 시절의 그녀는 복음주의의 열렬한 신봉자였으나 차차로 당시의 새 사상에 접촉하여 과학주의·실증주의에 입각한 사상을 품게 되어 기독교를 떠난다. 그러나 그녀의 도덕관을 이루는 기저(基底)에는 종교적인 심정이 일생을 일관하고 있다. 1854년 이후에 처자가 있는 조지 루이스와 동거생활을 하게 되어 세상의 비난을 받았으나 조지 엘리엇이란 이름으로 &lt;플로스강(江)의 물레방아&gt;(1860), &lt;미들마치&gt;(1872) 등의 걸작을 내면서 작가로서 그녀의 위치는 부동한 것이 된다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1819-11-22</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/81/George_Eliot_at_30_by_François_D'Albert_Durade.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Margaret_Atwood"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.victorianweb.org/authors/eliot/index.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">George Eliot es el seudónimo que empleó la escritora británica Mary Anne Evans.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">George Eliot</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">George Eliot, eigentlich Mary Anne Evans, war eine englische Schriftstellerin, Übersetzerin und Journalistin, die zu den erfolgreichsten Autoren des viktorianischen Zeitalters zählt. Romane wie Middlemarch und Die Mühle am Floss gehören zu den Klassikern englischer Literatur.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishEssayists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthName xml:lang="en">Mary Anne Evans</dbpedia-owl:birthName>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishNovelists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://webscript.princeton.edu/~geliot/eliot-texts/eliot-sillynovels.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">George Eliot, pseudonym för Mary Ann Evans, född 22 november 1819 nära Nuneaton, Warwickshire, död 22 december 1880 i Chelsea, London, var en brittisk romanförfattare, estetiker.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/George_Eliot"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Джордж_Элиот"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/research/fa/eliot.html"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">George Eliot</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Τζορτζ_Έλιοτ"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Evans</foaf:surname>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Eliot?oldid=494530196"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/printable/6794"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Джордж Элиот — английская писательница. Ошибка: неверное или отсутствующее изображение В этой статье не хватает ссылок на источники информации. Информация должна быть проверяема, иначе она может быть поставлена под сомнение и удалена. Вы можете отредактировать эту статью, добавив ссылки на авторитетные источники. Эта отметка стоит на статье с 6 октября 2011.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Christopher_Hitchens"/>
    <dbpprop:birthName xml:lang="en">Mary Anne Evans</dbpprop:birthName>
    <dbpprop:restingPlace xml:lang="en">Highgate Cemetery , Highgate, London</dbpprop:restingPlace>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">Novelist</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">George Eliot, eigentlich Mary Anne Evans, war eine englische Schriftstellerin, Übersetzerin und Journalistin, die zu den erfolgreichsten Autoren des viktorianischen Zeitalters zählt. Romane wie Middlemarch und Die Mühle am Floss gehören zu den Klassikern englischer Literatur.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">乔治·艾略特</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">I suoi romanzi sono ambientati prevalentemente nella provincia inglese e sono famosi per il loro stile realista e la loro perspicacia psicologica. Mary Anne usa uno pseudonimo a partire dalla sua prima opera narrativa, "Scenes of Clerical Life"; a differenza di altre scrittrici a lei contemporanee o precedenti (per esempio, le sorelle Bronte), la Evans utilizza un pen-name non tanto per ragioni sociali, quanto per vezzo.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cheyne_Walk"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/George_Eliot"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1880_deaths"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">George Eliot, pseudonym för Mary Ann Evans, född 22 november 1819 nära Nuneaton, Warwickshire, död 22 december 1880 i Chelsea, London, var en brittisk romanförfattare, estetiker.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Highgate"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableWork rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Mill_on_the_Floss"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Mary Anne Evans, més coneguda pel pseudònim George Eliot, fou una novel·lista, periodista i traductora anglesa. Una de les millors plomes de l'època victoriana, és autora de set novel·les, la majoria situades a l'Anglaterra provinciana i conegudes pel seu realisme i l'anàlisi psicològica.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ジョージ・エリオット（George Eliot 1819年11月22日 - 1880年12月22日）は、イギリスの女流作家のペンネーム。本名はメアリー・アン [メアリ・アン メアリ・アン]（Mary Anne [Mary Ann]）あるいは[マリアン マリアン]・エバンス（[Marian Marian] Evans）。ウォリックシャー出身。代表作は「サイラス・マーナー」、「ミドルマーチ」など。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jane_Austen"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Miguel_de_Cervantes"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_novelists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.kirjasto.sci.fi/gelliot.htm"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/gutendata/resource/people/Eliot_George_1819-1880"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">George Eliot era o pseudônimo de Mary Ann Evans, uma novelista autodidata britânica. O seu primeiro trabalho literário, de 1844, foi a tradução da Vida de Jesus de David Strauss. O tema principal dos seus romances, como em Silas Marner, é a vida das pessoas simples, que retrata com uma sensibilidade reconhecida por várias gerações de leitores. Desenvolveu o método da análise psicológico característico da ficção moderna. Seu Middlemarch (1872) é considerado um dos maiores romances do século XIX. Faleceu em 22 de dezembro de 1880. Encontra-se sepultada no Cemitério de Highgate, Grande Londres na Inglaterra.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Novelist</dbpprop:occupation>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1819-11-22</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">George Eliot, de son vrai nom Mary Anne Evans, est une romancière britannique née le 22 novembre 1819 à Nuneaton et morte le 22 décembre 1880 à Londres. Elle est considérée comme un des plus grands écrivains victoriens, tous sexes confondus. Ses romans, qui se situent dans une Angleterre provinciale, sont connus pour leur réalisme et leur profondeur psychologique. Elle prit un nom de plume à consonance masculine afin que son œuvre soit prise au sérieux. Bien que les auteurs féminins de cette période aient pu publier librement sous leur vrai nom, l'usage d'un nom masculin lui aurait permis de s'assurer que ses œuvres ne soient pas perçues comme de simples romans d'amour. Le fait d'avoir voulu préserver sa vie privée des curiosités du public et de sa relation scandaleuse avec George Henry Lewes pourrait aussi avoir influencé cette décision.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Artist"/>
    <dbpprop:no rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">17954</dbpprop:no>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">The Life of George Eliot ''by John Morley'</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-writer-noun-1"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
