<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VIII_of_England">
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">헨리 8세는 잉글랜드의 국왕이자 아일랜드의 영주이며, 1509년 4월 21일부터 서거할 때까지 아일랜드와 프랑스의 왕위 소유권을 주장하였다. 그의 아버지 헨리 7세의 뒤를 이어 튜더 왕가 출신으로는 두 번째로 등극하였다. 헨리 8세는 영국의 역사에 있어서 매우 중요한 인물 가운데 한 명이다. 비록 치세 초반기에는 14세기 존 위클리프 이후 활력을 얻기 시작한 종교개혁을 강력히 억압하였지만, 로마 교황청과 대립한 왕으로 더 알려졌다. 이 싸움은 결국 헨리 8세가 종교개혁을 단행하여 6세기 이래 로마 가톨릭의 지배를 받던 잉글랜드 교회를 독립시키고, 로마 교황 대신 잉글랜드 국왕이 잉글랜드 교회의 우두머리로 자리 잡는 결과를 가져오게 된다.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/45/Henry-VIII-kingofengland_1491-1547.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ヘンリー8世（Henry VIII, 1491年6月28日 - 1547年1月28日）は、テューダー朝のイングランド王（在位：1509年4月22日（戴冠は6月24日） - 1547年1月28日）、アイルランド王（在位（自称）：1541年 - 1547年）。イングランド王ヘンリー7世の次男。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.luminarium.org/renlit/tudorbio.htm"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_royalty"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Greenwich"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvfrkZpwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Sovereign110628644"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Генрих VIII Тюдор — король Англии с 22 апреля 1509, сын и наследник короля Генриха VII, второй английский монарх из династии Тюдоров. С согласия Римской католической церкви, английские короли именовались также «Повелителями Ирландии», однако в 1541 году, по требованию отлучённого от католической церкви Генриха VIII, ирландский парламент наделил его титулом «Король Ирландии». Образованный и одарённый, Генрих правил как представитель европейского абсолютизма, к концу царствования жёстко преследовал своих действительных и мнимых политических оппонентов. В поздние годы страдал от лишнего веса и других проблем со здоровьем. Генрих VIII больше всего известен Английской Реформацией, что сделало Англию в большинстве своем протестантской нацией; и необычным для христианина числом браков — всего у короля было 6 жён, из которых с двумя он развёлся, а двух казнил по обвинению в измене. Король стремился произвести на свет наследника мужского пола для консолидации власти династии Тюдоров. Развод Генриха VIII с его первой супругой, Екатериной Арагонской, повлек за собой отлучение короля от католической церкви и ряд церковных реформ в Англии, когда англиканская церковь отделилась от римской католической. Кроме того, постоянная смена супруг и фавориток короля и церковная реформация оказались серьёзной ареной для политической борьбы и привели к ряду казней политических деятелей, среди которых был, например, Томас Мор.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1547-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=oEy_3aDT61sC&amp;vid=OCLC02338418&amp;dq=%22%09Luther%27s+Correspondence+and+Other+Contemporary+Letters%22&amp;jtp=333"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:WIMA"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Enrico_VIII_d'Inghilterra"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Annulment"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Palace of Placentia, Greenwich</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.luminarium.org/renlit/vallieres.htm"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Henri VIII est roi d'Angleterre de 1509 à 1547. La controverse juridique et théologique relative à la validité de son premier mariage et surtout celle, interminable, autour de son annulation entraîneront des conséquences religieuses, politiques et diplomatiques considérables. D'abord privée, la question prit une importance européenne majeure à la fin des années 1520 et fit basculer l'Angleterre dans l'anglicanisme, à la suite de la rupture avec Rome et le catholicisme romain.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Генріх VIII Тюдор — король Англії з 1509 року, успадкував трон від свого батька Генріха VII, одружився з Катериною Арагонською, вдовою свого брата. У період з 1513 по 1529 рік Генріх розвивав зовнішню політику під керівництвом свого лорда-канцлера кардинала Уолсі, якого замінив Томас Мор в 1529 — після того, як Уолсі не вдалося домогтися в Папи Римського Климента VII дозволу для Генріха на розлучення. Після 1532 Генріх розірвав відносини з папством, оголосив себе главою англійської церкви, розпустив монастирі і розлучився з Катериною Арагонською. Пізніше він був одружений з: Анною Болейн (страчена), Джейн Сеймур (померла), Анною Клевською (розлучена), Катериною Говард (страчена) і Катериною Парр. Трон успадкував його син Едуард VI. Виступав проти реформації, але пізніше, усвідомивши, що йому потрібен спадкоємець, виступив за реформацію.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_monarchs"/>
    <dbpprop:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1547-01-28</dbpprop:deathDate>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Генріх VIII (король Англії)</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/97615501?title=Henry%20VIII%20and%20the%20English%20Reformation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Palace_of_Whitehall"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Greenwich"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/St_George's_Chapel,_Windsor_Castle"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Henry VIII</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=q4Y9AAAAcAAJ"/>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Duke_of_Cornwall"/>
    <dbpprop:house rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tudor_dynasty"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://tudorhistory.org/wives/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/RenaissanceComposers"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Jindřich_VIII._Tudor"/>
    <dbpprop:issue rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Elizabeth_I_of_England"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_VIII_of_England"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Enric VIII va ser rei d'Anglaterra i senyor d’Irlanda des del 22 d'abril de 1509 fins a la seva mort. Va ser el segon monarca de la casa Tudor, fill d'Enric VII i Elisabet de York. Famós per haver-se casat sis vegades i per exercir el poder més absolut entre tots els monarques anglesos. Entre els fets més notables del seu regnat s'inclou la seva ruptura amb la Església Catòlica Romana, i el seu establiment com cap de l’Església d'Anglaterra (Església Anglicana), la dissolució dels monestirs, i la unió d'Anglaterra amb Gal·les. També va promulgar legislacions importants, com les diverses actes de separació amb l'Església de Roma, de la seva designació com cap suprem de l'Església d'Anglaterra, les Union Acts de 1535 i 1542, que van unificar a Anglaterra i Gal·les com una sola nació, la Buggery Act de 1533, primera legislació contra la sodomia a Anglaterra, la Witchcraft Act de 1542, que castigava amb la mort la bruixeria. Va ser un àvid apostador i jugador de daus. En la seva joventut va practicar, esports com justes, caça i royal tennis, avantpassat de l'actual tennis. Va ser també un músic complet, escriptor i poeta. També es va involucrar en la reconstrucció i millorament de diversos edificis importants, com el Palau Nonsuch, la capella del King's College a Cambridge, i l’Abadia de Westminster a Londres. En molts casos es tractava d'edificis confiscats, per exemple al Cardenal Thomas Wolsey, entre ells Christ Church a Oxford, el palau de Hampton Court, el palau de Whitehall i el Trinity College a Cambridge. La protecció que va dispensar al pintor alemany Hans Holbein es va traduir en una formidable sèrie de retrats i dibuixos a color, que efigien a molts personatges de la Cort d'aquella època. Destaca la efígie del propi Enric VIII, del Museu Thyssen-Bornemisza.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lord_Warden_of_the_Cinque_Ports"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1491_births"/>
    <dbpprop:after rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edward_VI_of_England"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/BritishRoyalty"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Henryk_VIII_Tudor"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:parent rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VII_of_England"/>
    <dbpprop:spouses rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jane_Seymour"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:successor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edward_VI_of_England"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Henrik VIII av England (engelsk Henry VIII) var konge av England og Lord av Irland (senere konge av Irland) fra 22. april 1509 til sin død. Han er mest kjent for å ha utløst den engelske reformasjon og for sine mange ekteskap. Han ble tronarving etter at hans eldre bror Arthur, prins av Wales døde i 1502. Henrik VIII ble beryktet på grunn av sine kvinnehistorier og han kunne visstnok til tider være tyrannisk, men han regnes også som en sterk monark som hadde folkets støtte.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">VIII. Henrik angol király, VII. Henrik angol király fia. Az angol történelem egyik legkülönlegesebb szereplője volt. Az ő uralkodása alatt vált le az anglikán egyház a katolikus egyházról, záratták be a kolostorokat Angliában, s ő lett az új egyház feje is. Széles körben ismert arról is, hogy hat felesége volt, akik közül kettőt lefejeztetett.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsEndYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1547-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsEndYear>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Princes_of_Wales"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.uni-mannheim.de/mateo/camenaref/cmh/cmh213.html"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Henry VIII của Anh</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Lords_Warden_of_the_Cinque_Ports"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Henryk VIII – król Anglii od 21 kwietnia 1509 do końca życia, lord Irlandii w latach 1494–1542, następnie król Irlandii 1542–1547. Drugi monarcha z dynastii Tudorów (po swoim ojcu, Henryku VII). Doprowadził w latach 20. i 30. XVI wieku do rozłamu z Kościołem rzymskokatolickim oraz ustanowienia niezależnego Kościoła anglikańskiego; za jego panowania dokonano kasaty klasztorów. Zasłynął sześcioma małżeństwami oraz ścinaniem niektórych swoich małżonek.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:spouses rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Anne_Boleyn"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Henrique VIII de Inglaterra foi rei de Inglaterra a partir de 21 de abril de 1509 até à sua morte. Foi-lhe concedido o título de rei da Irlanda pelo Parlamento Irlandês em 1541, tendo obtido anteriormente o título de Lorde da Irlanda. Foi o segundo monarca da dinastia Tudor, sucedendo a seu pai, Henrique VII, e pretendente ao trono francês. Henrique VIII foi uma figura marcante na História, ficando famoso por se ter casado seis vezes e por ter exercido o poder mais absoluto de entre todos os monarcas ingleses. Entre os fatos mais relevantes de seu reinado se inclui a ruptura com a Igreja Católica Romana e seu estabelecimento como líder da Igreja da Inglaterra (ou Igreja Anglicana), a dissolução dos monastérios, e a união da Inglaterra com Gales. Também promulgou legislações importantes, como as várias atas de separação com a Igreja de Roma, de sua designação como Chefe Supremo da Igreja de Inglaterra, as Union Acts de 1535 e 1542, que unificaram a Inglaterra e Gales como uma só nação, a Buggery Act de 1533, primeira legislação contra a sodomia na Inglaterra, a Witchcraft Act de 1542, que castigava com a morte a bruxaria, "por invocar ou conjurar a um espírito demoníaco".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Burials_at_St_George's_Chapel,_Windsor_Castle"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ヘンリー8世_(イングランド王)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/2993196?title=The%20Tudor%20Revolution%20in%20Government%3a%20Administrative%20Changes%20in%20the%20Reign%20of%20Henry%20VIII"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Henri VIII est roi d'Angleterre de 1509 à 1547. La controverse juridique et théologique relative à la validité de son premier mariage et surtout celle, interminable, autour de son annulation entraîneront des conséquences religieuses, politiques et diplomatiques considérables. D'abord privée, la question prit une importance européenne majeure à la fin des années 1520 et fit basculer l'Angleterre dans l'anglicanisme, à la suite de la rupture avec Rome et le catholicisme romain. Les difficultés économiques du règne sont venues surdéterminer et aggraver le conflit, qui déboucha régulièrement sur une violence politique sanglante souvent arbitraire. Celle-ci toucha indistinctement jusqu'aux plus hauts échelons de l'État et de la société : la condamnation à mort était la sanction courante de la défaveur royale. Les préoccupations dynastiques d'Henri VIII, deuxième monarque de la jeune Maison Tudor qui venait de mettre un terme à la guerre des Deux-Roses, l'amenèrent à contracter six mariages, dont deux se terminèrent par la mise à mort de l'épouse rejetée. Pourtant, chacun de ses trois enfants légitimes lui succède sur le trône d'Angleterre.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Ερρίκος_Η'_της_Αγγλίας"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.co.uk/books?id=it1CAAAAIAAJ&amp;source=gbs_navlinks_s"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Royalty"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/DukesOfCornwall"/>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Prince_of_Wales"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/PersonWithOccupation"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.03p77"/>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Monarchy_of_Ireland"/>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">King of England</dc:description>
    <dbpprop:signature xml:lang="en">HenryVIIISig.svg</dbpprop:signature>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.amazon.com/dp/069401043X"/>
    <dbpprop:spouses rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catherine_Howard"/>
    <dbpprop:predecessor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VII_of_England"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Enric VIII va ser rei d'Anglaterra i senyor d’Irlanda des del 22 d'abril de 1509 fins a la seva mort. Va ser el segon monarca de la casa Tudor, fill d'Enric VII i Elisabet de York. Famós per haver-se casat sis vegades i per exercir el poder més absolut entre tots els monarques anglesos.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Jindřich VIII. Tudor byl král Anglie a Irska a uchazeč o trůn Francie od 21. dubna 1509 až do své smrti. Byl následníkem Jindřicha VII. a druhý anglický panovník z rodu Tudorovců. Jindřich VIII. byl významnou postavou anglické historie. I když větší část svého vládnutí strávil surovým potlačováním protestantské reformace, je známější pro politické spory s římskokatolickou církví. Tyto rozpory nakonec vedly k odloučení anglické církve, rušení klášterů a ustanovení anglického panovníka jako nejvyššího představeného církve v Anglii. Podporu panovníka získala reformace v Anglii za vlády jeho následníka Eduarda VI. a Alžběty I. , když jeho dcera Marie přechodně obnovila v zemi vliv papeže. Jindřich také zajistil právní spojení Anglie a Walesu a je věhlasný tím, že měl šest žen a dvě z nich byly popraveny.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Henry VIII of England</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Henryk VIII – król Anglii od 21 kwietnia 1509 do końca życia, lord Irlandii w latach 1494–1542, następnie król Irlandii 1542–1547. Drugi monarcha z dynastii Tudorów (po swoim ojcu, Henryku VII). Doprowadził w latach 20. i 30. XVI wieku do rozłamu z Kościołem rzymskokatolickim oraz ustanowienia niezależnego Kościoła anglikańskiego; za jego panowania dokonano kasaty klasztorów. Zasłynął sześcioma małżeństwami oraz ścinaniem niektórych swoich małżonek. Znaczące akty prawne uchwalone za jego panowania kilka ustaw rozdzielających Kościół anglikański od Kościoła katolickiego oraz ustanawiających Henryka VIII głową Kościoła anglikańskiego; Akty Unii 1536–1543 (łączące Anglię i Walię w jeden naród); Dekret o Sodomii (tzw. Buggery Act) 1533 – pierwsze angielskie prawo przeciw sodomii; Ustawa o Czarach (tzw. Witchcraft Act) 1542 – karząca śmiercią za "wywoływanie lub wyczarowywanie złych duchów". Henryk znany był jako chciwy karciarz i gracz w kości. W młodości celował w sporcie – zwłaszcza w tenisie, lubił polowania. Był także utalentowanym muzykiem, kompozytorem i poetą; legenda przypisuje mu autorstwo popularnej piosenki "Greensleeves". Za napisanie popularnego (ok. 20 wydań w Anglii i Europie) traktatu poddającego krytyce nauki Marcina Lutra w 1521 otrzymał od papieża tytuł "obrońcy wiary". Za jego panowania wybudowano i uświetniono kilka budowli, takich jak kaplica King’s College, kościół Christ Church, Oxford, Pałac Hampton Court, Pałac Nonsuch oraz Opactwo Westminsterskie. Inwestował we flotę, zwiększył liczbę okrętów z 5 do 53 (w tym "Mary Rose", której pozostałości znajdują się w Muzeum Morskim w Portsmouth).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_Anglicans"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=oEy_3aDT61sC&amp;vid=OCLC02338418&amp;dq=%22%09Luther%27s+Correspondence+and+Other+Contemporary+Letters%22&amp;jtp=374"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Earls_Marshal"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1491-06-28</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Heinrich VIII. Tudor, englisch Henry Tudor und walisisch Harri Tewdwr oder Tudur König von England und Irland, war der zweite Herrscher des Hauses Tudor, das mit der Eheschließung zwischen seinem Vater Heinrich VII. und seiner Mutter Elizabeth of York das Ende der englischen Rosenkriege herbeigeführt hatte. Nach dem plötzlichen Tod seines älteren Bruders Arthur im Jahr 1502 wurde der zehnjährige Heinrich unerwartet Thronerbe. Seine Thronbesteigung am 21.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Henry_VIII_of_England"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/RoyalFamily"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Male_Shakespearean_characters"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=q0cDAAAAMAAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=intitle:henry+intitle:viii+inauthor:pollard&amp;lr=&amp;as_brr=0"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Military_leaders_of_the_Italian_Wars"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PrincesOfWales"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.jstor.org/stable/2640109"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=Udk9AAAAcAAJ"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.liverpoolmuseums.org.uk/walker/exhibitions/henry/default.asp"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/6981860?title=Divorced%2c%20Beheaded%2c%20Survived%3a%20A%20Feminist%20Reinterpretation%20of%20the%20Wives%20of%20Henry%20VIII"/>
    <dbpprop:succession xml:lang="en">King of England and Ireland</dbpprop:succession>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Greenwich"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Knights_of_the_Garter"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Henry VIII of England</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.amazon.com/dp/034543708X/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Enrique VIII fue rey de Inglaterra y señor de Irlanda desde el 22 de abril de 1509 hasta su muerte. Fue el segundo monarca de la casa Tudor, descendiente de su padre, Enrique VII. Famoso por haberse casado seis veces y por ejercer el poder más absoluto entre todos los monarcas ingleses. Entre los hechos más notables de su reinado se incluye su ruptura con la Iglesia Católica Romana, y su establecimiento como cabeza de la Iglesia de Inglaterra (Iglesia Anglicana), la disolución de los monasterios, y la unión de Inglaterra con Gales. También promulgó legislaciones importantes, como las varias actas de separación con la Iglesia de Roma, de su designación como cabeza suprema de la Iglesia de Inglaterra, las Union Acts de 1535 y 1542, que unificaron a Inglaterra y Gales como una sola nación, la Buggery Act de 1533, primera legislación contra la sodomía en Inglaterra, la Witchcraft Act de 1542, que castigaba con la muerte la brujería. La protección que dispensó al pintor alemán Hans Holbein se tradujo en una formidable serie de retratos y dibujos en color, que efigian a muchos personajes de la Corte de aquella época. Destaca la efigie del propio Enrique VIII, del Museo Thyssen-Bornemisza.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/KnightsOfTheGoldenFleece"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Hendrik VIII was koning van Engeland, Heer van Ierland en later ook koning van Ierland. Hij stamde uit het Huis Tudor, en was een zoon van Hendrik VII en van Elizabeth van York. Hendrik staat bekend als het prototype van de zelfbewuste renaissance-vorst. Hij was intelligent en geïnteresseerd in kunst en wetenschap. Hij werd echter ook beschouwd als liefdeloos, egoïstisch en wreed. Tegenstrevers, echtgenotes of dienaren die hem in de weg stonden ruimde hij meedogenloos uit de weg.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:S-ttl"/>
    <dbpprop:rows rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2</dbpprop:rows>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.amazon.com/dp/1903365996/"/>
    <dbpprop:before rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VII_of_England"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/헨리_8세"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_people_of_Welsh_descent"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Recipients_of_the_Golden_Rose"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/45/Henry-VIII-kingofengland_1491-1547.jpg/200px-Henry-VIII-kingofengland_1491-1547.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/8851653?title=Henry%20VIII%20and%20the%20Reformation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://web.archive.org/web/20070522020910/www.tudor-portraits.com/Henry_VIII.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Hendrik VIII was koning van Engeland, Heer van Ierland en later ook koning van Ierland. Hij stamde uit het Huis Tudor, en was een zoon van Hendrik VII en van Elizabeth van York. Hendrik staat bekend als het prototype van de zelfbewuste renaissance-vorst. Hij was intelligent en geïnteresseerd in kunst en wetenschap. Hij werd echter ook beschouwd als liefdeloos, egoïstisch en wreed. Tegenstrevers, echtgenotes of dienaren die hem in de weg stonden ruimde hij meedogenloos uit de weg. Hendrik was berucht vanwege zijn huwelijksperikelen; hij heeft zes vrouwen gehad, van wie hij er twee liet onthoofden. Tijdens zijn bewind werden Engeland en Wales wettelijk verenigd in één koninkrijk, meer dan twee eeuwen na de verovering van Wales door Engeland. Een nog belangrijker ontwikkeling was de afscheiding van de Anglicaanse Kerk van de Kerk van Rome, vanwege een conflict met de paus over de ontbinding van zijn eerste huwelijk. Hiermee werkte hij onbedoeld de protestantse reformatie in de hand. Hij liet zich in 1511 door paus Julius II betrekken in de Oorlog van de Liga van Kamerijk tegen Frankrijk, waarbij hij in de rug werd aangevallen door Frankrijks bondgenoot Schotland. Hij en vooral zijn echtgenote Catharina van Aragon - die de in Frankrijk vechtende Hendrik "waarnam" - wisten Schotland in 1513 echter een zware nederlaag toe te brengen in de Slag bij Flodden Field. In Frankrijk boekte hij enkele militaire successen, zoals in de slag bij Guinegate (1513).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Enric VIII d'Anglaterra</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/DukesOfYork"/>
    <dbpprop:successor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edward_VI_of_England"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">亨利八世</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:religion xml:lang="en">Christianity</dbpprop:religion>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Enrique VIII fue rey de Inglaterra y señor de Irlanda desde el 22 de abril de 1509 hasta su muerte. Fue el segundo monarca de la casa Tudor, descendiente de su padre, Enrique VII. Famoso por haberse casado seis veces y por ejercer el poder más absoluto entre todos los monarcas ingleses.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_excommunicated_by_the_Roman_Catholic_Church"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Founders_of_English_schools_and_colleges"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Heinrich_VIII._(England)"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MilitaryLeadersOfTheItalianWars"/>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1491-06-28</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:House_of_Tudor"/>
    <dbpprop:issue rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mary_I_of_England"/>
    <dbpprop:issueLink xml:lang="en">#Marriages and issue</dbpprop:issueLink>
    <dbpedia-owl:predecessor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VII_of_England"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishMonarchs"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.luminarium.org/renlit/tudor.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/85955084?title=Henry%20VIII%3a%20The%20Mask%20of%20Royalty"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Генрих_VIII"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/?id=lWUDAAAAQAAJ"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Henry VIII of England</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:issuePipe xml:lang="en">Among others</dbpprop:issuePipe>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Enrico VIII fu il secondo monarca della Dinastia Tudor, succeduto al padre Enrico VII d'Inghilterra. Fu il fondatore della Chiesa Anglicana, nata in seguito allo scisma religioso, quindi alla separazione dalla Chiesa cattolica di Roma. Nei primi tempi fu un fiero oppositore delle teorie di Lutero, e per questo motivo ottenne da Papa Leone X il titolo di Defensor Fidei, ossia "Difensore della fede", titolo che ancora oggi compare sulle monete inglesi con l'acronimo latino DEF. FID..</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.pbs.org/wnet/sixwives/"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Palace_of_Placentia"/>
    <dbpprop:alternativeNames xml:lang="en">Henry Tudor</dbpprop:alternativeNames>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=p2MOt53sCCgC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=intitle:King%27s+intitle:Reformation+inauthor:bernard&amp;lr=&amp;num=30&amp;as_brr=0&amp;sig=WTvpwPbd8txXGzbj0RP3pA9Qut8"/>
    <dbpprop:idx xml:lang="en">Henry_VIII</dbpprop:idx>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleExcommunicatedByTheRomanCatholicChurch"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Генріх VIII Тюдор — король Англії з 1509 року, успадкував трон від свого батька Генріха VII, одружився з Катериною Арагонською, вдовою свого брата. У період з 1513 по 1529 рік Генріх розвивав зовнішню політику під керівництвом свого лорда-канцлера кардинала Уолсі, якого замінив Томас Мор в 1529 — після того, як Уолсі не вдалося домогтися в Папи Римського Климента VII дозволу для Генріха на розлучення.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBurial rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">4</dbpprop:placeOfBurial>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Henrik VIII oli Englannin kuningas ja Irlannin hallitsija (myöhemmin kuningas) vuosina 1509–1547. Hän oli Tudor-suvun toinen monarkki seuraten valtaistuimelle isäänsä Henrik VII:tä. Hän on kuuluisa kuudesta avioliitostaan sekä siitä, että hänellä oli ehkä enemmän valtaa kuin yhdelläkään muulla englantilaisella monarkilla.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Henrik VIII av England (engelsk Henry VIII) var konge av England og Lord av Irland (senere konge av Irland) fra 22. april 1509 til sin død. Han er mest kjent for å ha utløst den engelske reformasjon og for sine mange ekteskap. Han ble tronarving etter at hans eldre bror Arthur, prins av Wales døde i 1502. Henrik VIII ble beryktet på grunn av sine kvinnehistorier og han kunne visstnok til tider være tyrannisk, men han regnes også som en sterk monark som hadde folkets støtte. Han styrket utenrikspolitikken på bekostning av innenriksaffærer, og sørget for at landet ble en sjømakt. Han skal også ha vært ganske lærd. Han interesserte seg for musikk og spilte selv, og skrev også selv musikk og sangtekster. Den mest kjente av disse er «Pastime with Good Company», også kjent som «The Kynges Ballade». I yngre år var han en dyktig atlet, og drev med dysting, jakt og tennis. Senere ble han svært overvektig, og de siste årene led han av dårlig helse.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:years rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1493</dbpprop:years>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Henry VIII (28 June 1491 – 28 January 1547) was King of England from 21 April 1509 until his death. He was Lord, and later King, of Ireland, as well as continuing the nominal claim by the English monarchs to the Kingdom of France. Henry was the second monarch of the House of Tudor, succeeding his father, Henry VII. Besides his six marriages, Henry VIII is known for his role in the separation of the Church of England from the Roman Catholic Church. Henry's struggles with Rome led to the separation of the Church of England from papal authority, the Dissolution of the Monasteries, and establishing himself as the Supreme Head of the Church of England. Yet he remained a believer in core Catholic theological teachings, even after his excommunication from the Catholic Church. Henry oversaw the legal union of England and Wales with the Laws in Wales Acts 1535–1542. Henry was considered an attractive, educated and accomplished king in his prime and has a reputation as "one of the most charismatic rulers to sit on the English throne". Besides ruling with absolute power, he also engaged himself as an author and composer. His desire to provide England with a male heir—which stemmed partly from personal vanity and partly because he believed a daughter would be unable to consolidate the Tudor Dynasty and the fragile peace that existed following the Wars of the Roses—led to the two things for which Henry is remembered: his six marriages, and the English Reformation, making England a mostly Protestant nation. In later life he became morbidly obese and his health suffered; his public image is frequently depicted as one of a lustful, egotistical, harsh, and insecure king.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:years rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1494</dbpprop:years>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_pretenders_to_the_French_throne"/>
    <dbpprop:issue rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Edward_VI_of_England"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1491</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Henry VIII là vua Anh, Chúa đất Ireland rồi sau đó là vua Ireland, đồng thời cũng giữ danh hiệu vua Pháp. Ông trị vì từ ngày 21 tháng 4 năm 1509 đến khi băng hà ngày 28 tháng 1 năm 1547. Henry VIII là vị quân vương thứ nhì của nhà Tudor, kế vị vua cha Henry VII. Henry VIII là một trong những vị vua nổi tiếng nhất của vương quốc Anh vào thế kỷ 16. Từ năm 1533 đến năm 1540 ông đưa ra nhiều cải cách cho nước Anh. Vua Henry VIII đã được mời đến Roma và thành lập Nhà thờ Anh quốc (Church of England).</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Генрих VIII Тюдор — король Англии с 22 апреля 1509, сын и наследник короля Генриха VII, второй английский монарх из династии Тюдоров. С согласия Римской католической церкви, английские короли именовались также «Повелителями Ирландии», однако в 1541 году, по требованию отлучённого от католической церкви Генриха VIII, ирландский парламент наделил его титулом «Король Ирландии».</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">亨利八世（英语：Henry VIII，1491年6月28日－1547年1月28日），是英格蘭亨利七世次子，都铎王朝第二任国王，1509年4月22日繼位。他也是愛爾蘭領主，後來更成爲愛爾蘭國王。亨利八世為了休妻而另娶新皇后而與當時的羅馬教皇反目，推行宗教改革，並通过一些重要法案，容許自己另娶，並将當時英國主教立為英國國教會大主教，使英国教会脱离罗马教廷，自己成为英格蘭最高宗教领袖，並解散修道院，使英国王室的权力因此达到顶峰。他在位期間，把威尔士并入英格兰。雖然有說亨利八世在離世前成爲新教徒，但是他一生都提倡天主教儀式及教條。他的後裔愛德華六世，以及伊麗莎白一世都繼續推行改革。但是，他的女兒瑪麗一世在位期間曾恢復天主教的地位。亨利八世曾經有六次婚姻，其中有兩個妻子被其下令斬首。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/8546253?title=The%20Earlier%20Tudors%2c%201485-1558"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Renaissance_composers"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Henrik VIII, född 28 juni 1491, död 28 januari 1547, var son till kung Henrik VII av England och dennes drottning Elizabeth av York, yngre bror till kronprins Arthur (som dock avled 2 april 1502 15 år gammal) samt far till efterträdarna Edvard VI, Maria I och Elisabet I. Han blev kung av England 1509, då han efterträdde sin far, som den andre engelske monarken av huset Tudor och förblev kung till sin död.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Enrique_VIII_de_Inglaterra"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">King of England</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Henrique_VIII_de_Inglaterra"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=oEy_3aDT61sC&amp;vid=OCLC02338418&amp;dq=%22%09Luther%27s+Correspondence+and+Other+Contemporary+Letters%22&amp;jtp=160"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Henrique VIII de Inglaterra foi rei de Inglaterra a partir de 21 de abril de 1509 até à sua morte. Foi-lhe concedido o título de rei da Irlanda pelo Parlamento Irlandês em 1541, tendo obtido anteriormente o título de Lorde da Irlanda. Foi o segundo monarca da dinastia Tudor, sucedendo a seu pai, Henrique VII, e pretendente ao trono francês.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Henri_VIII_d'Angleterre"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1547-01-28</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <dbpprop:years rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">21</dbpprop:years>
    <dbpprop:reign rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gMonthDay">--04-21</dbpprop:reign>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Jindřich VIII. Tudor</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1547</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.archsoc.com/games/Henry.html"/>
    <dbpprop:spouses rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catherine_of_Aragon"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:S-aft"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Henrik VIII oli Englannin kuningas ja Irlannin hallitsija (myöhemmin kuningas) vuosina 1509–1547. Hän oli Tudor-suvun toinen monarkki seuraten valtaistuimelle isäänsä Henrik VII:tä. Hän on kuuluisa kuudesta avioliitostaan sekä siitä, että hänellä oli ehkä enemmän valtaa kuin yhdelläkään muulla englantilaisella monarkilla. Hänen tavoitteensa saada avioero ensimmäisestä vaimostaan johti Englannin ja katolisen kirkon välirikkoon, itsenäisen Englannin kirkon perustamiseen ja luostareiden lakkauttamiseen, ja oli siten ensimmäinen vaihe Englannin uskonpuhdistuksessa. Hänen kaudellaan Wales liitettiin pysyväksi osaksi Englannin valtakuntaa. Henrik VIII tunnetaan intohimoisena uhkapelurina. Nuoruudessaan hän menestyi urheilussa, erityisesti keskiaikaisessa "tenniksessä". Hän oli myös taitava muusikko, kirjailija ja runoilija. Lisäksi hän osallistui lukuisien merkittävien rakennusten, mm. Westminster Abbeyn, rakennuttamiseen. »Komein ruhtinas, jonka olen nähnyt; tavallista pitempi mies, lyhyet, suoraksi kammatut kullanruskeat hiukset, ja niin kauniit pyöreät kasvot, että ne sopisivat kauniille naiselle; kaulansa on melko pitkä ja paksu. Hän puhuu ranskaa, englantia ja latinaa, ja vähän italiaa, osaa soittaa luuttua ja harppua ja laulaa nuoteista, jännittää jousen helpommin kuin kukaan mies Englannissa ja turnailee loistavasti. » (Venetsialainen diplomaatti Pasqualigo vuonna 1515)</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:S-bef"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Henry VIII (28 June 1491 – 28 January 1547) was King of England from 21 April 1509 until his death. He was Lord, and later King, of Ireland, as well as continuing the nominal claim by the English monarchs to the Kingdom of France. Henry was the second monarch of the House of Tudor, succeeding his father, Henry VII. Besides his six marriages, Henry VIII is known for his role in the separation of the Church of England from the Roman Catholic Church.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:parent rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Elizabeth_of_York"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Knights_of_the_Golden_Fleece"/>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Earl_Marshal"/>
    <dbpprop:years rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1541</dbpprop:years>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Dukes_of_Cornwall"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ヘンリー8世（Henry VIII, 1491年6月28日 - 1547年1月28日）は、テューダー朝のイングランド王（在位：1509年4月22日（戴冠は6月24日） - 1547年1月28日）、アイルランド王（在位（自称）：1541年 - 1547年）。イングランド王ヘンリー7世の次男。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Henrik VIII, född 28 juni 1491, död 28 januari 1547, var son till kung Henrik VII av England och dennes drottning Elizabeth av York, yngre bror till kronprins Arthur (som dock avled 2 april 1502 15 år gammal) samt far till efterträdarna Edvard VI, Maria I och Elisabet I. Han blev kung av England 1509, då han efterträdde sin far, som den andre engelske monarken av huset Tudor och förblev kung till sin död. Han är känd för att ha varit gift sex gånger och för att vara den brittiske monark som har utövat mest obegränsad makt. Betydelsefulla händelser under hans regeringstid var brytningen med den romersk-katolska kyrkan och den följande etableringen av den självständiga Engelska kyrkan, klosterupplösningen och föreningen av England och Wales till ett rike. Flera viktiga lagar drevs igenom under hans tid vid makten, däribland flera lagar som skilde den engelska kyrkan från den romersk-katolska och gjorde honom till överhuvud för kyrkan i England, lagarna Laws in Wales Acts (1535-1542), som förenade England och Wales till ett rike, Buggery Act 1533, som var den första lagen mot sodomi i England, samt Witchcraft Act (1542), en häxerilag, som bestraffade "åkallande eller frambesvärjande av onda andar" med döden. Henrik är känd för att ha varit en skicklig vadslagare och tärningsspelare. Han var i sin ungdom duktig i flera idrotter, särskilt real tennis. Han var även en duktig musiker, författare och poet. Enligt en legend ska han ha skrivit den populära folksången Greensleeves och även Pastyme With Good Company. Han bidrog till uppförandet och förbättrandet av flera byggnader, däribland King's College Chapel vid universitetet i Cambridge, Christ Church College vid universitetet i Oxford, slottet vid Hampton Court, Nonsuch Palace i Surrey och kyrkan Westminster Abbey i London.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/KnightsOfTheGarter"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Dukes_of_York"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Enrico VIII fu il secondo monarca della Dinastia Tudor, succeduto al padre Enrico VII d'Inghilterra. Fu il fondatore della Chiesa Anglicana, nata in seguito allo scisma religioso, quindi alla separazione dalla Chiesa cattolica di Roma. Nei primi tempi fu un fiero oppositore delle teorie di Lutero, e per questo motivo ottenne da Papa Leone X il titolo di Defensor Fidei, ossia "Difensore della fede", titolo che ancora oggi compare sulle monete inglesi con l'acronimo latino DEF. FID.. In seguito, tuttavia, arrivò ad un insanabile contrasto col Papa. Sposato sei volte e detentore di un potere assoluto incontrastato, segnò fortemente le vicende inglesi. Decretò lo scioglimento dei monasteri e l'unione dell'Inghilterra con il Galles.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:title rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_English_monarchs"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Henry_VIII_of_England?oldid=495388647"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Henry VIII là vua Anh, Chúa đất Ireland rồi sau đó là vua Ireland, đồng thời cũng giữ danh hiệu vua Pháp. Ông trị vì từ ngày 21 tháng 4 năm 1509 đến khi băng hà ngày 28 tháng 1 năm 1547. Henry VIII là vị quân vương thứ nhì của nhà Tudor, kế vị vua cha Henry VII. Henry VIII là một trong những vị vua nổi tiếng nhất của vương quốc Anh vào thế kỷ 16. Từ năm 1533 đến năm 1540 ông đưa ra nhiều cải cách cho nước Anh. Vua Henry VIII đã được mời đến Roma và thành lập Nhà thờ Anh quốc (Church of England).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/104189416"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromGreenwich"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath xml:lang="en">Palace of Whitehall, London</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Henry_VIII_of_England"/>
    <dbpprop:spouses rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catherine_Parr"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Portrait_by_Hans_Holbein_the_younger"/>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace xml:lang="en">Palace of Whitehall, London</dbpprop:deathPlace>
    <dbpprop:years rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1502</dbpprop:years>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118548204</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishComposers"/>
    <dbpprop:issue rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/second">1.0</dbpprop:issue>
    <dbpprop:coronation rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">24</dbpprop:coronation>
    <dbpprop:mother rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Elizabeth_of_York"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishPeopleOfWelshDescent"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">King Henry VIII after Hans Holbein the Younger, Walker Art Gallery, Liverpool</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">VIII. Henrik angol király, VII. Henrik angol király fia. Az angol történelem egyik legkülönlegesebb szereplője volt. Az ő uralkodása alatt vált le az anglikán egyház a katolikus egyházról, záratták be a kolostorokat Angliában, s ő lett az új egyház feje is. Széles körben ismert arról is, hogy hat felesége volt, akik közül kettőt lefejeztetett.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.british-history.ac.uk/catalogue.aspx?type=3&amp;gid=126"/>
    <dbpprop:issue rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry,_Duke_of_Cornwall"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpprop:father rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_VII_of_England"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Former_Roman_Catholics"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://historicalpodcasts.googlepages.com/henryviii"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">亨利八世（英语：Henry VIII，1491年6月28日－1547年1月28日），是英格蘭亨利七世次子，都铎王朝第二任国王，1509年4月22日繼位。他也是愛爾蘭領主，後來更成爲愛爾蘭國王。亨利八世為了休妻而另娶新皇后而與當時的羅馬教皇反目，推行宗教改革，並通过一些重要法案，容許自己另娶，並将當時英國主教立為英國國教會大主教，使英国教会脱离罗马教廷，自己成为英格蘭最高宗教领袖，並解散修道院，使英国王室的权力因此达到顶峰。他在位期間，把威尔士并入英格兰。雖然有說亨利八世在離世前成爲新教徒，但是他一生都提倡天主教儀式及教條。他的後裔愛德華六世，以及伊麗莎白一世都繼續推行改革。但是，他的女兒瑪麗一世在位期間曾恢復天主教的地位。亨利八世曾經有六次婚姻，其中有兩個妻子被其下令斬首。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.historylearningsite.co.uk/henry8.htm"/>
    <dbpprop:spouses rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Anne_of_Cleves"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1547_deaths"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">헨리 8세는 잉글랜드의 국왕이자 아일랜드의 영주이며, 1509년 4월 21일부터 서거할 때까지 아일랜드와 프랑스의 왕위 소유권을 주장하였다. 그의 아버지 헨리 7세의 뒤를 이어 튜더 왕가 출신으로는 두 번째로 등극하였다. 헨리 8세는 영국의 역사에 있어서 매우 중요한 인물 가운데 한 명이다. 비록 치세 초반기에는 14세기 존 위클리프 이후 활력을 얻기 시작한 종교개혁을 강력히 억압하였지만, 로마 교황청과 대립한 왕으로 더 알려졌다. 이 싸움은 결국 헨리 8세가 종교개혁을 단행하여 6세기 이래 로마 가톨릭의 지배를 받던 잉글랜드 교회를 독립시키고, 로마 교황 대신 잉글랜드 국왕이 잉글랜드 교회의 우두머리로 자리 잡는 결과를 가져오게 된다. 비록 그가 임종하기까지 얼마간 영국 성공회 신자였다는 주장도 있고, 헨리 8세가 자신의 첫 번째 부인인 아라곤의 캐서린과의 결혼을 무효로 선언하고 두 번째 부인인 앤 볼린과 결혼하면서 로마 교황청에 의해 파문 당했지만, 그의 생애 대부분 동안 그는 로마 가톨릭교회의 전례와 교리를 지지하였다. 본격적인 잉글랜드 종교개혁 운동은 그의 후계자인 에드워드 6세와 엘리자베스 1세 때부터였다. 또한 헨리 8세는 잉글랜드와 웨일스의 통합을 이끌기도 하였다. 대중문화에서 그는 강력한 왕권을 과시하며 여섯 번이나 결혼한 군주로 유명하다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Converts_to_Anglicanism_from_Roman_Catholicism"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Heinrich VIII. (England)</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Heinrich VIII. Tudor, englisch Henry Tudor und walisisch Harri Tewdwr oder Tudur König von England und Irland, war der zweite Herrscher des Hauses Tudor, das mit der Eheschließung zwischen seinem Vater Heinrich VII. und seiner Mutter Elizabeth of York das Ende der englischen Rosenkriege herbeigeführt hatte. Nach dem plötzlichen Tod seines älteren Bruders Arthur im Jahr 1502 wurde der zehnjährige Heinrich unerwartet Thronerbe. Seine Thronbesteigung am 21. April 1509 war in England die erste friedliche seit beinahe 100 Jahren und wurde von der Bevölkerung euphorisch gefeiert. Berühmt-berüchtigt wurde er durch seine insgesamt sechs Eheschließungen, von denen zwei mit Scheidung und zwei mit der Hinrichtung der Ehefrau endeten. In Heinrichs Regierungszeit kam es zu großen sozialen und religiösen Veränderungen, die für England von enormer Bedeutung waren. Da seine erste Ehe mit Katharina von Aragón keinen männlichen Thronfolger hervorbrachte, strebte Heinrich in den 1520ern eine Scheidung durch den Papst an, in deren Folge er sich schließlich von der römisch-katholischen Kirche lossagte, sich selbst zum Oberhaupt der Kirche Englands erhob, die englischen Klöster auflöste und exkommuniziert wurde. Obwohl Heinrichs religiöse Überzeugungen bis zuletzt im Kern katholisch blieben, ebnete er mit der Ablehnung der Autorität des Papstes und dem Druck einer staatlich autorisierten englischen Bibel den Weg für die protestantische Reformation in England. In den Worten des Historikers Eric Ives hinterließ Heinrich damit „eine tiefere Spur in der englischen Geschichte als jeder andere Monarch seit der normannischen Eroberung Englands und alle, die ihm folgten. “ Heinrich war zudem der erste englische König mit einer Renaissanceausbildung, er sprach mehrere Sprachen, verfasste Gedichte, komponierte Musik und zeigte großes Interesse an religiösen Themen. In seiner Jugend war er ein athletischer, charismatischer Mann, in späteren Jahren jedoch fettleibig und chronisch krank. Bei seinem Tod fiel die Krone an seinen neunjährigen Sohn Eduard, nach dessen frühem Tod an seine Tochter Maria und schließlich an seine Tochter Elisabeth, mit der das Haus Tudor 1603 zu Ende ging.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://web.archive.org/web/20080214103619/http:/www.askaboutireland.ie/show_narrative_page.do?page_id=2863"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Palace_of_Placentia"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Henry VIII</foaf:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_composers"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Jindřich VIII. Tudor byl král Anglie a Irska a uchazeč o trůn Francie od 21. dubna 1509 až do své smrti. Byl následníkem Jindřicha VII. a druhý anglický panovník z rodu Tudorovců. Jindřich VIII. byl významnou postavou anglické historie. I když větší část svého vládnutí strávil surovým potlačováním protestantské reformace, je známější pro politické spory s římskokatolickou církví.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
