<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer">
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_political_theorists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Герберт Спенсер (англ. Herbert Spencer, 27 квітня 1820 — 8 грудня 1903) — англійський філософ і соціолог, один з родоначальників еволюціонізму, ідеї якого користувалися великою популярністю в кінці XIX століття, засновник органічної школи в соціології, ідеолог лібералізму. Остаточно затвердив в науковому обігу термін «соціологія».. Його соціологічні погляди є продовженням соціологічних переконань Сен-Сімона і Конта, певний вплив на розвиток ідеї еволюції зробили Ламарк і К. Бер, Сміт і Мальтус. З ім'ям Герберта Спенсера пов'язують два підходи до розгляду суспільних явищ: Розуміння суспільства як організму, подібному до біологічних, який керується тими ж законами організації, функціонування та розвитку. Вчення про всезагальну еволюцію, що розповсюджується на неорганічний, органічний та над органічний (соціальний) світ.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.marxists.org/archive/lafargue/1884/06/herbert-spencer.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Herbert Spencer was een Brits socioloog, filosoof en antropoloog Als 16-jarige begon Spencer te werken als civiel ingenieur bij de spoorwegen. In 1848 werd hij onderredacteur bij The Economist, toen al een belangrijke financiële krant. Herbert Spencer is de oorspronkelijke bedenker van de term 'survival of the fittest' . Hij publiceerde de term voor het eerst in Principles of Biology in 1864. De term wordt dus onterecht aan Charles Darwin toegewezen. Na de eerste druk van zijn Origin of Species in 1859 zal Darwin zijn term natural selection vervangen in survival of the fittest op aanraden van Alfred Russel Wallace. Spencer wordt bestempeld als pionier van het sociaal darwinisme. Hij schreef veel over de toepassing van de evolutietheorie op de menselijke maatschappij, maar gebruikte daarbij voornamelijk lamarckisme in plaats van darwinisme. Spencer schreef ook politieke werken. Hij wordt gezien als één van de toonaangevende liberale denkers van de 19e eeuw.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ClassicalLiberals"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfred_Marshall"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Ге́рберт Спе́нсер — британский философ и социолог, один из родоначальников эволюционизма, идеи которого пользовались большой популярностью в конце XIX века, основатель органической школы в социологии; идеолог либерализма. Его социологические взгляды являются продолжением социологических воззрений Сен-Симона и Конта, определённое влияние на развитие идеи эволюции оказали Ламарк и К. Бэр, Смит и Мальтус.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_economists"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Herbert Spencer</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1820-04-27</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/BritishPoliticalTheorists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=gUozqCwTGkEC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=herbert+spencer#PPR3,M2"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Herbert Spencer fou filòsof, psicòleg i sociòleg britànic, fundador de la filosofia evolucionista a Gran Bretanya i un dels més il·lustres positivistes del seu país. Enginyer de ferrocarrils i de formació autodidacta, es va interessar tant per la ciència com per les lletres. En l'any 1848 va assumir la direcció de la revista The Economist, òrgan del liberalisme radical de l'època.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/%C3%89mile_Durkheim"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/19th-centuryPhilosophers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://praxeology.net/HS-SP.htm#firstprinciples"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_agnostics"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Herbert Spencer (27 April 1820 – 8 December 1903) was an English philosopher, biologist, sociologist, and prominent classical liberal political theorist of the Victorian era. Spencer developed an all-embracing conception of evolution as the progressive development of the physical world, biological organisms, the human mind, and human culture and societies. He was "an enthusiastic exponent of evolution" and even "wrote about evolution before Darwin did. " As a polymath, he contributed to a wide range of subjects, including ethics, religion, anthropology, economics, political theory, philosophy, biology, sociology, and psychology. During his lifetime he achieved tremendous authority, mainly in English-speaking academia. "The only other English philosopher to have achieved anything like such widespread popularity was Bertrand Russell, and that was in the 20th century. " Spencer was "the single most famous European intellectual in the closing decades of the nineteenth century" but his influence declined sharply after 1900; "Who now reads Spencer?" asked Talcott Parsons in 1937. Spencer is best known for coining the concept "survival of the fittest", which he did in Principles of Biology (1864), after reading Charles Darwin's On the Origin of Species. This term strongly suggests natural selection, yet as Spencer extended evolution into realms of sociology and ethics, he also made use of Lamarckism.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:philosophicalSchool rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Classical_liberalism"/>
    <dbpprop:color xml:lang="en">#B0C4DE</dbpprop:color>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">8</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=99533534"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishEconomists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tokutomi_Soh%C5%8D"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:19th-century_philosophers"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Herbert Spencer war ein englischer Philosoph und Soziologe. Als erster wandte er die Evolutionstheorie auf die gesellschaftliche Entwicklung an und begründete damit das Paradigma des Evolutionismus, das von manchen als Vorläufer des Sozialdarwinismus angesehen wird.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jack_London"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Grant_Allen"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1820-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:birthYear>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Henry_Lewes"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Auguste_Comte"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.grundskyld.dk/0-Perplexed.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thomas_Henry_Huxley"/>
    <dbpprop:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1903-12-08</dbpprop:deathDate>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://oll.libertyfund.org/?option=com_staticxt&amp;staticfile=show.php%3Ftitle=1394"/>
    <dbpprop:schoolTradition rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Classical_liberalism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118616080</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Herbert Spencer war ein englischer Philosoph und Soziologe. Als erster wandte er die Evolutionstheorie auf die gesellschaftliche Entwicklung an und begründete damit das Paradigma des Evolutionismus, das von manchen als Vorläufer des Sozialdarwinismus angesehen wird.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=96054973"/>
    <dbpprop:signature xml:lang="en">HS_steel_portrait_sig.jpg</dbpprop:signature>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Herbert Spencer, född 27 april 1820 i Derby, död 8 december 1903, var en brittisk filosof och liberal. Redaktör vid tidskriften The Economist från 1848. Spencer anses av vissa som upphovsman till socialdarwinismen och var den som myntade uttrycket "survival of the fittest" - en ideologi som kom att upptas av de fascistiska rörelserna under 1900-talet. Men Spencer själv ville att människan och samhällen skulle utvecklas spontant och fritt. Han var en skarp motståndare till kolonialism och krigföring och försökte bl a organisera en Anti-Aggression League mot brittisk imperialism. Spencer vände sig kraftfullt mot nationalism och militarism och hävdade att de innebar en "återbarbarisering" efter en kort gyllene epok med fred och frihandel i Europa. Vad gäller Spencers utvecklingslära menade han att all utveckling går i cykler; liksom rymdens solsystem och galaxer enkom uppkommer, blomstrar och dör, så kommer människornas samhällen att följa samma mönster, en tanke som även återfinns centralt hos tänkare som Nietzsche och Spengler.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">赫伯特·斯宾塞</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Herbert Spencer – angielski filozof i socjolog.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Roderick_Long"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishPhilosophers"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Χέρμπερτ_Σπένσερ"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Roderick_Long"/>
    <dbpprop:notableIdeas rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Social_Darwinism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.constitution.org/hs/ignore_state.htm"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Herbert Spencer</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Brighton"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">허버트 스펜서는 영국 출신의 사회학자, 철학자이다. 오귀스트 콩트의 체계에 필적할 대규모의 종합사회학 체계를 세워 영국 사회학의 창시자가 되었다. 더비에서 출생하여, 철도 기사·경제 신문 기자를 지냈다. 일찍이 자연 과학에 흥미를 가졌던 그는 진화 철학을 주장하고, 진화가 우주의 원리라고 생각하여, 인간이 살아가는 사회에도 강한 사람만이 살 수 있다는 '적자 생존설'을 믿었으며, '사회 유기체설'을 주장하였다. 그의 진화론에 관한 이해는 오해된 부분이 많았고 또한 인문사회과학 분야에서 이러한 "진화론"적 입장은 더 이상 지지되지 못하고 있지만, 당시에 그의 영향력은 대단한 것이었다. 그는 심리학에서 의식의 진화 과정, 도덕적으로는 공리주의를 지지하였다. 저서로 《제1원리》, 《생물학 원리》, 《심리학 원리》, 《사회학 원리》 등이 있다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1903-12-08</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ayn_Rand"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ハーバート・スペンサー（Herbert Spencer, 1820年4月27日 - 1903年12月8日）は、イギリスの哲学者、社会学者、倫理学者。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Alfred_Marshall"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Libertarian_theorists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Charles_Darwin"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1903_deaths"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">허버트 스펜서는 영국 출신의 사회학자, 철학자이다. 오귀스트 콩트의 체계에 필적할 대규모의 종합사회학 체계를 세워 영국 사회학의 창시자가 되었다. 더비에서 출생하여, 철도 기사·경제 신문 기자를 지냈다. 일찍이 자연 과학에 흥미를 가졌던 그는 진화 철학을 주장하고, 진화가 우주의 원리라고 생각하여, 인간이 살아가는 사회에도 강한 사람만이 살 수 있다는 '적자 생존설'을 믿었으며, '사회 유기체설'을 주장하였다. 그의 진화론에 관한 이해는 오해된 부분이 많았고 또한 인문사회과학 분야에서 이러한 "진화론"적 입장은 더 이상 지지되지 못하고 있지만, 당시에 그의 영향력은 대단한 것이었다. 그는 심리학에서 의식의 진화 과정, 도덕적으로는 공리주의를 지지하였다. 저서로 《제1원리》, 《생물학 원리》, 《심리학 원리》, 《사회학 원리》 등이 있다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://fair-use.org/herbert-spencer/data-of-ethics"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">赫伯特·史賓賽（英语：Herbert Spencer，1820年4月27日－1903年12月8日），英國哲學家。他為人所共知的就是“社會達爾文主義之父”，所提出一套的學說把進化理論「適者生存」應用在社會學，尤其是教育及階級鬥爭。但是，他的著作對很多課題都有貢獻，包括規範、形而上學、宗教、政治、修辭、生物和心理學等等。在史賓賽的時代存在許多著名哲學家和科學家，譬如約翰·斯圖亞特·穆勒、托马斯·亨利·赫胥黎和查爾斯·達爾文都是當代知名的人物。</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Philosophers_of_science"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">赫伯特·史賓賽（英语：Herbert Spencer，1820年4月27日－1903年12月8日），英國哲學家。他為人所共知的就是“社會達爾文主義之父”，所提出一套的學說把進化理論「適者生存」應用在社會學，尤其是教育及階級鬥爭。但是，他的著作對很多課題都有貢獻，包括規範、形而上學、宗教、政治、修辭、生物和心理學等等。在史賓賽的時代存在許多著名哲學家和科學家，譬如約翰·斯圖亞特·穆勒、托马斯·亨利·赫胥黎和查爾斯·達爾文都是當代知名的人物。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Auberon_Herbert"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.amazon.com/dp/0521437407"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Murray_Rothbard"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Functionalism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://archives.ulrls.lon.ac.uk/dispatcher.aspx?action=search&amp;database=ChoiceArchive&amp;search=IN=MS791"/>
    <dbpprop:schoolTradition rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Evolutionism"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Spencer</foaf:surname>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Herbert Spencer</foaf:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Classical_liberals"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Herbert Spencer est un philosophe et sociologue anglais.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Herbert Spencer fue un naturalista, filósofo, psicólogo y sociólogo británico. Se dice comúnmente que promovió el darwinismo social en Gran Bretaña (sin embargo esta afirmación es historiográficamente discutible) y fue uno de los más ilustres positivistas de su país. Ingeniero civil y de formación autodidacta, se interesó tanto por la ciencia como por las letras.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.amazon.com/dp/1402182716"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=7900182"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Herbert Spencer là một triết gia; nhà lý thuyết chính trị tự do cổ điển; nhà lý thuyết xã hội học Anh. Spencer đã phát triển một khái niệm toàn diện tiến hóa như là sự phát triển tiến bộ của thế giới tự nhiên, của các cơ thể sinh vật, trí tuệ và của xã hội văn hóa con người. Con người sống độc thân suốt đời này đã đóng góp một loạt chủ đề khác nhau, bao gồm đạo đức học, tôn giáo, chính trị, triết học, sinh học, xã hội học, và tâm lý học. Đóng góp nổi tiếng nhất của ông là việc tạo ra thuật ngữ “sự sống sót của loài thích hợp nhất”, thuật ngữ ông tạo ra trong Nguyên lý Sinh vật (Principles of Biology, sau khi đọc Nguồn gốc muôn loài của Charles Darwin. Thuật ngữ này thừa nhận mạnh mẽ chọn lọc tự nhiên, nhưng Spencer lại mở rộng sự tiến hóa sang các lĩnh vực của xã hội học và đạo đức học và ông đã sử dụng chủ nghĩa Lamarck hơn là chọn lọc tự nhiên.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_Sidgwick"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_philosopher"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishAgnostics"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Philosopher"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/William_Graham_Sumner"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://etext.lib.virginia.edu/etcbin/toccer-new2?id=SpeFirs.xml&amp;images=images/modeng&amp;data=/texts/english/modeng/parsed&amp;tag=public&amp;part=all"/>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">English philosopher</dc:description>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpprop:mainInterests rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Positivism"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/98/Spencer1.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.panarchy.org/spencer/ignore.state.1851.html"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Stuart_Mill"/>
    <dbpprop:mainInterests rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Evolution"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Herbert Spencer was een Brits socioloog, filosoof en antropoloog Als 16-jarige begon Spencer te werken als civiel ingenieur bij de spoorwegen. In 1848 werd hij onderredacteur bij The Economist, toen al een belangrijke financiële krant. Herbert Spencer is de oorspronkelijke bedenker van de term 'survival of the fittest' . Hij publiceerde de term voor het eerst in Principles of Biology in 1864. De term wordt dus onterecht aan Charles Darwin toegewezen.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/36208"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Yan_Fu"/>
    <dbpprop:notableIdeas rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Survival_of_the_fittest"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Charles_Darwin"/>
    <dbpprop:mainInterests rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Laissez-faire"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">English philosopher</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Herbert Spencer fue un naturalista, filósofo, psicólogo y sociólogo británico. Se dice comúnmente que promovió el darwinismo social en Gran Bretaña (sin embargo esta afirmación es historiográficamente discutible) y fue uno de los más ilustres positivistas de su país. Ingeniero civil y de formación autodidacta, se interesó tanto por la ciencia como por las letras. Desde el punto de vista sociológico cabe considerarle como el primer autor que utilizó de forma sistemática los conceptos de estructura y función. Por otra parte, concibió la sociología como un instrumento dinámico al servicio de la reforma social. Dedicó su vida a elaborar su sistema de filosofía evolucionista, en la que considera la evolución natural como clave de toda la realidad, a partir de cuya ley mecánico-materialista cabe explicar cualquier nivel progresivo: la materia, lo biológico, lo psíquico, lo social, etc. En sus lecturas conoció la teoría de la evolución expuesta en el siglo XIX por el naturalista Charles Darwin. Su teoría fundacional para la biología moderna sostenía que los organismos biológicos evolucionan adquiriendo nuevos rasgos por adaptación al medio ambiente que se hacen hereditarios. Las teorías de Lamarck sobre la evolución influyeron profundamente en la obra de Spencer. Para Spencer nada, incluidas las tendencias humanitarias, debe interferir con las "leyes naturales", que implican que el "más apto" es quien sobrevive y los demás perecen. Sin embargo, y a pesar del nombre de sus ideas, Spencer no aceptaba la teoría de Darwin, proponiendo una versión del lamarquismo, de acuerdo a la cual los «órganos» se desarrollan por su uso (o degeneran dado la falta de uso) y esos cambios se transmiten de una generación a otra. Para Spencer, la sociedad es también un organismo, evolucionando hacia formas más complejas de acuerdo a la «ley de la vida», es decir, de acuerdo al principio de la sobrevivencia del más fuerte, tanto a nivel individual como de sociedades. Consecuentemente, Spencer se oponía —radicalmente— a todas las manifestaciones de «socialismo», tales como la educación publica generalizada u obligatoria, bibliotecas publicas, leyes de seguridad industrial, y, en general, a toda legislación o proyecto social. Aplicó la teoría de la evolución a las manifestaciones del espíritu y a los problemas sociales, entre ellos el de la educación, con su obra Educación: intelectual, moral, física. Su doctrina quedó principalmente expuesta en su Sistema de filosofía sintética (11 volúmenes). De su extensa bibliografía, cabe mencionar: La estática social (1850), Principios de psicología (1855), Primeros principios (1862), Principios de biología (1864), La clasificación de las ciencias (1864), La sociología descriptiva (1873), Principios de sociología (1877-1896) y El individuo contra el Estado (1884). Políticamente, desde la década de 1880 ingresó en la Liberty and Property Defence League, la cual en buena parte estaba influenciada por sus ideas. Desde el punto de vista sociologico, Spencer la define como "la historia natural de las sociedades", dicho de otro modo: un orden entre los cambios estructurales y funcionales que experimentan las sociedades. La sociologia de Spencer se centra en los fenomenos macrosociales (agregados sociales) asi como en sus funciones. Varios autores criticaron el a veces extremado realismo de Spencer (por sus semejanzas con el mecanicismo); entre ellos destacó el filósofo y psicólogo escocés Alexander Bain. A pesar de que Spencer no logró crear escuela, su ambicioso intento de sistematizar todo el conocimiento dentro del marco de la ciencia moderna y especialmente en términos de la evolución, le ha hecho merecedor de figurar entre los principales pensadores de finales del siglo XIX. [editar] Abreviatura La abreviatura Spencer se emplea para indicar a Title=Herbert Spencer;ns=0/Main/;language:wiki=es,locale=es como autoridad en la descripción y clasificación científica de los vegetales.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.shpltd.co.uk/elwick-spencer.pdf"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=96277756"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:mainInterest rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Utilitarianism"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Herbert Spencer var en engelsk filosof. Han overførte Darwins utviklingslære til å gjelde kunst, vitenskap og samfunnsyn. Spencers sosialdarwinisme fikk stor betydning for å rettferdiggjøre imperialismen. Det var Herbert Spencer som skapte uttrykket survival of the fittest.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Herbert Spencer est un philosophe et sociologue anglais.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace xml:lang="en">Derby, England</dbpprop:birthPlace>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/96054973?title=Social%20Statics%2c%20Abridged%20and%20Revised%3a%20Together%20with%20the%20Man%20Versus%20the%20State"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://mises.org/daily/4779/Herbert-Spencer-Social-Darwinist-or-Libertarian-Prophet"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.archive.org/search.php?query=mediatype%3A(texts)%20-contributor%3Agutenberg%20AND%20(subject%3A%22Spencer%2C%20Herbert%2C%201820-1903%22%20OR%20creator%3A%22Spencer%2C%20Herbert%2C%201820-1903%22)"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ハーバート・スペンサー（Herbert Spencer, 1820年4月27日 - 1903年12月8日）は、イギリスの哲学者、社会学者、倫理学者。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Anton_LaVey"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Auberon_Herbert"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:mainInterest rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Evolution"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=trlCAAAAIAAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=intitle:herbert+intitle:spencer&amp;lr=&amp;num=30&amp;as_brr=3"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://praxeology.net/HS-SP.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:philosophicalSchool rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Positivism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.iep.utm.edu/s/spencer.htm"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/LibertarianTheorists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Herbert Spencer fou filòsof, psicòleg i sociòleg britànic, fundador de la filosofia evolucionista a Gran Bretanya i un dels més il·lustres positivistes del seu país. Enginyer de ferrocarrils i de formació autodidacta, es va interessar tant per la ciència com per les lletres. En l'any 1848 va assumir la direcció de la revista The Economist, òrgan del liberalisme radical de l'època. Des del punt de vista sociològic cal considerar-lo com primer autor que va utilitzar de forma sistemàtica els conceptes d'estructura i funció. Per altra banda, va concebre la sociologia com un instrument dinàmic al servei de la reforma social. Va dedicar la seva vida a elaborar el seu sistema de filosofia evolucionista, en la qual considera l'evolució natural com clau de tota la realitat, a partir de la llei mecànic-materialista cal explicar qualsevol nivell progressiu: el material, el biològic, el psíquic, el social, etc. En les seves lectures va conèixer la teoria de l'evolució exposada a la fi del segle XVIII pel naturalista francès Jean Lamarck. La seva teoria, avui gairebé desacreditada, sostenia que els trets adquirits d'un organisme eren hereditaris. Les teories de Lamarck sobre l'evolució van influir profundament en l'obra de Spencer. Va aplicar la teoria de l'evolució a les manifestacions de l'esperit i als problemes socials, entre ells el de l'educació, amb la seva obra Educació: intel·lectual, moral i física. La seva doctrina va quedar principalment exposada en el seu Sistema de filosofia sintètica (11 volums). De la seva extensa bibliografia, cap esmentar: L'estàtica social, Principis de psicologia, Primers principis, Principis de biologia (1864), La classificació de les ciències, La sociologia descriptiva, Principis de sociologia i L'individu contra l'Estat. Malgrat que Spencer no va assolir crear una escola pròpia, el seu ambiciós intent de sistematitzar tot el coneixement dintre del marc de la ciència moderna i especialment en termes de l'evolució, li ha fet mereixedor de figurar entre els principals pensadors de finals del segle XIX.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.amazon.com/dp/1418188417"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Herbert Spencer byl klasický britský sociolog a filozof. Patří mezi zastánce tzv. „organicistického proudu“ v sociologii, jenž se vyznačuje důrazem na podobnost rysů lidské společnosti a biologického organismu. Mnoho z jeho myšlenek vstoupilo do všeobecného povědomí, jen málo lidí však dnes tuší, kdo je jejich původním autorem.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_anthropologists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Herbert Spencer oli englantilainen filosofi ja sosiologi, joka oli uuden ajan kehitysfilosofian merkittävin teoreetikko. Spencer oli oman käsityksensä mukaan synteettinen filosofi, joka syntetisoi luontoa, ihmistä ja yhteiskuntaa koskevat yleiset kehityslainalaisuudet, jotka olivat samat koko elollisessa luonnossa. Hän kuului aikansa ei-akateemisten ja itseoppineiden sosiologi-yhteiskuntafilosofien joukkoon. Spencer oli aikanaan hyvin suosittu. On laskettu, että hänen teoksiaan myytiin vuoteen 1913 mennessä 400 000 kappaletta, joka oli tuohon aikaan paljon. Hän pystyi elättämään itsensä kirjoituksillaan ja jopa palkkaamaan avustajia sekä julkaisemaan omaa kirjasarjaa Descriptive Sociology. Ennen tätä hän toimi mm. insinöörinä ja The Economist -lehden toimittajana. Euroopassa Spencerin suosio alkoi 1800-luvun lopulla hiipua, mutta Yhdysvalloissa hän oli vielä 1900-luvun alkuvuosikymmeninä merkittävä ajattelija. Charles Darwinin kehitysopista ja Auguste Comten positivismista saamiensa vaikutteiden pohjalta Spencer kehitti yhtenäisen filosofis-tieteellisen järjestelmän, jota hän sovelsi myös yhteiskunnan tarkasteluun. Sekä luonnon että ihmisyhteiskuntien kehitystä ohjaavat Spencerin mukaan luonnonvalinta ja olemassaolon taistelu. Hän perustelikin tunnetuimmat yhteiskuntapoliittiset kannanottonsa aina kyvykkäimpien eloonjäännillä. Hänen ajatteluaan leimasi vahva valtion vastaisuus ja hän vastusti niin köyhäinapua kuin kunnallista viemäriverkostoakin, sillä nämä puuttuvat evoluution toimintaan. Spencer nojaa kehityksen periaatteeseen. Kaikki tapahtuminen on siirtymistä hajanaisista yhtenäisempiin kokonaisuuksiin, erikoistumista ja siirtymistä järjestyneempään ja määrätympään. Sosiaalinen evoluutio on Spencerille differentaation kautta toteutuvaa uudenlaista yhteenkuuluvuutta. Spencerin mukaan filosofian pitää koota kaikki ilmiöt joiksikin korkeammiksi ja yleisimmiksi näkökannoiksi. Hänen mielestään kaikki tieto on kuitenkin suhteellista ja se riippuu ihmisen tietokyvyn luonteesta. Spencerin pääteos on moniosainen System of synthetic philosophy (1862-96). Muita hänen merkittäviä teoksiaan ovat mm. kirja Social Statics (1851) sekä pamfletti Man versus the State (1884).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bolenderinitiatives.com/sociology/herbert-spencer-1820-1903"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://oll.libertyfund.org/index.php?option=com_staticxt&amp;staticfile=show.php%3Fperson=165&amp;Itemid=28"/>
    <dbpprop:alternativeNames xml:lang="en">Спенсер, Герберт</dbpprop:alternativeNames>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableIdea rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Social_Darwinism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://praxeology.net/herbertspencerlibertarianprophet.pdf"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henry_Sidgwick"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/gutendata/resource/people/Spencer_Herbert_1820-1903"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://oll.libertyfund.org/Texts/LFBooks/Spencer0236/PrinciplesEthics/HTMLs/0155-02_Pt05_Apps.html"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=gztMAAAAIAAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=inauthor:herbert+inauthor:spencer&amp;lr=&amp;num=30&amp;as_brr=3"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=54665737"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PhilosophersOfScience"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Herbert Spencer</dbpprop:caption>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.gutenberg.org/dirs/etext04/8phil10.txt"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Herbert Spencer</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ayn_Rand"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Rhetoricians"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Herbert Spencer, född 27 april 1820 i Derby, död 8 december 1903, var en brittisk filosof och liberal. Redaktör vid tidskriften The Economist från 1848. Spencer anses av vissa som upphovsman till socialdarwinismen och var den som myntade uttrycket "survival of the fittest" - en ideologi som kom att upptas av de fascistiska rörelserna under 1900-talet. Men Spencer själv ville att människan och samhällen skulle utvecklas spontant och fritt.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Rhetoricians"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thorstein_Veblen"/>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace xml:lang="en">Brighton, England</dbpprop:deathPlace>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=98953755"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thorstein_Veblen"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/read/96277756?title=The%20Study%20of%20Sociology"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_libertarians"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/George_Henry_Lewes"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Herbert Spencer (27 April 1820 – 8 December 1903) was an English philosopher, biologist, sociologist, and prominent classical liberal political theorist of the Victorian era. Spencer developed an all-embracing conception of evolution as the progressive development of the physical world, biological organisms, the human mind, and human culture and societies. He was "an enthusiastic exponent of evolution" and even "wrote about evolution before Darwin did.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://oll.libertyfund.org/?option=com_staticxt&amp;staticfile=show.php%3Ftitle=273"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Herbert Spencer foi um filósofo inglês e um dos representantes do positivismo. Spencer foi um profundo admirador da obra de Charles Darwin. É dele a expressão "sobrevivência do mais apto", e em sua obra procurou aplicar as leis da evolução a todos os níveis da atividade humana. Spencer é considerado o "pai" do Darwinismo social, embora jamais tenha utilizado o termo.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jack_London"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ハーバート・スペンサー"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?as_q=&amp;num=30&amp;btnG=Google+Search&amp;as_epq=&amp;as_oq=&amp;as_eq=&amp;as_brr=3&amp;lr=&amp;as_vt=&amp;as_auth=herbert+spencer&amp;as_pub=&amp;as_sub=&amp;as_drrb=c&amp;as_miny=&amp;as_maxy=&amp;as_isbn="/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Herbert Spencer</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Herbert Spencer foi um filósofo inglês e um dos representantes do positivismo. Spencer foi um profundo admirador da obra de Charles Darwin. É dele a expressão "sobrevivência do mais apto", e em sua obra procurou aplicar as leis da evolução a todos os níveis da atividade humana. Spencer é considerado o "pai" do Darwinismo social, embora jamais tenha utilizado o termo. Com base em suas ideias, alguns autores procuraram justificar a divisão da sociedade em classes, sugerindo que estes seriam exemplos de seleção natural. Faleceu em 8 de dezembro de 1903. Esta sepultado no Cemitério de Highgate, Londres na Inglaterra.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:philosophicalSchool rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Evolutionism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.lewrockwell.com/orig3/long3.html"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henri_Bergson"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=3559105"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=hTBVAAAAMAAJ&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=inauthor:herbert+inauthor:spencer&amp;lr=&amp;num=30&amp;as_brr=3"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Molto apprezzato, specialmente nel mondo anglosassone, nel 1902 venne candidato al Premio Nobel per la Letteratura.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishAnthropologists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Henri_Bergson"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Герберт Спенсер (англ. Herbert Spencer, 27 квітня 1820 — 8 грудня 1903) — англійський філософ і соціолог, один з родоначальників еволюціонізму, ідеї якого користувалися великою популярністю в кінці XIX століття, засновник органічної школи в соціології, ідеолог лібералізму. Остаточно затвердив в науковому обігу термін «соціологія».. Його соціологічні погляди є продовженням соціологічних переконань Сен-Сімона і Конта, певний вплив на розвиток ідеї еволюції зробили Ламарк і К. Бер, Сміт і Мальтус.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:era rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/19th-century_philosophy"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/%C3%89mile_Durkheim"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=gUozqCwTGkEC&amp;printsec=frontcover&amp;dq=inauthor:herbert+inauthor:spencer&amp;lr=&amp;num=30&amp;as_brr=3"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Vaz_Ferreira"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Derby"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromDerby"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.01kznw"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Herbert Spencer var en engelsk filosof. Han overførte Darwins utviklingslære til å gjelde kunst, vitenskap og samfunnsyn. Spencers sosialdarwinisme fikk stor betydning for å rettferdiggjøre imperialismen. Det var Herbert Spencer som skapte uttrykket survival of the fittest.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableIdea rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Survival_of_the_fittest"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Stuart_Mill"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Derby"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Spencer, Herbert</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Auguste_Comte"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1903-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:deathYear>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thomas_Henry_Huxley"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Philosopher"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Herbert</foaf:givenName>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herbert_Spencer?oldid=495409174"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Herbert Spencer byl klasický britský sociolog a filozof. Patří mezi zastánce tzv. „organicistického proudu“ v sociologii, jenž se vyznačuje důrazem na podobnost rysů lidské společnosti a biologického organismu. Mnoho z jeho myšlenek vstoupilo do všeobecného povědomí, jen málo lidí však dnes tuší, kdo je jejich původním autorem.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Герберт Спенсер</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:mainInterests rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Utilitarianism"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Herbert Spencer là một triết gia; nhà lý thuyết chính trị tự do cổ điển; nhà lý thuyết xã hội học Anh. Spencer đã phát triển một khái niệm toàn diện tiến hóa như là sự phát triển tiến bộ của thế giới tự nhiên, của các cơ thể sinh vật, trí tuệ và của xã hội văn hóa con người. Con người sống độc thân suốt đời này đã đóng góp một loạt chủ đề khác nhau, bao gồm đạo đức học, tôn giáo, chính trị, triết học, sinh học, xã hội học, và tâm lý học.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Molto apprezzato, specialmente nel mondo anglosassone, nel 1902 venne candidato al Premio Nobel per la Letteratura.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:era rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">19</dbpprop:era>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">27</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Burials_at_Highgate_Cemetery"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.marxists.org/archive/plekhanov/1895/anarch/index.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Herbert Spencer – angielski filozof i socjolog.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Grant_Allen"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Gutenberg_author"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:mainInterest rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Positivism"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath xml:lang="en">Brighton, England</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://mises.org/journals/lar/pdfs/2_2/2_2_9.pdf"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Charles_Darwin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:mainInterest rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Laissez-faire"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Murray_Rothbard"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/98/Spencer1.jpg/200px-Spencer1.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=c2rjtEWeYvwC&amp;pg=PA9&amp;lpg=PA9&amp;dq=%22Remarks+on+Spencer's+Definition+of+Mind%22&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=-dky4KGHk4&amp;sig=uzT7uc3v4FJLlyrAhhN9M_-qj68&amp;hl=en&amp;ei=n--cTOaFL4bGsAPQs-3VAQ&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;ct=result&amp;resnum=3&amp;ved=0CBwQ6AEwAg#v=onepage&amp;q=%22Remarks%20on%20Spencer's%20Definition%20of%20Mind%22&amp;f=false"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Yan_Fu"/>
    <dbpprop:region xml:lang="en">Western philosophy</dbpprop:region>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jean-Baptiste_Lamarck"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tokutomi_Soh%C5%8D"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Anton_LaVey"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_philosophers"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Herbert_Spencer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.historians.org/annual/2006/06program/precirculated/Session145_Rafferty.pdf"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jean-Baptiste_Lamarck"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/BritishLibertarians"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Herbert Spencer</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:id xml:lang="en">Herbert+Spencer</dbpprop:id>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Ге́рберт Спе́нсер — британский философ и социолог, один из родоначальников эволюционизма, идеи которого пользовались большой популярностью в конце XIX века, основатель органической школы в социологии; идеолог либерализма. Его социологические взгляды являются продолжением социологических воззрений Сен-Симона и Конта, определённое влияние на развитие идеи эволюции оказали Ламарк и К. Бэр, Смит и Мальтус.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nikolay_Mikhaylovsky"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1820_births"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nikolay_Mikhaylovsky"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Спенсер,_Герберт"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-philosopher-noun-1"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Carlos_Vaz_Ferreira"/>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1820-04-27</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/William_Graham_Sumner"/>
    <dbpprop:schoolTradition rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Positivism"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Herbert Spencer oli englantilainen filosofi ja sosiologi, joka oli uuden ajan kehitysfilosofian merkittävin teoreetikko. Spencer oli oman käsityksensä mukaan synteettinen filosofi, joka syntetisoi luontoa, ihmistä ja yhteiskuntaa koskevat yleiset kehityslainalaisuudet, jotka olivat samat koko elollisessa luonnossa. Hän kuului aikansa ei-akateemisten ja itseoppineiden sosiologi-yhteiskuntafilosofien joukkoon. Spencer oli aikanaan hyvin suosittu.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Herbert Spencer</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.questia.com/PM.qst?a=o&amp;d=14557498"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Charles_Darwin"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/허버트_스펜서"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://praxeology.net/HS-FC.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://oll.libertyfund.org/Home3/Author.php?recordID=0236"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Derby"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
