<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch">
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Iris Murdoch DBE brit írónő és filozófus, legismertebb munkái egytől egyig morális és szexuális és pszichológiai jellegű témákat feszegetnek. Első regényét, A háló alatt címűt 2001-ben az American Modern Library a 20. század 100 legkiválóbb angol nyelvű regénye közé választotta.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishSocialists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">La Murdoch è conosciuta per le sue storie su temi filosofici, etici e sessuali. Il suo primo racconto pubblicato, Under the Net, fu selezionato nel 2001 dal Board editoriale degli Stati Uniti Modern Library come uno dei 100 migliori racconti in lingua Inglese del XX secolo. Nel 1987, fu nominata Dame Commander dell'Ordine dell'Impero Britannico.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Леді Айріс Мердок — англійська письменниця і філософ. Лауреат Букерівської премії, лідер за кількістю влучень у число фіналістів (short list) Букера (шість разів). Народилася в англо-ірландській родині. Вивчала класичну філологію в Оксфордському університеті (1938—1942) і філософію — в Кембріджському університеті (1947—1948). Викладала філософію в Оксфорді.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">艾瑞斯·梅鐸女爵士，DBE（Dame Iris Murdoch，1919年7月15日－1999年2月8日）是出身於愛爾蘭的作家。她的家鄉位於都柏林，但幼時移居至倫敦，並於牛津大學和劍橋大學修讀哲學。 梅鐸的第一本小說網之下於1954年入選美國現代圖書館（American Modern Library）的「20世紀百本最傑出英文小說」；而1978年的大海，大海則獲得布克獎，她很快就被譽為“全英國最聰明的女人”。 晚年的艾瑞斯·梅鐸不幸患上了阿茲海默症，後來死於安養中心，終年不足80歲。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://dementia.stir.ac.uk/aboutus_irismbuilding"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.guardian.co.uk/reviews/biography/0,6121,1036391,00.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1954-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Iris Murdoch var en irsk-engelsk forfatter og filosof. Hun er mest kjent for sine fortellinger om etiske og seksuelle emner. Hennes første utgitte roman, Under the Net, ble i 2001 valgt ut av redaksjonen i det amerikanske Modern Library som en av de 100 beste engelskspråklige romanene fra 1900-tallet. I 1987 ble hun utnevnt til Dame Commander av Order of the British Empire. Hun ble derved adlet og fikk rett til å føre tiltaleformen Dame foran sitt navn. Murdoch levde med Alzheimers sykdom i årene før hun døde i 1999.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_philosophers"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Iris Murdoch est un écrivain britannique.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Jean Iris Murdoch – anglo-irlandzka pisarka i filozofka.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118585835</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fyodor_Dostoyevsky"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_educated_at_Badminton_School"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Deaths_from_Alzheimer's_disease"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Writer"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Dublin_(city)"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1919-07-15</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Communist_Party_of_Great_Britain_members"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Jean Iris Murdoch DBE war eine anglo-irische Schriftstellerin und Philosophin. Sie ist bekannt für ihre Romane, die detaillierte Personenbeschreibungen mit fesselnden Handlungen verbinden und meist von ethischen oder erotisch-sexuellen Themen handeln. Ihr erster Roman Unter dem Netz wurde 2001 von der Redaktion des amerikanischen Verlags Modern Library als einer der 100 besten englischsprachigen Romane des 20. Jahrhunderts ausgewählt.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdochová"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1999_deaths"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Iris Murdoch est un écrivain britannique.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dublin"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Gifford_Lecturers"/>
    <dbpprop:period rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1954</dbpprop:period>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace xml:lang="en">Oxfordshire, England</dbpprop:deathPlace>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath xml:lang="en">Oxfordshire, England</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Jean Iris Murdoch foi uma escritora e filósofa irlandesa. Frequentou escolas progressistas, primeiramente a Froebel Demonstration School e depois a Badminton School, em Bristol. Estudou Literaturas Clássicas, História Antiga e Filosofia na Sommerville College, tendo efectuado uma pós-graduação também em Filosofia. Foi membro activo do Partido Comunista até se distanciar da ideologia; trabalhou na U.N.N.R.A. e deu aulas no Royal College of Art. A partir de 1963 dedicou-se à escrita, tendo produzido 26 romances em 40 anos, os últimos escritos já enquanto sofria de Alzheimer. Em 1956 casou-se com John Bayley, crítico e professor. Faleceu a 8 de Fevereiro de 1999 em Oxford. Em 2008, o The Times nomeou-a na sua lista dos "50 maiores escritores britânicos desde 1945". A sua história está retratada num filme de Richard Eyre intitulado Iris, protagonizado por Kate Winslet e Judi Dench.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">艾瑞斯·梅鐸</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1919_births"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Dame Jean Iris Murdoch, was een filosofe, die haar grootste bekendheid echter dankt aan haar werk als romanschrijfster.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.arlindo-correia.com/120204.html"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_Newnham_College,_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Jean Iris Murdoch, DBE, oli irlantilaissyntyinen Englannissa työskennellyt kirjailija ja filosofi. Murdochin romaaneissa voimakas henkilökuvaus ja monimutkaiset juonikuviot yhdistyvät eettiseen tai seksuaaliseen tematiikkaan. Murdoch opiskeli filosofiaa Oxfordin yliopistossa Ludwig Wittgensteinin opetuksessa. Hän kirjoitti yli 25 romaania, kirjallisuusesseitä ja näytelmiä. Vuonna 1978 Murdochille myönnettiin arvostettu Booker-kirjallisuuspalkinto teoksesta The Sea, the Sea. Sen suomennos ilmestyi vuonna 1981 nimellä Meri, meri. Murdoch julkaisi 26 romaania 40 vuoden aikana. Hän joutui lopettamaan kirjoittamisen vuonna 1995 sairastuttuaan Alzheimerin tautiin. Richard Eyren elokuva Iris (2001) kertoo Murdochin elämästä, etenkin viimeisistä vuosista. Sen nimiosissa ovat Kate Winslet ja Judi Dench.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Iris Murdoch</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromDuBlin(city)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/William_Shakespeare"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_Somerville_College,_Oxford"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Jean Iris Murdoch DBE war eine anglo-irische Schriftstellerin und Philosophin. Sie ist bekannt für ihre Romane, die detaillierte Personenbeschreibungen mit fesselnden Handlungen verbinden und meist von ethischen oder erotisch-sexuellen Themen handeln. Ihr erster Roman Unter dem Netz wurde 2001 von der Redaktion des amerikanischen Verlags Modern Library als einer der 100 besten englischsprachigen Romane des 20. Jahrhunderts ausgewählt. Murdoch ist außerdem die Titelperson in Richard Eyres preisgekrönter Filmbiographie Iris von 2001. Darin wird die Geschichte ihres Verfalls durch die Alzheimer-Krankheit aus der Sicht ihres Mannes John Bayley beschrieben, zu der Zeit, als sie in North Oxford lebten. Murdoch wurde von Kate Winslet und Judi Dench dargestellt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">艾瑞斯·梅鐸女爵士，DBE（Dame Iris Murdoch，1919年7月15日－1999年2月8日）是出身於愛爾蘭的作家。她的家鄉位於都柏林，但幼時移居至倫敦，並於牛津大學和劍橋大學修讀哲學。 梅鐸的第一本小說網之下於1954年入選美國現代圖書館（American Modern Library）的「20世紀百本最傑出英文小說」；而1978年的大海，大海則獲得布克獎，她很快就被譽為“全英國最聰明的女人”。 晚年的艾瑞斯·梅鐸不幸患上了阿茲海默症，後來死於安養中心，終年不足80歲。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Dame Iris Murdoch DBE (15 July 1919 – 8 February 1999) was an Irish-born British author and philosopher, best known for her novels about political and social questions of good and evil, sexual relationships, morality, and the power of the unconscious. Her first published novel, Under the Net, was selected in 2001 by the editorial board as one of Modern Library's 100 best English-language novels of the 20th century.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Booker_Prize_winners"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c6/Iris_Murdoch.jpg/200px-Iris_Murdoch.jpg"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishNovelists"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iris_Murdoch?oldid=494513072"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Dublin, Ireland</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:20th-century_philosophers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_socialists"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Iris Murdoch</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_writer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://fass.kingston.ac.uk/research/iris-murdoch/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Oxfordshire"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfSomervilleCollege,Oxford"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Plato"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fyodor_Dostoyevsky"/>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Novelist</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_novelists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ジーン・アイリス・マードック（Jean Iris Murdoch, 1919年7月15日 - 1999年2月8日）は、アイルランド出身の英国の哲学者・作家・詩人。その小説は、倫理的・性的な主題を巻き込んだ、キャラクター造形の豊かさと、読者を惹き付けるような構想ゆえに名高い。「愛する事を教えてくれたあなた。今度は忘れる事を教えて下さい」という格言が有名である。 処女出版小説『網のなか Under the Net』（訳：鈴木寧）は、2001年に米国の『モダン・ライブラリー』誌編集部によって、20世紀の英語小説ベスト100の一冊に選ばれた。1987年に大英帝国勲章を授与され、デイムの称号を得た。 2001年のアメリカ映画『アイリス』は、最晩年にアルツハイマー症を患うまでの彼女の姿を、6歳下の夫ジョン・ベイリーの視点を通して描き出している。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Iris Murdoch</dbpprop:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/William_Shakespeare"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Jean Iris Murdoch DBE va ser una escriptora i filòsofa britànica, nascuda irlandesa, coneguda fonamentalment per les seues novel·les en les que combina una rica caracterització dels personatges i arguments que involucren aspectes ètics o temes sexuals. La seua primera novel·la publicada, Under the Net, va ser seleccionada l'any 2001 pel comitè editorial de la companyia nord-americana Modern Library com una de les 100 millors novel·les en llengua anglesa del Segle XX. L'any 1987, va ser distingida amb l'Orde de l'Imperi Britànic.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Dame Jean Iris Murdoch, DBE fue una escritora y filósofa irlandesa, mejor conocida por sus novelas, en las que combina una rica caracterización con animados argumentos, involucrando, por lo general, temas de índole moral o sexual. Su primera novela publicada, Bajo la red, fue seleccionada en 2001 por la American Modern Library como una de las 100 mejores novelas en lengua inglesa del siglo XX. En 1987, fue nombrada Dama Comandante de la Orden del Imperio Británico.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WomenPhilosophers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Dame Jean Iris Murdochová byla britská prozaička a filozofka irského původu. Její romány jsou většinou fantaskní povahy s filozofickým podtextem. Typické jsou časté odkazy na díla Tolstého a Dostojevského a další ruské realisty. Několikrát se dostala do užší nominace na literární cenu Man Booker Prize.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishWomenWriters"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_philosophers"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Мёрдок,_Айрис"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_women_writers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/BritishPeopleOfIrishDescent"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-writer-noun-1"/>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Philosopher</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jean-Paul_Sartre"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Айрис Мёрдок — английская писательница и философ. Лауреат Букеровской премии, лидер по числу попаданий в число финалистов (short list) Букера (шесть раз). Родилась в англо-ирландской семье. Изучала классическую филологию в Оксфордском университете (1938—1942) и философию — в Кембриджском (1947—1948). Преподавала философию в Оксфорде. Там же в 1956 вышла замуж за Джона Бейли, профессора английской литературы, писателя и художественного критика, с которым прожила около 40 лет.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Jean Iris Murdoch DBE va ser una escriptora i filòsofa britànica, nascuda irlandesa, coneguda fonamentalment per les seues novel·les en les que combina una rica caracterització dels personatges i arguments que involucren aspectes ètics o temes sexuals. La seua primera novel·la publicada, Under the Net, va ser seleccionada l'any 2001 pel comitè editorial de la companyia nord-americana Modern Library com una de les 100 millors novel·les en llengua anglesa del Segle XX.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfNewnhamCollege,Cambridge"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Simone_Weil"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/20th-centuryPhilosophers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_dramatists_and_playwrights"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/아이리스_머독"/>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1919-07-15</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1999-02-08</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Iris Murdoch var en irsk-engelsk forfatter og filosof. Hun er mest kjent for sine fortellinger om etiske og seksuelle emner. Hennes første utgitte roman, Under the Net, ble i 2001 valgt ut av redaksjonen i det amerikanske Modern Library som en av de 100 beste engelskspråklige romanene fra 1900-tallet. I 1987 ble hun utnevnt til Dame Commander av Order of the British Empire. Hun ble derved adlet og fikk rett til å føre tiltaleformen Dame foran sitt navn.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Dames_Commander_of_the_Order_of_the_British_Empire"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Raymond_Queneau"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Murdoch, Iris</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.guardian.co.uk/departments/biography/story/0,6000,1034600,00.html"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Айріс Мердок</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:spouse xml:lang="en">John Bayley, 1956-1999</dbpprop:spouse>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">아이리스 머독 여사는 영국의 여류 소설가다. 아일랜드의 더블린에서 태어났다. 옥스퍼드 대학 졸업 후, 오랫동안 모교에서 철학을 강의했다. 처음에는 &lt;사르트르론&gt;(1953)을 썼으나, 후에는 소설 창작에 전념하여, 현대 영국의 대표적인 소설가 중 한 사람이 되었다. 그의 작품 경향은 다양하여 대표작이라고 평가된 &lt;종(鍾)&gt;(1958), &lt;소박한 장미&gt;(1962)와 같은 시정이 풍부한 작품과, &lt;잘린 목&gt;(1961)과 같이 복잡하고 위험한 인간 관계를 그린 것도 있다. 이 밖의 작품에 처녀작인 &lt;그물 속&gt;(1954)을 비롯하여 &lt;요술쟁이로부터의 도주&gt; &lt;모래성&gt; &lt;유니콘&gt; &lt;수녀와 병사&gt; &lt;철학자의 제자들&gt; 등이 있다. 1987년 대영 제국 훈장 2등급(DBE, 작위급 훈장)을 받았다.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Writer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:spouse rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Bayley_(writer)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Arthur_Schopenhauer"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Iris</foaf:givenName>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/c/c6/Iris_Murdoch.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Леді Айріс Мердок — англійська письменниця і філософ. Лауреат Букерівської премії, лідер за кількістю влучень у число фіналістів (short list) Букера (шість разів). Народилася в англо-ірландській родині. Вивчала класичну філологію в Оксфордському університеті (1938—1942) і філософію — в Кембріджському університеті (1947—1948). Викладала філософію в Оксфорді. Там же в 1956 вийшла заміж за Джона Бейлі, професора англійської літератури, письменника і художнього критика, з яким прожила близько 40 років. Дітей у письменниці не було. Мердок написала 26 романів і є автором філософських і драматичних творів. Дебютом Мердок у літературі став роман 1954 року «Під мережею». У 1987 році їй було присуджено звання Дами Командора ордена Британської імперії. У 1995 році Айріс Мердок пише свій останній роман «Дилема Джексона», який був прийнятий критиками досить холодно. Останні роки життя письменниця боролася з хворобою Альцгеймера. Айріс Мердок померла 8 лютого 1999 року в будинку престарілих. Айріс Мердок багатьма визнається одним з кращих романістів XX століття і визнаним класиком сучасної літератури. Про життя письменниці в 2001 році був знятий фільм «Айріс», де роль Айріс виконали Кейт Вінслет і Джуді Денч. Обидві актриси за свої ролі були номіновані на премію «Оскар». Архів паперів Айріс Мердок зібраний в бібліотеці Університету Айова.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">La Murdoch è conosciuta per le sue storie su temi filosofici, etici e sessuali. Il suo primo racconto pubblicato, Under the Net, fu selezionato nel 2001 dal Board editoriale degli Stati Uniti Modern Library come uno dei 100 migliori racconti in lingua Inglese del XX secolo. Nel 1987, fu nominata Dame Commander dell'Ordine dell'Impero Britannico.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Dame Jean Iris Murdoch, DBE fue una escritora y filósofa irlandesa, mejor conocida por sus novelas, en las que combina una rica caracterización con animados argumentos, involucrando, por lo general, temas de índole moral o sexual. Su primera novela publicada, Bajo la red, fue seleccionada en 2001 por la American Modern Library como una de las 100 mejores novelas en lengua inglesa del siglo XX. En 1987, fue nombrada Dama Comandante de la Orden del Imperio Británico.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Artist"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marcel_Proust"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_poets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Dame Iris Murdoch DBE (15 July 1919 – 8 February 1999) was an Irish-born British author and philosopher, best known for her novels about political and social questions of good and evil, sexual relationships, morality, and the power of the unconscious. Her first published novel, Under the Net, was selected in 2001 by the editorial board as one of Modern Library's 100 best English-language novels of the 20th century. In 1987, she was made a Dame Commander of the Order of the British Empire. In 2008, The Times named Murdoch among their list of "The 50 greatest British writers since 1945".</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Plato"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishPoets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Simone_Weil"/>
    <dbpprop:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1999-02-08</dbpprop:deathDate>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sigmund_Freud"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Jean Iris Murdoch – anglo-irlandzka pisarka i filozofka.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishPhilosophers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ジーン・アイリス・マードック（Jean Iris Murdoch, 1919年7月15日 - 1999年2月8日）は、アイルランド出身の英国の哲学者・作家・詩人。その小説は、倫理的・性的な主題を巻き込んだ、キャラクター造形の豊かさと、読者を惹き付けるような構想ゆえに名高い。「愛する事を教えてくれたあなた。今度は忘れる事を教えて下さい」という格言が有名である。 処女出版小説『網のなか Under the Net』（訳：鈴木寧）は、2001年に米国の『モダン・ライブラリー』誌編集部によって、20世紀の英語小説ベスト100の一冊に選ばれた。1987年に大英帝国勲章を授与され、デイムの称号を得た。 2001年のアメリカ映画『アイリス』は、最晩年にアルツハイマー症を患うまでの彼女の姿を、6歳下の夫ジョン・ベイリーの視点を通して描き出している。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.arlindo-correia.com/021001.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Iris Murdoch, född 15 juli 1919 i Dublin, Irland, död 8 februari 1999 i Oxford, Oxfordshire, England, Storbritannien. Var en brittisk författare och filosof. Murdoch fick sin utbildning vid Somerville College i Oxford (bl.a. forntida historia och filosofi). Hon har skrivit en rad psykologiska romaner som innehåller såväl mytiska och symboliska element som nära, komplexa förhållanden. Hon var starkt influerad av Freud och Sartre.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Jean Iris Murdoch foi uma escritora e filósofa irlandesa. Frequentou escolas progressistas, primeiramente a Froebel Demonstration School e depois a Badminton School, em Bristol. Estudou Literaturas Clássicas, História Antiga e Filosofia na Sommerville College, tendo efectuado uma pós-graduação também em Filosofia. Foi membro activo do Partido Comunista até se distanciar da ideologia; trabalhou na U.N.N.R.A. e deu aulas no Royal College of Art.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Raymond_Queneau"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fellows_of_St_Anne's_College,_Oxford"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/アイリス・マードック"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Iris Murdoch</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishDramatistsAndPlaywrights"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.usfca.edu/jco/irismurdoch/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Arthur_Schopenhauer"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0gdgq"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Dame Jean Iris Murdochová byla britská prozaička a filozofka irského původu. Její romány jsou většinou fantaskní povahy s filozofickým podtextem. Typické jsou časté odkazy na díla Tolstého a Dostojevského a další ruské realisty. Několikrát se dostala do užší nominace na literární cenu Man Booker Prize.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:British_people_of_Irish_descent"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Iris_Murdoch"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Murdoch</foaf:surname>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace xml:lang="en">Dublin, Ireland</dbpprop:birthPlace>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Dame Jean Iris Murdoch, was een filosofe, die haar grootste bekendheid echter dankt aan haar werk als romanschrijfster.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/saturday_review/story/0,3605,548346,00.html"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marcel_Proust"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.thewordtravels.com/iris-murdoch.html"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1919</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Iris Murdoch</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FellowsOfStAnne'sCollege,Oxford"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">아이리스 머독 여사는 영국의 여류 소설가다. 아일랜드의 더블린에서 태어났다. 옥스퍼드 대학 졸업 후, 오랫동안 모교에서 철학을 강의했다. 처음에는 &lt;사르트르론&gt;(1953)을 썼으나, 후에는 소설 창작에 전념하여, 현대 영국의 대표적인 소설가 중 한 사람이 되었다. 그의 작품 경향은 다양하여 대표작이라고 평가된 &lt;종(鍾)&gt;(1958), &lt;소박한 장미&gt;(1962)와 같은 시정이 풍부한 작품과, &lt;잘린 목&gt;(1961)과 같이 복잡하고 위험한 인간 관계를 그린 것도 있다. 이 밖의 작품에 처녀작인 &lt;그물 속&gt;(1954)을 비롯하여 &lt;요술쟁이로부터의 도주&gt; &lt;모래성&gt; &lt;유니콘&gt; &lt;수녀와 병사&gt; &lt;철학자의 제자들&gt; 등이 있다. 1987년 대영 제국 훈장 2등급(DBE, 작위급 훈장)을 받았다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1999</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Iris Murdoch DBE brit írónő és filozófus, legismertebb munkái egytől egyig morális és szexuális és pszichológiai jellegű témákat feszegetnek. Első regényét, A háló alatt címűt 2001-ben az American Modern Library a 20. század 100 legkiválóbb angol nyelvű regénye közé választotta.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/archive/writers/12207.shtml"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Jean Iris Murdoch, DBE, oli irlantilaissyntyinen Englannissa työskennellyt kirjailija ja filosofi. Murdochin romaaneissa voimakas henkilökuvaus ja monimutkaiset juonikuviot yhdistyvät eettiseen tai seksuaaliseen tematiikkaan. Murdoch opiskeli filosofiaa Oxfordin yliopistossa Ludwig Wittgensteinin opetuksessa. Hän kirjoitti yli 25 romaania, kirjallisuusesseitä ja näytelmiä. Vuonna 1978 Murdochille myönnettiin arvostettu Booker-kirjallisuuspalkinto teoksesta The Sea, the Sea.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sigmund_Freud"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jean-Paul_Sartre"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Айрис Мёрдок — английская писательница и философ. Лауреат Букеровской премии, лидер по числу попаданий в число финалистов (short list) Букера (шесть раз). Родилась в англо-ирландской семье. Изучала классическую филологию в Оксфордском университете (1938—1942) и философию — в Кембриджском (1947—1948). Преподавала философию в Оксфорде. Там же в 1956 вышла замуж за Джона Бейли, профессора английской литературы, писателя и художественного критика, с которым прожила около 40 лет. Детей у писательницы не было. Мёрдок написала 26 романов и является автором философских и драматических произведений. Дебютом Мёрдок в литературе стал роман 1954 года «Под сетью». В 1987 году ей было присуждено звание Дамы Командора ордена Британской империи. В 1995 году Айрис Мердок пишет свой последний роман «Дилемма Джексона», который был принят критиками довольно холодно. Последние годы жизни писательница боролась с болезнью Альцгеймера. Айрис Мёрдок умерла 8 февраля 1999 года в доме престарелых. Айрис Мердок многими признается одним из лучших романистов XX века и признанным классиком современной литературы. О жизни писательницы в 2001 году был снят фильм «Айрис», где роль Айрис исполнили Кейт Уинслет и Джуди Денч. Обе актрисы за свои роли были номинированы на премию «Оскар». Архив бумаг Айрис Мёрдок собран в библиотеке Университета Айова.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Iris Murdoch, född 15 juli 1919 i Dublin, Irland, död 8 februari 1999 i Oxford, Oxfordshire, England, Storbritannien. Var en brittisk författare och filosof. Murdoch fick sin utbildning vid Somerville College i Oxford (bl.a. forntida historia och filosofi). Hon har skrivit en rad psykologiska romaner som innehåller såväl mytiska och symboliska element som nära, komplexa förhållanden. Hon var starkt influerad av Freud och Sartre. Bland hennes mest kända romaner kan nämnas Eskapad (1954), Flykten från förtrollaren (1956), Klockan (1958), En hemlig ros (1962), Änglarnas tid (1966) och Havet, havet (1978; för vilken hon erhöll Bookerpriset). Adlad (DBE - Dame of the Order of the British Empire) 1987.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Iris Murdochová</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Artist"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
