<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lough_Swilly">
    <foaf:primaryTopic rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly">
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Lough Swilly – zatoka podobna do fiordu, leżąca w Irlandii pomiędzy wschodnią częścią półwyspu Inishowen w hrabstwie Donegal i resztą północnego Donegalu. Na północnych krańcach półwyspu znajdują się przylądki Inishowen Head i Dunaff Head. Miasta położone nad lough (irlandzkie pojęcie oznaczające m. in. zatokę) to Buncrana i Rathmullan. Na południowym krańcu Lough Swilly leży Letterkenny. Zatoka była używana jako port przez Royal Navy podczas I wojny światowej. Brytyjczycy zbudowali też sporo fortów aby chronić zatokę, których ruiny można zobaczyć na przylądku Lenan Head, Dunree i Buncranie.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/County_Donegal"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/f/fb/Lough_swilly.jpg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Lough Swilly (Loch Súilí på irsk) er en fjord på nordkysten av øya Irland. Fjorden ligger i grevskapet Donegal i Republikken Irland, og skiller Inishowenhalvøya i vest fra resten av det nordlige Donegal. Ved fjordmunningen i nord ligger nesene Fanad Head og Dunaff Head. Blant tettstedene som ligger ved fjorden finner vi Buncrana på Inishowensiden og Rathmullan på vestsiden. Innerst i fjorden ligger Letterkenny. Ved to anledninger har fjorden spilt en viktig rolle i irsk historie.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-7.53662 55.1538)</geo:geometry>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.041xdt"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/LoughsOfCountyDonegal"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fjords_of_Ireland"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/GeoclassInlet"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Лох-Суилли"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/SeaLoughsOfIreland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Der Lough Swilly ist ein fjordartiger Meeresarm, der zwischen den Halbinseln Fanad im Westen und Inishowen im Osten im Norden der Republik Irland im County Donegal liegt. Er ist etwa 45 Kilometer lang und in der Mitte drei bis fünf Kilometer breit. Das Nordende des Lough Swilly säumen Fanad Head und Dunaff Head. Orte am Rande des Meeresarmes sind Buncrana im Osten und Rathmullan und Portsalon im Westen. Am Südende des Lough Swilly liegt die Stadt Letterkenny. Nach einem fehlgeschlagenen Aufstand im September 1607, verließen Aodh Mór Ó Néill, 2. Earl of Tyrone und Rory O'Donnell von Rathmullan aus über den Lough Swilly Irland; auch als Flucht der Grafen bekannt. Im Oktober 1798 wurde während der Irischen Rebellion von 1798 eine französische Flotte, die Truppen unter der Führung von Wolfe Tone anlanden sollte, am Eingang des Lough Swilly abgefangen und zerstört. Lough Swilly wurde von der Royal Navy im 1. Weltkrieg als Ankerplatz genutzt und die Engländer bauten eine Reihe von Forts am Rande des Loughs, um diesen zu sichern. Die Überreste einiger der Forts können unter anderem bei Lenan Head, Dunree (heute ein Museum) oder nahe Buncrana besichtigt werden. Der Lough Swilly war auch einer der Treaty Ports, die nach der Bildung der Irischen Freistaates, durch den Anglo-Irischen Vertrag unter der Herrschaft der Engländer verblieben.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Sea_loughs_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Lough Swilly (Loch Súilí på irsk) er en fjord på nordkysten av øya Irland. Fjorden ligger i grevskapet Donegal i Republikken Irland, og skiller Inishowenhalvøya i vest fra resten av det nordlige Donegal. Ved fjordmunningen i nord ligger nesene Fanad Head og Dunaff Head. Blant tettstedene som ligger ved fjorden finner vi Buncrana på Inishowensiden og Rathmullan på vestsiden. Innerst i fjorden ligger Letterkenny. Ved to anledninger har fjorden spilt en viktig rolle i irsk historie. Det var fra Lough Swilly den såkalte jarlenes flukt fant sted, da Hugh O'Neill, 2. jarl av Tyrone og Rory O'Donnell, 1. jarl av Tyrconnel flyktet fra Irland i spetember 1607 etter et mislykket opprør. I oktober 1798 ble en fransk flåtestyrke som forsøkte å sette i land Wolfe Tone og tropper som skulle støtte det irske opprøret, men ble avskåret ved fjordmunningen. Fjorden ble brukt som et ankringssted for Royal Navy under første verdenskrig. Restene av befestninger som britene bygde for å beskytte fjorden kan fortsatt sees ved Lenan Head (i dag et museum) og utenfor Buncrana. Lough Swilly var en av tre britiske traktathavner etter den anglo-irske traktat fra 1921, og var under britisk kontroll som flåtebase til 1938.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">El Lough Swilly (irlandés, Loch Súilí, "Lago de Sombras" o el "Lago de los Ojos") en la República de Irlanda es un cuerpo hídrico tipo fiordo que queda entre el lado occidental de la península de Inishowen y la península de Fanad, en el condado de Donegal. En el extremo septentrional del lago están Fanad Head con su famoso faro y Dunaff Head. Las ciudades situadas en el lough incluyen Buncrana en Inishowen y Rathmullan en el lado occidental. En el extremo meridional del Lough queda Letterkenny. El lough es también famoso por su observación de la vida salvaje y buceo en los numerosos naufragios, incluyendo el SS Laurentic hundido por una mina alemana (posible torpedo), que se hundió con 3.211 lingotes de oro de la que se recuperaron 3.191. En el sur del lough una serie de islas fueron obtenidas por el sistema de pólderes y la tierra reclamada durante los años 1800 para la agricultura y el Lough Swilly a los terraplenes del Ferrocarril de Derry City. Estas tierras ganadas están hoy considerados como uno de los primeros humedales de Irlanda para la conservación de la naturaleza y la ornitología, que sostiene más de 4.000 cisnes cantores y miles de ánsares caretos, barnaclas cariblancos y carinegras, así como gansos comunes.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Lough Swilly</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Der Lough Swilly ist ein fjordartiger Meeresarm, der zwischen den Halbinseln Fanad im Westen und Inishowen im Osten im Norden der Republik Irland im County Donegal liegt. Er ist etwa 45 Kilometer lang und in der Mitte drei bis fünf Kilometer breit. Das Nordende des Lough Swilly säumen Fanad Head und Dunaff Head. Orte am Rande des Meeresarmes sind Buncrana im Osten und Rathmullan und Portsalon im Westen. Am Südende des Lough Swilly liegt die Stadt Letterkenny.</rdfs:comment>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lough_Swilly?oldid=482190476"/>
    <dbpprop:location rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ireland"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Lough Swilly (Irish: Loch Súilí, meaning "Lake of Shadows" or the "Lake of Eyes") in Ireland is a glacial fjord or sea inlet lying between the western side of the Inishowen Peninsula and the Fanad Peninsula, in County Donegal. Along with Carlingford Lough and Killary Harbour it is one of three known glacial fjords in Ireland. At the northern extremities of the lough are Fanad Head with its famous lighthouse and Dunaff Head.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:imageOcean xml:lang="en">Lough swilly.jpg</dbpprop:imageOcean>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Lough Swilly (Irish: Loch Súilí, meaning "Lake of Shadows" or the "Lake of Eyes") in Ireland is a glacial fjord or sea inlet lying between the western side of the Inishowen Peninsula and the Fanad Peninsula, in County Donegal. Along with Carlingford Lough and Killary Harbour it is one of three known glacial fjords in Ireland. At the northern extremities of the lough are Fanad Head with its famous lighthouse and Dunaff Head. Towns situated on the lough include Buncrana on Inishowen and Rathmullan on the western side. At the southern end of the Lough lies Letterkenny. The lough is also famous for its wildlife-watching (dolphins, porpoise, sea birds, migratory geese and swans) and diving on the numerous ship wrecks, including the SS Laurentic sunk by a German mine (possible torpedo), which went down with 3,211 ingots of gold of which 3,191 were recovered. In the south of the lough a number of islands (Burt, Inch, Coney, Big Isle) were poldered and the land reclaimed during the 19th century for agriculture and the Lough Swilly to Derry City Railway embankments. These reclaimed lands are now regarded as one of Ireland's premier wetlands for wildlife conservation and birdwatching, supporting over 4,000 Whooper Swans and thousands of Greenland white front, Barnacle, Greylagg and Brent geese.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <dbpprop:cities rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Inishowen"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Article_Feedback_5"/>
    <dbpprop:oceanName xml:lang="en">Lough Swilly</dbpprop:oceanName>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_ocean"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Лох-Суилли — один из трёх ледниковых фьордов в Ирландии, расположенный в графстве Донегол между полуостровами Инишоуэн и Фанад. Имеет в глубину 15-50 метров, судоходен. Высота прилива колеблется от 1,4 м до 3,7 м. На побережье залива есть как эффектные клифы, так и песчаные пляжи. Летом у залива живёт полярная крачка, зимой — темноклювая гагара; в заливе есть как обычные, так и серые тюлени, водятся лососи. Как место обитания различных видов животных залив защищён по ряду признаков; он входит в European Habitats and Birds Directive, Wetlands of International Importance (по Рамсарской конвенции), Natural Heritage Area (по законодательству Ирландии, акты 1976 и 2000 годов).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fb/Lough_swilly.jpg/200px-Lough_swilly.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Il Lough Swilly (Loch Súilí in gaelico irlandese) è una vasta e stretta insenatura dell'Irlanda settentrionale. Situata tra le penisole di Inishowen, ad est, e di Fanad, ad ovest, è una massa stretta di acqua salata che s'inoltra nelle coste del Donegal, nella Repubblica d'Irlanda. L'insenatura è delimitata nelle sue estremità settentrionali da Capo Fanad e da Capo Dunaff, mentre i principali centri abitati che vi si affacciano sono Buncrana, su Inishowen, e Rathmullan nella zona invece occidentale. La cittadina di Letterkenny, invece, non si affaccia sul Lough Swilly, ma è situata a breve distanza. A seconda delle maree, l'aspetto dell'insenatura cambia notevolmente, creando con l'acqua alta vari isolotti, tra cui Inch Island, talmente vicina ad Inishowen da esservi collegata con un ponte.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Лох-Суилли — один из трёх ледниковых фьордов в Ирландии, расположенный в графстве Донегол между полуостровами Инишоуэн и Фанад. Имеет в глубину 15-50 метров, судоходен. Высота прилива колеблется от 1,4 м до 3,7 м. На побережье залива есть как эффектные клифы, так и песчаные пляжи. Летом у залива живёт полярная крачка, зимой — темноклювая гагара; в заливе есть как обычные, так и серые тюлени, водятся лососи.</rdfs:comment>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">55.15377 -7.53662</grs:point>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Lough Swilly (iiriksi Loch Súilí "Varjojen järvi" tai "Silmien järvi") on 25 mailia (noin 40 kilometriä) pitkä jääkautinen vuono tai lahti Irlannissa Inishowenin niemimaan ja Fanadin niemimaan välissä Donegalin kreivikunnassa. Se on Carlingford Loughin ja Killary Harbourin ohella yksi Irlannin kolmesta jääkautisesta vuonosta.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:oceanName xml:lang="en">Loch Súilí</dbpprop:oceanName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Il Lough Swilly (Loch Súilí in gaelico irlandese) è una vasta e stretta insenatura dell'Irlanda settentrionale. Situata tra le penisole di Inishowen, ad est, e di Fanad, ad ovest, è una massa stretta di acqua salata che s'inoltra nelle coste del Donegal, nella Repubblica d'Irlanda.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Lough Swilly (iiriksi Loch Súilí "Varjojen järvi" tai "Silmien järvi") on 25 mailia (noin 40 kilometriä) pitkä jääkautinen vuono tai lahti Irlannissa Inishowenin niemimaan ja Fanadin niemimaan välissä Donegalin kreivikunnassa. Se on Carlingford Loughin ja Killary Harbourin ohella yksi Irlannin kolmesta jääkautisesta vuonosta.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Lough Swilly – zatoka podobna do fiordu, leżąca w Irlandii pomiędzy wschodnią częścią półwyspu Inishowen w hrabstwie Donegal i resztą północnego Donegalu. Na północnych krańcach półwyspu znajdują się przylądki Inishowen Head i Dunaff Head. Miasta położone nad lough (irlandzkie pojęcie oznaczające m. in. zatokę) to Buncrana i Rathmullan. Na południowym krańcu Lough Swilly leży Letterkenny. Zatoka była używana jako port przez Royal Navy podczas I wojny światowej.</rdfs:comment>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">55.1538</geo:lat>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-7.53662</geo:long>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">El Lough Swilly (irlandés, Loch Súilí, "Lago de Sombras" o el "Lago de los Ojos") en la República de Irlanda es un cuerpo hídrico tipo fiordo que queda entre el lado occidental de la península de Inishowen y la península de Fanad, en el condado de Donegal. En el extremo septentrional del lago están Fanad Head con su famoso faro y Dunaff Head. Las ciudades situadas en el lough incluyen Buncrana en Inishowen y Rathmullan en el lado occidental. En el extremo meridional del Lough queda Letterkenny.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Le Lough Swilly est une espèce de profond fjord situé au nord de l'Irlande entre la péninsule d'Inishowen à l'est et la péninsule de Fanad à l'ouest, dans le comté de Donegal. A l'extrémité nord du Lough se trouvent le cap Fanad avec son célèbre phare et le cap Dunaff. Sur ses rives se trouvent les villes de Buncrana à l'est et Rathmullan sur le côté ouest. À l'extrémité sud du Lough se trouve Letterkenny.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Le Lough Swilly est une espèce de profond fjord situé au nord de l'Irlande entre la péninsule d'Inishowen à l'est et la péninsule de Fanad à l'ouest, dans le comté de Donegal. A l'extrémité nord du Lough se trouvent le cap Fanad avec son célèbre phare et le cap Dunaff. Sur ses rives se trouvent les villes de Buncrana à l'est et Rathmullan sur le côté ouest. À l'extrémité sud du Lough se trouve Letterkenny. De 1922 à 1938, le site de Lough Swilly constitua l'une des trois bases militaires souveraines britanniques établies lors du Treaty ports dans l'État libre d'Irlande. Le Lough est célèbre pour l'observation de sa faune (dauphins, marsouins, oiseaux de mer, oies et cygnes migrateurs) et la plongée sur de nombreuses épaves de navires, y compris les SS Laurentic coulé par une mine allemande (possible torpille), qui a coulé avec lingots d'or dont ont été récupérés. Dans le sud du Lough un certain nombre d'îles (Burt, Inch, Coney, Grand Isle) ont été poldérisées et les terrain mis en culture dans les années 1800 et remblayés pour la voie de chemin de fer reliant Lough Swilly à Derry City. Ces terres récupérées sont désormais considérées comme l'une des zones humides les plus importantes d'Irlande pour la conservation de la faune et de la flore, abritant plus de cygnes sauvages, des milliers d'Oies rieuses, Barnacles, Oies cendrées et Bernaches cravants.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lough_Swilly"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Lough Swilly</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:inflow rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/River_Swilly"/>
  </rdf:Description>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://mpii.de/yago/resource/Lough_Swilly">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lough_Swilly"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
