<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Marcus_Manlius">
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus (died 384 BC) was consul of the Roman Republic in 392 BC. He was the brother of Aulus Manlius Capitolinus. The Manlii were a patrician gens. During the Gallic siege of Rome in 390 (or 387) BC, the account of which became partly mythologized, Marcus Manlius held out for months with a small garrison on the citadel (arx), while the rest of Rome was abandoned. When Gauls under the command of Brennus were attempting to scale the Capitoline, Manlius was roused by the cackling of the sacred geese, rushed to the spot, and threw down the foremost assailants. After the sack of Rome left the plebeians in pitiful condition, they were forced to borrow large sums of money from the patricians, and once again became the poor debtor class of Rome. Manlius, the hero of Rome, fought for them. Livy says, with some inaccuracy, that he was the first patrician to act as a populist . Seeing a centurion led to prison for debt, he freed him with his own money, and even sold his estate to relieve other poor debtors, while he accused the Senate of embezzling public money. He was charged with aspiring to kingly power, and condemned by the comitia, but not until the assembly had adjourned to a place outside the walls, where they could no longer see the Capitol which he had saved. The Senate condemned him to death in 385 BC, and he was thrown from the Tarpeian Rock one year later. He is considered the second martyr in the cause of social reform at Rome. His house on the Capitoline Hill was razed, and the Senate decreed that no patrician should live there henceforth. The Manlii themselves resolved that no patrician Manlius should bear the name of Marcus. According to Mommsen, the story of the saving of the Capitol was a later invention to justify his cognomen, which may be better explained by his domicile. Preceded byLucius Lucretius Tricipitinus Flavus (Suffect) and Servius Sulpicius Camerinus (Suffect) Consul of the Roman Republicwith Lucius Valerius Potitus Poplicola 392 BC Succeeded byConsular tribunes References</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus byl konzul a patricij římské republiky. V době gallské války bránil v Římě Kapitol, který zůstal nedobyt (odtud získal přezdívku Capitolinus). Krátce po skončení gálské války těžce nesl úspěchy Marca Furia Camilla, který se zasloužil o vítězství nad Gally a kvůli svému pocitu nedocenění přešel Capitolinus od patricijů k plebejům. Zastával se právních pří plebejů, které se týkaly dluhů způsobené válkou a obnovou zničeného Říma Gally. Sám vysvobozoval tyto dlužníky placením jejich dlužné částky, což mu přineslo velikou oblibu u plebejů. Poté začal veřejně vystupovat proti senátu a obvinil jej z toho, že se snaží zotročit plebeje. Ve stejné době, kdy měl veliký vliv mezi plebeji, je senátem předvolán k soudu a odsouzen za pokus převratu k trestu smrti. Podle historika Livia Marcus Manlius Capitolinus chtěl plebeje využít pouze k tomu, aby revolucí svrhl senát a nastolil královskou vládu.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Marcus Manlius</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Marcus_Manlius_Capitolinus"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Marc Manli Capitolí (Marcus Manlius T. F. A. N. Capitolinus) fou un magistrat romà. Fou cònsol el 392 aC amb Luci Valeri Pòtit i va fer la guerra als eques, rebent el dret d'ovació mentre el seu col·lega va rebre els honors del triomf. Una pesta va afectar la ciutat i els dos cònsols en van ser afectats i van haver de renunciar i es va nomenar un interrei. El 390 aC els gals van entrar a Roma i l'endemà van atacar el Capitoli. Marc Manli que vivia justament a la vora del Capitoli, va reunir tota la gent que va poder i va rebutjar als atacants i va resistir un temps de setge fins que els gals se'n van anar. El 387 aC fou nomenat interrei (inter rex). El 385 aC va abandonar la seva consideració de patrici i va entrar als plebeus. Es diu que tenia el projecte d'esdevenir tirà o rei de Roma i que es va voler aprofitar de la força revolucionaria dels plebeus. Els patricis van nomenar dictador a Aule Corneli Cos. En un moment, mentre el dictador era absent de Roma, Manli va intentar utilitzar la violència i es va comportar com un demagog. El dictador va tornar a la ciutat i va amonestar a Manli al que va cridar davant seu; Manli s'hi va presentar acompanyat d'un nombrós grup de plebeus però el dictador no es va atemorir i el va detenir i empresonar per sedició. Els plebeus van manifestar el seu dol però no van fer rés contra el dictador. El senat va mirar d'apaivagar la indignació dels plebeus amb repartiments de terres però això fou interpretat com un suborn pels plebeus i va escalfar els ànims fins al punt que Manli va haver de ser alliberat per evitar l'esclat de la revolució. Amb això les peticions dels plebeus encara van créixer més. El 384 aC, com que no hi havia cap amenaça exterior, Manli va ordenar l'aixecament dels plebeus, però els tribuns consulars van actuar i van agafar Manli que fou acusat d'alta traïció i portat davant el poble al camp de Mart i després a la cova Petelínia prop de la porta Nomentana (ja que des del Camp de Mart es veia el Capitoli que Manli havia salvat). Fou condemnat a mort i tirat des de la roca Tarpeia. La gens Mànlia va considerar que hi havia portat la desgràcia i va decidir que en el futur cap més membre portaria el nom de Marc.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Marcus_Manlius_Capitolinus"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Marcus_Manlius"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Марк_Манлий_Капитолин"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus byl konzul a patricij římské republiky. V době gallské války bránil v Římě Kapitol, který zůstal nedobyt (odtud získal přezdívku Capitolinus). Krátce po skončení gálské války těžce nesl úspěchy Marca Furia Camilla, který se zasloužil o vítězství nad Gally a kvůli svému pocitu nedocenění přešel Capitolinus od patricijů k plebejům. Zastával se právních pří plebejů, které se týkaly dluhů způsobené válkou a obnovou zničeného Říma Gally.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Marcus Manlius dit parfois « Capitolinus », a été consul à Rome. Pendant l'invasion gauloise, les Romains s’étaient réfugiés dans la citadelle du Capitole. Une nuit, les Gaulois voulurent entrer dans la citadelle. Ils ne firent aucun bruit et ne réveillèrent personne, mais une fois en haut de la citadelle, les oies consacrées à Junon, aussi appelées « oies du Capitole », que l'on avait épargnées malgré la disette, s’éveillèrent et poussèrent des cris, qui réveillèrent le guerrier Marcus Manlius. Il cria pour réveiller les soldats romains, et pendant que ceux-ci s'agitaient en essayant de comprendre ce qui se passait, Marcus Manlius donna un coup de bouclier au premier Gaulois ayant posé le pied sur le sommet de la citadelle et le renversa. Celui-ci tomba et entraîna tous ses compagnons avec lui dans sa chute. Marcus Manlius fut alors considéré comme un des héros du dévouement à la République romaine, tout comme Horatius Coclès, Caius Mucius Scaevola ou encore Lacus Curtius. Cet épisode mythologique est relaté chez Tite-Live : Histoire romaine, Livre V, 47 Mais plus tard, Marcus Manlius, ambitieux, fut accusé par le dictateur Camille de vouloir se faire roi (donc considéré comme un traître à sa patrie) ainsi que d'avoir détourné une partie de l'or gaulois et fut condamné à être précipité du haut de la roche Tarpéienne.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:before xml:lang="en">Lucius Lucretius Tricipitinus Flavus  and Servius Sulpicius Camerinus</dbpprop:before>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Марк Манлий Капитолин — римский консул, герой обороны Капитолия. В 390 году до н. э. галлы напали на Рим и захватили город. Только на капитолийском холме укрылась часть жителей, которая наотрез отказывалась сдаться врагам. Галлы же, не способные взять хорошо защищенный холм, но и не желавшие уходить ни с чем, предприняли отчаянную попытку ночного штурма. Часть варваров под покровом ночи должна была взобраться по отвесной части холма и, убив стражу, открыть ворота остальным силам.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Марк Манлій Капітолін</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Succession_box"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it"></rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:4th-century_BC_Romans"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">マルクス・マンリウス・カピトリヌス（ラテン語: Marcus Manlius Capitolinus, 生没年不詳）は、共和政ローマで紀元前392年に執政官をつとめた人物。 伝承によると、紀元前390年のアッリアの戦い後ローマはブレンヌス率いるガリア人に包囲され、敵がカピトルの丘をよじ登ろうしていた時、マンリウスは聖なるあひるが鳴くのを耳にして目覚め、その場に急行、敵をなぎ倒したと言う。「カピトリヌス」の名はその時の功績によるものとテオドール・モムゼンは考えている。 そして数年後、彼は元老院で議員たちが公金を横領していると告発していた時、あるケントゥリオが債務により牢につながれているのを目にして、自らの懐の金で彼を解放し、また貧しい債務者のために自らの土地を手放したという。しかしながら彼は王に近い権力を手に入れようとしたということで告発され、彼の救ったカピトルの丘がもはや見えないところで民会が延期されると民会でも非難された。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus (died 384 BC) was consul of the Roman Republic in 392 BC. He was the brother of Aulus Manlius Capitolinus. The Manlii were a patrician gens. During the Gallic siege of Rome in 390 (or 387) BC, the account of which became partly mythologized, Marcus Manlius held out for months with a small garrison on the citadel (arx), while the rest of Rome was abandoned.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Марк Манлій Капітолін (д/н — † 384 рік до н.  е. ) — політичний та військовий діяч ранньої Римської республіки.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:after rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Tribuni_militum_consulari_potestate"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus war ein römischer Patrizier aus der gens Manlii. Er war Consul im Jahr 392 v. Chr.. Mit seinem Amtskollegen Lucius Valerius Potitus soll er einen erfolgreichen Krieg gegen die Äquer geführt haben, wofür er eine Ovatio erhalten habe und Valerius Potitus einen Triumph. Der Überlieferung nach hat er das Kapitol vor einem nächtlichen Angriff der Gallier gerettet. Nachdem die Römer im Jahr 387 v. Chr. eine vernichtende Niederlage an der Allia gegen die Gallier hinnehmen mussten, drangen die Gallier unter Führung des Brennus nach Rom ein und zündeten große Teile der Stadt an. Viele Bewohner flüchteten vor den plündernden Angreifern. Einige davon flohen zusammen mit Manlius auf das Kapitol, den Burgberg Roms. Der Sage nach verrieten schnatternde Gänse die Angreifer, die den Berg hochschlichen. Im Jahr 385 v. Chr. wurde Manlius angeklagt, nach dem Königstitel zu streben und deswegen ein Jahr später hingerichtet. Antoine de La Fosse hat unter dem Titel Manlius Capitolinus eine Tragödie geschrieben.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Marcus Manlius dit parfois « Capitolinus », a été consul à Rome. Pendant l'invasion gauloise, les Romains s’étaient réfugiés dans la citadelle du Capitole. Une nuit, les Gaulois voulurent entrer dans la citadelle.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus was een Romeinse patricische politicus die leefde in het begin van het begin van de 4e eeuw v. Chr.. Hij was consul in 392 v. Chr. en speelde een heldhaftige leidersrol in de legende van de Ganzen van het Capitool. Hij wordt door de traditie beschouwd als de tweede martelaar in de strijd van de Romeinse plebejers voor hun sociale ontvoogding.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/RomanRepuBlicanConsuls"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Marc Manli Capitolí (Marcus Manlius T. F. A. N. Capitolinus) fou un magistrat romà. Fou cònsol el 392 aC amb Luci Valeri Pòtit i va fer la guerra als eques, rebent el dret d'ovació mentre el seu col·lega va rebre els honors del triomf. Una pesta va afectar la ciutat i els dos cònsols en van ser afectats i van haver de renunciar i es va nomenar un interrei. El 390 aC els gals van entrar a Roma i l'endemà van atacar el Capitoli.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpprop:years rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">392</dbpprop:years>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Manlius Capitolinus, Marcus</dbpprop:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Marco_Manlio_Capitolino"/>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">Consul of the Roman Republic</dbpprop:title>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marcus_Manlius"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus war ein römischer Patrizier aus der gens Manlii. Er war Consul im Jahr 392 v. Chr.. Mit seinem Amtskollegen Lucius Valerius Potitus soll er einen erfolgreichen Krieg gegen die Äquer geführt haben, wofür er eine Ovatio erhalten habe und Valerius Potitus einen Triumph. Der Überlieferung nach hat er das Kapitol vor einem nächtlichen Angriff der Gallier gerettet. Nachdem die Römer im Jahr 387 v. Chr.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.021t_m"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Marcus Manlius Capitolinus was een Romeinse patricische politicus die leefde in het begin van het begin van de 4e eeuw v. Chr.. Hij was consul in 392 v. Chr. en speelde een heldhaftige leidersrol in de legende van de Ganzen van het Capitool. Hij wordt door de traditie beschouwd als de tweede martelaar in de strijd van de Romeinse plebejers voor hun sociale ontvoogding.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">マルクス・マンリウス・カピトリヌス（ラテン語: Marcus Manlius Capitolinus, 生没年不詳）は、共和政ローマで紀元前392年に執政官をつとめた人物。 伝承によると、紀元前390年のアッリアの戦い後ローマはブレンヌス率いるガリア人に包囲され、敵がカピトルの丘をよじ登ろうしていた時、マンリウスは聖なるあひるが鳴くのを耳にして目覚め、その場に急行、敵をなぎ倒したと言う。「カピトリヌス」の名はその時の功績によるものとテオドール・モムゼンは考えている。 そして数年後、彼は元老院で議員たちが公金を横領していると告発していた時、あるケントゥリオが債務により牢につながれているのを目にして、自らの懐の金で彼を解放し、また貧しい債務者のために自らの土地を手放したという。しかしながら彼は王に近い権力を手に入れようとしたということで告発され、彼の救ったカピトルの丘がもはや見えないところで民会が延期されると民会でも非難された。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it"></dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Manlii"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/マルクス・マンリウス・カピトリヌス"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Marc Manli Capitolí II</rdfs:label>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Marcus_Manlius?oldid=458834975"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Марк Манлий Капитолин — римский консул, герой обороны Капитолия. В 390 году до н. э. галлы напали на Рим и захватили город. Только на капитолийском холме укрылась часть жителей, которая наотрез отказывалась сдаться врагам. Галлы же, не способные взять хорошо защищенный холм, но и не желавшие уходить ни с чем, предприняли отчаянную попытку ночного штурма. Часть варваров под покровом ночи должна была взобраться по отвесной части холма и, убив стражу, открыть ворота остальным силам. Но как только галлы стали подниматься на холм, их услышали священные гуси в храме Юноны и подняли сильный шум. Первым проснувшимся от гогота был Марк Манлий, он вступил в схватку сбросив поднявшегося галла со скалы. Из-за возникшего шума проснулись другие солдаты и уснувшие часовые, таким образом отбив вражескую атаку. Данный подвиг сделал из Манлия народного героя и его по праву стали называть Капитолийским. Он имел много наград и был очень почитаем среди плебса. Впоследствии Манлий, будучи патрицием, выступил в защиту плебеев и, обвиненный патрициями в попытке восстановления царской власти, был сброшен с Тарпейской скалы.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Марк Манлій Капітолін (д/н — † 384 рік до н.  е. ) — політичний та військовий діяч ранньої Римської республіки.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:384_BC_deaths"/>
    <dbpprop:years xml:lang="en">with Lucius Valerius Potitus Poplicola</dbpprop:years>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Roman_Republican_consuls"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Marcus_Manlius_Capitolinus"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
