<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_University">
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/University"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpprop:endowment xml:lang="en">US $2.827 billion</dbpprop:endowment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">New York University (NYU) er et privat, ikke-kommersielt forskningsbasert universitet i New York i USA. Den største campusen ligger i Greenwich Village i Manhattan. Universitetet ble grunnlagt i 1831 av Albert Gallatin og en gruppe prominente newyorkere og er idag det største private ikke-kommersielle universitetet i USA. Det har også en avdeling på Bedford Square i London, i bygningen som før var boligen til Lord Chancellor i Storbritannia, 6 Bedford Square.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:gurWorld rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">22</dbpprop:gurWorld>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">Articles and topics related to New York University</dbpprop:title>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">New York University (NYU) is de grootste particuliere universiteit van de Verenigde Staten. De universiteit, in 1831 opgericht door Albert Gallatin, is gevestigd in Greenwich Village in de stad New York. De hoofdcampus bevindt zich voornamelijk rond Washington Square Park en Broadway. De universiteit heeft een eigen hospitaal en herbergt de Stern School of Business.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:thesW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">44</dbpprop:thesW>
    <dbpprop:arwuNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">21</dbpprop:arwuNu>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Die New York University (NYU) ist eine Universität in New York City, Vereinigte Staaten. Die Universität ist die größte private Universität der Vereinigten Staaten mit insgesamt 54.919 Studenten (Herbst 2009) – davon 21.636 im Bachelor-, 21.766 im Master- bzw. Promotionsstudium oder im Berufsdoktorat (Medizin/Jura). Sie verfügte im Jahr 2010 über ein Gesamtbudget von ca. 2 Mrd.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:usnwrSoc rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">14</dbpprop:usnwrSoc>
    <dbpprop:calendar xml:lang="en">Semester</dbpprop:calendar>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/뉴욕_대학교"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_US_university_ranking"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">New York University (NYU) är ett universitet i USA, beläget i City of New York i delstaten New York. Universitetet grundades 1831 av Albert Gallatin. Campuset ligger i stadsdelen Greenwich Village på Manhattan. Wikimedia Commons har media som rör Title=New York University;ns=0/Main/;language:wiki=sv,locale=svBilder &amp; media 		 			NYU's campuses. svg 			 NYU:s olika universitetsområden 			 		 		 			NYU's Bobst library-2. jpg 			 Bobst Library, bibliotek 			 		 		 			NYU-Gallatin School. jpg 			 Gallatin School 			 		 		 			Main buildingNYU. JPG 			 Huvudbyggnaden 			 		 		 			NYU Hockey. jpg 			 NYU:s ishockeylag 			 		 		 			NYU Maison francaise. gif 			 Maison francaise 			 		 		 			NYU trolley. jpg 			 Campus-buss</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_City"/>
    <dbpprop:students rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">50917</dbpprop:students>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Collegiate_Athletic_Association"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Uniwersytet Nowojorski (ang. New York University) (NYU), uniwersytet w Nowym Jorku, największa szkoła wyższa w Nowym Jorku i jedna z największych w USA. Główny kampus uniwersytetu znajduje się w Greenwich Village na Manhattanie. NYU został założony w 1831 przez Alberta Gallatina i grupę prominentnych nowojorczyków, stał się największym prywatnym uniwersytetem non-profit w Stanach. Uczelnia składa się z 14 szkół, college'ów i wydziałów skupionych w 6 częściach Manhattanu. NYU posiada także oddziały zagraniczne w Londynie, Paryżu, Pradze, Berlinie, Ghanie, Madrycie i Szanghaju.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:usnwrEd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">15</dbpprop:usnwrEd>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_University"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Middle_States_Association_of_Colleges_and_Schools"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-university-noun-2"/>
    <dbpprop:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Sexton"/>
    <dbpprop:usnwrPsycc rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">29</dbpprop:usnwrPsycc>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">L’université de New York est une université privée américaine située à New York. Son campus principal est situé dans le quartier de Greenwich Village dans le borough de Manhattan. Fondée en 1831 par l’homme politique américain Albert Gallatin et un groupe de New-Yorkais, elle est devenue la plus grande université privée à but non lucratif du pays, avec un nombre total d’étudiants supérieur à . Elle regroupe quinze établissements (Schools, Colleges et Divisions) répartis sur six campus à travers Manhattan.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:publictransit rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eighth_Street_%E2%80%93_New_York_University_(BMT_Broadway_Line)"/>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Division_III_(NCAA)"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Нью-Йоркський університет</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">La Universidad de Nueva York, es una universidad privada ubicado en Nueva York, Estados Unidos (no debe confundirse con la Universidad de la Ciudad de Nueva York). Fue fundada en 1831 por Albert Gallatin y un grupo de neoyorquinos. NYU se ha convertido en una de las mayores universidades privadas de los Estados Unidos y del mundo, con una población estudiantil de 39.408 alumnos (sin incluir los 12.526 estudiantes que participan en programas que no otorgan créditos). La Universidad de Nueva York ha crecido hasta comprender actualmente 14 escuelas e instituciones asociadas. Cuenta con 6 grandes centros en Manhattan y con instalaciones propias en Londres, París, Tel Aviv, Buenos Aires, Florencia, Praga, Madrid, Berlín, Accra y Shanghái.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:postgrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">18990</dbpprop:postgrad>
    <dbpprop:arwuSci rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">76</dbpprop:arwuSci>
    <dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour xml:lang="en">Violet and White</dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour>
    <dbpprop:alumni rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">350000</dbpprop:alumni>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">New York University (NYU) is de grootste particuliere universiteit van de Verenigde Staten. De universiteit, in 1831 opgericht door Albert Gallatin, is gevestigd in Greenwich Village in de stad New York. De hoofdcampus bevindt zich voornamelijk rond Washington Square Park en Broadway. De universiteit heeft een eigen hospitaal en herbergt de Stern School of Business.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">40.73</geo:lat>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvW_sZZwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidade_de_Nova_Iorque"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ニューヨーク大学 （New York University, NYU）は、アメリカ合衆国、ニューヨーク市にある私立総合大学である。校訓は、Perstare et praestare "To persevere and to excel"。 ニューヨーク市立大学（CUNY）、ニューヨーク州立大学（SUNY）等との混同に注意。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Urban_area"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_university"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">New York University (NYU) je soukromá, výzkumná univerzita amerického města New York. Její hlavní kampus se nachází v Greenwich Village na Manhattanu. Byla založena v roce 1831 a jde o největší soukromou, nevýdělečnou instituci poskytující vyšší vzdělání v USA s více než 50 000 studenty. NYU je organizovaná do 16 škol, fakult a kateder, které se nacházejí v 6 střediscích na Manhattanu, Brooklynu a Bronxu. Poskytuje možnost studia v zahraničí v Londýně, Paříži, Florencii, Praze, Madridu, Berlíně, Akře, Šanghaji, Buenos Aires a Tel Avivu včetně školy Tisch School of the Arts v Singapuru. V r. 2010 dojde k otevření dalších ve Washington D.C. a Abu Dhabi.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0bwfn"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Collegiate_Athletic_Association"/>
    <dbpprop:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Urban_area"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">New Yorkin yliopisto (engl. New York University) on yksityinen, voittoatuottamaton ja uskontokunnista riippumaton tutkimusyliopisto New Yorkissa, Yhdysvalloissa. Sitä pidetään yleisesti yhtenä maailman parhaista yliopistoista, ja sen useimmat koulut sijoittuvat kansallisessa vertailussa kymmenen parhaan joukkoon omilla aloillaan. New York University on perustettu 1831, alkuperäiseltä nimeltään University of the City of New York. Sen tunnusväri on violetti ja rehtorina toimii John Sexton. Yli 50 000 opiskelijallaan NYU on maan suurin yksityinen voittoatuottamaton yliopisto. Monien muiden tunnettujen yliopistojen tapaan myös NYU on viime aikoina avannut kansainvälisiä kampuksia eri puolilla maailmaa. NYU on newyorkilaisen (liberaalin ja moniarvoisen) elämäntavan sekä kaikenlaisen edistyksellisyyden äänenkannattaja. Tästä syystä yliopisto on elimellinen osa kaupungin arkipäivää monin tavoin. Yliopiston jokakeväinen valmistumisjuhla järjestetään perinteisesti Washington Square Parkissa, julkisessa puistossa. Myös yksittäisen koulun todistusten jako voi tapahtua poissa yliopiston tiloista, esim. Radio City Music Hallissa joka on kaupallisen taide-elämän keskus. Monista amerikkalaisista yliopistoista poiketen New York Universityllä ei ole omaa selkeästi rajattua ja muusta kaupungista eristettyä kampusaluetta vaan toimipisteet ovat sijoittuneet ympäri Manhattania. Alueellisesti NYUn perinteinen keskus, ja siten eräänlainen pääkampus, löytyy Washington Square Parkin ympäristöstä Greenwich Villagessa, jossa lähes kaikki rakennukset ovat NYUn tai siihen liittyvien instituutioiden hallinnassa. Täällä sijaitsevat muun muassa Bobst library, yliopiston opiskelija- ja muita palveluja tarjoava Kimmel Center, oikeustieteellinen tiedekunta, Steinhardt School sekä Stern Business School. Muita pienempiä toimipisteitä ja opiskelijoille suunnattuja asuntoloita on ympäri kaupunkia mm. Union Squarella ja Murray Hillillä. Syynä perinteisen kampuksen puuttumiseen on yliopiston ikä – yliopisto kehittyi vähitellen kasvavan kaupungin mukana, jolloin siitä tuli osa aikansa kaupunkikuvaa - lähinnä West Villagea. Yksityistä, ja tästä syystä arvostetumpaa, New York Universityä (NYU) ei tule sekoittaa suurempaan City University of New Yorkiin (CUNY), joka on New York Cityn alueella toimiva julkisista (public) varoista rahoitettu yliopistojärjestelmä. Entisiä opiskelijoita ovat mm. Michael C. Hall, John F. Kennedy, Jr. , Oliver Stone, Wayne Shorter ja John Woodruff.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CollegeOrUniversity"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">L'Università di New York (New York University o NYU) è un'università privata con sede a New York City. È considerata una delle università più famose e prestigiose del mondo. La sede principale della NYU si trova nel Greenwich Village di Manhattan. Fondata nel 1831 è una delle più grandi istituzioni private di istruzione postsuperiore negli Stati Uniti. L'università è organizzata in 18 facoltà, collegi ed istituti situati non solo a New York tra Manhattan e Brooklyn, ma in tutto il mondo. Essa offre ai propri studenti la possibilità di studiare all'estero presso i campus a Londra, Parigi, Firenze, Praga, Madrid, Berlino, Accra, Shanghai, Buenos Aires e Tel Aviv, oltre al campus di Singapore della Tisch School of the Arts e un campus globale di arti libere ad Abu Dhabi che è stato aperto a settembre 2010. Con circa 12.500 residenti, la NYU è il settimo più grande sistema di residenze universitarie negli Stati Uniti e il più grande tra le università private. Alcune delle prime fraternità del paese si sono formate proprio presso la NYU. Le squadre sportive dell'università sono chiamate "the Violets" (le Viole), in cui nome proviene dal colore principale, viola, del logo dell'università. La mascotte della scuola è stata modellata a partire dalla lince. Quasi tutte le squadre sportive presso la NYU partecipano alla NCAA Division III e alla University Athletic Association. Nonostante abbia numerosi giocatori di football nella All-American, la New York University non possiede una propria squadra di calcio dal 1960. L'università è regolarmente classificata come una delle istituzioni accademiche più prestigiose nel mondo. Conta 33 premi Nobel, tre vincitori del Premio Abel, 16 vincitori del Premio Pulitzer, 21 vincitori del premio Academy, Emmy, Grammy, e Tony Award. Tra le facoltà vi è inoltre il prestigioso Polytechnic Institute of New York University che è parte integrante dell'università dal 2008. Dai 158 iscritti del 1831, la NYU conta oltre 40.000 studenti divisi tra i 14 istituti e facoltà nei diversi quartieri di Manhattan e Brooklyn. Dai 14 conferenzieri degli inizi (tra cui l'inventore Samuel Morse), ora insegnano a tempo pieno oltre 3.100 professori.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:qsW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">44</dbpprop:qsW>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">New York University (NYU) is a private, nonsectarian research university based in New York City, USA. NYU's main campus is situated in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of Lower Manhattan. Founded in 1831, NYU is one of the largest private nonprofit institutions of American higher education. NYU was elected to the Association of American Universities in 1950.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/EducationalInstitution"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidad_de_Nueva_York"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">New York University</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:cmup rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">24</dbpprop:cmup>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ニューヨーク大学"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_University"/>
    <dbpprop:undergrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">19401</dbpprop:undergrad>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ニューヨーク大学 （New York University, NYU）は、アメリカ合衆国、ニューヨーク市にある私立総合大学である。校訓は、Perstare et praestare "To persevere and to excel"。 ニューヨーク市立大学（CUNY）、ニューヨーク州立大学（SUNY）等との混同に注意。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuSoc rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">11</dbpprop:arwuSoc>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.nyu.edu"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Нью-Йоркський університет (скорочено NYU) — приватний світський університет у Нью-Йорку, основний кампус якого розташований у Грінвич-Віллидж в одній з частин Манхеттена. Заснований 1831 року, і на цей час є найбільшим приватним некомерційним закладом вищої освіти в США, у якому навчається більш 50 000 студентів.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:state xml:lang="en">collapsed</dbpprop:state>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Universitat de Nova York</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Die New York University (NYU) ist eine Universität in New York City, Vereinigte Staaten. Die Universität ist die größte private Universität der Vereinigten Staaten mit insgesamt 54.919 Studenten (Herbst 2009) – davon 21.636 im Bachelor-, 21.766 im Master- bzw. Promotionsstudium oder im Berufsdoktorat (Medizin/Jura). Sie verfügte im Jahr 2010 über ein Gesamtbudget von ca. 2 Mrd. USD ohne Berücksichtigung des Klinikums (NYU Langone Medical Center) und der Medizin (NYU School of Medicine) – ein Mehrfaches der Summen, die deutschen Universitäten ähnlicher Größe wie der Universität zu Köln oder der Ludwig-Maximilians-Universität München jeweils zur Verfügung stehen. Die NYU ist Mitglied der Association of American Universities, eines seit 1900 bestehenden Verbundes führender forschungsintensiver nordamerikanischer Universitäten. Der Campus der Universität liegt im Greenwich Village in Manhattan, New York. Die Universität besteht aus 14 Fakultäten und Colleges. Die Universität ist besonders bekannt für ihre wirtschaftswissenschaftlichen Fakultäten, Volkswirtschaft, Jura, Medizin, Informatik, Mathematik, Philosophie, Politikwissenschaften und Neurowissenschaften.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">220</dbpprop:logo>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Nova York, o New York University en anglès (es fa servir l'acrònim NYU), és una institució privada d'educació universitària i investigació, i una de les més prestigioses del món. Establerta a Nova York, Estats Units el 1831 per Albert Gallatin i un grup de destacats novaiorquesos, la NYU ha esdevingut la major universitat privada sense ànim de lucre dels Estats Units, amb una població universitària de 39.408 estudiants (sense incloure els 12.526 estudiants que participen en programes que no atorguen crèdits). La Nova York University ha crescut fins a comprendre actualment 14 escoles i institucions associades. Compta amb 6 grans centres a Manhattan i amb instal·lacions pròpies a Londres, París, Florència, Praga, Madrid, Berlín, Accra i Shanghai.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Perstare et praestare (Latin)</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <dbpedia-owl:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/John_Sexton"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Organization"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Università_di_New_York"/>
    <dbpprop:chairman rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Martin_Lipton"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5128634/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">50917</dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:chairman rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Martin_Lipton"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">29</dbpprop:arwuW>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">New York University (NYU) är ett universitet i USA, beläget i City of New York i delstaten New York. Universitetet grundades 1831 av Albert Gallatin. Campuset ligger i stadsdelen Greenwich Village på Manhattan. Wikimedia Commons har media som rör Title=New York University;ns=0/Main/;language:wiki=sv,locale=svBilder &amp; media 		 			NYU's campuses. svg 			 NYU:s olika universitetsområden 			 		 		 			NYU's Bobst library-2.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Kohn_Pedersen_Fox_buildings"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">40.73 -73.995</grs:point>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:National_Association_of_Independent_Colleges_and_Universities_members"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">뉴욕 대학교는 미국의 뉴욕 주 뉴욕에 있는 사립대학이다. 뉴욕 대학교는 1831년에 창립된 역사깊은 학교이며, 영화 전공의 티쉬 예술대(Tisch School of the Arts)와 세계 최상위권 비지니스 대학과 대학원으로 알려진 스턴 경영대(Stern School Of Business), 또한 하버드, 스탠포드 등과 순위를 겨루는 법과대학원(School of Law)으로 유명하다. 뉴욕대가 위치한 뉴욕 시의 맨해튼 남부인 그레내치 빌리지 지역은 첨단 예술을 자랑하는 곳으로, 뉴욕 중의 뉴욕이라 할 수 있으며, 각종 화랑과 공연장이 밀집되어 있어 연중 활기가 넘치는 곳이다. 현재 교수진에 노벨상 수상자 3명을 보유하고 있으며, 50개 이상의 다양한 연구소에 많은 학생들이 참여할 수 있도록 많은 기회를 제공해 주고 있다. 총 14개의 단과대학에서 2,500 여개의 코스를 제공하고 있으며 교수와 학생 비율은 1:11 이다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.nyu.edu/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">L'Università di New York (New York University o NYU) è un'università privata con sede a New York City. È considerata una delle università più famose e prestigiose del mondo. La sede principale della NYU si trova nel Greenwich Village di Manhattan. Fondata nel 1831 è una delle più grandi istituzioni private di istruzione postsuperiore negli Stati Uniti. L'università è organizzata in 18 facoltà, collegi ed istituti situati non solo a New York tra Manhattan e Brooklyn, ma in tutto il mondo.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">New York University (NYU) er et privat, ikke-kommersielt forskningsbasert universitet i New York i USA. Den største campusen ligger i Greenwich Village i Manhattan. Universitetet ble grunnlagt i 1831 av Albert Gallatin og en gruppe prominente newyorkere og er idag det største private ikke-kommersielle universitetet i USA. Det har også en avdeling på Bedford Square i London, i bygningen som før var boligen til Lord Chancellor i Storbritannia, 6 Bedford Square. De 16 skolene og collegene omfatter: College of Arts and Science (1831) Gallatin School of Individualized Study School of Social Work Steinhardt School of Culture, Education and Human Development Stern School of Business Tisch School of the Arts College of Dentistry College of Nursing Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences Institute of Fine Arts School of Continuing and Professional Studies School of Law School of Medicine Graduate School of Arts and Science Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Det var 40 870 studenter og 4 380 vitenskapelig ansatte ved NYU i 2006, og det samme året var skolepengene US$ 33 420. Undervisningen gis opp til doktorgradsnivå. NYU Library System, inkludert Bobst Library, hadde i 2006 4 939 724 titler og var dermed det 34. største biblioteket i USA.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Нью-Йоркский университет (англ. &amp;#160;New York University, NYU) — частный, исследовательский университет США, расположенный в Нью-Йорке. Университет является самым крупным научно-исследовательским некоммерческим частным университетом Соединённых Штатов. В нём обучаются 39 408 студентов (по данным на осень 2004 года). Нью-Йоркский университет — член Ассоциации американских университетов, объединяющей с 1900 года ведущие научно-исследовательские университеты Северной Америки. Нью-Йоркский университет состоит из 16 школ, институтов и колледжей. Главный корпус университета располагается в Гринвич-Виллидж в Манхеттене, Нью-Йорк. Среди выпускников и преподавателей университета 31 нобелевский лауреат, 3 лауреата премии Абеля, 16 лауреатов Пулитцеровской премии, 19 лауреатов премии «Оскар», Эмми, Грэмми и Тони, а также стипендиатов фондов МакАртура и Гуггенхайма и членов Национальной академии наук США. Нью-Йоркский университет имеет одно из самых больших количеств выпускников в мире. На конец 2004 года оно составляло 350 000 человек, из них 17 000 заграничных студентов.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_university"/>
    <dbpprop:nickname rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/NYU_Violets"/>
    <foaf:nick xml:lang="en">Violets</foaf:nick>
    <dbpprop:thesN rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">32</dbpprop:thesN>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://nyupress.org/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/UniversitiesAndCollegesInNewYorkCity"/>
    <dbpprop:colors xml:lang="en">Violet and White</dbpprop:colors>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">纽约大学</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Uniwersytet Nowojorski (ang. New York University) (NYU), uniwersytet w Nowym Jorku, największa szkoła wyższa w Nowym Jorku i jedna z największych w USA. Główny kampus uniwersytetu znajduje się w Greenwich Village na Manhattanie. NYU został założony w 1831 przez Alberta Gallatina i grupę prominentnych nowojorczyków, stał się największym prywatnym uniwersytetem non-profit w Stanach. Uczelnia składa się z 14 szkół, college'ów i wydziałów skupionych w 6 częściach Manhattanu.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:usnwrLaw rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6</dbpprop:usnwrLaw>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/University"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Navboxes"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Universities_and_colleges_in_Manhattan"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_York_University?oldid=495353178"/>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-73.995</geo:long>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">A Universidade de Nova York (em inglês New York University; NYU) é uma importante universidade privada, sediada na cidade de Nova Iorque. Seu campus principal situa-se no bairro Greenwich Village, na ilha de Manhattan. Ela foi fundada em 1831 por Albert Gallatin e um grupo de ilustres novaiorquinos. A NYU hoje é a maior universidade particular sem fins lucrativos dos Estados Unidos, com mais de 50 mil alunos regulares, sem mencionar os mais de 12 mil inscritos em programas especiais.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">New York University (NYU) is a private, nonsectarian research university based in New York City, USA. NYU's main campus is situated in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of Lower Manhattan. Founded in 1831, NYU is one of the largest private nonprofit institutions of American higher education. NYU was elected to the Association of American Universities in 1950. The university counts 34 Nobel Prize winners, 3 Abel Prize winners, 10 National Medal of Science recipients, 16 Pulitzer Prize winners, 21 Academy Award winners, and Emmy, Grammy, and Tony Award winners among its faculty and alumni. NYU also has MacArthur and Guggenheim Fellowship holders as well as National Academy of Sciences members among its past and present graduates and faculty. NYU is organized into 18 schools, colleges, and institutes, located in six centers throughout Manhattan and Downtown Brooklyn, as well as more than a dozen other sites across the world, with plans for further expansion.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.gonyuathletics.com/"/>
    <dbpprop:residents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">12000</dbpprop:residents>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Нью-Йоркский университет (англ.  New York University, NYU) — частный, исследовательский университет США, расположенный в Нью-Йорке. Университет является самым крупным научно-исследовательским некоммерческим частным университетом Соединённых Штатов. В нём обучаются 39 408 студентов (по данным на осень 2004 года). Нью-Йоркский университет — член Ассоциации американских университетов, объединяющей с 1900 года ведущие научно-исследовательские университеты Северной Америки.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:free xml:lang="en">Washington Square News</dbpprop:free>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/UniversitiesAndCollegesInNewYork"/>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York_City"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">纽约大学（New York University，缩写为NYU）是一所位于美国纽约市曼哈顿的研究型私立大学。主要的校區位於曼哈頓格林威治村的附近區域，以華盛頓廣場為中心。学校於1831年成立，今日已經成為全美國境內規模最大的私立非營利高等教育机构，在各类大学排名中均名列前茅。 紐約大學由18個學院和研究所組成，大部分的校舍集中于曼哈顿和布鲁克林下城，同时在倫敦、巴黎、佛羅倫斯、布拉格、馬德里、柏林、阿克拉、上海、特拉維夫、布宜諾斯艾利斯和阿布達比等地設有海外研習場所。 纽约大学目前拥有33名诺贝尔奖得主（參考至2006年諾貝爾獎得主最多的大學），3名阿贝尔奖得主，9名美国国家科学奖章得主，16名普利策奖得主，19名奥斯卡金像奖得主（全美大学中最多）。此外，还拥有多名艾美獎、托尼奖、麦克阿瑟奖、古根海姆奖得主。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:established rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1831</dbpprop:established>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">La Universidad de Nueva York, es una universidad privada ubicado en Nueva York, Estados Unidos (no debe confundirse con la Universidad de la Ciudad de Nueva York). Fue fundada en 1831 por Albert Gallatin y un grupo de neoyorquinos. NYU se ha convertido en una de las mayores universidades privadas de los Estados Unidos y del mundo, con una población estudiantil de 39.408 alumnos (sin incluir los 12.526 estudiantes que participan en programas que no otorgan créditos).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">뉴욕 대학교는 미국의 뉴욕 주 뉴욕에 있는 사립대학이다. 뉴욕 대학교는 1831년에 창립된 역사깊은 학교이며, 영화 전공의 티쉬 예술대(Tisch School of the Arts)와 세계 최상위권 비지니스 대학과 대학원으로 알려진 스턴 경영대(Stern School Of Business), 또한 하버드, 스탠포드 등과 순위를 겨루는 법과대학원(School of Law)으로 유명하다. 뉴욕대가 위치한 뉴욕 시의 맨해튼 남부인 그레내치 빌리지 지역은 첨단 예술을 자랑하는 곳으로, 뉴욕 중의 뉴욕이라 할 수 있으며, 각종 화랑과 공연장이 밀집되어 있어 연중 활기가 넘치는 곳이다. 현재 교수진에 노벨상 수상자 3명을 보유하고 있으며, 50개 이상의 다양한 연구소에 많은 학생들이 참여할 수 있도록 많은 기회를 제공해 주고 있다. 총 14개의 단과대학에서 2,500 여개의 코스를 제공하고 있으며 교수와 학생 비율은 1:11 이다. 인문 과학대, 미대, 티쉬 예술대, 경영대, 행정대, 법대, 의대, 사회대, 치의대, 간호대, 교육대 등으로 구성되어 있다. 매년 미국 국내 대학 순위를 발표하는 시사 주간지 US News &amp; World Report에서 2009년에는 33위를 기록하였다. 학생들은 미국의 어느 지역에서도 제공하지 않는 기회를 부여 받고 있다. 월가에서의 인턴십, 메트로폴리탄 미술관에서의 수업, 뉴욕 병원에서의 현장학습 등은 뉴욕시와 이 대학이 가진 유대관계로 인해 가능하며, 실제로 뉴욕시 전체가 뉴욕대 캠퍼스라 해도 과언이 아니다. 또한 뉴욕대는 미국에서 학생이 가장 많은 사립 대학중 하나라고 한다. 학부에는 약 19,400여명의 학생이 있으며, 대학원에는 약 18,990여명이 재학 중이다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">New York University</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:usnwrNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">33</dbpprop:usnwrNu>
    <dbpprop:motto xml:lang="en">Perstare et praestare</dbpprop:motto>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Нью-Йоркский_университет"/>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">19</dbpprop:athletics>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/16/New_York_University_Seal.svg"/>
    <dbpprop:freeLabel xml:lang="en">Newspaper</dbpprop:freeLabel>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_university"/>
    <dbpprop:mottoeng xml:lang="en">To persevere and to excel</dbpprop:mottoeng>
    <dbpprop:usnwrBus rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6</dbpprop:usnwrBus>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">纽约大学（New York University，缩写为NYU）是一所位于美国纽约市曼哈顿的研究型私立大学。主要的校區位於曼哈頓格林威治村的附近區域，以華盛頓廣場為中心。学校於1831年成立，今日已經成為全美國境內規模最大的私立非營利高等教育机构，在各类大学排名中均名列前茅。 紐約大學由18個學院和研究所組成，大部分的校舍集中于曼哈顿和布鲁克林下城，同时在倫敦、巴黎、佛羅倫斯、布拉格、馬德里、柏林、阿克拉、上海、特拉維夫、布宜諾斯艾利斯和阿布達比等地設有海外研習場所。 纽约大学目前拥有33名诺贝尔奖得主（參考至2006年諾貝爾獎得主最多的大學），3名阿贝尔奖得主，9名美国国家科学奖章得主，16名普利策奖得主，19名奥斯卡金像奖得主（全美大学中最多）。此外，还拥有多名艾美獎、托尼奖、麦克阿瑟奖、古根海姆奖得主。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:profess rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3428</dbpprop:profess>
    <dbpprop:wamoNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">44</dbpprop:wamoNu>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Nova York, o New York University en anglès (es fa servir l'acrònim NYU), és una institució privada d'educació universitària i investigació, i una de les més prestigioses del món.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">New York University</rdfs:label>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-73.995 40.73)</geo:geometry>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Нью-Йоркський університет (скорочено NYU) — приватний світський університет у Нью-Йорку, основний кампус якого розташований у Грінвич-Віллидж в одній з частин Манхеттена. Заснований 1831 року, і на цей час є найбільшим приватним некомерційним закладом вищої освіти в США, у якому навчається більш 50 000 студентів.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L’université de New York est une université privée américaine située à New York. Son campus principal est situé dans le quartier de Greenwich Village dans le borough de Manhattan. Fondée en 1831 par l’homme politique américain Albert Gallatin et un groupe de New-Yorkais, elle est devenue la plus grande université privée à but non lucratif du pays, avec un nombre total d’étudiants supérieur à .</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EduCAtionalInstitutionsEstablishedIn1831"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">A Universidade de Nova York (em inglês New York University; NYU) é uma importante universidade privada, sediada na cidade de Nova Iorque. Seu campus principal situa-se no bairro Greenwich Village, na ilha de Manhattan. Ela foi fundada em 1831 por Albert Gallatin e um grupo de ilustres novaiorquinos. A NYU hoje é a maior universidade particular sem fins lucrativos dos Estados Unidos, com mais de 50 mil alunos regulares, sem mencionar os mais de 12 mil inscritos em programas especiais. A universidade inclui catorze escolas, faculdades e divisões, que ocupam seis grandes centros em Manhattan. A NYU também tem instalações próprias em Londres, Paris, Florença, Praga, Madri, Berlim, Acra e Xangai.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:New_York_University"/>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.nyu.edu/"/>
    <dbpprop:usnwrPolsci rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">17</dbpprop:usnwrPolsci>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">New Yorkin yliopisto (engl. New York University) on yksityinen, voittoatuottamaton ja uskontokunnista riippumaton tutkimusyliopisto New Yorkissa, Yhdysvalloissa. Sitä pidetään yleisesti yhtenä maailman parhaista yliopistoista, ja sen useimmat koulut sijoittuvat kansallisessa vertailussa kymmenen parhaan joukkoon omilla aloillaan. New York University on perustettu 1831, alkuperäiseltä nimeltään University of the City of New York. Sen tunnusväri on violetti ja rehtorina toimii John Sexton.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">New York University</dbpprop:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpprop:mascot rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Bobcat"/>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_Athletic_Association"/>
    <dbpprop:usnwrMedc rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">30</dbpprop:usnwrMedc>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/New_York_University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">To persevere and to excel</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <dbpedia-owl:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/usDollar">2.827E9</dbpedia-owl:endowment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpprop:forbes rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:forbes>
    <dbpedia-owl:facultySize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">6755</dbpedia-owl:facultySize>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">New York University</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">19401</dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:mascot xml:lang="en">Bobcat</dbpedia-owl:mascot>
    <dbpedia-owl:staff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">15286</dbpedia-owl:staff>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Université_de_New_York"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">New York University (NYU) je soukromá, výzkumná univerzita amerického města New York. Její hlavní kampus se nachází v Greenwich Village na Manhattanu. Byla založena v roce 1831 a jde o největší soukromou, nevýdělečnou instituci poskytující vyšší vzdělání v USA s více než 50 000 studenty. NYU je organizovaná do 16 škol, fakult a kateder, které se nacházejí v 6 střediscích na Manhattanu, Brooklynu a Bronxu.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">18990</dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/16/New_York_University_Seal.svg/200px-New_York_University_Seal.svg.png"/>
    <dbpprop:faculty rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6755</dbpprop:faculty>
    <dbpprop:arwuMed rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">51</dbpprop:arwuMed>
    <dbpprop:staff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">15286</dbpprop:staff>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.nyu.edu/"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuLife rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">41</dbpprop:arwuLife>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
