<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns9="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin">
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Philip Arthur Larkin was een Engels schrijver, dichter en jazz-criticus. Hij werd geassocieerd met 'The Movement'. Larkin werd geboren als enige zoon van Sydney Larkin, een schatbewaarder in Coventry. Hij ging naar school in het City's King Henry VIII School in Coventry, daarna ging hij naar St. John's College in Oxford. Hij kon hier met enig geluk zijn diploma behalen. De oorlog was namelijk al begonnen en Larkin werd opgeroepen door het Britse leger maar werd afgekeurd doordat hij slecht zag.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Philip Larkin</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.philiplarkin.com/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And where and when I shall myself die.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">In time the curtain-edges will grow light.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:memorials xml:lang="en">Martin Jennings  bronze statue, Paragon Station, Hull</dbpprop:memorials>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Academics_of_the_University_of_Leicester"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://web.archive.org/web/20070422162900/http:/philiplarkin.com/essays/Goodman/larkin_librarian.htm"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Philip Arthur Larkin est un poète, un romancier et un critique de jazz anglais. Il a passé sa vie active comme bibliothécaire d'université et s'est vu offrir le poste de Poet Laureate mais l'a décliné. Larkin est généralement considéré comme le poète anglais le plus important de la seconde moitié du XX siècle. Le Times (5 janv 2008) le classe comme le plus grand écrivain anglais depuis 1945.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">菲利普·拉金</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:id rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5491</dbpprop:id>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.clivejames.com/pieces/snakecharmers/larkin"/>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">300</dbpprop:width>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/W._B._Yeats"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">As all they might have done had they been loved.</dbpprop:quote>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Φίλιπ_Λάρκιν"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Philip Arthur Larkin (9. elokuuta 1922 – 2. joulukuuta 1985) on yksi merkittävimpiä brittiläisiä 1900-luvun loppupuolen runoilijoita. Vuonna 2008 The Times nimesi hänet Britannian merkittävimmäksi sodanjälkeiseksi kirjailijaksi. Andrew Motion on luonnehtinut hänen runojaan "hyvin englantilaisiksi". Hänen vuonna 1992 julkaistut kirjeensä pönkittivät ristiriitaisia näkemyksiä hänen elämästään, ja niistä paljastuneet vanhoilliset näkemykset nostattivat kohua. Lisa Jardine on kuvannut häntä rasistiksi ja naisvihaajaksi. Larkin oli henkilönä hyvin vakavamielinen. Hän ei kaivannut mainetta, eivätkä kirjalliset piirit onnistuneet houkuttamaan häntä.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And kneel upon the stone,</dbpprop:quote>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_poets"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118569740</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And the last difficult pride in being humble.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Photograph by Fay Godwin</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">By loving others, but across most it sweeps</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:deathCause rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Esophageal_cancer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1985-12-02</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FellowsOfTheRoyalSocietyOfLiterature"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Kingston_upon_Hull"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1922_births"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/48/Philip_Larkin_in_a_library.gif"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Philip Arthur Larkin', född 9 augusti 1922 i Coventry, död 2 december 1985 i Hull, var en brittisk poet, romanförfattare och jazzkritiker. Larkin studerade från 1930 till 1940 vid King Henry VIII School i Coventry och i oktober 1940 begav han sig till St John's College, Oxford för att studera engelsk litteratur. Under sin tid i Oxford träffade han Kingsley Amis, med vilken han utvecklade en livslång vänskap. Kort efter sin examen vid Oxford, fick Larkin tjänsten som stadsbibliotekarie i Wellington, Shropshire. 1946 blev han assisterande bibliotekarie vid University of Leicester och, 1950, underbibliotekarie vid Queen's University Belfast. Vid denna tid hade han givit ut två romaner och sin första diktsamling. I mars 1955, fick Larkin tjänsten som bibliotekarie vid University of Hull, en tjänst som han hade fram till sin död.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And say why it never worked for me</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/W._H._Auden"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio4/schedule/2008/04/29/day/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Why did he think adding meant increase?</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:notableWorks xml:lang="en">The Whitsun Weddings , High Windows</dbpprop:notableWorks>
    <dbpprop:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/St_John's_College,_Oxford"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Critic"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Novelist110363573"/>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-0.430608</geo:long>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "Dockery and Son" , The Whitsun Weddings</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">In everyone there sleeps</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Quote_box"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1922-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:birthYear>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Cancer_deaths_in_England"/>
    <dbpprop:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1985-12-02</dbpprop:deathDate>
    <dbpprop:parents xml:lang="en">Sydney Larkin , Eva Emily Day</dbpprop:parents>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">菲利普·拉金，CH，CBE，FRSL（Philip Larkin，1922年8月9日－1985年12月2日），20世纪后半叶英国著名诗人，小说家、爵士樂评论家。1955年以第二部诗集《少受欺骗者》获得关注，之后又出版了《降灵节婚礼》和《高窗》。1984年曾被授予英国桂冠诗人称号，但被他谢绝。 拉金生于考文垂，1940年进入牛津大学圣约翰学院，43年毕业。在读期间结识金斯利·艾米斯，成为一生的挚友。 毕业后就任威灵顿多所图书馆馆长。55年就任赫尔大学图书馆馆长直至逝世。03年被讀詩會选为英国“最受欢迎诗人”，08年被泰晤士报评为英国战后最伟大诗人。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2010/dec/06/unknown-philip-larkin-poem-found-shoebox"/>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace xml:lang="en">Hull, Humberside, , England</dbpprop:deathPlace>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Isolate rather this element</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Philip Arthur Larkin was een Engels schrijver, dichter en jazz-criticus. Hij werd geassocieerd met 'The Movement'. Larkin werd geboren als enige zoon van Sydney Larkin, een schatbewaarder in Coventry. Hij ging naar school in het City's King Henry VIII School in Coventry, daarna ging hij naar St. John's College in Oxford. Hij kon hier met enig geluk zijn diploma behalen. De oorlog was namelijk al begonnen en Larkin werd opgeroepen door het Britse leger maar werd afgekeurd doordat hij slecht zag. Na zijn studie ging Larkin weer bij zijn ouders wonen, waarna hij in 1943 bibliothecaris werd in Shropshire. Eerder al, in 1940, was Larkins eerste gedicht 'Ultimatum' gepubliceerd in The Listener, en ook in 1943 verschenen A Stone Church Damaged By A Bomb, 'Mythological Introduction' en I dreamed of an out-thrust arm of land in het blad Oxford Poetry; nu hij bibliothecaris was, ging hij gewoon verder met het schrijven en publiceren van gedichten. In 1946 verscheen zijn eerste novelle Jill en vlak daarna, in 1947, werd A Girl in Winter uitgebracht. Larkin was ondertussen bibliothecaris aan de Universiteit van Leicester, daarna ging hij naar de Universiteit van Belfast. In Belfast werd XX poems gepubliceerd. Larkin verhuisde weer en werd bibliothecaris in Hull in het jaar 1955. Het was in dat jaar dat zijn bundel The Less Deceived gepubliceerd werd. Deze bundel geldt als zijn belangrijkste bundel. Enkele jaren later begon Larkin met het schrijven van jazz-recensies voor The Daily Telegraph; dit bleef hij doen tot in 1971. Later werden deze recensies gebundeld in 'All what Jazz'. Ondertussen had hij in 1964 een nieuwe gedichtenbundel, The Whitsun Weddings, uitgebracht, waarvoor hij enkele prijzen ontving. Zijn laatste gedichtenbundel High Windows dateert van 1974. Larkin was een gevierd schrijver en dichter, en ontving vele prijzen, waaronder de CBE en The German Shakespeare-Prize. In 1982 werd Larkin professor aan de Universiteit van Hull. In 1984 ontving hij een emeritus aan de Universiteit van Oxford en werd hij verkozen tot Lid van Bestuur van de British Library. In 1984 kreeg Philip Larkin ook de kans om Poet Laureate te worden na de dood van John Betjeman maar uit principe accepteerde hij de titel niet. Hij dacht namelijk dat hij, mede door zijn achteruitgaande gezondheidstoestand, zijn 'poëtische gave' nagenoeg kwijt was. In plaats van Philip Larkin werd Ted Hughes de nieuwe Poet Laureate. In 1985 moest Philip Larkin worden opgenomen in het ziekenhuis ten gevolge van slokdarmkanker. Hij ontving nog de Order of the Companion of Honour, een prijs voor zijn verdiensten in kunst, literatuur, religie of wetenschap, maar hij kon zelf niet meer aanwezig zijn op de uitreiking in Buckingham Palace. Nog datzelfde jaar stierf hij op 63-jarige leeftijd.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Philip Larkin</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Jazz"/>
    <dbpprop:align xml:lang="en">left</dbpprop:align>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://entertainment.timesonline.co.uk/tol/arts_and_entertainment/books/article3889722.ece"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ihull.org/larkin/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it"></dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Ларкин,_Филип"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Philip Arthur Larkin var en engelsk lyriker, romanforfatter og jazzkritiker. Han arbeidet som universitetsbibliotekar. Larkin betraktes som en av de fremste engelske lyrikerne på siste halvdel av 1900-tallet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-0.430608 53.7836)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">That spreads through other lives like a tree</dbpprop:quote>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Coventry"/>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">53.7836</geo:lat>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Being brave
Lets no one off the grave.
Death is no different whined at than withstood.</dbpprop:quote>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.channel4.com/culture/microsites/L/larkin/index.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:employer rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Hull"/>
    <dbpprop:quoted xml:lang="en">true</dbpprop:quoted>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_agnostics"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/West_Midlands_(county)"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Larkin</foaf:surname>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1922-08-09</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0b_hb"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.philiplarkin.com/AL/alprevious/al04con.html"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Academics_of_the_University_of_Hull"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:English_librarians"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace xml:lang="en">Coventry, Warwickshire, , England</dbpprop:birthPlace>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromCoventry"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Philip Larkin</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Waking at four to soundless dark, I stare.</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishPoets"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_educated_at_King_Henry_VIII_School,_Coventry"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cottingham,_East_Riding_of_Yorkshire"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlacePosition rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin__restingPlacePosition__1"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/St_John's_College,_Oxford"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Unresting death, a whole day nearer now,</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/East_Riding_of_Yorkshire"/>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">The Less Deceived</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Warwickshire"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">菲利普·拉金，CH，CBE，FRSL（Philip Larkin，1922年8月9日－1985年12月2日），20世纪后半叶英国著名诗人，小说家、爵士樂评论家。1955年以第二部诗集《少受欺骗者》获得关注，之后又出版了《降灵节婚礼》和《高窗》。1984年曾被授予英国桂冠诗人称号，但被他谢绝。 拉金生于考文垂，1940年进入牛津大学圣约翰学院，43年毕业。在读期间结识金斯利·艾米斯，成为一生的挚友。 毕业后就任威灵顿多所图书馆馆长。55年就任赫尔大学图书馆馆长直至逝世。03年被讀詩會选为英国“最受欢迎诗人”，08年被泰晤士报评为英国战后最伟大诗人。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2008/may/07/photography.art"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1922-08-09</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Philip Arthur Larkin war ein englischer Dichter, Autor und Jazzkritiker. Er arbeitete als Universitätsbibliothekar in Hull. Larkin gilt als einer der bedeutendsten englischen Dichter des 20. Jahrhunderts.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">Poet, Novelist, Jazz critic, Librarian</dc:description>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">A sense of life lived according to love.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Of . . . No, that's not the difference: rather how</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishLibrarians"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">The unbeatable slow machine</dbpprop:quote>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Formalist_poets"/>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath xml:lang="en">Hull, Humberside , England</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Your wants, the world's for you, and</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:restingPlace xml:lang="en">Cottingham municipal cemetery</dbpprop:restingPlace>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Philip Arthur Larkin, CH, CBE, FRSL (9 August 1922 – 2 December 1985) is widely regarded as one of the great English poets of the latter half of the twentieth century. His first book of poetry, The North Ship, was published in 1945, followed by two novels, Jill (1946) and A Girl in Winter (1947), but he came to prominence in 1955 with the publication of his second collection of poems, The Less Deceived, followed by The Whitsun Weddings (1964) and High Windows (1974). He contributed to The Daily Telegraph as its jazz critic from 1961 to 1971, articles gathered together in All What Jazz: A Record Diary 1961–71 (1985), and he edited The Oxford Book of Twentieth Century English Verse (1973). He was the recipient of many honours, including the Queen's Gold Medal for Poetry. He was offered, but declined, the position of poet laureate in 1984, following the death of John Betjeman. After graduating from Oxford in 1943 with a first in English language and literature, Larkin became a librarian. It was during the thirty years he served as university librarian at the Brynmor Jones Library at the University of Hull that he produced the greater part of his published work. His poems are marked by what Andrew Motion calls a very English, glum accuracy about emotions, places, and relationships, and what Donald Davie described as lowered sights and diminished expectations. Eric Homberger called him "the saddest heart in the post-war supermarket"—Larkin himself said that deprivation for him was what daffodils were for Wordsworth. Influenced by W. H. Auden, W. B. Yeats, and Thomas Hardy, his poems are highly structured but flexible verse forms. They were described by Jean Hartley, the ex-wife of Larkin's publisher George Hartley (The Marvell Press), as a "piquant mixture of lyricism and discontent", though anthologist Keith Tuma writes that there is more to Larkin's work than its reputation for dour pessimism suggests. Larkin's public persona was that of the no-nonsense, solitary Englishman who disliked fame and had no patience for the trappings of the public literary life. The posthumous publication by Anthony Thwaite in 1992 of his letters triggered controversy about his personal life and political views, described by John Banville as hair-raising, but also in places hilarious. Lisa Jardine called him a "casual, habitual racist, and an easy misogynist", but the academic John Osborne argued in 2008 that "the worst that anyone has discovered about Larkin are some crass letters and a taste for porn softer than what passes for mainstream entertainment". Despite the controversy Larkin was chosen in a 2003 Poetry Book Society survey, almost two decades after his death, as Britain's best-loved poet of the previous 50 years, and in 2008 The Times named him Britain's greatest post-war writer. In 2010, 25 years after his death, Larkin's adopted home city, Kingston upon Hull commemorated him with the Larkin 25 Festival which culminated in the unveiling of a statue of Larkin by Martin Jennings on 2 December 2010, the 25th anniversary of his death.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <ns9:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philip_Larkin?oldid=493568179"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Life is an immobile, locked,</dbpprop:quote>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Jazz_writers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AcademicsOfTheUniversityOfLeicester"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:occupation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Novel"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpprop:salign xml:lang="en">center</dbpprop:salign>
    <dbpedia-owl:occupation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin__1"/>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">240</dbpprop:width>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Philip Arthur Larkin foi um poeta inglês. Seu primeiro livro de poesia, The North Ship, foi publicado em 1945. Após se graduar em língua inglesa e literatura na Universidade de Oxford, em 1943, Larkin virou bibliotecário e passou 30 anos de sua vida cuidando da biblioteca na Universidade de Hull. Philip fazia parte do grupo de poetas ingleses The Movement, juntamente com Elizabeth Jennings, Kingsley Amis e Thom Gunn.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfStJohn'sCollege,Oxford"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Philip Larkin</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Philip Arthur Larkin – angielski poeta, pisarz i krytyk jazzowy.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fellows_of_the_Royal_Society_of_Literature"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Cholmondeley_Award_winners"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1985-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:deathYear>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">Collected Poems</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "I Remember, I Remember" ,</dbpprop:source>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_St_John's_College,_Oxford"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Librarian"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathCause rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Esophageal_cancer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:occupation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Librarian"/>
    <dbpprop:employer rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/second">9.46728E8</dbpprop:employer>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Philip Arthur Larkin', född 9 augusti 1922 i Coventry, död 2 december 1985 i Hull, var en brittisk poet, romanförfattare och jazzkritiker. Larkin studerade från 1930 till 1940 vid King Henry VIII School i Coventry och i oktober 1940 begav han sig till St John's College, Oxford för att studera engelsk litteratur. Under sin tid i Oxford träffade han Kingsley Amis, med vilken han utvecklade en livslång vänskap.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_person"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Novel"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.faber.co.uk/work/sunday-sessions/9780571244041/"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Till then I see what's really always there:</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Philip Arthur Larkin, CH, CBE, FRSL (9 August 1922 – 2 December 1985) is widely regarded as one of the great English poets of the latter half of the twentieth century. His first book of poetry, The North Ship, was published in 1945, followed by two novels, Jill (1946) and A Girl in Winter (1947), but he came to prominence in 1955 with the publication of his second collection of poems, The Less Deceived, followed by The Whitsun Weddings (1964) and High Windows (1974).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Dockery, now:</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">9</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Philip Arthur Larkin war ein englischer Dichter, Autor und Jazzkritiker. Er arbeitete als Universitätsbibliothekar in Hull. Larkin gilt als einer der bedeutendsten englischen Dichter des 20. Jahrhunderts.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "Faith Healing" , The Whitsun Weddings</dbpprop:source>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Philip Arthur Larkin</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">To some it means the difference they could make</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Three-handed struggle between</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Librarian110257948"/>
    <dbpprop:nationality xml:lang="en">British</dbpprop:nationality>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Philip Arthur Larkin, CBE fue un poeta, bibliotecario, novelista y crítico de jazz británico. En 1945 publicó su primer libro de poesía, El barco del norte, al que le siguieron dos novelas, Jill (1946) y Una chica en invierno (1947), pero adquirió notabilidad en 1955 con la publicación de su segunda colección de poemas, Un engaño menor, seguido por Las bodas de Pentecostés (1964) y Ventanas altas (1974).</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Deaths_from_esophageal_cancer"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Philip Larkin</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Philip_Larkin"/>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "Love Again" , posthumously published</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">'You look as if you wished the place in Hell,'
My friend said, 'judging from your face.' 'Oh well,
I suppose it's not the place's fault,' I said.
'Nothing, like something, happens anywhere.'</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:imageSize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">170</dbpprop:imageSize>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EnglishAgnostics"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And are required lastly to give up pride,</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Poet, librarian, novelist, jazz critic</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Making all thought impossible but how</dbpprop:quote>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">53.78360555555555 -0.43060833333333337</grs:point>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AcademicsOfTheUniversityOfHull"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Philip Arthur Larkin, CBE fue un poeta, bibliotecario, novelista y crítico de jazz británico. En 1945 publicó su primer libro de poesía, El barco del norte, al que le siguieron dos novelas, Jill (1946) y Una chica en invierno (1947), pero adquirió notabilidad en 1955 con la publicación de su segunda colección de poemas, Un engaño menor, seguido por Las bodas de Pentecostés (1964) y Ventanas altas (1974). Entre 1961 y 1971, trabajó en el periódico The Daily Telegraph como su crítico de jazz, y editó The Oxford Book of Twentieth-Century English Verse (1973). Recibió varios honores, incluyendo la Queen's Gold Medal for Poetry. En 1984, después de la muerte de John Betjeman, le fue ofrecida la posición de poeta laureado del Reino Unido, la cual rechazó. Es considerado por la crítica como uno de los poetas ingleses más aclamados de la segunda mitad del siglo XX. Después de graduarse de Oxford en 1943 con títulos en inglés y literatura inglesa, Larkin comenzó a trabajar como bibliotecario. Durante los treinta años en los que se desempeñó como bibliotecario universitario en la Biblioteca Brynmor Jones de la Universidad de Hull produjo la mayor parte de su obra publicada. Sus poemas están marcados por lo que el poeta inglés Andrew Motion describe como una «exactitud melancólica y muy inglesa para tratar las emociones, los lugares y los relaciones». Eric Homberger mencionó que Larkin era «el corazón más triste en el mercado de posguerra», y el mismo Larkin dijo que la pobreza era para él lo que los narcisos eran para Wordsworth. Influenciado por W. H. Auden, W. B. Yeats y Thomas Hardy, sus poemas están formados por versos muy estructurados pero flexibles. Jean Hartley, la exesposa del editor de Larkin, George Hartley (The Marvell Press) los describió como «una mezcla estimulante de lirismo y descontento», aunque el antólogo Keith Tuma aseguró que hay más en la obra de Larkin que lo que sugiere su reputación de pesimista adusto. La personalidad pública de Larkin era la de un inglés solitario e insensato a quien no le gustaba la fama y que no tenía paciencia para los enredos de la vida literaria pública. En 1922, cuando el poeta y escritor Anthony Thwaite publicó de manera póstuma sus cartas, se generó una controversia sobre su vida personal y sus opiniones políticas, descrita por John Banville como escalofriante, pero también divertida en cierto punto. La historiadora británica Lisa Jardine lo describió como un «racista empedernido y misógino», pero el académico John Osborne sostuvo en 2008 que «lo peor que pudieron descubrir sobre Larkin fueron unas pocas cartas supinas y que le gustaba el porno más suave que el que entretiene a las masas». A pesar de la controversia, Larkin fue elegido en una encuesta de 2003 (casi dos décadas después de su muerte) organizada por la Poetry Book Society como el poeta más aclamado de los últimos cincuenta años, y en 2008 The Times lo nombró el mejor poeta de posguerra de Gran Bretaña. En 2010, veinticinco años después de su fallecimiento, la ciudad donde vivía Larkin, Kingston upon Hull, lo conmemoró con el Festival Larkin 25. El festival culminó el 2 de diciembre, el día del vigésimo quinto aniversario de su muerte, con la revelación de una estatua erigida en su honor y esculpida por Martin Jennings.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">I work all day, and get half-drunk at night.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "Toads" , The Less Deceived</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poet"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Members_of_the_Order_of_the_Companions_of_Honour"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And sways them on in a sort of sense</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">To me it was dilution.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Philip Arthur Larkin foi um poeta inglês. Seu primeiro livro de poesia, The North Ship, foi publicado em 1945. Após se graduar em língua inglesa e literatura na Universidade de Oxford, em 1943, Larkin virou bibliotecário e passou 30 anos de sua vida cuidando da biblioteca na Universidade de Hull. Philip fazia parte do grupo de poetas ingleses The Movement, juntamente com Elizabeth Jennings, Kingsley Amis e Thom Gunn.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:bgcolor xml:lang="en">#FFFFF0</dbpprop:bgcolor>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">That brings what you'll get.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Philip Arthur Larkin – angielski poeta, pisarz i krytyk jazzowy.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Thomas_Hardy"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Фи́лип А́ртур Ла́ркин — британский поэт, писатель и джазовый критик. Всю свою жизнь проработал университетским библиотекарем. В 1984 году Ларкину было предложено почётное звание Поэта-лауреата, которое он отверг. За свои литературные заслуги награждён Орденом Кавалеров Славы и Орденом Британской империи. В 2008 году газета The Times назвала Ларкина лучшим британским писателем послевоенной эпохи (Толкин, например, занял в этом списке лишь 6-е место) Филип Ларкин сыграл судьбоносную роль в литературной карьере британской писательницы Барбары Пим, опубликовав в The Times Literary Supplement статью о ней, назвав «самым недооцененным автором столетия».</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:occupation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poet"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Philip Arthur Larkin byl anglický básník, prozaik a jazzový kritik. Obecně je považován za jednoho z nejvýznamnějších anglických básníků druhé poloviny 20. století. Poprvé se dostal do popředí v roce 1955 publikací své druhé básnické sbírky The Less Deceived, po níž následovaly The Whitsun Weddings (1964) a High Windows (1974). Po smrti Johna Betjemana v roce 1984 mu byl nabídnut post dvorního básníka Spojeného království, který však Larkin nepřijal.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1985_deaths"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Philip Arthur</foaf:givenName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Philip Arthur Larkin (9. elokuuta 1922 – 2. joulukuuta 1985) on yksi merkittävimpiä brittiläisiä 1900-luvun loppupuolen runoilijoita. Vuonna 2008 The Times nimesi hänet Britannian merkittävimmäksi sodanjälkeiseksi kirjailijaksi. Andrew Motion on luonnehtinut hänen runojaan "hyvin englantilaisiksi". Hänen vuonna 1992 julkaistut kirjeensä pönkittivät ristiriitaisia näkemyksiä hänen elämästään, ja niistä paljastuneet vanhoilliset näkemykset nostattivat kohua.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Фи́лип А́ртур Ла́ркин — британский поэт, писатель и джазовый критик. Всю свою жизнь проработал университетским библиотекарем. В 1984 году Ларкину было предложено почётное звание Поэта-лауреата, которое он отверг. За свои литературные заслуги награждён Орденом Кавалеров Славы и Орденом Британской империи.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Only nineteen, he must have taken stock</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "Come then to prayers" , Collected Poems</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.poetryarchive.org/poetryarchive/singlePoet.do?poetId=7076"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvqpqZZwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">For we have tried</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Coventry, Warwickshire , England</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "Aubade" , Collected Poems</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">All courages on these despairs,</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Larkin, Philip Arthur</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "The Life with a Hole in it" ,</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Convinced he was he should be added to!</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Philip Arthur Larkin est un poète, un romancier et un critique de jazz anglais. Il a passé sa vie active comme bibliothécaire d'université et s'est vu offrir le poste de Poet Laureate mais l'a décliné. Larkin est généralement considéré comme le poète anglais le plus important de la seconde moitié du XX siècle. Le Times (5 janv 2008) le classe comme le plus grand écrivain anglais depuis 1945.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Philip Arthur Larkin byl anglický básník, prozaik a jazzový kritik. Obecně je považován za jednoho z nejvýznamnějších anglických básníků druhé poloviny 20. století. Poprvé se dostal do popředí v roce 1955 publikací své druhé básnické sbírky The Less Deceived, po níž následovaly The Whitsun Weddings (1964) a High Windows (1974). Po smrti Johna Betjemana v roce 1984 mu byl nabídnut post dvorního básníka Spojeného království, který však Larkin nepřijal.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.nybooks.com/articles/18715"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:NPG_name"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Why should I let the toad work
        Squat on my life?
Can't I use my wit as a pitchfork
        And drive the brute off?</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it"></rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Of what he wanted, and been capable</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/48/Philip_Larkin_in_a_library.gif/200px-Philip_Larkin_in_a_library.gif"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Commanders_of_the_Order_of_the_British_Empire"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Humberside"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Philip Arthur Larkin var en engelsk lyriker, romanforfatter og jazzkritiker. Han arbeidet som universitetsbibliotekar. Larkin betraktes som en av de fremste engelske lyrikerne på siste halvdel av 1900-tallet.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Coventry"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
