<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Princeton_University">
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Princeton_University"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">7</dbpprop:arwuW>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Università_di_Princeton"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Uniwersytet Princeton – naukowo-badawczy uniwersytet prywatny w Stanach Zjednoczonych, działający w mieście Princeton w stanie New Jersey. Nazwa także odnosi się do college'u, czyli instytucji studiów licencjackich. Właśnie głównie ci studenci historycznie tworzą kulturę kampusu i afiszują swoją przynależność doń, w znaczeniu "Princeton man", w ścisłym odróżnieniu od "Yale man" czy "Harvard man". Studenci z Princeton odwiecznie rywalizują ze studentami z Yale i Harvardu. Rywalizacja ta nagminnie trwa przez całe życie i tyczy takich spraw jak zatrudnienie. Należy sportowo i kulturowo do Ivy League. U.S. World &amp; News Report corocznie przyznaje Uniwersytetowi Princeton miejsca w pierwszej 15-stce najlepszych uniwersytetów na świecie, oraz pierwszej 3-ce najlepszych uniwersytetów w Stanach Zjednoczonych. Barwy szkoły to kolor czarny i pomarańczowy (jasny). Od początku swojego istnienia szkoła ta wydała 35 laureatów Nagrody Nobla. Uniwersytet z budżetem równym 17,1 miliarda dolarów oraz 7567 studentami jest ośrodkiem o najwyższym wyposażeniu finansowym przypadającym na jednego studenta na świecie.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/University"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Princeton_University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Collegiate_Athletic_Association"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Princeton University är ett av USA:s främsta universitet. Det är beläget i staden Princeton i New Jersey. Det bildades 1746, då som College of New Jersey, och bytte till sitt nuvarande namn 1896, vilket gör den till USA:s fjärde äldsta högskola. Universitetet erbjuder, förutom grundutbildning och forskarutbildning i humaniora, naturvetenskap och samhällsvetenskap även utbildningar inom arkitektur, teknik, förvaltning och internationella studier.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:facultySize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">1172</dbpedia-owl:facultySize>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Princetonská univerzita (Princeton University) je jedna z nejprestižnějších univerzit v USA. Je to soukromá univerzita, sídlící ve městě Princeton, New Jersey. Je také jedním z osmi členů Ivy League. Byla založena roku 1746 v Elizabeth, New Jersey, původně pod názvem College of New Jersey. Roku 1756 se přesunula do Princetonu a roku 1896 se přejmenovala na “Princeton University”.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:faculty rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1172</dbpprop:faculty>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Princeton,_New_Jersey"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Princeton University är ett av USA:s främsta universitet. Det är beläget i staden Princeton i New Jersey. Det bildades 1746, då som College of New Jersey, och bytte till sitt nuvarande namn 1896, vilket gör den till USA:s fjärde äldsta högskola. Universitetet erbjuder, förutom grundutbildning och forskarutbildning i humaniora, naturvetenskap och samhällsvetenskap även utbildningar inom arkitektur, teknik, förvaltning och internationella studier. Forskning bedrivs bland annat på plasma, meteorologi och jetmotordrift. Skolan grundades i Elizabeth i New Jersey men flyttade till Princeton 1756. Formellt bytte den namn till Princeton University 1896. Princeton University är ett av de som ingår i Ivy League, ett samlingsnamn för åtta privata högprestigeuniversitet i USA. Skolan har 7 000 studenter och mer än 1 100 anställda, forskare och lärare.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">La Universidad de Princeton, localizada en Princeton, Nueva Jersey, Estados Unidos es una de las ocho universidades de la Ivy League. Fue fundada como el College of New Jersey en 1746, y estuvo originalmente localizada en Elizabeth (Nueva Jersey). Reconocida como una de las más prestigiosas universidades del mundo, la universidad fue trasladada a Princeton en 1756, manteniendo el nombre original. El nombre fue cambiado oficialmente a Universidad de Princeton ("Princeton University") en 1896.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Прінстонський університет — один із найстаріших і найпрестижніших університетів США, розташований у місті Прінстон, штат Нью-Джерсі. Входить у Лігу плюща. Прінстонський університет був заснований в 1746 році як Коледж Нью-Джерсі (College of New Jersey). Став четвертим коледжем колоній. Перші заняття проходили в будинку засновника університету священика Джонатана Дікінсона в місті Нью-Брансвік. Переїхав у місто Прінстон в 1756 році.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:filename xml:lang="en">Old Nassau.ogg</dbpprop:filename>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">프린스턴 대학교(Princeton University)는 1746년에 설립한 미국 뉴저지 주 프린스턴에 있는 사립 대학으로, 미국 동부 8개 명문 아이비리그에 속해 있으며, 미국의 최고 대학 중 하나로 손꼽힌다. 프린스턴 대학교는 미국에서 4번째 대학으로, 하버드 대학교, 윌리엄 앤 메리 대학교, 예일 대학교 다음으로 수립되었다. 전통적으로 학부 교육과 학문 연구에 중심을 두고 있으나, 최근에는 대학원 교육에도 중점을 둬서 다양한 분야에서 많은 석박사를 배출하고 있다. 프린스턴대는 학부(undergraduate)와 대학원(graduate)에서 인문, 사회과학, 자연과학, 공학을 제공한다. 우드로 윌슨 공공국제정책대학원(Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs)이 전문대학원으로 석사 박사과정을 제공한다. 도서관에는 6백만권 이상의 책을 소장하고 있다. 프린스턴 대학은 전 분야에 걸쳐 훌륭한 교육을 제공하고 있으며, 그 중에서도 수학, 철학, 물리학 등이 특히 유명하며 역사, 영어, 경제학 등도 잘 알려진 분야에 속한다. 유에스 뉴스 앤드 월드 리포트에서 매년 매기는 미국 대학 순위에서 하버드 대학교, 예일 대학교와 함께 1위를 다투는 명문 대학이다. 학생 수가 다른 아이비리그 학교에 비하여 적은 편이며 학생 대 교수의 비율이 5대 1정도이다. 뉴욕시와 필라델피아의 중간에 있는 뉴저지의 전원도시 프린스턴 지역에 위치하고 있다. 프린스턴 대학교는 한국의 초대 대통령인 이승만 박사가 박사학위를 받은곳이며, 미국 제28대 대통령 우드로 윌슨과 제4대 대통령 제임스 매디슨, 국방부 장관을 지낸 도널드 럼스펠드, 구글의 최고 경영자 에릭 슈미트, 이베이의 최고 경영자 메그 위트먼 등 많은 뛰어난 인물을 배출했다. 오랜 역사를 통해 이 학교가 배출한 졸업생의 수는 전 세계 120여국에 약 6만 3천명 정도에 달한다고 한다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">5113</dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents>
    <dbpprop:arwuSoc rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6</dbpprop:arwuSoc>
    <dbpprop:students rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">7567</dbpprop:students>
    <dbpprop:campus xml:lang="en">Suburban,</dbpprop:campus>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Princeton, localitzada a Princeton, Nova Jersey és una de les vuit universitats de la Ivy League . Va ser fundada com el College of New Jersey el 1746, i va estar originalment localitzada a Elizabeth, Nova Jersey. Reconeguda com una de les més prestigioses universitats del món, la universitat va ser traslladada a Princeton el 1756, mantenint el nom original. El nom va ser oficialment canviat a Universitat de Princeton ("Princeton University") el 1896. Originalment va ser una institució presbiteriana, actualment laica. En ella van impartir classes els matemàtics Solomon Lefschetz, John Nash i George Dantzig (aquest últim, inventor de l'Algoritme simplex). En Albert Einstein ensenyava i investigava a l'Institut d'Estudis Avançats de Princeton, una institució propera a la Universitat, encara que independent. Princeton és una de les universitats més riques del món amb un dot financer que supera els 13 bilions de dòlars. Part d'aquests recursos són invertits en el Princeton University Art Museum que exhibeix obres de Monet, Gauguin, Warhol entre altres artistes preminents. Princeton és constantment qualificada entre les millors universitats d'EUA i del món amb set nominacions consecutives al primer lloc per la revista U. S News &amp; World Report.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Принстонский университет — частный университет, один из старейших и известнейших университетов в США. Входит в Лигу плюща и является одним из самых престижных вузов страны. Находится в городе Принстон, штат Нью-Джерси.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-74.6593 40.3487)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpprop:postgrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2479</dbpprop:postgrad>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Under God's Power She Flourishes</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Middle_States_Association_of_Colleges_and_Schools"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Princeton, localitzada a Princeton, Nova Jersey és una de les vuit universitats de la Ivy League . Va ser fundada com el College of New Jersey el 1746, i va estar originalment localitzada a Elizabeth, Nova Jersey. Reconeguda com una de les més prestigioses universitats del món, la universitat va ser traslladada a Princeton el 1756, mantenint el nom original. El nom va ser oficialment canviat a Universitat de Princeton ("Princeton University") el 1896.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Princeton University is een particuliere universiteit uit de Verenigde Staten. De universiteit werd in 1746 gesticht in Elizabeth (New Jersey) als "College of New Jersey". In 1756 verplaatste men het college naar Princeton (New Jersey), maar de oorspronkelijke naam werd vooralsnog behouden. Pas in 1896 werd het College of New Jersey omgedoopt in Princeton University. Princeton was de vierde universiteit in de geschiedenis van de Verenigde Staten die begon met het geven van lessen.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:format rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ogg"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Navboxes"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EduCAtionalInstitutionsEstablishedInThe1740s"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/University"/>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">38</dbpprop:athletics>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">学生数は学部生4800人、大学院生2000人である。卒業生の中に2人の大統領がいる、アメリカ全土で8番目に古い、などで有名な大学である。2010年度の受験サイクルでは全受験者の8.8%が入学を許可された。なお、プリンストン高等研究所（Institute for Advanced Study）とは相互交流は盛んであるものの、プリンストン大学と直接の関係はない。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">150</dbpprop:logo>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">2479</dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:staff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">1103</dbpedia-owl:staff>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Universities_and_colleges_in_Mercer_County,_New_Jersey"/>
    <dbpprop:formerNames xml:lang="en">College of New Jersey</dbpprop:formerNames>
    <dbpprop:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Shirley_M._Tilghman"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/프린스턴_대학교"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ColonialColleges"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuLife rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">45</dbpprop:arwuLife>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Princetonin yliopisto New Jerseyssä Yhdysvalloissa on vuonna 1746 perustettu, Yhdysvaltain neljänneksi vanhin yliopisto. Sitä arvostetaan etenkin poliitikkojen, arkkitehtien ja teknisen alan oppilaitoksena. Tutkimusaloista näkyvimpiin nousi fysiikka, nykyisin mm. plasmafysiikka, kun Albert Einstein päätyi toisen maailmansodan jälkeen professoriksi Princetoniin. Princeton kuuluu Yhdysvaltojen eliittiyliopistojen joukkoon, jota kutsutaan nimellä "Ivy League". Princeton on yksi maailman rikkaimmista yliopistoista ja neljänneksi rikkain yliopisto Yhdysvalloissa noin 13 miljardin dollarin omaisuudella. Princeton sijoittuu usein kärkitiloille maailman yliopistojen välisissä vertailuissa. Muista Ivy League -yliopistoista Princeton eroaa maineeltaan siinä, että se panostaa myös perustutkinto-opiskelijoihin. Siellä voi suorittaa alemman tutkinnon sekä luonnontieteissä ja teknologiassa (B.S. E) että humanistisella puolella (B. A). Princeton eroaa muista yliopistoista myös siten, että sillä ei ole muun muassa lääketieteellistä, oikeustieteellistä eikä kauppatieteellistä tiedekuntaa. Princeton painottaa muun muassa teknologiaa, luonnontieteitä ja humanistisia tieteitä. Princetonin arvostetuin ja kuuluisin koulu on Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs, joka valmistaa oppilaita julkisiin ja kansainvälisiin tehtäviin.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:National_Association_of_Independent_Colleges_and_Universities_members"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour xml:lang="en">Orange and black</dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">(Latin)</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Universitas Princetoniensis</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:imageName xml:lang="en">Princeton shield.svg</dbpprop:imageName>
    <dbpprop:arwuEng rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">26</dbpprop:arwuEng>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/UniversitiesAndCollegesInNewJersey"/>
    <dbpprop:staff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1103</dbpprop:staff>
    <dbpprop:thesN rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5</dbpprop:thesN>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">普林斯顿大学（英語：Princeton University），又译普林斯敦大学，位於美国新泽西州的普林斯顿，是美国一所著名的私立研究型大学，八所常春藤盟校之一。 学校于1746年在新泽西州伊丽莎白镇创立，是美国殖民时期第四所成立的高等教育學院， 当时名为“新泽西学院”，1747年迁至新泽西州，1756年迁至普林斯顿，并于1896年正式改名为普林斯顿大学。（现今位于新泽西州Ewing的新泽西学院与本校无从属关系。） 虽然它最初是长老制的教育机构，但是现在已经成为非宗教大学，对学生亦无任何宗教上的要求。该校与普林斯顿高等研究院、普林斯顿神学院以及莱德大学西敏唱诗班学院有着较为密切的关系。普林斯顿保有浓厚的欧式教育学风，非常重视本科生教育，创立宗旨上强调训练学生具有人文及科学的综合素养。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Принстонский_университет"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Shirley_M._Tilghman"/>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Division_I_(NCAA)"/>
    <dbpprop:cgcNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2</dbpprop:cgcNu>
    <dbpprop:nickname xml:lang="en">Tigers</dbpprop:nickname>
    <dbpprop:usnwrEng rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">18</dbpprop:usnwrEng>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">普林斯顿大学（英語：Princeton University），又译普林斯敦大学，位於美国新泽西州的普林斯顿，是美国一所著名的私立研究型大学，八所常春藤盟校之一。 学校于1746年在新泽西州伊丽莎白镇创立，是美国殖民时期第四所成立的高等教育學院， 当时名为“新泽西学院”，1747年迁至新泽西州，1756年迁至普林斯顿，并于1896年正式改名为普林斯顿大学。（现今位于新泽西州Ewing的新泽西学院与本校无从属关系。） 虽然它最初是长老制的教育机构，但是现在已经成为非宗教大学，对学生亦无任何宗教上的要求。该校与普林斯顿高等研究院、普林斯顿神学院以及莱德大学西敏唱诗班学院有着较为密切的关系。普林斯顿保有浓厚的欧式教育学风，非常重视本科生教育，创立宗旨上强调训练学生具有人文及科学的综合素养。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">Links to related articles</dbpprop:title>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">La Universidad de Princeton, localizada en Princeton, Nueva Jersey, Estados Unidos es una de las ocho universidades de la Ivy League. Fue fundada como el College of New Jersey en 1746, y estuvo originalmente localizada en Elizabeth (Nueva Jersey). Reconocida como una de las más prestigiosas universidades del mundo, la universidad fue trasladada a Princeton en 1756, manteniendo el nombre original. El nombre fue cambiado oficialmente a Universidad de Princeton ("Princeton University") en 1896. Originalmente fue una institución presbiteriana, actualmente laica. En ella impartieron clases los matemáticos John Nash y George Dantzig (este último inventor del Algoritmo simplex). El famoso físico Albert Einstein enseñaba e investigaba en el Instituto de Estudios Avanzados de Princeton, una institución cercana a la Universidad, aunque independiente. Princeton es una de las universidades más ricas del mundo con un presupuesto que supera los 13 mil millones de dólares. Parte de estos recursos son invertidos en el museo de arte http://artmuseum. princeton. edu/ que exhibe numerosas pinturas, esculturas y arqueología; sus fondos suman 72.000 piezas. De historia ya centenaria, este museo cuenta con pinturas de Fra Angelico, Hendrick Goltzius, Goya (una de sus raras acuarelas sobre marfil), Monet, Gauguin, Warhol y muchos otros artistas preeminentes. Cuenta también con abundantes grabados y dibujos, arte africano, porcelanas... Princeton es constantemente calificada entre las mejores universidades de EE.  UU. y del mundo con siete nominaciones consecutivas al primer puesto por la revista US News &amp; World Report; este último año (2008) logró el puesto número uno por encima de las prestigiosas Harvard, Yale, Stanford y Chicago . Honoris Causa: Varios estudiantes destacados llegaron a los honores de Summa cuma laude, máximas alabanzas. Figuran en el cuadro de estudiantes de honor.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:colors xml:lang="en">Orange and black</dbpprop:colors>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_US_university_ranking"/>
    <foaf:nick xml:lang="en">Tigers</foaf:nick>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Universitat de Princeton</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:arwuN rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6</dbpprop:arwuN>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidad_de_Princeton"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidade_de_Princeton"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Uniwersytet Princeton – naukowo-badawczy uniwersytet prywatny w Stanach Zjednoczonych, działający w mieście Princeton w stanie New Jersey. Nazwa także odnosi się do college'u, czyli instytucji studiów licencjackich. Właśnie głównie ci studenci historycznie tworzą kulturę kampusu i afiszują swoją przynależność doń, w znaczeniu "Princeton man", w ścisłym odróżnieniu od "Yale man" czy "Harvard man". Studenci z Princeton odwiecznie rywalizują ze studentami z Yale i Harvardu.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:calendar xml:lang="en">Semester</dbpprop:calendar>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Princeton University is a private research university located in Princeton, New Jersey, United States. It is one of the eight universities of the Ivy League, and one of the nine Colonial Colleges founded before the American Revolution. Princeton provides undergraduate and graduate instruction in the humanities, social sciences, natural sciences and engineering. Princeton does not have schools of medicine, law, divinity, or business, but it does offer professional degrees through the Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs, the Princeton University School of Engineering and Applied Science and the School of Architecture. Founded in 1746 in Elizabeth, New Jersey, as the College of New Jersey, the university moved to Newark in 1747, then to Princeton in 1756 and was renamed Princeton University in 1896. The present-day College of New Jersey in nearby Ewing, New Jersey, is an unrelated institution. Princeton was the fourth chartered institution of higher education in the American colonies. Princeton had close ties to the Presbyterian Church, but has never been affiliated with any denomination and today imposes no religious requirements on its students. The university has ties with the Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton Theological Seminary, and the Westminster Choir College of Rider University. Princeton has been associated with 35 Nobel Laureates, 17 National Medal of Science winners, and three National Humanities Medal winners. On a per-student basis, Princeton has the largest university endowment in the world.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Collegiate_Athletic_Association"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Đại học Princeton là một đại học tư thục tọa lạc ở Princeton, New Jersey, Hoa Kỳ. Đó là viện đại học xếp thứ tư trong các trường và viện đại học cổ xưa nhất ở Hoa Kỳ và một trong tám trường và viện đại học của Ivy League. Được thành lập tại Elizabeth, New Jersey vào năm 1746 mang tên đại học New Jersey, trường được dời về Newark năm 1747, sau đó về Princeton năm 1756 và đổi tên là "Đại học Princeton" năm 1896. (trường hiện nay mang tên đại học New Jersey ở gần Ewing, New Jersey là một trường không liên quan). Princeton cung cấp nhiều chương trình nghiên cứu sau đại học (đáng kể nhất là chương trình Ph.D. ), và xếp hạng tốt nhất trong nhiều ngành, bao gồm toán, vật lý, thiên văn và vật lý plasma, kinh tế, lịch sử và triết học. Tuy vậy, trường không có một loạt các khoa đào tạo sau đại học như nhiều đại học khác — ví dụ, Princeton không có trường y khoa, trường luật khoa, hay trường quản trị kinh doanh. Trường chuyên nghiệp nổi tiếng nhất là Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs (thường được học sinh gọi là "Woody Woo"), thành lập năm 1930 mang tên School of Public and International Affairs và được đổi tên vào năm 1948. Trường cũng có các chương trình sau đại học trong các ngành kỹ thuật, kiến trúc và tài chính. Thư viện trường có hơn 11 triệu đầu sách. Thư viện chính của trường, thư viện Firestone, chứa khoảng 4 triệu cuốn sách, là một trong những thư viện đại học lớn nhất trên thế giới (và trong các thư viện lớn nhất có "các kệ sách mở" đã từng tồn tại). Trong bộ sưu tập của nó có cả những bản sách vô giá như tập bài thuyết pháp Blickling. Bên cạnh Firestone, trường còn có nhiều thư viện chuyên ngành, bao gồm kiến trúc, lịch sử nghệ thuật, nghiên cứu Đông Á, kỹ thuật, địa lý, ngoại giao và chính sách công và nghiên cứu Cận Đông.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.05zl0"/>
    <dbpprop:undergrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5113</dbpprop:undergrad>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/EducationalInstitution"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.princeton.edu/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">프린스턴 대학교(Princeton University)는 1746년에 설립한 미국 뉴저지 주 프린스턴에 있는 사립 대학으로, 미국 동부 8개 명문 아이비리그에 속해 있으며, 미국의 최고 대학 중 하나로 손꼽힌다. 프린스턴 대학교는 미국에서 4번째 대학으로, 하버드 대학교, 윌리엄 앤 메리 대학교, 예일 대학교 다음으로 수립되었다. 전통적으로 학부 교육과 학문 연구에 중심을 두고 있으나, 최근에는 대학원 교육에도 중점을 둬서 다양한 분야에서 많은 석박사를 배출하고 있다. 프린스턴대는 학부(undergraduate)와 대학원(graduate)에서 인문, 사회과학, 자연과학, 공학을 제공한다. 우드로 윌슨 공공국제정책대학원(Woodrow Wilson School of Public and International Affairs)이 전문대학원으로 석사 박사과정을 제공한다. 도서관에는 6백만권 이상의 책을 소장하고 있다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1746_establishments_in_the_Thirteen_Colonies"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Đại học Princeton</rdfs:label>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-74.6593</geo:long>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Listen"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Princeton University er et privat universitet i Princeton i New Jersey i USA. Det er den fjerde eldste institusjonen for høyere utdanning i USA, grunnlagt i byen Elisabeth i 1746 som College of New Jersey. Det inntar i 2008 tolvte plass globalt på Times´ liste over verdens beste universiteter. I 1896 flyttet institusjonen til Princeton, og fikk samtidig navnet Princeton University. Samme år ble Woodrow Wilson ansatt som professor her, og han var rektor fra 1902. Under hans ledelse tok lærestedet et kvalitetssprang og etablerte seg som et av lndets ledende universitet. Wilson ble deretter nominert og valgt til guvernør i New Jersey. Princeton er ett av åtte Ivy League-universiteter i USA. I 2006 var det ialt 7 242 studenter ved Princeton, og skolepengene utgjorde US$ 33 000 årlig. Med 1 025 vitenskapelig ansatte samme år, ga det en student:lærer-tetthet på 7:1, som er meget stor lærertetthet selv blant de bedre amerikanske universitetene.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.princeton.edu/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/usDollar">1.71E10</dbpedia-owl:endowment>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_university"/>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.princeton.edu/"/>
    <dbpprop:qsW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">13</dbpprop:qsW>
    <dbpprop:usnwrNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:usnwrNu>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Princeton,_New_Jersey"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">7567</dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">40.34873 -74.65931</grs:point>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/プリンストン大学"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Прінстонський університет</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Educational_institutions_established_in_the_1740s"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">普林斯顿大学</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Die Princeton University ist eine in der Stadt Princeton im US-Bundesstaat New Jersey gelegene Universität. Sie ist die viertälteste Universität der USA und Gründungsmitglied der Association of American Universities, eines seit 1900 bestehenden Verbundes führender forschungsintensiver nordamerikanischer Universitäten, sowie der „Ivy League“. Princeton ist eine der angesehensten Universitäten der Welt. Außerdem ist sie eine der reichsten Universitäten mit einem Kapitalstock von über siebzehn Milliarden US-Dollar, der durch Spenden der Alumni angesammelt wurde (das weltweit größte Pro-Kopf-Vermögen einer Universität). Ebenfalls in Princeton befindet sich das Institute for Advanced Study. Obwohl es eine enge Zusammenarbeit gibt, hat das Institut keine formelle Verbindung mit der Princeton-Universität.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wamoNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">31</dbpprop:wamoNu>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvV1x_5wpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Middle_Atlantic_Intercollegiate_Sailing_Association"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:formerName xml:lang="en">College of New Jersey (1746–1896)</dbpedia-owl:formerName>
    <dbpprop:gur rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">12</dbpprop:gur>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Princetonská univerzita (Princeton University) je jedna z nejprestižnějších univerzit v USA. Je to soukromá univerzita, sídlící ve městě Princeton, New Jersey. Je také jedním z osmi členů Ivy League. Byla založena roku 1746 v Elizabeth, New Jersey, původně pod názvem College of New Jersey. Roku 1756 se přesunula do Princetonu a roku 1896 se přejmenovala na “Princeton University”. Princeton byla čtvrtá instituce pro vyšší vzdělávání ve Spojených Státech, a Princeton tvrdí, že to byla „čtvrtá vysoká škola založená v britské Severní Americe. “ Princeton se tradičně zaměřuje na program bakalářského studia a akademická studia, nicméně v posledních desetiletích zvýšil svůj zájem o postbakalářské studium a nabízí velké množství vysoce hodnocených profesionálních magisterských úrovní a Ph.D. programů. Princeton University Library čítá přes šest milionů knih. Oblasti výzkumu mimo jiné zahrnují antropologii, geofyziku, entomologii a robotiku, zatímco Forrestal Campus má speciální zařízení pro studium fyziky plazmy a meteorologie. Princeton neměl nikdy žádné oficiální náboženské svazky, což bylo vzácné mezi americkými univerzitami té doby. Jednoho času měl úzký vztah s Presbyteriánskou církví, ale dnes je nesektářský a nedává na své studenty žádné náboženské požadavky. Univerzita má vazby k Institute for Advanced Study, Princeton Theological Seminary a Westminster Choir College z Rider University.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Princetonská_univerzita"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Princetonin yliopisto New Jerseyssä Yhdysvalloissa on vuonna 1746 perustettu, Yhdysvaltain neljänneksi vanhin yliopisto. Sitä arvostetaan etenkin poliitikkojen, arkkitehtien ja teknisen alan oppilaitoksena. Tutkimusaloista näkyvimpiin nousi fysiikka, nykyisin mm. plasmafysiikka, kun Albert Einstein päätyi toisen maailmansodan jälkeen professoriksi Princetoniin. Princeton kuuluu Yhdysvaltojen eliittiyliopistojen joukkoon, jota kutsutaan nimellä "Ivy League".</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Принстонский университет — частный университет, один из старейших и известнейших университетов в США. Входит в Лигу плюща и является одним из самых престижных вузов страны. Находится в городе Принстон, штат Нью-Джерси.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/71/Princeton_shield.svg"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/5102955/"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_University?oldid=494372609"/>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">40.3487</geo:lat>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Princeton University</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ivy_League"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">A Universidade Princeton (em inglês Princeton University), localizada em Princeton, estado de Nova Jérsei, Estados Unidos, é uma das oito prestigiosas universidades da Ivy League. Fundada como College of New Jersey em 1746, esteve originalmente localizada por um ano em Elizabeth, no mesmo estado norte-americano, depois em Newark, por nove anos, também em Nova Jérsey. Em 1756, foi finalmente transferida para Princeton, onde se estabeleceu no edifício histórico conhecido por Nassau Hall, construído nas terras então doadas por Nathaniel Fitz Randolph. O edifício, que foi temporariamente a capital dos EUA, em 1783, abrigou todos os cursos oferecidos pela universidade durante meio século. Hoje, porém, Princeton conta com diversos prédios em seu campus principal, nos quais abriga seus cursos de graduação e pós-graduação. Fundada inicialmente como College of New Jersey, Princeton manteve seu nome original por 150 anos. Em 1896, quando a expansão do seu currículo trouxe à Faculdade o status de universidade, foi oficialmente rebatizada para Princeton University. Atualmente, é reconhecida como uma das mais prestigiadas universidades do mundo, oferecendo diversos graus em graduação e pós-graduação, mais notavelmente o grau de Ph.D.. Está classificada como a melhor em muitas áreas, incluindo matemática, física e astronomia, economia, história e filosofia. Princeton está entre as universidades mais ricas do mundo, com uma dotação de pouco mais de onze bilhões de dólares (a quarta maior do mundo), sustentada pelas contínuas doações de seus ex-alunos e mantida por conselheiros de investimento. Parte da riqueza de Princeton é investida em seu museu de arte, que possui em seu acervo permanente obras de Claude Monet e Andy Warhol, dentre outros preeminentes artistas. Fundada originalmente como uma instituição presbiteriana, tem hodiernamente orientação laica.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ivy_League"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Princetonská univerzita</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_university"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">A Universidade Princeton (em inglês Princeton University), localizada em Princeton, estado de Nova Jérsei, Estados Unidos, é uma das oito prestigiosas universidades da Ivy League. Fundada como College of New Jersey em 1746, esteve originalmente localizada por um ano em Elizabeth, no mesmo estado norte-americano, depois em Newark, por nove anos, também em Nova Jérsey.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Πανεπιστήμιο_Πρίνστον"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-university-noun-2"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Princeton University</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:arwuSci rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3</dbpprop:arwuSci>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Princeton_University"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Princeton_University"/>
    <dbpprop:endowment xml:lang="en">US$ 17.1 billion</dbpprop:endowment>
    <dbpprop:country xml:lang="en">United States</dbpprop:country>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Université_de_Princeton"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Прінстонський університет — один із найстаріших і найпрестижніших університетів США, розташований у місті Прінстон, штат Нью-Джерсі. Входить у Лігу плюща. Прінстонський університет був заснований в 1746 році як Коледж Нью-Джерсі (College of New Jersey). Став четвертим коледжем колоній. Перші заняття проходили в будинку засновника університету священика Джонатана Дікінсона в місті Нью-Брансвік. Переїхав у місто Прінстон в 1756 році. Прінстон відіграв помітну роль у подіях Американської революції: підпис його ректора Джона Візерспуна стоїть під Декларацією незалежності, шоста частина учасників Конституційного конвенту були випускниками Прінстона. В 1877 заснована магістратура, в 1896 Прінстон отримав статус університету, а в 1902 його ректором став Вудро Вільсон, який сприяв тому, що університет має сьогодні такий авторитет. Складається з Прінстонського коледжу, магістратури і дослідницьких центрів. Має спільні будівлі з Інститутом перспективних досліджень. Старий будинок - Нассау-хол (1756), місце проведення Другого континентального конгресу. В структуру університету входять провідний регіональний театр Маккартера, художній музей і музей природної історії. Бібліотека нараховує понад 4,8 млн. томів. В університеті навчається близько 5 тис. студентів та 2,5 тис. аспірантів та докторантів.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">L'université de Princeton (Princeton University) est située dans la ville de Princeton dans l'État du New Jersey, aux États-Unis. Membre de l'Ivy League, elle a été fondée en 1746 en tant que collège du New Jersey. Elle devient l'université de Princeton en 1896.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Eastern_Pennsylvania_Rugby_Union"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Middle_Atlantic_Intercollegiate_Sailing_Association"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Đại học Princeton là một đại học tư thục tọa lạc ở Princeton, New Jersey, Hoa Kỳ. Đó là viện đại học xếp thứ tư trong các trường và viện đại học cổ xưa nhất ở Hoa Kỳ và một trong tám trường và viện đại học của Ivy League. Được thành lập tại Elizabeth, New Jersey vào năm 1746 mang tên đại học New Jersey, trường được dời về Newark năm 1747, sau đó về Princeton năm 1756 và đổi tên là "Đại học Princeton" năm 1896.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Colonial_Colleges"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Princeton University is a private research university located in Princeton, New Jersey, United States. It is one of the eight universities of the Ivy League, and one of the nine Colonial Colleges founded before the American Revolution. Princeton provides undergraduate and graduate instruction in the humanities, social sciences, natural sciences and engineering.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:titlestyle xml:lang="en">background:black;color:#FF6600</dbpprop:titlestyle>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">A Princetoni Egyetem (Princeton University) a New Jersey állambeli Princetonban található egyetem, az Amerikai Egyesült Államok ötödik legidősebb és egyik legelőkelőbb felsőoktatási intézménye. A Princetonon van építészeti, mérnöki és nemzetközi ügyek iskola. A kutatások széles területet ölelnek fel, közöttük van a plazmafizika, meteorológia és a sugárhajtás kutatása. Az erdős egyetemi területen plazmafizikai és meteorológiai létesítmények vannak.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Princeton University</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/71/Princeton_shield.svg/200px-Princeton_shield.svg.png"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">L'Università di Princeton, situata a Princeton nel New Jersey, è una delle maggiori università della Ivy League ed è riconosciuta come una delle più prestigiose università nel mondo. È inoltre la quarta più antica istituzione di educazione superiore degli Stati Uniti. Fu fondata come College del New Jersey nel 1746 ed era originariamente collocata a Elizabeth (New Jersey). La scuola si trasferì a Princeton nel 1756, ancora col suo nome originale.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:forbes rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2</dbpprop:forbes>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Die Princeton University ist eine in der Stadt Princeton im US-Bundesstaat New Jersey gelegene Universität. Sie ist die viertälteste Universität der USA und Gründungsmitglied der Association of American Universities, eines seit 1900 bestehenden Verbundes führender forschungsintensiver nordamerikanischer Universitäten, sowie der „Ivy League“. Princeton ist eine der angesehensten Universitäten der Welt.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Princeton University is een particuliere universiteit uit de Verenigde Staten. De universiteit werd in 1746 gesticht in Elizabeth (New Jersey) als "College of New Jersey". In 1756 verplaatste men het college naar Princeton (New Jersey), maar de oorspronkelijke naam werd vooralsnog behouden. Pas in 1896 werd het College of New Jersey omgedoopt in Princeton University. Princeton was de vierde universiteit in de geschiedenis van de Verenigde Staten die begon met het geven van lessen. De universiteit behoort tot de Ivy League, een groep particuliere universiteiten uit de Verenigde Staten die bekendstaan om hun hoge academische niveau. Princeton is een van de meest prestigieuze universiteiten ter wereld, met zeer hoge toelatingseisen, en werd in het afgelopen decennium door U.S. News &amp; World Report gezien als beste universiteit in de Verenigde Staten. Ook behoort Princeton tot de negen Colonial Colleges, de negen Amerikaanse universiteiten die opgericht werden voor de Amerikaanse Revolutie.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:mottoeng xml:lang="en">Under God's Power She Flourishes</dbpprop:mottoeng>
    <dbpprop:state xml:lang="en">autocollapse</dbpprop:state>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">Old Nassau</dbpprop:title>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">A Princetoni Egyetem (Princeton University) a New Jersey állambeli Princetonban található egyetem, az Amerikai Egyesült Államok ötödik legidősebb és egyik legelőkelőbb felsőoktatási intézménye. A Princetonon van építészeti, mérnöki és nemzetközi ügyek iskola. A kutatások széles területet ölelnek fel, közöttük van a plazmafizika, meteorológia és a sugárhajtás kutatása. Az erdős egyetemi területen plazmafizikai és meteorológiai létesítmények vannak. Az egyetem kapcsolatban áll a Brookhaveni Nemzeti Laboratóriummal. Az 1948-ban megnyílt Harvey S. Firestone Könyvtár és a művészeti múzeum épülete gazdag gyűjteménnyel rendelkezik. Az egyetemet eredetileg New Jersey-i Főiskola néven alapították 1746-ban, és eredetileg Elizabeth, New Jersey volt a székhelye. 1756-ban került át Princetonba. Jelenlegi nevét 1896-ban kapta. Eredetileg presbiteriánus intézmény volt, jelenleg viszont nem tesz különbséget hallgatói között vallási alapon. A Princeton az Ivy League nyolc iskolájának egyike és tagja a Association of American Universities-nek.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Princeton University</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CollegeOrUniversity"/>
    <dbpprop:established rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1746</dbpprop:established>
    <dbpprop:thesW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5</dbpprop:thesW>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Princeton University er et privat universitet i Princeton i New Jersey i USA. Det er den fjerde eldste institusjonen for høyere utdanning i USA, grunnlagt i byen Elisabeth i 1746 som College of New Jersey. Det inntar i 2008 tolvte plass globalt på Times´ liste over verdens beste universiteter. I 1896 flyttet institusjonen til Princeton, og fikk samtidig navnet Princeton University. Samme år ble Woodrow Wilson ansatt som professor her, og han var rektor fra 1902.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">L'Università di Princeton, situata a Princeton nel New Jersey, è una delle maggiori università della Ivy League ed è riconosciuta come una delle più prestigiose università nel mondo. È inoltre la quarta più antica istituzione di educazione superiore degli Stati Uniti. Fu fondata come College del New Jersey nel 1746 ed era originariamente collocata a Elizabeth (New Jersey). La scuola si trasferì a Princeton nel 1756, ancora col suo nome originale. Il nome fu cambiato ufficialmente in "Università di Princeton" nel 1896. Insegna in questa università l'economista Paul Krugman, mentre in passato vi hanno insegnato gli economisti Ben Bernanke e John P. Lewis. Secondo la celebre rivista americana U.S. News &amp; World Report che stila ogni anno dal 1983 la classifica delle migliori Università degli U.S.A. essa è per l'anno 2010 al primo posto a pari merito con l'Università di Harvard mentre l'Università di Yale segue al terzo posto. Sebbene originariamente fosse un’istituzione presbiteriana, l'università oggi non è più confessionale e non richiede alcuna dichiarazione religiosa ai suoi allievi.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:latinName xml:lang="en">Universitas Princetoniensis</dbpprop:latinName>
    <dbpprop:state xml:lang="en">New Jersey</dbpprop:state>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Princeton_University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_university"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">学生数は学部生4800人、大学院生2000人である。卒業生の中に2人の大統領がいる、アメリカ全土で8番目に古い、などで有名な大学である。2010年度の受験サイクルでは全受験者の8.8%が入学を許可された。なお、プリンストン高等研究所（Institute for Advanced Study）とは相互交流は盛んであるものの、プリンストン大学と直接の関係はない。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L'université de Princeton (Princeton University) est située dans la ville de Princeton dans l'État du New Jersey, aux États-Unis. Membre de l'Ivy League, elle a été fondée en 1746 en tant que collège du New Jersey. Elle devient l'université de Princeton en 1896.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
