<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Public_Record_Office_of_Northern_Ireland">
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Public Record Office of Northern Ireland</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Public Record Office of Northern Ireland (PRONI) er en offentlig etat i Nord-Irland, med lokaler i Belfast. Den skiller seg fra andre offentlige arkivetater i Det forente kongerike ved at det har både offentlige og private dokumenter. Etaten fungerer som arkiv for offentlige dokumenter, tilsvarende Public Record Office i England og Wales, som manuskriptarkiv med nasjonalbibliotekfunksjon og som arkiv for tidligere grevskap i Nord-Irland. Dette inkluderer også en stor mengde kirkelige og private dokumenter.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.065432"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The Public Record Office of Northern Ireland (PRONI) is situated in Belfast, Northern Ireland. It is a division within the Department of Culture, Arts and Leisure (DCAL). The Public Record Office of Northern Ireland is distinguished from other archival institutions in the United Kingdom by its unique combination of private and official records. The Record Office is not the Northern Ireland equivalent or imitation of any Great Britain or Republic of Ireland archival institution. It combines the functions and responsibilities of a range of institutions: it is at the same time Public Record Office, Manuscripts Department of a National Library, County Record Office for the six counties of Northern Ireland, and holder of a large range of private records. This range of remit, embracing, among others, central and local government, the Churches and the private sector, is unique to Northern Ireland.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Organisations_based_in_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">54.5663</geo:lat>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-5.95897</geo:long>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_genealogy"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Public Record Office of Northern Ireland (PRONI) er en offentlig etat i Nord-Irland, med lokaler i Belfast. Den skiller seg fra andre offentlige arkivetater i Det forente kongerike ved at det har både offentlige og private dokumenter. Etaten fungerer som arkiv for offentlige dokumenter, tilsvarende Public Record Office i England og Wales, som manuskriptarkiv med nasjonalbibliotekfunksjon og som arkiv for tidligere grevskap i Nord-Irland.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:History_of_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The Public Record Office of Northern Ireland (PRONI) is situated in Belfast, Northern Ireland. It is a division within the Department of Culture, Arts and Leisure (DCAL). The Public Record Office of Northern Ireland is distinguished from other archival institutions in the United Kingdom by its unique combination of private and official records. The Record Office is not the Northern Ireland equivalent or imitation of any Great Britain or Republic of Ireland archival institution.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Archives_in_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_Record_Office_of_Northern_Ireland?oldid=481158461"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Culture_in_Belfast"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Public_Record_Office_of_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Northern_Ireland_Executive"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.proni.gov.uk"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Public_Record_Office_of_Northern_Ireland"/>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-5.95897 54.5663)</geo:geometry>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">54.566269444444444 -5.958966666666667</grs:point>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
