<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Saint_Patrick">
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Anglican_saints"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Патрик, Патрикий 250px Витраж в оклендском соборе Светлого ХристаРождение: 371/ 373 / 385 / 387 / 389 / 415 Место: вероятно, Британия (совр. Англия, Уэльс), точно не известно Смерть: 457 / 460 / 461 / 469 / 492 / 493 Место кончины точно не известно Почитается: Католичество, православие, англиканство День памяти: 17 марта Покровитель: Ирландии, Нигерии Труды: Confessio, Epistola ad Coroticum, предположительно — ряд гимнов.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.confessio.ie"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Romano-BritishSaints"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_saint"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Der heilige Patrick von Irland war ein christlicher Missionar und gilt in Irland als Nationalheiliger.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">San Patricio fue un misionero cristiano y es conocido como el santo patrón de Irlanda, junto a Santa Brígida y San Columba, fue un predicador y religioso de Britania, tradicionalmente considerado el introductor de la religión cristiana en la isla. En España es patrón de la ciudad de Murcia y su antiguo Reino, debido a que la reconquista de estos territorios se produjo el día de la festividad del santo del año 1452, tras la victoria obtenida por las tropas cristianas de Juan II de Castilla en la Batalla de los Alporchones. También es patrón de la localidad granadina de Albuñol debido a que, según la tradición, apareció una imagen del santo en la playa proveniente de los restos de un naufragio de un barco irlandés.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Thánh Patrick là một người La Mã-Anh và là nhà truyền giáo của Giáo hội Công giáo Rôma. Ông được biết tới nhiều nhất qua vai trò là thánh quan thầy của Ireland hoặc là sứ đồ của Ireland, tuy nhiên Brigid của Kildare và Colmcille là thánh quan thầy chính thức. Hai lá thư thực sự khi ông còn sống được lấy làm nguồn tư liệu chủ yếu khi viết về tiểu sử của ông. Khi còn là chàng thanh niên 16 tuổi, Patrick bị người Irish bắt khi đang ở Wales.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eastern_Orthodox_Church"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Saint</foaf:givenName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Der heilige Patrick von Irland war ein christlicher Missionar und gilt in Irland als Nationalheiliger.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:majorShrine rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Armagh"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Святой_Патрик"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:4th-century_people"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">圣帕特里克主教（英语：St. Patrick；拉丁语：Sanctus Patricius；愛爾蘭語：Naomh Pádraig；威爾斯文：Sant Patrig。386年–461年），其慶日在3月17日，為圣帕特里克节，在很多有愛爾蘭人血統的國家都會有慶祝活動。 聖派翠克於385年左右出生於蘇格蘭。幼年時曾被俘至愛爾蘭，為人牧羊。獲自由後，出家，成為聖職人員，後被立為愛爾蘭區主教，竭力宣傳福音，奠定愛爾蘭天主教會的信仰基礎。461年逝世。 聖派翠克是愛爾蘭教區的主保聖人。英國國旗中，白底，紅色X形狀，就是代表著他。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/MedievalIrishSaints"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Celtic_Christian_bishops"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.documentacatholicaomnia.eu/30_10_0387-0493-_Patricius,_Sanctus.html"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/5th-centuryIrishPeople"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cumbria"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Romano-British_saints"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Banna_Venta_Berniae"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Monomyths"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Christian_missionaries_in_Ireland"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:380s_births"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:4th-century_Irish_people"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/8/86/Saint_Patrick_(window).jpg"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Saint Patrick</dbpprop:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Christian_folklore"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">성 파트리치오는 아일랜드의 수호성인이다. 영국과 아일랜드에서 전도한 선교사이자 주교이다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Patrick"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Medieval_Irish_saints"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ucc.ie/celt"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/PersonWithOccupation"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_folklore"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Thánh Patrick là một người La Mã-Anh và là nhà truyền giáo của Giáo hội Công giáo Rôma. Ông được biết tới nhiều nhất qua vai trò là thánh quan thầy của Ireland hoặc là sứ đồ của Ireland, tuy nhiên Brigid của Kildare và Colmcille là thánh quan thầy chính thức. Hai lá thư thực sự khi ông còn sống được lấy làm nguồn tư liệu chủ yếu khi viết về tiểu sử của ông. Khi còn là chàng thanh niên 16 tuổi, Patrick bị người Irish bắt khi đang ở Wales. Ông bị bắt giam 6 năm trước khi trốn thoát được và trở về với gia đình. Sau khi theo đạo Công giáo, ông trở về Ireland với chức giám mục cai quản vùng Bắc và Tây của đảo Ireland, nhưng ông biết rất ít về khu vực mà ông được bổ nhiệm để cai quản. Vào thế kỷ thứ bảy, ông được phong làm thánh quan thầy của Ireland. Đa số những tài liệu chi tiết về ông được viết từ khi thánh nhân học (hagiographies) bắt đầu từ thế kỷ thứ bảy trở đi, và những chi tiết này được chỉ trích nặng nề. Những thông tin chấp nhận được là biên niên sử của Ulster (Annals of Ulster), viết rằng ông sống từ năm 340 đến 440 sau công nguyên, và là người cai quản vùng phía Bắc của Ireland ngày nay từ năm 428 trở về sau. Những năm tháng nói về thánh Patrick không thể xác định rõ được nhưng có nhiều phỏng đoán trên một số tài liệu đáng tinh cậy là ngày làm việc tích cực truyền giáo của ông là trong nửa sau thế kỷ thứ năm. Ngày thánh Patrick được ăn mừng vào ngày 17 tháng ba, là ngày thánh Patrick qua đời. Lễ này được ăn mừng, kỷ niệm tại Ireland và một số nước khác trên thế giới. Nó được coi là ngày lễ vừa mang tính tôn giáo vừa mang tính thế tục. Tại các giáo phận ở Ireland và các nước khác, đây là lễ trọng (solemnity) và là lễ buộc phải tham dự. Nó còn là tượng trưng cho ngày lễ ăn mừng Ireland.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Saint_Patrick"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Patrick_d'Irlande"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Medieval_Irish_writers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Pyhä Patrick on Irlannin suojeluspyhimys, jonka ansioksi on nimetty kristinuskon vakiinnuttaminen Irlantiin 400-luvulla. Pyhä Patrick on myös Nigerian suojelupyhimys sekä insinöörien ja karkotettujen suojelupyhimys. Hänen muistopäivänsä on 17. maaliskuuta, joka tunnetaan Pyhän Patrickin päivänä. Pyhän Patrickin päivä on Irlannin kansallispäivä, jota juhlitaan, paitsi Irlannissa, myös muualla maailmassa irlantilaisten keskuudessa. Esimerkiksi Yhdysvalloissa Pyhän Patrickin päivää juhlitaan yleensä suurellisesti. Pyhä Patrick oli luultavasti kotoisin Kilpatrickista Skotlannista. Tosin Patrickin syntymäpaikaksi on myös arveltu Ison-Britannian länsirannikkoa ja Ranskan pohjoisrannikkoa. Hän joutui rosvojen kaappaamaksi ja orjaksi Irlantiin. Orjuudessa hänestä tuli harras kristitty. Hän pakeni, opiskeli luostarissa Ranskassa ja palasi Irlantiin käännytystyöhön ja järjesti kirkolliset olot.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_celebrated_in_the_Lutheran_liturgical_calendar"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/パトリキウス"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Patricius is de beroemdste missionaris van Ierland en is heilig verklaard. Hij is werkzaam geweest in de vijfde eeuw. Noch van het begin van zijn activiteiten, noch van zijn geboorte is een precieze datum bekend. Er zijn twee boeken van zijn hand, de Belijdenis en de Brief aan de soldaten van Coroticus. Daarin wordt duidelijk dat hij als jongen van 16 door Ierse heidenen als slaaf naar het eiland gebracht werd. Daar werd hij schaapherder en leerde Iers. Door een visioen kon hij vluchten en keerde hij naar zijn ouders terug, maar volgens een andere legende werd hij door heidense Ieren na 6 jaar naar Gallië gebracht. Hij ging de priesteropleiding volgen in Auxerre in het toenmalige Gallië. Paus Celestinus I (422-432) gaf hem de opdracht het heidense Ierland te kerstenen. Hij keerde naar het eiland terug om op de meest afgelegen plekken waar nog nooit een prediker gezien was het christendom te brengen. Mogelijk werd hij door zijn vroegere leraar, bisschop Germanus van Auxerre, tot eerste bisschop van Ierland gewijd. Hij had het niet makkelijk, omdat de katholieke Britten hem minachtten vanwege zijn lagere achtergrond en de Ieren hem wantrouwden omdat hij een vreemdeling was. Halverwege de 5e eeuw vestigde hij zijn bisschopszetel in Armagh. Hij zou honderden kerken hebben gesticht. Hij overleed in of na 461, mogelijk in Armagh of Saul. Waar hij is begraven is onbekend. In later tijden werd vooral in het bisdom Armagh, dat het primaat van Ierland opeiste, zorgvuldig een cultus rond zijn persoon opgebouwd. Vandaag geldt hij als dé Ierse heilige bij uitstek. Een populaire legende over hem vertelt hoe hij de slangen uit Ierland verdreef (vandaar dat er geen slangen zijn op het eiland), en hoe hij een shamrock, een klaverblad, gebruikte als symbool voor de goddelijke Drie-eenheid van het katholieke geloof. Hij wordt ook voornamelijk afgebeeld met de shamrock in zijn hand, en het klaverblad is ook een embleem voor Ierland (alhoewel de harp het officiële symbool is). De nationale feestdag van Ierland is dan ook naar hem vernoemd, St. Patrick's Day of Lá Fhéile Pádraig, en wordt gevierd op 17 maart. Verder is hij de patroon van kuipers, mijnwerkers, smeden en het vee en beschermt hij tegen ongedierte, veeziekte en het kwaad.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Patricius is de beroemdste missionaris van Ierland en is heilig verklaard. Hij is werkzaam geweest in de vijfde eeuw. Noch van het begin van zijn activiteiten, noch van zijn geboorte is een precieze datum bekend. Er zijn twee boeken van zijn hand, de Belijdenis en de Brief aan de soldaten van Coroticus. Daarin wordt duidelijk dat hij als jongen van 16 door Ierse heidenen als slaaf naar het eiland gebracht werd. Daar werd hij schaapherder en leerde Iers.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_bishops"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Pyhä Patrick on Irlannin suojeluspyhimys, jonka ansioksi on nimetty kristinuskon vakiinnuttaminen Irlantiin 400-luvulla. Pyhä Patrick on myös Nigerian suojelupyhimys sekä insinöörien ja karkotettujen suojelupyhimys. Hänen muistopäivänsä on 17. maaliskuuta, joka tunnetaan Pyhän Patrickin päivänä. Pyhän Patrickin päivä on Irlannin kansallispäivä, jota juhlitaan, paitsi Irlannissa, myös muualla maailmassa irlantilaisten keskuudessa.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth xml:lang="en">unknown, late 4th century to mid-5th century</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/religion/religions/christianity/saints/patrick_1.shtml"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ChristianMissionariesInIreland"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Northern_Brythonic_saints"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-saint-noun-2"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/5th-centuryBishops"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:5th-century_Irish_people"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Saint Patrick was a Romano-British and Christian missionary, who is the most generally recognized patron saint of Ireland or the Apostle of Ireland, although Brigid of Kildare and Colmcille are also formally patron saints. Two authentic letters from him survive, from which come the only generally-accepted details of his life. When he was about 16, he was captured from Wales by Irish raiders and taken as a slave to Ireland, where he lived for six years before escaping and returning to his family. After entering the Church, he returned to Ireland as an ordained bishop in the north and west of the island, but little is known about the places where he worked. By the seventh century, he had come to be revered as the patron saint of Ireland. Most available details of his life are from later hagiographies from the seventh century onwards, and these are now not accepted without detailed criticism. Uncritical acceptance of the Annals of Ulster would imply that he lived from 340 to 440, and ministered in what is modern-day Northern Ireland from AD 428 onwards. The dates of Patrick's life cannot be fixed with certainty but, on a widespread interpretation, he was active as a missionary in Ireland during the second half of the fifth century. Saint Patrick's Day is observed on March 17, the date of his death. It is celebrated both inside and outside Ireland, as both a liturgical and non-liturgical holiday. In the dioceses of Ireland, it is both a solemnity and a holy day of obligation; outside Ireland, it can be a celebration of Ireland itself.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:5th-century_Christian_saints"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Saint Patrick (vers 385–461) est un saint chrétien fêté le 17 mars. Il est considéré comme l'évangélisateur de l'Irlande et comme le fondateur du christianisme irlandais.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Eastern_Orthodox_saints"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:majorShrine rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Glastonbury_Abbey"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.gutenberg.org/etext/18482"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118641514</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AnglicanSaints"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">성 파트리치오는 아일랜드의 수호성인이다. 영국과 아일랜드에서 전도한 선교사이자 주교이다.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:patronage xml:lang="en">Ireland, Nigeria, Montserrat, Roman Catholic Archdiocese of New York, Boston, Loíza, Murcia , engineers, paralegals, Roman Catholic Archdiocese of Melbourne; invoked against snakes, sins, witchcraft</dbpprop:patronage>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/성_파트리치오"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Svatý_Patrik"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Patrick</foaf:surname>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Banna Venta Berniae, Britain</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Saint_Patrick?oldid=495505591"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Sant Patrici —nascut com a Maewyin Succat en gaèlic — va ser un religiós britó, missioner i evangelitzador de les terres d'Irlanda i fundador del cristianisme en aquesta illa. Venerat com a sant per diverses confessions cristianes, és el sant patró d'Irlanda, celebrat per les comunitats irlandeses d'arreu del món.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Saint"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">圣帕特里克主教（英语：St. Patrick；拉丁语：Sanctus Patricius；愛爾蘭語：Naomh Pádraig；威爾斯文：Sant Patrig。386年–461年），其慶日在3月17日，為圣帕特里克节，在很多有愛爾蘭人血統的國家都會有慶祝活動。 聖派翠克於385年左右出生於蘇格蘭。幼年時曾被俘至愛爾蘭，為人牧羊。獲自由後，出家，成為聖職人員，後被立為愛爾蘭區主教，竭力宣傳福音，奠定愛爾蘭天主教會的信仰基礎。461年逝世。 聖派翠克是愛爾蘭教區的主保聖人。英國國旗中，白底，紅色X形狀，就是代表著他。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Patrick von Irland</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_saints"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Saint Patrick</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ucc.ie/celt/published/L201060/index.html"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_legends"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">För mansnamnet Patrick, se Patrik. Sankt Patrick Sankt Patrick Glasmålning föreställande Sankt Patrick, i Cathedral of Christ the Light, Oakland, Kalifornien. Föddcirka 387Död17 mars 461Vördas inomRomersk-katolska kyrkanAnglikanska kyrkogemenskapenÖstortodox kristendomHelgondag17 marsAttributBiskopsklädd med mitra och kräklaSkyddshelgon förIrland, Nigeria, New York, Boston Patrick, Patricius (iriska Pádraig, naomh Pádraig), i Sverige tidigare känd som Sankt Patrik vilket numera oftast skrivs Patrick, född på 300- eller 400-talet någonstans längs den brittiska västkusten, död 17 mars (årtal okänt) vid Saul nära Downpatrick, County Down, Irland, är Irlands skyddshelgon (St. Patrick). Patricks minnesdag firas den 17 mars.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/IrishBishops"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/São_Patrício"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.075wq"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_Roman_Catholic_saints"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Sant Patrici —nascut com a Maewyin Succat en gaèlic — va ser un religiós britó, missioner i evangelitzador de les terres d'Irlanda i fundador del cristianisme en aquesta illa. Venerat com a sant per diverses confessions cristianes, és el sant patró d'Irlanda, celebrat per les comunitats irlandeses d'arreu del món.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Patrick av Irland (Patricius Magonus Sucatus, oftest bare kjent som St. Patrick, irsk Naomh Pádraig) var Irlands apostel. Han er skytshelgen for øya, og St. Patricks dag, 17. mars, er Republikken Irlands nasjonaldag. Patrick var brite av romersk avstamning. Stedet han kom fra lå sannsynligvis på vestkysten av Storbritannia, mellom Firth of Clyde i Skottland og Severn.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Patrizio_d'Irlanda"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Patrick, Saint</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lutheranism"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://stpatricksday.com/history/stpatrick/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/86/Saint_Patrick_(window).jpg/200px-Saint_Patrick_(window).jpg"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NorthernBrythonicSaints"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:5th-century_people"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">È venerato come santo dalla Chiesa cattolica e ortodossa. Assieme a San Columba di Iona ed a Santa Brigida d'Irlanda è il patrono dell'Irlanda. Era figlio di Calphurnius e Conchessa, appartenenti ad una famiglia nobile romana. Viene festeggiato da tutta la comunità irlandese del mondo il 17 marzo, data della sua morte.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">圣巴特利爵</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:majorShrine rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Armagh"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">17</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ucc.ie/celt/published/L201061/index.html"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Irish_slaves"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpprop:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Lutheranism"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/5th-centuryWriters"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Saint Patrick</foaf:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Άγιος_Πατρίκιος"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.catholic.org/saints/saint.php?saint_id=89"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ottmar-mickmann.de"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/5th-centuryChristianSaints"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Святий Патрик</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Anglican_Communion"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Svatý Patrik (irsky Naomh Pádraig, angl. Saint Patrick) byl starověký křesťanský duchovní, mnich a misionář pocházející z římské Británie a působící v druhé polovině 5. století v Irsku. Naše povědomí o něm je velmi mlhavé, drtivou většinu informací poskytují jednak dva nedatované listy, jichž je sv. Patrik autorem, jednak starověké legendy a jejich soupisy, jejichž nejstarší záznamy pocházejí ze 7. století. Řada moderních historiků je navíc přesvědčena, že část činů, které legendy sv. Patrikovi připisují, ve skutečnosti vykonal misionář Palladius, s nímž postava sv. Patrika v legendách postupně splynula. Život sv. Patrika nelze s jistotou přesně datovat. Ulsterské anály udávají jako rok narození 387 a rok úmrtí 461, obě data však byla zpochybněna. Víme, že sv. Patrik pocházel ze vznešené velšanské rodiny a jeho původní jméno znělo Maewyn Succat (resp. v polatinštěné verzi Magonus Succetus). V šestnácti letech byl unesen otrokáři do Irska, odtamtud po šesti letech uprchl a vrátil se domů. Poté se stal mnichem a vrátil se do Irska, kde misionářsky působil v druhé polovině 5. století. Jeho přesné postavení není jasné, pravděpodobně byl biskupem či opatem s biskupskými pravomocemi. Podle tradice byl prvním opatem a biskupem z Armaghu, ovšem tato informace není podepřena žádnými solidními podklady. Podle tradice byl pohřben v Down Cathedral v Downpatricku po boku sv. Brigity a sv. Kolumby, taktéž patronů Irska, nicméně nikdy to nebylo potvrzeno hmatatelnými důkazy. Minimálně na lokální úrovni byl patrně uctíván jako světec prakticky ihned po své smrti. O míře významu, kterou mu současníci přisuzovali, svědčí i zuřivý spor o to, kde bude pohřben, který přivedl sever Irska na pokraj občanské války. V Irsku a státech s významným irským přistěhovalectvím je mu zasvěcena celá řada kostelů, mezi nimi i větší počet katedrál. Jeho symbolem je zelená barva a jetelový trojlístek, s jehož pomocí údajně vysvětloval princip Nejsvětější Trojice. Svatému Patrikovi, přezdívanému též Apoštol Irska či Věrozvěst Irska (popř. Irů), se připisuje klíčová úloha v pokřesťanštění Irska. Je patronem Irska a jeho svátek, Den svatého Patrika (Saint Patrick's Day), slavený 17. března, tj. v předpokládaný den jeho smrti, je zároveň nejvýznamnějším svátkem Irska a všech Irů a je spojen s rozsáhlými bujarými oslavami, jejichž náboženský rozměr je již poněkud potlačen. Irové svátek slaví všude ve světě, s charakteristickými „zelenými“ oslavami se lze tedy setkat nejen v Irsku, ale i např. ve Spojených státech amerických, Kanadě či České republice.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Saint_Patrick"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Medieval_legends"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EasternOrthodoxSaints"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Patricio_de_Irlanda"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:4th-century_births"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">È venerato come santo dalla Chiesa cattolica e ortodossa. Assieme a San Columba di Iona ed a Santa Brigida d'Irlanda è il patrono dell'Irlanda. Era figlio di Calphurnius e Conchessa, appartenenti ad una famiglia nobile romana. Viene festeggiato da tutta la comunità irlandese del mondo il 17 marzo, data della sua morte.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Eastern_Orthodox_Church"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:5th-century_deaths"/>
    <dbpprop:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Anglican_Communion"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/IrishRomanCatholicSaints"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Święty_Patryk"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Patrick av Irland (Patricius Magonus Sucatus, oftest bare kjent som St. Patrick, irsk Naomh Pádraig) var Irlands apostel. Han er skytshelgen for øya, og St. Patricks dag, 17. mars, er Republikken Irlands nasjonaldag. Patrick var brite av romersk avstamning. Stedet han kom fra lå sannsynligvis på vestkysten av Storbritannia, mellom Firth of Clyde i Skottland og Severn. Andre steder som hevder å være hans fødested er Boulogne-sur-Mer i Frankrike og Kilpatrick ved Dumbarton i Skottland, men det er mindre belegg for dette. Hans far het Calpurnius Sucatus, og var embetsmann og diakon. Hans bestefar Potius var prest; det var på den tiden ikke noe krav om sølibat for presteskapet. Til tross for farens stilling i kirken vokste Patrick ikke opp i et religiøst hjem. Da han var 16 ble han bortført av sjørøvere og solgt som trell til høvdingen Milchu i Antrim i Irland. Der arbeidet han som hyrde, muligens i nærheten av Slemish. Han lærte seg å snakke keltisk, og begynte å bli opptatt av religion og bønn. Etter seks år drømte han at han snart skulle vende hjem, og snart etter ble han løslatt eller klarte å flykte. Han kom seg med et skip til kontinentet, og var blant annet i Gallia og Italia før han kom hjem til familien. Vel hjemme hadde han en ny drøm, hvor han ble kalt til Irland for å virke som misjonær der. Det antas at han reiste til Gallia for å bli utdannet som prest av Germanus av Auxerre etter å ha levd om munk på Lérins i årene 412–415. Han var muligens også i Tours under studiene. Deretter skal han ha virket omkring 15 år i Auxerre, men det er også mulig at han reiste hjem tidligere og fullførte utdannelsen i Britannia. Han fikk ingen høyere utdannelse, noe han senere savnet. Hans latinske skrifter bar preg av et uelegant og til tider simpelt språk. Tradisjonen forteller at han i 432 vendte tilbake til Irland, og at han da hadde blitt vigslet til biskop av St. Germanus. Med seg hadde han også en hjelpebiskop, en prest, en rettskyndig og flere håndverkere. Det fantes da allerede noe kristne i Irland, og pave Celestin I hadde i 431 sendt Palladius som irenes første biskop. Etter å ha misjonert en tid der reiste Palladius til Skottland, hvor han mente det var lettere å få konvertitter. Det ble derfor Patrick som ble den første misjonær som lyktes i å spre kristendommen til et større område i Irland. Han virket særlig i det nordlige, det sentrale og det vestlige Irland, og organiserte kirken der. Patrick skal ha konfrontert høvdingen Laoghaire i Tara på påskeaften. Han tente på påskelyset på høyden Slane, brakte druidene til taushet og omvendte kongens døtre. I Leitrim rev han ned gudebildet av Crom Cruach. Han traff også Milchu igjen, og omvendte ham. Irland har en særstilling i Vest-Europa, ettersom det er det eneste landet i regionen hvor ingen misjonærer led martyrdøden. Han skrev selv Bekjennelser, som forteller om misjonsarbeidet. I 444 opprettet han sitt bispesete i Armagh, som fortsatt er Irlands kirkelige hovedstad. Han opprettet også flere andre bispedømmer. Årsaken til at han selv valgte Armagh var antagelig at en mektig konge holdt til i området. Patrick opprettet også klostre, men levde antagelig ikke selv som munk. Mot slutten av sitt liv hadde han en 40 dagers fasteretrett på Cruachan Aigli i Mayo. Til minne om denne utfør mange Croagh Patrick-valfarten. Han var også en tid ved Lough Derg, hvor det finnes en sten som det sies at han knelte så ofte på at det er avtrykk etter knærne hans i den. To legender omkring St. Patrick er særlig kjent: Han skal ha forvist alle slanger fra Irland, og han skal ha brukt en trebladet kløver (= shamrock) for å forklare Treenigheten. Dette siste er helt usannsynlig, siden Treenigheten var en etablert del av hedensk keltisk religion. Keltiske guder har tre ansikter, de opptrer tre og tre, eller viser seg på tre måter. Nettopp på grunn av dette fellestrekket betraktet kristne keltere sin tidligere religion som førkristen, ikke antikristen. Men disse historiene har blitt vanlige symboler for ham, og trekløveren er også å regne som et irsk nasjonalsymbol. Han forklaring baserer seg på at trekløverens blad er tre adskilte deler, men samtidig ett blad, slik Treenigheten er tre adskilte personer samtidig som det er én gud. Få år før sin død innkalte han til en synode og ga andre i oppdrag å lede kirken i Irland. Han døde antagelig i 461, tradisjonelt tidfestet til 17. mars som derfor er hans festdag. Antagelig døde han et sted sør for Belfast, og skal ha blitt gravlagt i Saul ved Downpatrick, Down i dagens Nord-Irland. Men det er også andre steder som hevdet å være hans siste hvilested, blant annet Glastonbury i England. Legenden om at han skal ha tilbrakt sine siste år som abbed i Glastonbury Abbey er dog helt uten historisk grunnlag. En av hans tenner og en klokke som tilhørte ham oppbevares i National Museum i Dublin. Om hans død vet man bare at den fant sted 17. mars, ifølge irske kilder i året 493. Muirchú moccu Mactheni opplyser i sin meget upålitelige biografi fra ca 695 at «folk i Ulaid sier at helt til slutten av året da han døde, var nattemørket mindre tett enn vanlig. Det er ingen tvil om at dette var et vitnesbyrd om gjerningene til denne betydningsfulle mannen. » Muirchú opplyser videre at like før Patricks død, oppfylte Gud hans ønske om at han alene og ikke Kristus skulle dømme alle irer. Hans helgenkult spredte seg raskt til de mange irske klostrene som fantes rundt om i Europa i tidlig middelalder. I moderne tid har den spredd seg med irske emigranter til blant annet USA og Australia. Den største katedralen i New York er viet til ham, og paraden i New York på St. Patricks dag er en av de tre største feiringene av dagen, sammen med paradene i Dublin og Manchester.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catholic_Church"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Патрик, Патрикий 250px Витраж в оклендском соборе Светлого ХристаРождение: 371/ 373 / 385 / 387 / 389 / 415 Место: вероятно, Британия (совр. Англия, Уэльс), точно не известно Смерть: 457 / 460 / 461 / 469 / 492 / 493 Место кончины точно не известно Почитается: Католичество, православие, англиканство День памяти: 17 марта Покровитель: Ирландии, Нигерии Труды: Confessio, Epistola ad Coroticum, предположительно — ряд гимнов. Подвижничество: проповедь христианства в Ирландии Свято́й Па́трик — христианский святой, покровитель Ирландии и Нигерии. Почитание распространено в католицизме, в отдельных протестантских церквях; в православной церкви имеет место местное почитание в отдельных общинах, вопрос с общецерковным почитанием поместными православными церквами не решён. Святому Патрику посвящено множество соборов и церквей по всему миру, наиболее известный из которых — собор Святого Патрика в Дублине, построенный в 1191 году. Настоятелем собора в XVIII веке был писатель Джонатан Свифт. Единственным источником сравнительно надёжных биографических сведений о Патрике являются его собственные произведения — «Исповедь» (Confessio) и обращённое к неизвестному по другим источникам британскому завоевателю «Послание к воинам короля Коротика». Как автор «Исповеди», написанной на латинском языке, святой Патрик считается родоначальником ирландской литературы.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">São Patrício foi primeiramente um missionário cristão, sendo depois sagrado bispo e santo padroeiro da Irlanda, juntamente com Santa Brígida de Kildare e São Columba. É considerado o Apóstolo da Irlanda. Nascido na costa oeste da Grã-Bretanha, a pequena localidade galesa de Banwen é frequentemente referida como seu lugar de nascimento, embora haja muitas hipóteses sobre este facto. Quando tinha dezesseis anos foi capturado e vendido como escravo para a Irlanda, de onde escapou e retornou à casa de sua família seis anos mais tarde. Iniciou então sua vida religiosa e retornou para a ilha de onde tinha fugido para pregar o Evangelho. Converteu centenas de pessoas, muitas delas se tornaram monges. Para explicar como a Santíssima Trindade era três e um ao mesmo tempo utilizava o trevo de três folhas e por isso o mesmo tem papel importante na cultura Irlandesa. Foi incentivador do sacramento da confissão particular, tal como conhecemos hoje, visto que antes o mesmo era realizado de forma comunitária. Um século mais tarde essa prática se propagou para o restante da Europa. A crença popular atribui a São Patrício o desaparecimento das cobras da ilha onde fica a Irlanda sendo a razão de em algumas gravuras do santo ele aparecer esmagando esses animais com seu cajado. Mas algumas evidências científicas sugerem que a Irlanda Pós-Era Glacial não era habitada por serpentes . Muito reverenciado nos Estados Unidos devido ao grande número de imigrantes irlandeses. Em Manhattan, Nova Iorque, há uma catedral com o seu nome, sede da arquidiocese da metrópole. No dia 17 de março há diversas comemorações na Irlanda e nos Estados Unidos, conhecidas como paradas de São Patrício, onde ocorrem festejos e desfiles em memória do santo, sendo essa a principal forma de afirmação do orgulho dos imigrantes e descendentes de irlandeses na América. No livro As Brumas de Avalon (1979), de Marion Zimmer Bradley, Patrício é retratado como um bispo fanático, preconceituoso contra outras religiões e politicamente ambicioso, procurando, sempre que possível, passar por cima da autoridade do próprio rei. Referências</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Wonderworkers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Święty Patryk, irl. Pádraig Mac Calprainn, Naomh Pádraig, Pádraig Naofaur, cs. Swiatitiel Patrik, jepiskop Irłandskij – biskup i apostoł Irlandii, święty Kościoła katolickiego i prawosławnego, misjonarz i organizator życia religijnego w Irlandii.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:5th-century_writers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.oxforddnb.com/view/article/21562"/>
    <dbpprop:veneratedIn rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catholic_Church"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/4th-centuryIrishPeople"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Święty Patryk, irl. Pádraig Mac Calprainn, Naomh Pádraig, Pádraig Naofaur, cs. Swiatitiel Patrik, jepiskop Irłandskij – biskup i apostoł Irlandii, święty Kościoła katolickiego i prawosławnego, misjonarz i organizator życia religijnego w Irlandii.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Roman_Britain"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">パトリキウス（Patricius, 387年? - 461年3月17日）は、アイルランドにキリスト教を広めた司教（主教）。カトリック教会・聖公会・ルーテル教会・正教会で聖人。「アイルランドの使徒」と呼ばれた。アイルランドの守護聖人。しばしば英語名で聖パトリック (Saint Patrick) とも呼ばれる。パトリキイとも。アイルランド語ではPádraigと綴り、ポーリクなどと発音する。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Svatý Patrik (irsky Naomh Pádraig, angl. Saint Patrick) byl starověký křesťanský duchovní, mnich a misionář pocházející z římské Británie a působící v druhé polovině 5. století v Irsku. Naše povědomí o něm je velmi mlhavé, drtivou většinu informací poskytují jednak dva nedatované listy, jichž je sv. Patrik autorem, jednak starověké legendy a jejich soupisy, jejichž nejstarší záznamy pocházejí ze 7. století. Řada moderních historiků je navíc přesvědčena, že část činů, které legendy sv.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">För mansnamnet Patrick, se Patrik. Sankt Patrick Sankt Patrick Glasmålning föreställande Sankt Patrick, i Cathedral of Christ the Light, Oakland, Kalifornien.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Cleric"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:5th-century_bishops"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">パトリキウス（Patricius, 387年? - 461年3月17日）は、アイルランドにキリスト教を広めた司教（主教）。カトリック教会・聖公会・ルーテル教会・正教会で聖人。「アイルランドの使徒」と呼ばれた。アイルランドの守護聖人。しばしば英語名で聖パトリック (Saint Patrick) とも呼ばれる。パトリキイとも。アイルランド語ではPádraigと綴り、ポーリクなどと発音する。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/IrishSlaves"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Saint"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Saint Patrick (vers 385–461) est un saint chrétien fêté le 17 mars. Il est considéré comme l'évangélisateur de l'Irlande et comme le fondateur du christianisme irlandais.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Святий Па́трик, теж Патрикій Ірландський — святий патрон і просвітитель Ірландії, святитель, видатний місіонер та чудотворець який навернув ірландців до християнської віри.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gMonthDay">--03-17</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <dbpprop:majorShrine rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Glastonbury_Abbey"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Saint Patrick was a Romano-British and Christian missionary, who is the most generally recognized patron saint of Ireland or the Apostle of Ireland, although Brigid of Kildare and Colmcille are also formally patron saints. Two authentic letters from him survive, from which come the only generally-accepted details of his life.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:feastDay rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">17</dbpprop:feastDay>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Святий Па́трик, теж Патрикій Ірландський — святий патрон і просвітитель Ірландії, святитель, видатний місіонер та чудотворець який навернув ірландців до християнської віри.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">San Patricio fue un misionero cristiano y es conocido como el santo patrón de Irlanda, junto a Santa Brígida y San Columba, fue un predicador y religioso de Britania, tradicionalmente considerado el introductor de la religión cristiana en la isla.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Thánh Patrick</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Holiday_characters"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Cleric"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Patrici d'Irlanda</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Svatý Patrik</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleCelebratedInTheLutheranLiturgicalCalendar"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">São Patrício foi primeiramente um missionário cristão, sendo depois sagrado bispo e santo padroeiro da Irlanda, juntamente com Santa Brígida de Kildare e São Columba. É considerado o Apóstolo da Irlanda. Nascido na costa oeste da Grã-Bretanha, a pequena localidade galesa de Banwen é frequentemente referida como seu lugar de nascimento, embora haja muitas hipóteses sobre este facto.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Patrick_von_Irland"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
