<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath">
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_writers_of_German_descent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:child rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nicholas_Hughes"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Writer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Sylvia Plath va ser una escriptora estatunidenca coneguda sobretot per la seva obra poètica, concretament, per ser una de les principals autores del gènere de la poesia confessional. Gairebé tota l'obra poètica de Plath ha estat traduïda al català per Montserrat Abelló i Soler. Plath estigué casada amb el poeta anglès Ted Hughes.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dbpprop:pseudonym xml:lang="en">Victoria Lucas</dbpprop:pseudonym>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_short_story_writers"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Smith_College_alumni"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And I
Am the arrow,

The dew that flies
Suicidal, at one with the drive
Into the red

Eye, the cauldron of morning.</dbpprop:quote>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Sylvia Plath</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:notableworks xml:lang="en">The Bell Jar and Ariel</dbpprop:notableworks>
    <dbpprop:bgcolor xml:lang="en">#FFFFF0</dbpprop:bgcolor>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fulbright_Scholars"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1960-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsStartYear>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rv9jMX5wpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Theodore_Roethke"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Boston"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.Sylvia-Plath.org"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">希薇亞·普拉斯（英语：Sylvia Plath，1932年10月27日－1963年2月11日），美國詩人、小說家、兒童作家與短篇故事作家。 除了較為著名的詩作外，普拉斯也以筆名維多利亞·盧卡斯創作了傳記小說《瓶中美人》（又譯《鐘形罩》、《鐘瓶》）。書中主角，聰慧、有抱負的史密斯學院學生艾瑟·葛林伍德，便是普拉斯的化身，後於紐約時尚雜誌實習期間，展開了一段精神崩潰的歷程，正如同普拉斯在《Mademoiselle》雜誌工作時，經歷心理掙扎、自殺未遂的過程。 同安·塞克斯頓，普拉斯被公認是自白詩重要的推動者之一。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Сильвія Плат — американська поетеса і письменниця, яка вважається однією з засновниць жанру «сповідальної поезії» в англомовній літературі. За життя Плат вийшла лише поетична збірка «Колос» (англ. The Colossus &amp; Other Poems, Лондон, 1960) і напівавтобіографічний роман «Під скляним ковпаком» (1963). Злет творчої кар'єри поетеси був перерваний трагедією: на початку 1963 року, страждаючи від важкої депресії, Сильвія Плат покінчила з собою.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Sylvia Plath (ur. 27 października 1932 w Jamaica Plain k. Bostonu, zm. 11 lutego 1963 w Londynie) – amerykańska poetka, pisarka i eseistka, zaliczana do grona tzw. poetów wyklętych. Współcześnie znana m. in. dzięki na poły autobiograficznej powieści Szklany klosz. Jej poezja należy do nurtu poezji konfesyjnej. Sylvia Plath jest przy tym jedną z czołowych postaci kierunku w literaturze lat pięćdziesiątych i sześćdziesiątych XX wieku, określanego mianem Konfesjonalistów (ang. Confessionalist).</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/20th-centuryWomenWriters"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Newnham_College,_Cambridge"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://zitgist.com/music/artist/9b73926a-d249-4dfd-841b-db3a56be5d9f"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PoetsWhoCommittedSuicide"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Sylvia Plath fue una escritora estadounidense especialmente conocida como poetisa, aunque también es autora de obras en prosa, como una novela semi-autobiográfica, La campana de cristal (bajo el pseudónimo de Victoria Lucas), y relatos y ensayos. Junto con Anne Sexton, Plath es reconocida como uno de los principales cultivadoras del género de la poesía confesional iniciado por Robert Lowell y W. D. Snodgrass. Estuvo casada con el escritor Ted Hughes, quien tras su muerte se encargó de la edición de su poesía completa.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?id=aMUkBQ-3mnUC&amp;pg=PA11&amp;lpg=PA11&amp;dq=dangerous+confessions+reading+sylvia+plath&amp;source=bl&amp;ots=rhy83_ED2d&amp;sig=4XuJXepIrr-nnL_gNEZwcayZvoI&amp;hl=en&amp;ei=pacJTO-rIMP7lwfRzrCzDg&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=book_result&amp;ct=result&amp;resnum=1&amp;ved=0CBIQ6AEwAA#v=onepage&amp;q=dangerous%20confessions%20reading%20sylvia%20plath&amp;f=false"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Conosciuta principalmente per le sue poesie, ha anche scritto il romanzo semi-autobiografico La campana di vetro (The Bell Jar) sotto lo pseudonimo di Victoria Lucas. La protagonista del libro, Esther Greenwood, è una brillante studentessa dello Smith College, che inizia a soffrire di psicosi durante un tirocinio presso un giornale di moda newyorkese. La trama ha un parallelo nella vita della Plath, che ha trascorso un periodo presso la rivista femminile Mademoiselle, successivamente al quale, in preda a un forte stato di depressione, ha tentato il suicidio. Assieme ad Anne Sexton, la Plath è stata l'autrice che più ha contribuito allo sviluppo del genere della poesia confessionale, iniziato da Robert Lowell e W. D. Snodgrass. Autrice anche di vari racconti e di un unico dramma teatrale a tre voci, per lunghi periodi della sua vita ha tenuto un diario, di cui sono state pubblicate le numerose parti sopravvissute. Parti del diario sono invece state distrutte dall'ex-marito, il poeta laureato inglese Ted Hughes, da cui ebbe due figli, Frieda Rebecca e Nicholas. Morì suicida all'età di trent'anni.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanWomenWriters"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FulbrightScholars"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Sylvia Plath byla americká spisovatelka, autorka románů a krátkých povídek, básnířka a esejistka. Nejznámější je jako básnířka, ale známá je také pro své poloautobiografické dílo The Bell Jar (v češtině Pod skleněným zvonem), popisující její zápas s klinickou depresí, zmatkem v sobě a celoživotní neschopností vyrovnat se se smrtí otce, která ji velmi zasáhla. Jí a Anne Sextonové je připisován vzestup zpovědní poezie, se kterou přišli Robert Lowell a W. D. Snodgrass. V roce 1956 se provdala za britského básníka Teda Hughese a měli spolu dvě děti. Rozešli se v roce 1962.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">실비아 플라스는 미국의 시인이자 단편소설작가이다. 어렸을 때부터 문학에 재능을 보였으며, 시와 함께 자전적 성격의 소설인 《벨 자(The Bell Jar)》로 명성을 얻었다. 영국의 계관시인 테드 휴스과 결혼했고, 사후 컬트적인 명성을 얻었다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1963_deaths"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Writer110794014"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/シルヴィア・プラス"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Writer"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dbpprop:restingPlace xml:lang="en">Heptonstall Church, West Yorkshire, England, UK</dbpprop:restingPlace>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_novelists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Confessional_poetry"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Louise_Gl%C3%BCck"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_expatriates_in_the_United_Kingdom"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Novelist110363573"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Artist"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Plath, Sylvia</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Robert_Lowell"/>
    <dbpprop:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Newnham_College,_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpprop:signature xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath signature.svg</dbpprop:signature>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Sylvia Plath var en amerikansk forfatter. Hun er mest kjent for sine dikt, og romanen The Bell Jar.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Artists_who_committed_suicide"/>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dbpprop:alt xml:lang="en">A black-and-white photo of a Caucasian woman with shoulder-length hair. She is seated facing the camera, wearing a sweater, with bookshelves behind her.</dbpprop:alt>
    <dbpedia-owl:language rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/English_language"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Плат,_Сильвия"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Sylvia Plath</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">シルヴィア・プラス（Sylvia Plath, 1932年10月27日 - 1963年2月11日）は、アメリカ合衆国マサチューセッツ州ボストン出身の女性詩人・作家。 ドイツ系の大学教授の父親とオーストリア系2世の母を持つ裕福な家庭に育つ。幼いときから文才を発揮、8歳で初めての詩を発表した。その後も詩や短編を新聞などに発表していた。 その一方、双極性障害に悩まされており、スミス・カレッジ在学中に自殺未遂を起こしている。学業を一時中断して病院に入ったが、後に回復して大学を卒業した。 その後、フルブライト奨学金を得てケンブリッジ大学に留学。留学中に出会った詩人テッド・ヒューズと1956年に結婚し、二人の子供に恵まれた。1960年に初めての詩集を発表。しかし流産、夫との不和、創作の行き詰まり、経済的な問題などを苦に1963年に自殺した。 亡くなった後にいくつかの作品集が発表され、死後29年たってからピューリッツァー賞を受賞した。 彼女の一生は2003年に『シルヴィア』という題名で映画化された。グウィネス・パルトローがシルヴィアを、ダニエル・クレイグがテッド・ヒューズを演じた。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanPeopleOfAustrianDescent"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:20th-century_poets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:movement rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Confessional_poetry"/>
    <dbpprop:language rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/English_language"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Sylvia Plath là một nhà thơ, nhà văn Mỹ. Người đời thường so sánh thơ của bà với loại "thơ xưng tội" (confessional poetry) của Robert Lowell và W.D. Snodgrass.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Writers_from_Boston,_Massachusetts"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_diarists"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Sylvia</foaf:givenName>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_people_of_Austrian_descent"/>
    <dbpprop:shortDescription xml:lang="en">American poet, novelist</dbpprop:shortDescription>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Sylvia Plath oli yhdysvaltalainen kirjailija ja runoilija. Parhaiten hänet tunnetaan amerikkalaista runoutta uudistaneista runoistaan.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:spouse rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ted_Hughes"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Poets_who_committed_suicide"/>
    <dbpprop:awards rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Woodrow_Wilson_National_Fellowship_Foundation"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">350</dbpprop:width>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/e/e4/Sylvia_plath.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Massachusetts"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Sylvia Plath amerikai költő, író, novellista, gyerekkönyvíró.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Sylvia Plath, née le 27 octobre 1932 à Jamaica Plain, dans la banlieue de Boston, et morte le 11 février 1963 à Londres, est une écrivaine américaine ayant produit essentiellement des poèmes, mais aussi un roman, des nouvelles, des livres pour enfants et des essais.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:placeOfDeath xml:lang="en">London, England</dbpprop:placeOfDeath>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_Newnham_College,_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpprop:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_Kingdom"/>
    <dbpprop:education xml:lang="en">B.A. with highest honors</dbpprop:education>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ArtistsWhoCommittedSuicide"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Sylvia Plath war eine US-amerikanische Schriftstellerin. Als Plaths Hauptwerk gilt ihre Lyrik, insbesondere der nachgelassene Lyrikband Ariel, sowie ihr einziger Roman Die Glasglocke. Daneben schrieb Plath Kurzgeschichten und Kinderbücher. Sylvia Plaths Literatur wird zumeist im Kontext ihrer Lebensgeschichte gewertet. Ihre Gedichte gelten als Confessional Poetry (Bekenntnislyrik), und auch in ihrer Prosa verarbeitete sie autobiografische Erlebnisse wie einen Suizidversuch oder die Beziehung zu ihrem Ehemann Ted Hughes. Erste Arbeiten veröffentlichte Plath bereits zu Lebzeiten, der literarische Erfolg setzte aber erst postum nach ihrem Suizid mit der Veröffentlichung nachgelassener Gedichte sowie der US-Publikation ihres Romans in den späten 60er und frühen 70er Jahren ein. Neben ihrem Werk wurde auch Plaths Leben und ihr früher Tod zum Gegenstand des öffentlichen Interesses. Plath wurde zu einer Symbolfigur der Frauenbewegung stilisiert und ihre Lebensgeschichte als Spiegelbild der Rolle der Frau in der Gesellschaft verstanden.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Autobiography"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfDeath rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1963-02-11</dbpprop:dateOfDeath>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_diarists"/>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Plath</foaf:surname>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_Unitarians"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e4/Sylvia_plath.jpg/200px-Sylvia_plath.jpg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/poetryseason/poets/sylvia_plath.shtml"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1932-10-27</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Sylvia Plath</rdfs:label>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.073bb"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Robert_Lowell"/>
    <dbpprop:salign xml:lang="en">right</dbpprop:salign>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanWritersOfGermanDescent"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_child_writers"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1932-10-27</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Sylvia Plath fue una escritora estadounidense especialmente conocida como poetisa, aunque también es autora de obras en prosa, como una novela semi-autobiográfica, La campana de cristal (bajo el pseudónimo de Victoria Lucas), y relatos y ensayos. Junto con Anne Sexton, Plath es reconocida como uno de los principales cultivadoras del género de la poesía confesional iniciado por Robert Lowell y W. D. Snodgrass.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Sylvia Plath, född 27 oktober 1932 i Boston, Massachusetts, död 11 februari 1963 i London, Storbritannien, var en amerikansk poet och författare. Hon studerade vid Smith College när hon erhöll stipendium till studier vid Cambridge-universitetet i England. Där träffade hon den engelske poeten Ted Hughes. De gifte sig 1957, men tog ut skilsmässa 1962. Hon skrev suggestiv, kraftfull och i högsta grad personlig lyrik, som ofta uttryckte ett slags övergivenhet. De sista dikterna, som publicerades postumt av Hughes, är också de mest kända. Med titlar som "Daddy" och "Medusa" gör de aggressivt upp med författarinnans förflutna. I "Lady Lazarus" är hon kvinnan som lär sig att dö och återuppstå, hela tiden vackrare. När samlingen "Ariel" släpptes, blev Plath snabbt en ikon för 70-talets framväxande kvinnorörelse.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:spouse rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ted_Hughes"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dbpprop:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Confessional_poetry"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanExpatriatesInTheUnitedKingdom"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanEssayists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Сильвія Плат</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1932-10-27</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_short_story_writers"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from "The Colossus",</dbpprop:source>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Glascock_Prize_winners"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Artist"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-writer-noun-1"/>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Love set you going like a fat gold watch.
The midwife slapped your footsoles, and your bald cry
Took its place among the elements.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Sylvia Plath, née le 27 octobre 1932 à Jamaica Plain, dans la banlieue de Boston, et morte le 11 février 1963 à Londres, est une écrivaine américaine ayant produit essentiellement des poèmes, mais aussi un roman, des nouvelles, des livres pour enfants et des essais. Si elle est surtout connue en tant que poète, elle tire également sa notoriété de The Bell Jar, roman d'inspiration autobiographique qui décrit en détail les circonstances de sa première dépression, au début de sa vie d'adulte. Depuis son suicide en 1963, Sylvia Plath est devenue une figure emblématique dans les pays anglo-saxons, les féministes voyant dans son œuvre l'archétype du génie féminin écrasé par une société dominée par les hommes, les autres voyant en elle une icône dont la poésie, en grande partie publiée après sa mort, fascine comme la bouleversante chronique d'un suicide annoncé.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Sylvia Plath amerikai költő, író, novellista, gyerekkönyvíró.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:nationality xml:lang="en">American</dbpprop:nationality>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">希薇亞·普拉斯（英语：Sylvia Plath，1932年10月27日－1963年2月11日），美國詩人、小說家、兒童作家與短篇故事作家。 除了較為著名的詩作外，普拉斯也以筆名維多利亞·盧卡斯創作了傳記小說《瓶中美人》（又譯《鐘形罩》、《鐘瓶》）。書中主角，聰慧、有抱負的史密斯學院學生艾瑟·葛林伍德，便是普拉斯的化身，後於紐約時尚雜誌實習期間，展開了一段精神崩潰的歷程，正如同普拉斯在《Mademoiselle》雜誌工作時，經歷心理掙扎、自殺未遂的過程。 同安·塞克斯頓，普拉斯被公認是自白詩重要的推動者之一。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanPoets"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Sylvia Plath va ser una escriptora estatunidenca coneguda sobretot per la seva obra poètica, concretament, per ser una de les principals autores del gènere de la poesia confessional. Gairebé tota l'obra poètica de Plath ha estat traduïda al català per Montserrat Abelló i Soler. Plath estigué casada amb el poeta anglès Ted Hughes.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">The Colossus and Other Poems, 1960</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Сильвія Плат — американська поетеса і письменниця, яка вважається однією з засновниць жанру «сповідальної поезії» в англомовній літературі. За життя Плат вийшла лише поетична збірка «Колос» (англ. The Colossus &amp; Other Poems, Лондон, 1960) і напівавтобіографічний роман «Під скляним ковпаком» (1963). Злет творчої кар'єри поетеси був перерваний трагедією: на початку 1963 року, страждаючи від важкої депресії, Сильвія Плат покінчила з собою. Визнання поетичного таланту Плат більшою мірою відбулось після її смерті. У 1965 році була видана збірка «Аріель», яка отримала захоплені відгуки критиків і стала одним з головних бестселерів англо-американської поезії XX століття. У 1982 році за книгу «Збірка віршів» (Collected Poems) Плат отримала посмертно Пулітцерівську премію. Сильвія Плат була дружиною британського поета-лауреата Теда Х'юза. Цей шлюб був не лише союзом двох люблячих людей, а й творчим тандемом, де провідну роль відігравав Х'юз, а Плат забезпечувала йому можливість творити. Після смерті дружини Х'юз заснував фонд Estate of Sylvia Plath, який розпоряджався правами на літературну спадщину поетеси. Довгий час у пресі тривала дискусія з приводу самогубства Плат і «винності» Х'юза у її смерті. Деякі шанувальники її поетичного дару, а також літературні критики прямо звинувачували Х'юза і називали його «вбивцею Сильвії Плат». Як справжній представник сповідальної поезії, Сильвія Плат писала про власні переживання, відчуття, страхи. Серед тем її лірики були сім'я, жіноча доля, природа, і смерть.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Suicides_by_carbon_monoxide_poisoning"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Suicides_in_London"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:activeYearsEndYear rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gYear">1963-01-01T00:00:00+02:00</dbpedia-owl:activeYearsEndYear>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfNewnhamCollege,Cambridge"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Heptonstall"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/culture/culturepicturegalleries/8846565/Sylvia-Plath-drawings-at-The-Mayor-Gallery.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath (October 27, 1932 – February 11, 1963) was an American poet, novelist and short story writer. Born in Boston, Massachusetts, she studied at Smith College and Newnham College, Cambridge before receiving acclaim as a professional poet and writer. She married fellow poet Ted Hughes in 1956 and they lived together first in the United States and then England, having two children together: Frieda and Nicholas.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Conosciuta principalmente per le sue poesie, ha anche scritto il romanzo semi-autobiografico La campana di vetro (The Bell Jar) sotto lo pseudonimo di Victoria Lucas. La protagonista del libro, Esther Greenwood, è una brillante studentessa dello Smith College, che inizia a soffrire di psicosi durante un tirocinio presso un giornale di moda newyorkese.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:signatureAlt xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath</dbpprop:signatureAlt>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Σύλβια_Πλαθ"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Sylvia Plath war eine US-amerikanische Schriftstellerin. Als Plaths Hauptwerk gilt ihre Lyrik, insbesondere der nachgelassene Lyrikband Ariel, sowie ihr einziger Roman Die Glasglocke. Daneben schrieb Plath Kurzgeschichten und Kinderbücher. Sylvia Plaths Literatur wird zumeist im Kontext ihrer Lebensgeschichte gewertet.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Massachusetts"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118594877</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:20th-century_novelists"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WritersWhoCommittedSuicide"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanDiarists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Sylvia Plath (27 oktober 1932 – 11 februari 1963) was een Amerikaanse dichteres, romanschrijfster en essayiste. Hoewel ze vooral bekend is om haar poëzie, oogstte ze ook faam met haar semi-autobiografische roman The Bell Jar, waarin haar worsteling met depressies gedetailleerd wordt beschreven. Na haar zelfmoord is ze voor velen een icoon geworden.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth xml:lang="en">Boston, Massachusetts, United States</dbpprop:placeOfBirth>
    <dbpedia-owl:pseudonym xml:lang="en">Victoria Lucas</dbpedia-owl:pseudonym>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleWithBipolarDisorder"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_women_writers"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Quote_box"/>
    <dbpprop:period rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1960</dbpprop:period>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Sylvia Plath foi uma poetisa, romancista e contista norte-americana. Reconhecida principalmente por sua obra poética, Sylvia Plath escreveu também um romance semi-autobiográfico, "A Redoma de Vidro" ("The Bell Jar"), sob o pseudônimo Victoria Lucas, com detalhamentos do histórico de sua luta contra a depressão. Assim como Anne Sexton, Sylvia Plath é creditada por dar continuidade ao gênero de poesia confessional, iniciado por Robert Lowell e W.D. Snodgrass.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">실비아 플라스는 미국의 시인이자 단편소설작가이다. 어렸을 때부터 문학에 재능을 보였으며, 시와 함께 자전적 성격의 소설인 《벨 자(The Bell Jar)》로 명성을 얻었다. 영국의 계관시인 테드 휴스과 결혼했고, 사후 컬트적인 명성을 얻었다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.iun.edu/~plath"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Sylvia Plath (ur. 27 października 1932 w Jamaica Plain k. Bostonu, zm. 11 lutego 1963 w Londynie) – amerykańska poetka, pisarka i eseistka, zaliczana do grona tzw. poetów wyklętych. Współcześnie znana m. in. dzięki na poły autobiograficznej powieści Szklany klosz. Jej poezja należy do nurtu poezji konfesyjnej. Sylvia Plath jest przy tym jedną z czołowych postaci kierunku w literaturze lat pięćdziesiątych i sześćdziesiątych XX wieku, określanego mianem Konfesjonalistów (ang. Confessionalist).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:20th-century_women_writers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/West_Yorkshire"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Sylvia Plath, född 27 oktober 1932 i Boston, Massachusetts, död 11 februari 1963 i London, Storbritannien, var en amerikansk poet och författare. Hon studerade vid Smith College när hon erhöll stipendium till studier vid Cambridge-universitetet i England. Där träffade hon den engelske poeten Ted Hughes. De gifte sig 1957, men tog ut skilsmässa 1962. Hon skrev suggestiv, kraftfull och i högsta grad personlig lyrik, som ofta uttryckte ett slags övergivenhet.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_essayists"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1932_births"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/W._H._Auden"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableWork rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ariel_(book)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1963-02-11</dbpedia-owl:deathDate>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Sylvia Plath (October 27, 1932 – February 11, 1963) was an American poet, novelist and short story writer. Born in Boston, Massachusetts, she studied at Smith College and Newnham College, Cambridge before receiving acclaim as a professional poet and writer. She married fellow poet Ted Hughes in 1956 and they lived together first in the United States and then England, having two children together: Frieda and Nicholas. Following a long struggle with depression and a marital separation, Plath committed suicide in 1963. Controversy continues to surround the events of her life and death, as well as her writing and legacy. Plath is credited with advancing the genre of confessional poetry and is best known for her two published collections: The Colossus and Other Poems and Ariel. In 1982, she became the first poet to win a Pulitzer Prize posthumously, for The Collected Poems. She also wrote The Bell Jar, a semi-autobiographical novel published shortly before her death.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Female_suicides"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_writer"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/W._H._Auden"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Theodore_Roethke"/>
    <dbpprop:source xml:lang="en">from Morning Song, Ariel, 1965</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpedia-owl:deathPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/London"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Sylvia Plath oli yhdysvaltalainen kirjailija ja runoilija. Parhaiten hänet tunnetaan amerikkalaista runoutta uudistaneista runoistaan.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Sylvia Plath byla americká spisovatelka, autorka románů a krátkých povídek, básnířka a esejistka. Nejznámější je jako básnířka, ale známá je také pro své poloautobiografické dílo The Bell Jar (v češtině Pod skleněným zvonem), popisující její zápas s klinickou depresí, zmatkem v sobě a celoživotní neschopností vyrovnat se se smrtí otce, která ji velmi zasáhla. Jí a Anne Sextonové je připisován vzestup zpovědní poezie, se kterou přišli Robert Lowell a W. D. Snodgrass.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_poets"/>
    <dbpprop:children rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Frieda_Hughes"/>
    <dbpprop:deathDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1963-02-11</dbpprop:deathDate>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">250</dbpprop:width>
    <dbpprop:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Smith_College"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Sylvia Plath var en amerikansk forfatter. Hun er mest kjent for sine dikt, og romanen The Bell Jar.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:quoted xml:lang="en">true</dbpprop:quoted>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Writers_who_committed_suicide"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">希薇亞·普拉斯</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">Nights, I squat in the cornucopia
Of your left ear, out of the wind,

Counting the red stars and those of plum-color.
The sun rises under the pillar of your tongue.
My hours are married to shadow.
No longer do I listen for the scrape of a keel
On the blank stones of the landing.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Poet, novelist, and short story writer</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:American_novelists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:notableWork rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Bell_Jar"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WritersFromBoston,Massachusetts"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/실비아_플래스"/>
    <dbpprop:align xml:lang="en">right</dbpprop:align>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sylvia_Plath?oldid=495376498"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Сильвия Плат — американская поэтесса и писательница, считающаяся одной из основательниц жанра «исповедальной поэзии» в англоязычной литературе. При жизни Плат вышли лишь поэтический сборник «Колосс» (англ.  The Colossus &amp; Other Poems, Лондон, 1960) и полуавтобиографический роман «Под стеклянным колпаком» (1963). В 1965 году был опубликовал сборник «Ариэль», который удостоился восторженных отзывов критики, став одним из главных бестселлеров англо-американской поэзии XX века.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://jco.usfca.edu/onplath.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:award rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fulbright_Program"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.poets.org/poet.php/prmPID/11"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Сильвия Плат — американская поэтесса и писательница, считающаяся одной из основательниц жанра «исповедальной поэзии» в англоязычной литературе. При жизни Плат вышли лишь поэтический сборник «Колосс» (англ. &amp;#160;The Colossus &amp;amp; Other Poems, Лондон, 1960) и полуавтобиографический роман «Под стеклянным колпаком» (1963). В 1965 году был опубликовал сборник «Ариэль», который удостоился восторженных отзывов критики, став одним из главных бестселлеров англо-американской поэзии XX века. В 1982 году за книгу Collected Poems («Собрание стихотворений») Плат получила посмертно Пулитцеровскую премию. Сильвия Плат была женой британского поэта-лауреата Теда Хьюза. Этот брак был не только союзом двух любящих людей, но и творческим тандемом, где ведущую роль играл Хьюз, а Плат обеспечивала ему возможность творить. Отношения Плат и Хьюза закончились трагедией: в начале 1963 года, страдая от тяжелой депрессии, последовавшей за разрывом с мужем, Сильвия Плат покончила с собой. У неё осталось двое детей. После смерти жены Хьюз основал Estate of Sylvia Plath, который распоряжался правами на литературное наследие поэтессы. Признание поэтического таланта Плат в большей степени произошло после её смерти. Одновременно с этим в прессе развернулась «истерия» по поводу её самоубийства и «виновности» Хьюза в её смерти. Некоторые поклонники её поэтического дара, а также литературные критики прямо обвиняли Хьюза и называли его «убийцей Сильвии Плат». Как истинный представитель исповедальной поэзии, Сильвия Плат писала о собственных переживаниях, ощущениях, страхах. Среди тем её лирики были семья, женская судьба, природа, и смерть.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:quote xml:lang="en">And here you come, with a cup of tea
Wreathed in steam.
The blood jet is poetry,
There is no stopping it.
You hand me two children, two roses.</dbpprop:quote>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">300</dbpprop:width>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Sylvia Plath (27 oktober 1932 – 11 februari 1963) was een Amerikaanse dichteres, romanschrijfster en essayiste. Hoewel ze vooral bekend is om haar poëzie, oogstte ze ook faam met haar semi-autobiografische roman The Bell Jar, waarin haar worsteling met depressies gedetailleerd wordt beschreven. Na haar zelfmoord is ze voor velen een icoon geworden.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AmericanNovelists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Sylvia Plath là một nhà thơ, nhà văn Mỹ. Người đời thường so sánh thơ của bà với loại "thơ xưng tội" (confessional poetry) của Robert Lowell và W.D. Snodgrass.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:source rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gMonthDay">--10-12</dbpprop:source>
    <dbpedia-owl:genre rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Autobiography"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/WomenDiarists"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://library.uvic.ca/site/spcoll/guides/sc060.html"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Sylvia Plath foi uma poetisa, romancista e contista norte-americana. Reconhecida principalmente por sua obra poética, Sylvia Plath escreveu também um romance semi-autobiográfico, "A Redoma de Vidro" ("The Bell Jar"), sob o pseudônimo Victoria Lucas, com detalhamentos do histórico de sua luta contra a depressão. Assim como Anne Sexton, Sylvia Plath é creditada por dar continuidade ao gênero de poesia confessional, iniciado por Robert Lowell e W.D. Snodgrass.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Pulitzer_Prize_for_Poetry_winners"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:child rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Frieda_Hughes"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Women_poets"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/SmithCollegeAlumni"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Plath in 1957</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">シルヴィア・プラス（Sylvia Plath, 1932年10月27日 - 1963年2月11日）は、アメリカ合衆国マサチューセッツ州ボストン出身の女性詩人・作家。 ドイツ系の大学教授の父親とオーストリア系2世の母を持つ裕福な家庭に育つ。幼いときから文才を発揮、8歳で初めての詩を発表した。その後も詩や短編を新聞などに発表していた。 その一方、双極性障害に悩まされており、スミス・カレッジ在学中に自殺未遂を起こしている。学業を一時中断して病院に入ったが、後に回復して大学を卒業した。 その後、フルブライト奨学金を得てケンブリッジ大学に留学。留学中に出会った詩人テッド・ヒューズと1956年に結婚し、二人の子供に恵まれた。1960年に初めての詩集を発表。しかし流産、夫との不和、創作の行き詰まり、経済的な問題などを苦に1963年に自殺した。 亡くなった後にいくつかの作品集が発表され、死後29年たってからピューリッツァー賞を受賞した。 彼女の一生は2003年に『シルヴィア』という題名で映画化された。グウィネス・パルトローがシルヴィアを、ダニエル・クレイグがテッド・ヒューズを演じた。</rdfs:comment>
    <dc:description xml:lang="en">American poet, novelist</dc:description>
    <dbpprop:movement rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Confessional_poetry"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:source rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#gMonthDay">--02-01</dbpprop:source>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Pseudonymous_writers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:award rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Woodrow_Wilson_National_Fellowship_Foundation"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Sylvia Plath</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:width rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:width>
    <dbpedia-owl:restingPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/England"/>
    <dbpprop:children rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nicholas_Hughes"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Sylvia_Plath"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Boston"/>
    <dbpprop:awards rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Fulbright_Program"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Smith_College"/>
    <dbpprop:influenced rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Louise_Gl%C3%BCck"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/arts/poetry/outloud/plath.shtml"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
