<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times">
    <dbpprop:postText xml:lang="en">What?</dbpprop:postText>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">The Irish Times ist eine irische überregionale Tageszeitung, gegründet am 29. März 1859 in Dublin.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">The Irish Times – irlandzki dziennik wydawany od 29 marca 1859. Gazeta powstała jako reprezentacja środowisk anglikańskich, które opowiadały się za pozostaniem Irlandii w składzie Wielkiej Brytanii, obecnie ma profil socjalno-liberalny i lewicowy ekonomicznie. Jego sprzedaż utrzymuje się dziennie na poziomie 106 926 egzemplarzy (2009).</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:foundingDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1859-03-29</dbpedia-owl:foundingDate>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpprop:political rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Social_liberalism"/>
    <dbpprop:format rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Broadsheet"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/NewspaperSeries"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The Irish Times is an Irish daily broadsheet newspaper launched on 29 March 1859. The editor is Kevin O'Sullivan who succeeded Geraldine Kennedy in 2011; the deputy editor is Paul O'Neill. The Irish Times is considered to be Ireland's newspaper of record, and is published every day except Sundays. It employs 420 people. Though formed as a Protestant Nationalist paper, within two decades and under new owners it had become the voice of Irish Unionism.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:headquarter rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">The Irish Times est le journal irlandais de référence. Il a été créé à la fin des années 1850. Son principal concurrent est l’Irish Independent qui est la plus grosse vente de la presse quotidienne d’Irlande.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:cols rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3</dbpprop:cols>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Clarify"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">The Irish Times — ирландская ежедневная широкоформатная газета, издается с 29 марта 1859 года. Кевин О'Салливан — действующий редактор, сменивший в 2011 году Джеральдин Кеннеди. The Irish Times — ирландская зарегистрированная газета, издается ежедневно, кроме воскресенья. Помощником редактора является Пол О’Нилл. Изначально, издание было основано как ирландская националистическая газета, затем, после смены владельца издания, 2 десятилетия была голосом ирландских юнионистов (сторонники более тесного политического и культурного сближения Ирландии и Великобритании). На сегодняшний день, газета больше не считается ни юнионистской ни националистической, а воспринимается просто как либеральная пресса. Её наиболее выдающиеся корреспонденты: автор и обозреватель искусства Финтан О’Тул, сатирик Мириам Лорд и основатель премьер-министр Ирландии Гаррет Фицджеральд. Такие известные личности, как Тони Блэр, Билл Клинтон и другие, писали статьи для этой газеты. Наиболее известные колонки: Drapier (анонимная ежедневная колонка политиков, дающих «внутреннюю» точку зрения о политике), «An Irishman’s Diary» — «Дневник ирландца» (до этого автором был вызывающий противоречивые отклики Кевин Майерс, пока он не ушёл к конкуренту Irish Independent, и сейчас для нее пишет Фрэнк МакНэлли, и «Rite and Reason» — ежедневная колонка о религии, её обозреватель Пэтси МакГарри. Для колонки о спорте пишут Том Хамфриз с Locker Room и статьи о гольфе — Филип Рейд. В настоящее время он обозреватель «The Irish Times» по гольфу. Одной из самых известных колонок была язвительная и юмористическая сатира «Cruiskeen Lawn», для которой писал Майлз на Гапалинь — псевдоним Брайана О’Нолана. Также он писал книги под псевдонимом Флэнн О’Брайен. Название колонки «Cruiskeen Lawn» является англизированным транскрибированием ирландского словосочетания «cruiscin lan», что означает «наполненный целиком небольшой кувшин». Колонка «Cruiskeen Lawn» впервые появилась в начале 1940-х гг. и продержалась более 25 лет. За приделами Ирландии есть множество филиалов данной газеты. Она имеет штатных корреспондентов в Вашингтоне, Париже, Берлине, Пекине, Брюсселе, Лондоне, Африке и других частях света.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/WrittenWork"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/40/The_Irish_Times_logo.svg/200px-The_Irish_Times_logo.svg.png"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CreativeWork"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Irish_Times?oldid=493857571"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Newspapers_published_in_the_Republic_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.irishtimes.com/games/crosswords/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The Irish Times is an Irish daily broadsheet newspaper launched on 29 March 1859. The editor is Kevin O'Sullivan who succeeded Geraldine Kennedy in 2011; the deputy editor is Paul O'Neill. The Irish Times is considered to be Ireland's newspaper of record, and is published every day except Sundays. It employs 420 people. Though formed as a Protestant Nationalist paper, within two decades and under new owners it had become the voice of Irish Unionism. Today it is no longer considered a Unionist paper; it is generally perceived as being politically liberal and progressive, as well as being right-wing on economic issues. The paper's most prominent columnists include writer and arts commentator Fintan O'Toole and the satirist Miriam Lord. Former Taoiseach, Garret FitzGerald was also a columnist. Senior international figures, including Tony Blair, Bill Clinton and others have written for its op-ed page. Its most prominent columns have included Drapier (an anonymous column produced weekly by a politician, giving the 'insider' view of politics); Rite and Reason, a weekly religious column, edited by Patsy McGarry, Religious Affairs Editor; and the long-running "An Irishman's Diary", previously penned by Patrick Campbell in the forties (under the pseudonym 'Quidnunc'), Seamus Kelly from 1949-1979 (also writing as 'Quidnunc'), and more recently by Kevin Myers. Since the latter's move to the rival Irish Independent, "An Irishman's Diary" is now usually the work of Frank McNally. On the sports pages, Philip Reid is the paper's golf correspondent. One of its most famous columns was the biting and humorous Cruiskeen Lawn satire column written by Myles na gCopaleen, the pen name of Brian O'Nolan (Brian Ó Nualláin) who also wrote books using the name Flann O'Brien. Cruiskeen Lawn is an anglicised spelling of the Irish words cruiscín lán, meaning 'the full little jug'. Cruiskeen Lawn made its debut in October 1940 and appeared with varying regularity until O'Nolan's death in 1966. The Irish Times has the most foreign bureaux of any Irish newspaper. It has had full-time correspondents in Washington, Paris, Berlin, Beijing, Brussels, London, Africa and other parts of the world. According to the Audit Bureau of Circulations, it had a daily circulation of 100,951 during the first six months of 2011.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:type xml:lang="en">Daily newspaper</dbpprop:type>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-newspaper-noun-2"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Newspaper"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">The Irish Times är en irländsk dagstidning som grundades i Dublin 1859. Tidningen är en av Irlands största och äldsta dagstidningar och har en upplaga på ca 117.730. Ursprungligen var Irish Times en protestantisk och nationalistisk, men har under årens lopp ändrat inriktning och är idag istället en liberal/socialdemokratisk tidning som är neutral när det gäller relationen mellan den irländska republiken och Nordirland.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpprop:foundation rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">29</dbpprop:foundation>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/PeriodicalLiterature"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PuBlicationsEstablishedIn1859"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Publications_established_in_1859"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">The Irish Times er en av Irlands største og eldste aviser. Den ble lansert mot slutten av 1850-årene. Avisen regnes som liberal, sosialdemokratisk og nøytral i spørsmålet om irsk enhet; den står ofte som motpol til Irish Independent, som regnes som populistisk med en høyrevridd økonomidekning. Opprinnelig var avisen protestantisk og nasjonalistisk, men innen ti årtier hadde den blitt unionisme, og støttet de som ønsket at Irland skulle forbli en del av Det forente kongerike Storbritannia og Irland. Etter at Den irske fristaten ble opprettet i 1922 snudde avisen, og ble mer radikal. Avisen kommer ut i fullformat.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">The Irish Times</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">The Irish Times és un diari irlandès de gran format fundat el 29 de març de 1859. L'editor actual és Geraldine Kennedy, que va succeir a Conor Brady el 2002. És publicat tots els dies excepte el diumenge. Durant la segona meitat del 2009 comptava amb una tirada de 106.926 exemplars diaris.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">The Irish Times é um jornal diário irlandês, publicado no formato standard. Foi fundado em 1859 e sua atual editora é Geraldine Kennedy, que substituiu Conor Brady em 2002. O jornal é considerado o mais influente da Irlanda.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Newspaper_companies_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpprop:date xml:lang="en">March 2012</dbpprop:date>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Newspaper"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">The Irish Times</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:editor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Kevin_O'Sullivan_(journalist)"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Div_col"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpprop:owners xml:lang="en">Irish Times Trust</dbpprop:owners>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">The Irish Times es un diario de gran formato, fundado el 29 de marzo de 1859. El editor actual es Geraldine Kennedy, quien sucedió a Conor Brady en 2002. Es publicado todos los días excepto el domingo. Durante la segunda mitad de 2009, contaba con una tirada de 106.926 ejemplares diarios. La primera aparición del periódico con el nombre de The Irish Times se produjo en 1823, pero cerró en 1825. El título fue revivido como una publicación de tres veces por semana por el comandante Lawrence E. Knox, la primera edición se publicó el 29 de marzo de 1859. Originalmente fue fundada como un moderado periódico nacionalista protestante. Aunque se formó como un periódico nacionalista irlandés protestante, en las últimas dos décadas y bajo nuevos propietarios, se ha convertido en un portavoz de los unionistas, que reclaman que Irlanda mantenga vínculos estrechos o se convierta en parte del Reino Unido.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rv9wRmpwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">The Irish Times is een landelijk dagblad dat verschijnt in Ierland. De krant werd gesticht in 1859 en stond in zijn beginjaren bekend als spreekbuis van de protestantse nationalisten. Later werd de krant de spreekbuis van de Unionisten. Na de deling van het eiland in de Ierse Vrijstaat en Noord-Ierland veranderde de krant opnieuw van koers. Tegenwoordig geldt de krant als gematigd liberaal/sociaaldemocratisch. De oplage van de Irish Times bedraagt 117.543 (eerste zes maanden 2005).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">The Irish Times on Irlannin myydyimpiä sanomalehtiä. Sitä pidetään yleisesti liberaalina ja sosiaalidemokraattisena, vastakohtana oikeistolaiselle Irish Independentille.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">The Irish Times is een landelijk dagblad dat verschijnt in Ierland. De krant werd gesticht in 1859 en stond in zijn beginjaren bekend als spreekbuis van de protestantse nationalisten. Later werd de krant de spreekbuis van de Unionisten. Na de deling van het eiland in de Ierse Vrijstaat en Noord-Ierland veranderde de krant opnieuw van koers. Tegenwoordig geldt de krant als gematigd liberaal/sociaaldemocratisch. De oplage van de Irish Times bedraagt 117.543 (eerste zes maanden 2005). Hoofdredacteur is Geraldine Kennedy.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">The Irish Times on Irlannin myydyimpiä sanomalehtiä. Sitä pidetään yleisesti liberaalina ja sosiaalidemokraattisena, vastakohtana oikeistolaiselle Irish Independentille.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.irishtimes.com/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.012vh7"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Newspaper106267145"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">The Irish Times är en irländsk dagstidning som grundades i Dublin 1859. Tidningen är en av Irlands största och äldsta dagstidningar och har en upplaga på ca 117.730. Ursprungligen var Irish Times en protestantisk och nationalistisk, men har under årens lopp ändrat inriktning och är idag istället en liberal/socialdemokratisk tidning som är neutral när det gäller relationen mellan den irländska republiken och Nordirland. Tidningen har ett stort antal korrespondenter i utlandet, bland annat i Washington, Moskva, Peking, London, Centralamerika, Sydamerika och Afrika. Chefredaktör för tidningen är siden 2011 Kevin O'Sullivan. Fil:Newspaper Cover. svg Denna artikel om en tidning eller tidskrift är bara påbörjad. Du kan hjälpa till genom att utöka den.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.irishtimes.com/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:editor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Kevin_O'Sullivan_(journalist)"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">The Irish Times</foaf:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">The Irish Times é um jornal diário irlandês, publicado no formato standard. Foi fundado em 1859 e sua atual editora é Geraldine Kennedy, que substituiu Conor Brady em 2002. O jornal é considerado o mais influente da Irlanda.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">The Irish Times</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:small xml:lang="en">no</dbpprop:small>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NewspapersPuBlishedInIreland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:format rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Broadsheet"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">The Irish Times es un diario de gran formato, fundado el 29 de marzo de 1859. El editor actual es Geraldine Kennedy, quien sucedió a Conor Brady en 2002. Es publicado todos los días excepto el domingo. Durante la segunda mitad de 2009, contaba con una tirada de 106.926 ejemplares diarios. La primera aparición del periódico con el nombre de The Irish Times se produjo en 1823, pero cerró en 1825. El título fue revivido como una publicación de tres veces por semana por el comandante Lawrence E.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">The Irish Times — ирландская ежедневная широкоформатная газета, издается с 29 марта 1859 года. Кевин О'Салливан — действующий редактор, сменивший в 2011 году Джеральдин Кеннеди. The Irish Times — ирландская зарегистрированная газета, издается ежедневно, кроме воскресенья. Помощником редактора является Пол О’Нилл.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">250</dbpprop:logo>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">The Irish Times – irlandzki dziennik wydawany od 29 marca 1859. Gazeta powstała jako reprezentacja środowisk anglikańskich, które opowiadały się za pozostaniem Irlandii w składzie Wielkiej Brytanii, obecnie ma profil socjalno-liberalny i lewicowy ekonomicznie. Jego sprzedaż utrzymuje się dziennie na poziomie 106 926 egzemplarzy (2009).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_newspaper"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/4/40/The_Irish_Times_logo.svg"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Work"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">The Irish Times est le journal irlandais de référence. Il a été créé à la fin des années 1850. Son principal concurrent est l’Irish Independent qui est la plus grosse vente de la presse quotidienne d’Irlande.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">The Irish Times er en av Irlands største og eldste aviser. Den ble lansert mot slutten av 1850-årene. Avisen regnes som liberal, sosialdemokratisk og nøytral i spørsmålet om irsk enhet; den står ofte som motpol til Irish Independent, som regnes som populistisk med en høyrevridd økonomidekning.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.irishtimes.com/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">The Irish Times és un diari irlandès de gran format fundat el 29 de març de 1859. L'editor actual és Geraldine Kennedy, que va succeir a Conor Brady el 2002. És publicat tots els dies excepte el diumenge. Durant la segona meitat del 2009 comptava amb una tirada de 106.926 exemplars diaris. Tot i que es va formar com un diari nacionalista irlandès protestant, en les últimes dues dècades i sota nous propietaris s'ha convertit en un portaveu dels unionistes, que reclamen que Irlanda mantingui vincles estrets o es converteixi en part del Regne Unit.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/The_Irish_Times"/>
    <dbpprop:headquarters rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">24</dbpprop:headquarters>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">The Irish Times</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">The Irish Times ist eine irische überregionale Tageszeitung, gegründet am 29. März 1859 in Dublin.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
