<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College,_Dublin">
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.csc.tcd.ie"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Trinity College (Kolegium Trójcy Świętej) – irlandzka uczelnia założona w roku 1592 przez królową Elżbietę I w Dublinie na terenie dawnego klasztoru Augustianów.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Collegium Sanctae et Individuae Trinitatis Reginae Elizabethae juxta Dublin</foaf:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://maps.google.com/maps?ll=53.344012,-6.256242&amp;spn=0.006547,0.014596&amp;t=k&amp;hl=en"/>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">53.3444</geo:lat>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Jonathan_Swift"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.mastersportal.eu/students/browse/university/73/university-of-dublin-trinity-college.html"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/EducationalInstitution"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Le Trinity College Dublin (TCD), fondé en 1592 par la reine Élisabeth I, est la seule constituante de l'Université de Dublin, la plus ancienne université d'Irlande. Conçue sur le modèle des universités d'Oxford et Cambridge, l'université n'accepta pendant longtemps que des étudiants masculins et protestants, mais est aujourd'hui une université pluriculturelle. Elle est la première université irlandaise, ainsi que l'une des universités les plus importantes du monde.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Il Trinity College di Dublino è un prestigioso istituto d'istruzione a livello mondiale e, senz'altro, il più blasonato e antico d'Irlanda. L'istituzione, il cui nome ufficiale per esteso è College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, nasce ufficialmente nel 1592 con la fondazione ad opera di Elisabetta I.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:provost rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Patrick_Prendergast"/>
    <dbpprop:academicStaff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1404</dbpprop:academicStaff>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Trinity College (Irish: Coláiste na Tríonóide), formally known as the College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, is the sole constituent college of the University of Dublin in Ireland.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7f/Trinity_College_Dublin_Arms.svg/200px-Trinity_College_Dublin_Arms.svg.png"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Trinity College (Dublin)</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">トリニティ・カレッジ（英語：Trinity College、アイルランド語：Coláiste na Tríonóide, Baile Átha Cliath）はアイルランド共和国の首都ダブリンにあるアイルランド最古の大学。400年以上の歴史と伝統を誇る。 正式名称はダブリンにおけるエリザベス女王の神聖にして分割されざる三位一体大学（The College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin）。名称からわかるとおり、1592年にイングランドのエリザベス1世により設立された、ダブリン大学（University of Dublin）に所属する唯一のカレッジである。欧州にてTOP10にランキングされる名門大学のひとつ。 2009年のTimes Higher Education Supplement Global Rankにおいて、世界ランク43位。 大学はダブリン市内の中心部に設けられており、キャンパスの広さは47エーカー（19万m²）程度である。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="https://www.tcd.ie/history/1641/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.dance.tcdlife.ie"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">A dublini Trinity College Írország legrégebbi egyeteme, egy korábbi kolostor épületében kezdte meg működését 1592-ben Erzsébet királynő parancsára, célja a katolikus tanokkal szembeszálló jól képzett írországi protestáns értelmiség kinevelése volt.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Archives_in_the_Republic_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpprop:free rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/St_John's_College,_Cambridge"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/トリニティ・カレッジ_(ダブリン大学)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Trinity College on Dublinissa Irlannissa sijaitseva suuri yliopisto. Yliopiston virallinen nimi on College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin ja sen iirinkielinen nimi on Coláiste na Tríonóide. Kuningatar Elisabet I perusti Trinity Collegen vuonna 1592. Trinity kuuluu eurooppalaisten yliopistojen Coimbra-ryhmään, johon kuuluvat myös suomalaiset Turun yliopisto ja Åbo Akademi. Sen kirjastolla on vapaakappaleoikeus kaikkiin Irlannissa ja Yhdistyneessä kuningaskunnassa julkaistaviin kirjoihin. Vuosittain opiskelijoille järjestettävän Trinity Ballin väitetään olevan 6 000 kävijällään Euroopan suurin yksityinen musiikkitapahtuma. Vuoden 2006 tapahtuma oli järjestyksessään 47. Trinity Ball.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.authentik.com/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College_(Dublín)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Das Trinity College, Dublin (irisch Coláiste na Tríonóide, Baile Átha Cliath) ist eine renommierte Universität in der irischen Hauptstadt Dublin. Einer der berühmtesten Studenten war Samuel Beckett, der dort ab 1923 Sprachen studierte. Trinity College ist das einzige College der University of Dublin; es darf nicht verwechselt werden mit dem University College Dublin, das zur National University of Ireland gehört, oder der Dublin City University, dem ehemaligen National Institute for Higher Education. Trinity College ist Mitglied der Coimbra-Gruppe – ein 1985 gegründetes Netzwerk teils führender europäischer Universitäten.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">都柏林三一学院（TCD),是爱尔兰位于首都都柏林高校在。三一学院，正式名称College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin伊丽莎白女王都柏林附近圣和不可分割的三一学院，成立于1592，有女王 伊丽莎白一世认可。他是是都柏林圣三一大学的一部分，这是爱尔兰最古老大学。三一学院位于学院花园College Green，旧国会大厦对面，今天那里是爱尔兰银行的一个分支。 校园这里占地19英亩（190,000平方英尺），包含围绕中央公园和两个比赛场数的建筑物。 圣三一学院和都柏林圣三一大学是一个单一的实体，通常称为University of Dublin, Trinity College都柏林大学，圣三一学院。唯一的例外是考试之一，因为它以三一学院之名，培训和聘用员工，但以都柏林圣三一大学为名给了学位。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.eblanaphotonics.com/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/University"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Trinity College</dbpprop:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1592_establishments"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College_w_Dublinie"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">A dublini Trinity College Írország legrégebbi egyeteme, egy korábbi kolostor épületében kezdte meg működését 1592-ben Erzsébet királynő parancsára, célja a katolikus tanokkal szembeszálló jól képzett írországi protestáns értelmiség kinevelése volt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College_(Dublin)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">11844</dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-6.2577</geo:long>
    <dbpprop:country rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Republic_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.acollegemiscellany.com/scarves/dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://panoramicireland.com/arch/trinity.html"/>
    <dbpprop:latinName xml:lang="en">Collegium Sanctae et Individuae Trinitatis Reginae Elizabethae juxta Dublin</dbpprop:latinName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">O Trinity College, Dublin (TCD), conhecido corporativamente como The Provost, Fellows and Scholars of the College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, é uma universidade em Dublin, fundada em 1592 pela Rainha Isabel I do Reino Unido, no local onde se situava um antigo mosteiro agostiniano. É a única faculdade constituinte da Universidade de Dublin, a mais antiga da Irlanda, com quem forma a instituição educacional de maior prestígio no país.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-university-noun-2"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">16747</dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://linkedgeodata.org/triplify/node1155686454"/>
    <dbpprop:students rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">16747</dbpprop:students>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:University_of_Dublin"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Trinity College</foaf:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.011xy1"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_university"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Dublin"/>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">4903</dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.IdentiGEN.com/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Trinity College, formelt Provost, Fellows and Scholars of the College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, irsk navn Coláiste na Tríonóide, Baile Átha Cliath er det eneste kollegiet ved University of Dublin, som er Irlands eldste universitet. Kollegiet ble opprettet i 1592 av Elisabeth I av England. Det ligger på College Green i sentrum av Dublin, rett ovenfor den gamle parlamentsbygningen som nå tilhører Bank of Ireland. Campus er på 190 000m² med en blanding av gamle og nye bygninger. En av Irlands eldste skrifter, Book of Kells, er en av kollegets hovedattraksjoner, og trekker til seg et stort antall turister. I praksis er kollegiet og universitetet samme enhet, og de kalles derfor ofte kollektivt University of Dublin, Trinity College. Det viktigste unntaket fra dette er måten universitetsgrader gis på; kollegiet står for undervisningen, mens universitetet deler ut gradene.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tcdsu.org"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/7f/Trinity_College_Dublin_Arms.svg"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_College,_Dublin"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trinity_College,_Dublin?oldid=495486625"/>
    <dbpprop:established rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1592</dbpprop:established>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.icel.ie/"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Coláiste Thríonóid Naofa Neamhroinnte na Banríona Eilís gar do Bhaile Átha Cliath</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/File:University_of_Dublin,_Trinity_College.png"/>
    <rdfs:seeAlso rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Тринити_Колледж_(Дублин)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Dublin"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">The College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin</dbpprop:name>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">都柏林三一学院（TCD),是爱尔兰位于首都都柏林高校在。三一学院，正式名称College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin伊丽莎白女王都柏林附近圣和不可分割的三一学院，成立于1592，有女王 伊丽莎白一世认可。他是是都柏林圣三一大学的一部分，这是爱尔兰最古老大学。三一学院位于学院花园College Green，旧国会大厦对面，今天那里是爱尔兰银行的一个分支。 校园这里占地19英亩（190,000平方英尺），包含围绕中央公园和两个比赛场数的建筑物。 圣三一学院和都柏林圣三一大学是一个单一的实体，通常称为University of Dublin, Trinity College都柏林大学，圣三一学院。唯一的例外是考试之一，因为它以三一学院之名，培训和聘用员工，但以都柏林圣三一大学为名给了学位。</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Trinity_College,_Dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://alllergystandards.com"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.trinitynews.ie"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Education_in_Dublin_(city)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.insightsc.ie/"/>
    <dbpprop:postgrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">4903</dbpprop:postgrad>
    <dbpprop:freeLabel rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/List_of_Oxbridge_sister_colleges"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.iona.com/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Trinity College, formelt Provost, Fellows and Scholars of the College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, irsk navn Coláiste na Tríonóide, Baile Átha Cliath er det eneste kollegiet ved University of Dublin, som er Irlands eldste universitet. Kollegiet ble opprettet i 1592 av Elisabeth I av England. Det ligger på College Green i sentrum av Dublin, rett ovenfor den gamle parlamentsbygningen som nå tilhører Bank of Ireland.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.boards.ie/vbulletin/showpost.php?p=57151330&amp;postcount=45"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College_(Dublin)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/Drama/samuel-beckett-theatre/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:country rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Republic_of_Ireland"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.eneclann.ie/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Trinity College, Dublin (TCD), är ett irländskt college beläget i huvudstaden Dublin. Trinity College, som formellt heter College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, grundades år 1592 av Drottning Elizabeth I. Det är en del av Dublins universitet, som är Irlands äldsta. Trinity College är beläget på College Green, mittemot det gamla parlamentshuset, som idag är säte för den irländska riksbanken. Campuset upptar 19 hektar (190 000 kvadratmeter) och innehåller flera byggnader som omgärdar en stor park och två spelplaner. Trinity College och Dublins universitet är en enda enhet och kallas ofta för University of Dublin, Trinity College. Det enda undantaget gäller examensrätten, eftersom det är Trinity College som står för utbildningen och som anställer personalen, men Dublins universitet ger ut examina.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">トリニティ・カレッジ（英語：Trinity College、アイルランド語：Coláiste na Tríonóide, Baile Átha Cliath）はアイルランド共和国の首都ダブリンにあるアイルランド最古の大学。400年以上の歴史と伝統を誇る。 正式名称はダブリンにおけるエリザベス女王の神聖にして分割されざる三位一体大学（The College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin）。名称からわかるとおり、1592年にイングランドのエリザベス1世により設立された、ダブリン大学（University of Dublin）に所属する唯一のカレッジである。欧州にてTOP10にランキングされる名門大学のひとつ。 2009年のTimes Higher Education Supplement Global Rankにおいて、世界ランク43位。 大学はダブリン市内の中心部に設けられており、キャンパスの広さは47エーカー（19万m²）程度である。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Trinity College, Dublin</rdfs:label>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">53.3444 -6.2577</grs:point>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tchpc.tcd.ie/"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Trinity_College,_Dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.ctvr.ie/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Trinity College, Dublin (TCD), o formalmente College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin (Colegio de la Santa e Indivisible Trinidad de la Reina Isabel cerca de Dublín), fue fundado en 1592 por la Reina Isabel I, y es el único colegio constituyente de la University of Dublin, la universidad más antigua de Irlanda. El Trinity está ubicado en College Green opuesto a las antiguas Casas Irlandesas del Parlamento (ahora una sucursal del Banco de Irlanda).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Le Trinity College Dublin (TCD), fondé en 1592 par la reine Élisabeth I, est la seule constituante de l'Université de Dublin, la plus ancienne université d'Irlande. Conçue sur le modèle des universités d'Oxford et Cambridge, l'université n'accepta pendant longtemps que des étudiants masculins et protestants, mais est aujourd'hui une université pluriculturelle. Elle est la première université irlandaise, ainsi que l'une des universités les plus importantes du monde. Elle fait également partie des anciennes universités du Royaume-Uni et de l'Irlande.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:administrativeStaff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1456</dbpprop:administrativeStaff>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.xcomms.ie/"/>
    <dbpprop:imageSize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">180</dbpprop:imageSize>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-6.2577 53.3444)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cs.tcd.ie/CHI/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.reminiscence.ie/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">O Trinity College, Dublin (TCD), conhecido corporativamente como The Provost, Fellows and Scholars of the College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, é uma universidade em Dublin, fundada em 1592 pela Rainha Isabel I do Reino Unido, no local onde se situava um antigo mosteiro agostiniano. É a única faculdade constituinte da Universidade de Dublin, a mais antiga da Irlanda, com quem forma a instituição educacional de maior prestígio no país. O Trinity College está localizado em College Green, uma praça da capital irlandesa, no lado oposto à antiga sede do parlamento (Houses of Parliament). O campus ocupa 190 000 metros quadrados e atrai muitos turistas pelos seus interessantes edifícios, tanto os antigos quanto os modernos, situados em volta de espaços relvados amplos e de dois campos de desporto. As maiores atracções são a Old Library, biblioteca com 200.000 volumes decorada com bustos de eruditos e a harpa mais antiga da irlanda e o Book of Kells, manuscrito riquíssimo. Numerosas figuras irlandesas estudaram no Trinity College, entre as quais Samuel Beckett.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Trinity College (Kolegium Trójcy Świętej) – irlandzka uczelnia założona w roku 1592 przez królową Elżbietę I w Dublinie na terenie dawnego klasztoru Augustianów.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Il Trinity College di Dublino è un prestigioso istituto d'istruzione a livello mondiale e, senz'altro, il più blasonato e antico d'Irlanda. L'istituzione, il cui nome ufficiale per esteso è College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, nasce ufficialmente nel 1592 con la fondazione ad opera di Elisabetta I. Il Trinity College si dichiara un ente separato dall'Università di Dublino ma, essendone l'unico organismo, le due istituzioni vengono considerate come un corpus unicum. Il college si trova al centro di Dublino, in College Green, di fronte ad una filiale della Bank of Ireland, un tempo palazzo del Parlamento irlandese. L'università si estende su un'area di 220.000 m², includendo il complesso principale del college e il Trinity Technology and Enterprise Campus. La libreria al suo interno comprende circa un milione di testi ed un'importante collezione di antichi manoscritti, fra cui il famoso Libro di Kells. Inizialmente fu un college riservato ai protestanti, ma i Cattolici furono ammessi a partire dal 1793; le donne invece soltanto a partire dal 1904. Tra gli ex studenti del Trinity College ci sono Samuel Beckett, Oscar Wilde, Edmund Burke e Oliver Goldsmith; le statue degli ultimi due si trovano all'esterno dell'ingresso.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.trinityball.ie"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">都柏林三一学院</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Educational_institutions_established_in_the_1590s"/>
    <dbpprop:address rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/College_Green"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:provost rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Patrick_Prendergast"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College,_Dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/ISS/avms/photocentre/gallery1.php"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Trinity College, Dublin (TCD), är ett irländskt college beläget i huvudstaden Dublin. Trinity College, som formellt heter College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, grundades år 1592 av Drottning Elizabeth I. Det är en del av Dublins universitet, som är Irlands äldsta. Trinity College är beläget på College Green, mittemot det gamla parlamentshuset, som idag är säte för den irländska riksbanken.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.havok.com/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/info/trinity/history/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.etu.ie/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Das Trinity College, Dublin (irisch Coláiste na Tríonóide, Baile Átha Cliath) ist eine renommierte Universität in der irischen Hauptstadt Dublin. Einer der berühmtesten Studenten war Samuel Beckett, der dort ab 1923 Sprachen studierte.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/"/>
    <dbpprop:free rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Oriel_College,_Oxford"/>
    <dbpprop:imageName xml:lang="en">Trinity College Dublin Arms.svg</dbpprop:imageName>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Trinity_College_(Dublino)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.tcd.ie/iiis/"/>
    <dbpprop:undergrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">11844</dbpprop:undergrad>
    <dbpprop:nativeName xml:lang="en">Coláiste Thríonóid Naofa Neamhroinnte na Banríona Eilís gar do Bhaile Átha Cliath</dbpprop:nativeName>
    <dbpprop:telephone xml:lang="en">+353-1-896-1000</dbpprop:telephone>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cremeglobal.com/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://ireland.archiseek.com/buildings_ireland/dublin/southcity/trinity/index.html"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Coláiste na Tríonóide</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:address xml:lang="en">Dublin 2</dbpprop:address>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Trinity College, Dublin (TCD), o formalmente College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin (Colegio de la Santa e Indivisible Trinidad de la Reina Isabel cerca de Dublín), fue fundado en 1592 por la Reina Isabel I, y es el único colegio constituyente de la University of Dublin, la universidad más antigua de Irlanda. El Trinity está ubicado en College Green opuesto a las antiguas Casas Irlandesas del Parlamento (ahora una sucursal del Banco de Irlanda). El campus ocupa 47 acres (190.000 m²), con muchos edificios atractivos, tanto nuevos como viejos, centrados alrededor de grandes patios y dos campos de juego. El colegio y la universidad son efectivamente uno, y son usualmente referidos como tal colectivamente como University of Dublin, Trinity College. La principal excepción a esto es el otorgamiento de grados; el colegio provee todos los programas y el personal académico son miembros de él, pero la universidad confiere el grado.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CollegeOrUniversity"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Dublin"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Trinity College (Irish: Coláiste na Tríonóide), formally known as the College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin, is the sole constituent college of the University of Dublin in Ireland. Founded in 1592 by letters patent from Queen Elizabeth I as the "mother of a university", it was modelled after the collegiate universities of Oxford and of Cambridge, but unlike these only one college was established; as such, the designations "Trinity College" and "University of Dublin" are usually synonymous for practical purposes. It is one of the seven ancient universities of Britain and Ireland, as well as Ireland's oldest university. Originally established outside the city walls of Dublin in the buildings of the dissolved Augustinian Priory of All Hallows, Trinity College was set up in part to consolidate the rule of the Tudor monarchy in Ireland, and it was seen as the university of the Protestant Ascendancy for much of its history. Although Roman Catholics and Dissenters had been permitted to enter as early as 1793, certain restrictions on their membership of the college remained until 1873 (professorships, fellowships and scholarships were reserved for Protestants), and the Catholic Church in Ireland forbade its adherents, without permission from their bishop, from attending until 1970. Women were first admitted to the college as full members in 1904. Trinity College is now surrounded by Dublin and is located on College Green, opposite the former Irish Houses of Parliament. The college proper occupies 190,000 m, with many of its buildings ranged around large quadrangles (known as 'squares') and two playing fields. Academically, it is divided into three faculties comprising 24 schools, offering degree and diploma courses at both undergraduate and postgraduate levels. In 2011, it was ranked by the Times Higher Education World University Rankings as the 117th best university in the world, by the QS World University Rankings as the 65th best, by Eduniversal Global as 28th globally, and by all three as the best university in Ireland. The Library of Trinity College is a legal deposit library for Ireland and the United Kingdom, containing over 4.5 million printed volumes and significant quantities of manuscripts, maps and music.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:nativeName xml:lang="en">Coláiste na Tríonóide</dbpprop:nativeName>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">The College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin</foaf:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Trinity College on Dublinissa Irlannissa sijaitseva suuri yliopisto. Yliopiston virallinen nimi on College of the Holy and Undivided Trinity of Queen Elizabeth near Dublin ja sen iirinkielinen nimi on Coláiste na Tríonóide. Kuningatar Elisabet I perusti Trinity Collegen vuonna 1592. Trinity kuuluu eurooppalaisten yliopistojen Coimbra-ryhmään, johon kuuluvat myös suomalaiset Turun yliopisto ja Åbo Akademi.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
