<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Cambridge">
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/5/5d/University_of_Cambridge_Crest.svg/200px-University_of_Cambridge_Crest.svg.png"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Coimbra_Group"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Đại học Cambridge là một viện đại học tại thành phố Cambridge, Anh. Đây là viện đại học cổ xưa thứ hai tại các nước nói tiếng Anh, chỉ sau Viện Đại học Oxford. Năm 1209, do xung đột giữa các sinh viên và dân thành thị, nhiều học giả của Đại học Oxford đã chạy đến thành phố Cambridge và lập nên Đại học Cambridge.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:colours xml:lang="en">Cambridge Blue</dbpprop:colours>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Coimbra_Group"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Cambridge"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ケンブリッジ大学（University of Cambridge）は、イギリスのケンブリッジに所在する総合大学である。</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidade_de_Cambridge"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The University of Cambridge (informally known as Cambridge University or Cambridge) is a public research university located in Cambridge, United Kingdom. It is the second-oldest university in the English-speaking world, and the seventh-oldest in the world. In post-nominals the university's name is abbreviated as Cantab, a shortened form of Cantabrigiensis (an adjective derived from Cantabrigia, the Latinised form of Cambridge).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ケンブリッジ大学（University of Cambridge）は、イギリスのケンブリッジに所在する総合大学である。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Universitat de Cambridge</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:theTimes rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2</dbpprop:theTimes>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Cambridge és la segona universitat de parla anglesa més antiga del món, després de la d'Oxford. Segons la llegenda, la Universitat de Cambridge, a Anglaterra, va ser fundada al 1209 per acadèmics que van fugir d'Oxford, després d'una baralla amb agents d'aquesta ciutat. El rei Enric III d'Anglaterra els va concedir el monopoli de l'ensenyament en aquell lloc al 1231.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Cambridgen yliopisto (engl. University of Cambridge) on Cambridgessa Englannissa sijaitseva Oxfordin jälkeen maailman toiseksi vanhin englanninkielinen yliopisto. Cambridgen yliopisto koostuu 31 collegesta sekä yli 150 tiedekunnasta, laitoksesta, koulusta ja muusta instituutiosta. Lisäksi yliopistolla on suhteellisen pieni keskushallinto. Oxfordin ja Cambridgen yliopistot, joita kutsutaan yhteisnimityksellä Oxbridge, ovat pitkään kilpailleet keskenään.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Πανεπιστήμιο_του_Κέμπριτζ"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cambridge"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_university"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Russell_Group"/>
    <dbpprop:demonym xml:lang="en">Cantabrigian</dbpprop:demonym>
    <dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour xml:lang="en">Cambridge Blue</dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/G5_(education)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">剑桥大学（英语：University of Cambridge）位于英国剑桥郡的剑桥市，是英语世界裡成立的第二所大学。 剑桥大学的前身是一个在剑桥市成立的学者协会，早期的记录称协会的学者是因和牛津城市居民的争端，于1209年离开牛津来到剑桥的。剑桥大学和牛津大学经常被合称为牛剑，除了两所大学在文化和现实上的协作已成为英国社会史的一部分外，两所大学长久以来一直存在竞争。 剑桥大学在学术方面始终是世界领先的大学之一，曾经诞生了87位诺贝尔奖获得者。而根據2010年QS排名，劍橋大學全球排名第1。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk/societies/"/>
    <dbpprop:qsWorldUniversityRankings rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:qsWorldUniversityRankings>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Кембриджский_университет"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Oxbridge"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.dhs.kyutech.ac.jp/~ruxton/hatenkou.html"/>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk/"/>
    <dbpprop:faculty rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5999</dbpprop:faculty>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Ке́мбриджский университет — по времени основания второй университет в Великобритании после Оксфордского и четвертый в мире; один из «старинных университетов» Великобритании и Ирландии, один из наиболее известных университетов мира, член элитной Группы Рассел. Университет вырос из собрания ученых людей города Кембриджа, которое было образовано, судя по летописям, в 1209 году учеными, покинувшими город Оксфорд из-за того, что оксфордский студент убил жительницу города. В 1214 году были составлены формальные университетские правила. По ним назначался ректор и программа с экзаменами в конце. В средневековье все знания об окружающем мире получали в монастырях. Главным отличием от монастырей в них стало обучение наукам, философии, логике, математике. Университеты Кембриджа и Оксфорда часто вместе называют «Оксбридж». Вдобавок к прочному месту в истории британского общества, у этих университетов имеется долгая история соперничества друг с другом. Среди людей, так или иначе связанных с Кембриджским университетом, 88 нобелевских лауреатов — по этому показателю он занимает одно из первых мест среди высших учебных заведений мира.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cusu.cam.ac.uk/"/>
    <dbpprop:country xml:lang="en">England, UK</dbpprop:country>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">A Universidade de Cambridge é uma tradicional instituição de ensino superior do Reino Unido, sendo uma das mais importantes e a ainda em funcionamento do país. A Universidade de Cambridge, localiza-se na cidade de Cambridge, foi fundada em 1209, porém o rei Henry III concedeu-lhes o monopólio do ensino em 1231.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/EducationalInstitution"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Die britische University of Cambridge wurde im Jahr 1209 durch einen Auszug von Dozenten und Studenten aus Oxford gegründet. Die Universität besteht aus mehreren Colleges (insg. 31) und hat daher einen föderativen Charakter. Das offizielle Gründungsdatum des ersten Colleges, Peterhouse, war 1284. Die University of Cambridge gilt als eine der angesehensten Universitäten der Welt. Sie hat mehr Nobelpreisträger als irgendeine andere Universität auf der Welt hervorgebracht. Mitglieder der Universität haben 88 Nobelpreise gewonnen, rund 70 davon waren selbst Studenten in Cambridge. Die führende Stellung von Oxford und Cambridge im akademischen Leben Großbritanniens kommt in der ironisch zusammenfassenden Bezeichnung Oxbridge zum Ausdruck. Die Rivalität zwischen Oxford und Cambridge hält bis heute an und findet ihren folkloristischen Ausdruck in dem berühmten Boat Race, einem auf der Themse seit 1829 jährlich ausgetragenem Achterrennen der beiden Universitätsmannschaften. Da Oxford und Cambridge sowie einige weitere Traditionsuniversitäten sehr ähnlich aufgebaut sind – jedenfalls im Vergleich mit kontinentaleuropäischen Universitäten – wird ihre Struktur in dem Artikel Britische Universitäten dargestellt.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/OrganisationsBasedInEnglandWithRoyalPatronage"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The University of Cambridge (informally known as Cambridge University or Cambridge) is a public research university located in Cambridge, United Kingdom. It is the second-oldest university in the English-speaking world, and the seventh-oldest in the world. In post-nominals the university's name is abbreviated as Cantab, a shortened form of Cantabrigiensis (an adjective derived from Cantabrigia, the Latinised form of Cambridge). The university grew out of an association of scholars in the city of Cambridge that was formed in 1209, early records suggest, by scholars leaving Oxford after a dispute with townsfolk. The two "ancient universities" have many common features and are often jointly referred to as Oxbridge. In addition to cultural and practical associations as a historic part of British society, they have a long history of rivalry with each other. Cambridge ranks first in the world in both the 2010 and 2011 QS World University Rankings, sixth in the world in the 2011 Times Higher Education World University Rankings, and fifth in the world (and first in Europe) in the 2011 Academic Ranking of World Universities. Cambridge regularly contends with Oxford for first place in UK league tables. In the two most recently published rankings of UK universities by The Guardian newspaper, Cambridge was ranked first. Graduates of the university have won a total of 65 Nobel Prizes, the most of any university in the world. In 2009, the marketing consultancy World Brand Lab rated Cambridge University as the 50th most influential brand in the world, and the 4th most influential university brand, behind only Harvard, MIT and Stanford University, while in 2011, Cambridge ranked third, after Harvard and MIT, in The Times Higher Education World Reputation Rankings, which reflect the reputation of universities for educational and research excellence based on a survey of academics worldwide. Cambridge is a member of the Coimbra Group, the G5, the International Alliance of Research Universities, the League of European Research Universities and the Russell Group of research-led British universities. It forms part of the 'Golden Triangle' of British universities.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1209_establishments_in_England"/>
    <dbpprop:latinName xml:lang="en">Academia Cantabrigiensis</dbpprop:latinName>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">La Universidad de Cambridge es la segunda universidad de habla inglesa más antigua, después de Oxford. Según la historia, la Universidad de Cambridge, en Inglaterra, fue fundada en 1209 por académicos que huyeron de Oxford, tras una reyerta con agentes de dicha ciudad. El rey Enrique III de Inglaterra les concedió el monopolio de la enseñanza en aquel lugar en 1231.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">University of Cambridge</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:imageName xml:lang="en">University of Cambridge Crest.svg</dbpprop:imageName>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_UK_university_rankings"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpprop:mottoeng xml:lang="en">Non-literal: From this place, we gain enlightenment and precious knowledge</dbpprop:mottoeng>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpprop:theGuardian rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:theGuardian>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Cambridge"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Die britische University of Cambridge wurde im Jahr 1209 durch einen Auszug von Dozenten und Studenten aus Oxford gegründet. Die Universität besteht aus mehreren Colleges (insg. 31) und hat daher einen föderativen Charakter. Das offizielle Gründungsdatum des ersten Colleges, Peterhouse, war 1284. Die University of Cambridge gilt als eine der angesehensten Universitäten der Welt. Sie hat mehr Nobelpreisträger als irgendeine andere Universität auf der Welt hervorgebracht.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/International_Alliance_of_Research_Universities"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Univerzita_v_Cambridgi"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk/research/about/awards-announcements-and-prizes/nobel-prize-winners"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/International_Alliance_of_Research_Universities"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Coimbra_Group"/>
    <dbpprop:height rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">135</dbpprop:height>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">케임브리지 대학교(University of Cambridge)는 영국 잉글랜드 케임브리지에 위치한 영어권에서 두번째로 오래된 전통을 가진 종합 대학교이다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:theW xml:lang="en">=6</dbpprop:theW>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/University"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:University_of_Cambridge"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Visitor_attractions_in_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Centre for Mathematical Sciences .</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">12077</dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Non-literal: From this place, we gain enlightenment and precious knowledge</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <dbpprop:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/poundSterling">4.3E9</dbpprop:endowment>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Public_university"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Cambridge?oldid=495411710"/>
    <dbpprop:qsN rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:qsN>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">케임브리지 대학교(University of Cambridge)는 영국 잉글랜드 케임브리지에 위치한 영어권에서 두번째로 오래된 전통을 가진 종합 대학교이다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Université_de_Cambridge"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">De universiteit van Cambridge in de Engelse stad Cambridge is een van de oudste en bekendste universiteiten in het Verenigd Koninkrijk en de wereld.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:postgrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">6371</dbpprop:postgrad>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">52.2053</geo:lat>
    <dbpprop:arwuN rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:arwuN>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/G5_(education)"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Literal: From here, light and sacred draughts</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Organization"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Univerzita v Cambridgi, či Cambridgeská univerzita (anglicky University of Cambridge, často také Cambridge University, latinsky Universitas Cantabrigiensis) je druhá nejstarší univerzita v anglicky mluvící části světa. Univerzita sídlí v anglickém městě Cambridge. Dnes má přibližně 19 000 studentů rozdělených v 31 colleges (kolejích), což jsou víceméně nezávislé instituce, které mezi jiným poskytují studentům i ubytování a stravu. Společně s Oxfordskou univerzitou jsou označovány jako Oxbridge. Velmi známá je také jejich rivalita, která se táhne už od založení Cambridgeské university učenci prchajícími z Oxfordu. Je členem Coimbra Group, asociace sdružující nejvýznamnější evropské university.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Università_di_Cambridge"/>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/5/5d/University_of_Cambridge_Crest.svg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Universitetet i Cambridge, är ett engelskt universitet i staden Cambridge i grevskapet Cambridgeshire, cirka 80 km norr om London. Staden har fått sitt namn efter floden Cam som rinner genom den. Enligt traditionen grundades universitetet av missnöjda lärare och studenter från Oxford 1209, men som officiellt startår brukar anges 1284 vilket är året då universitetets äldsta college, Peterhouse, kom till. Idag finns det 31 colleges.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Đại học Cambridge</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Association_of_Commonwealth_Universities"/>
    <dbpprop:line rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">0</dbpprop:line>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">University of Cambridge</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Hinc lucem et pocula sacra (Latin)</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <dbpprop:mottoeng xml:lang="en">Literal: From here, light and sacred draughts</dbpprop:mottoeng>
    <dbpprop:viceChancellor xml:lang="en">Sir Leszek Borysiewicz</dbpprop:viceChancellor>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Educational_institutions_established_in_the_13th_century"/>
    <dbpprop:sundayTimes rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:sundayTimes>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidad_de_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Public_university"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:History_of_Cambridge"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EduCAtionalInstitutionsEstablishedInThe13thCentury"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/European_University_Association"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Universitetet i Cambridge, är ett engelskt universitet i staden Cambridge i grevskapet Cambridgeshire, cirka 80 km norr om London. Staden har fått sitt namn efter floden Cam som rinner genom den. Enligt traditionen grundades universitetet av missnöjda lärare och studenter från Oxford 1209, men som officiellt startår brukar anges 1284 vilket är året då universitetets äldsta college, Peterhouse, kom till. Idag finns det 31 colleges. Universitetets organisation beskrivs normalt som en konfederation av fakulteter, colleges och andra enheter. Fakulteterna består av ämnesinstitutioner och andra centrum och generellt kan man säga att fakulteterna är ansvariga för att bedriva forskning och att arrangera centraliserade undervisningsaktiviteter i kursform. Colleges, å sin sida, är de som antar studenter och svarar för deras boende med mera. Vid varje college sker också lärarledd handledning i smågrupper, så kallade supervisions. Många lärare vid universitetet är knutna både till en fakultet/institution och till ett college. Universitetet i Cambridge anses vara ett av världens mest framstående lärosäten. Det har producerat fler nobelpris än någon annan akademisk institution och många av de forskare som senare har belönats med nobelpriset har själva varit studenter vid universitetet som unga. I en världsranking 2005 hamnade Cambridge på 2:a plats. Cambridges och Oxfords sammantaget dominerande ställning bland de brittiska lärosätena har givit upphov till den skämtsamma hopdragningen Oxbridge av de båda städernas namn. Uttrycket myntades av författaren Virginia Woolf i essän Ett eget rum. Rivaliteten mellan universiteten tar sig bland annat uttryck i idrottskamper, så kallade "Varsity matches", varav den berömda rodden på Themsen är en.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/케임브리지_대학교"/>
    <dbpprop:complete rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1</dbpprop:complete>
    <dbpedia-owl:facultySize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">5999</dbpedia-owl:facultySize>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">University of Cambridge – drugi po Oksfordzie najstarszy angielski uniwersytet, założony w roku 1209. Znajduje się w Cambridge w środkowej Anglii. Uważany za jeden z najlepszych uniwersytetów w Europie i na świecie. Uniwersytety Oksfordzki i Cambridge określane są wspólną nazwą Oxbridge. Uniwersytet Cambridge Składa się z kilkunastu niezależnych kolegiów, z których najstarszym jest Peterhouse. Inne to m. in. Corpus Christi, King's, Queens', Trinity, Magdalene, Christ's, Wolfson. Większość kolegiów w Cambridge jest obecnie koedukacyjna. Obok działalności akademickiej w Cambridge prowadzone są prace badawcze w różnych dziedzinach nauki – np. ma tam swą siedzibę założone w 1871 roku Laboratorium Cavendisha, słynne z badań nad atomem czy strukturą DNA. Znany na całym świecie jest wyścig ósemek Oksford-Cambridge w wioślarstwie. Od 2010 r. urzędującym rektorem Uniwersytetu Cambridge jest brytyjski lekarz i immunolog polskiego pochodzenia, Sir Leszek Borysiewicz. Absolwenci Cambridge zdobyli 65 Nagród Nobla, więcej niż absolwenci jakiegokolwiek innego uniwersytetu na świecie</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:imageSize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">180</dbpprop:imageSize>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/University_of_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">University of Cambridge er det nest eldste universitet i den engelskspråklige verden. Det har noen av de strengeste adgangskriterier i Storbritannia, og er ved siden av University of Oxford et av verdens mest prestisjefylte universiteter (de to universitetene omtales ofte med teleskopordet Oxbridge). Cambridge inntar førsteplassen globalt på Times' liste over verdens beste universiteter. Hele 65 Nobelpriser er blitt vunnet av folk tilknyttet universitetet, og Cambridge har dermed etter mange estimater flere tilknyttede Nobelprisvinnere enn noe annet universitet. De tidligste arkivene er ikke bevart, men det er kjent at universitetet vokste frem fra en sammenslutning av forskere i Cambridge, England i 1209. De skal ha flyktet fra Oxford etter et sammenstøt med byens borgere.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">University of Cambridge – drugi po Oksfordzie najstarszy angielski uniwersytet, założony w roku 1209. Znajduje się w Cambridge w środkowej Anglii. Uważany za jeden z najlepszych uniwersytetów w Europie i na świecie. Uniwersytety Oksfordzki i Cambridge określane są wspólną nazwą Oxbridge. Uniwersytet Cambridge Składa się z kilkunastu niezależnych kolegiów, z których najstarszym jest Peterhouse. Inne to m. in. Corpus Christi, King's, Queens', Trinity, Magdalene, Christ's, Wolfson.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:viceChancellor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Leszek_Borysiewicz"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu"></dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Đại học Cambridge là một viện đại học tại thành phố Cambridge, Anh. Đây là viện đại học cổ xưa thứ hai tại các nước nói tiếng Anh, chỉ sau Viện Đại học Oxford. Năm 1209, do xung đột giữa các sinh viên và dân thành thị, nhiều học giả của Đại học Oxford đã chạy đến thành phố Cambridge và lập nên Đại học Cambridge. Ngày nay, Viện Đại học Cambridge là một trong những viện đại học danh tiếng nhất Vương quốc Liên hiệp Anh và Bắc Ireland cũng như của thế giới.88 người giành giải thưởng Nobel có liên hệ với Đại học Cambridge trong đó có 52 cựu sinh viên của trường . Viện Đại học Cambridge hiện có 31 trường đại học thành viên. đây là trường đại học danh tiếng và là giấc mơ của bao bạn sinh viên trên toàn thế giới</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Academia Cantabrigiensis</foaf:name>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Cambridge és la segona universitat de parla anglesa més antiga del món, després de la d'Oxford. Segons la llegenda, la Universitat de Cambridge, a Anglaterra, va ser fundada al 1209 per acadèmics que van fugir d'Oxford, després d'una baralla amb agents d'aquesta ciutat. El rei Enric III d'Anglaterra els va concedir el monopoli de l'ensenyament en aquell lloc al 1231. Al costat de la Universitat d'Oxford, la Universitat de Cambridge forma a una gran quantitat dels més destacats científics, escriptors i polítics de la Gran Bretanya. Ambdues institucions són conegudes conjuntament amb el malnom de Oxbridge i són integrants del Grup d'Universitats Russell i del Grup Coïmbra. Cambridge és la universitat que acumula més receptors del Premi Nobel entre ex-alumnes i professors, fet que la situa en un punt molt alt del rànquing d'universitats. Els trenta-un colleges que integren la universitat són institucions independents i separades de la pròpia universitat, que gaudeixen d'un ample nivell d'autonomia. El college més antic és Peterhouse, fundat al 1284 per Hugh Balsham, Bisbe de Ely. El segon college més antic va ser King's Hall, fundat al 1317, encara que ja no existeix com una institució independent. Molts colleges es van fundar als segles XIV i XV. Més abaix es lliura una llista completa dels colleges que composan actualment la universitat. No obstant això, alguns d'ells com Michaelhouse (que es va unir a King's Hall per crear Trinity, per ordre del rei Enric VII) i Gonville Hall ja no existeixen. En aquests primers anys, els colleges van ser fundats perquè els estudiants resessin per les ànimes dels fundadors i per aquest motiu aquestes institucions estaven vinculades amb freqüència a capelles o abadies. Al costat de la Dissolució dels Monestirs, ordenada al 1536, el rei Enric VIII va ordenar la dissolució de la Facultat de Dret Canònic i el cessament de les classes de "filosofia escolàstica". Així que en lloc de dedicar-se al dret canònic, els plans d'estudi dels colleges es van orientar als clàssics llatins i grecs, la Bíblia i les matemàtiques. Els primers colleges per a dones van ser Girton College, fundat al 1869, i Newnham College, fundat al 1872. Les primeres estudiants van rendir els seus exàmens al 1882, però les dones no van assolir plena pertinença a la universitat sinó fins a 1947, 20 anys després que Oxford. Dels 31 colleges que composan la Universitat de Cambridge a l'actualitat, tres són només per a dones (Lucy Cavendish, New Hall i Newnham) i quatre són exclusivament per a estudiants de postgrau (Clare Hall, Darwin, Wolfson i St. Edmunds). Hi ha certes activitats d'esplai associades a Cambridge. El rem és un esport popular i existeixen competicions entre colleges i contra Oxford. També existeixen competicions en altres esports, com el cricket i el rugbi. Entre els clubs de teatre, es troba el famós Footlights.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Culture_in_Cambridge"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/University"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu"></rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">剑桥大学</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CollegeOrUniversity"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Cambridgen yliopisto (engl. University of Cambridge) on Cambridgessa Englannissa sijaitseva Oxfordin jälkeen maailman toiseksi vanhin englanninkielinen yliopisto. Cambridgen yliopisto koostuu 31 collegesta sekä yli 150 tiedekunnasta, laitoksesta, koulusta ja muusta instituutiosta. Lisäksi yliopistolla on suhteellisen pieni keskushallinto. Oxfordin ja Cambridgen yliopistot, joita kutsutaan yhteisnimityksellä Oxbridge, ovat pitkään kilpailleet keskenään. Molemmat kuuluvat kultaiseen kolmioon yhdessä Imperial College Londonin kanssa. Perinteisesti Cambridgea on pidetty enemmän matemaattis-luonnontieteellisenä yliopistona ja Oxfordia humanistisena yliopistona. Kautta olemassaolonsa Cambridge on ollut ja on yhä yksi maailman tunnetuimmista akateemisista instituutioista. Yliopiston muodollisena johtajana eli kanslerina toimii lokakuusta 2011 alkaen David Sainsbury, joka seuraa tässä tehtävässä kuningatar Elisabet II:n puolisoa, prinssi Philipiä. Käytännössä yliopistoa johtaa sijaiskansleri. Cambridgen sijaiskansleri on 1. lokakuuta 2010 alkaen Leszek Borysiewicz edellisen sijaiskanslerin Alison Richardin seitsemänvuotisen kauden päätyttyä. Tunnettuihin suomalaisiin, jotka ovat opettaneet Cambridgen yliopistossa, kuuluvat filosofi Georg Henrik von Wright ja ekonomisti Seppo Honkapohja.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-university-noun-2"/>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(0.117222 52.2053)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">De universiteit van Cambridge in de Engelse stad Cambridge is een van de oudste en bekendste universiteiten in het Verenigd Koninkrijk en de wereld.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/League_of_European_Research_Universities"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5</dbpprop:arwuW>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">0.117222</geo:long>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Univerzita v Cambridgi, či Cambridgeská univerzita (anglicky University of Cambridge, často také Cambridge University, latinsky Universitas Cantabrigiensis) je druhá nejstarší univerzita v anglicky mluvící části světa. Univerzita sídlí v anglickém městě Cambridge. Dnes má přibližně 19 000 studentů rozdělených v 31 colleges (kolejích), což jsou víceméně nezávislé instituce, které mezi jiným poskytují studentům i ubytování a stravu. Společně s Oxfordskou univerzitou jsou označovány jako Oxbridge.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:motto xml:lang="en">Hinc lucem et pocula sacra</dbpprop:motto>
    <dbpprop:alt xml:lang="en">Centre for Mathematical Sciences .</dbpprop:alt>
    <dbpedia-owl:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Blue_(university_sport)"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/League_of_European_Research_Universities"/>
    <dbpprop:chancellor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/David_Sainsbury,_Baron_Sainsbury_of_Turville"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">剑桥大学（英语：University of Cambridge）位于英国剑桥郡的剑桥市，是英语世界裡成立的第二所大学。 剑桥大学的前身是一个在剑桥市成立的学者协会，早期的记录称协会的学者是因和牛津城市居民的争端，于1209年离开牛津来到剑桥的。剑桥大学和牛津大学经常被合称为牛剑，除了两所大学在文化和现实上的协作已成为英国社会史的一部分外，两所大学长久以来一直存在竞争。 剑桥大学在学术方面始终是世界领先的大学之一，曾经诞生了87位诺贝尔奖获得者。而根據2010年QS排名，劍橋大學全球排名第1。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:athletics xml:lang="en">The Sporting Blue</dbpprop:athletics>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ExemptCharities"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.07tg4"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.prweb.com/releases/2005/1/prweb201396.htm"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/European_University_Association"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">A Universidade de Cambridge é uma tradicional instituição de ensino superior do Reino Unido, sendo uma das mais importantes e a ainda em funcionamento do país. A Universidade de Cambridge, localiza-se na cidade de Cambridge, foi fundada em 1209, porém o rei Henry III concedeu-lhes o monopólio do ensino em 1231.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:theN xml:lang="en">=1</dbpprop:theN>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Russell_Group"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">18448</dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents>
    <dbpprop:established xml:lang="en">c. 1209</dbpprop:established>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk/"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">52.20527777777778 0.11722222222222221</grs:point>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvuL6TZwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">La Universidad de Cambridge es la segunda universidad de habla inglesa más antigua, después de Oxford. Según la historia, la Universidad de Cambridge, en Inglaterra, fue fundada en 1209 por académicos que huyeron de Oxford, tras una reyerta con agentes de dicha ciudad. El rey Enrique III de Inglaterra les concedió el monopolio de la enseñanza en aquel lugar en 1231. Junto a la Universidad de Oxford, la Universidad de Cambridge forma a una gran cantidad de los más destacados científicos, escritores y políticos de Gran Bretaña. Ambas instituciones son conocidas conjuntamente con el nombre de Oxbridge y son integrantes del Russell Group.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">L'Università di Cambridge è la seconda per anzianità delle università anglosassoni, dopo l'Università di Oxford, e la quarta in Europa. È considerata fra i migliori centri universitari britannici e mondiali; ospita quasi 20000 studenti e più di 5000 fra ricercatori e professori. Secondo la leggenda venne fondata da alcuni studenti nel 1209, dopo essere fuggiti da Oxford a seguito di una lite coi locali: tradizionalmente fra le due università, collettivamente conosciute con la dizione Oxbridge, esiste una forte rivalità accademica e non solo, come testimoniato dalla celeberrima regata. L'università di Cambridge si piazza regolarmente in cima alle classifiche mondiali: è risultata la seconda università nella classifica accademica delle università mondiali e la prima università nel continente europeo. I ricercatori di questa istituzione hanno ricevuto 88 premi Nobel. Nel 2010 è divenuta la prima università britannica ad essere classificata in vetta alla classifica QS World University Rankings, sorpassando Harvard. L'università è un membro del Gruppo Russell e del gruppo di Coimbra che includono le istituzioni più all'avanguardia nel campo della ricerca.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Russell_Group"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Univerzita v Cambridgi</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk/"/>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:logo>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Panorama"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Ке́мбриджский университет — по времени основания второй университет в Великобритании после Оксфордского и четвертый в мире; один из «старинных университетов» Великобритании и Ирландии, один из наиболее известных университетов мира, член элитной Группы Рассел. Университет вырос из собрания ученых людей города Кембриджа, которое было образовано, судя по летописям, в 1209 году учеными, покинувшими город Оксфорд из-за того, что оксфордский студент убил жительницу города.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/VisitorAttractionsInCambridge"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">University of Cambridge</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:chancellor rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/David_Sainsbury,_Baron_Sainsbury_of_Turville"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Organisations_based_in_Cambridge_with_royal_patronage"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">University of Cambridge er det nest eldste universitet i den engelskspråklige verden. Det har noen av de strengeste adgangskriterier i Storbritannia, og er ved siden av University of Oxford et av verdens mest prestisjefylte universiteter (de to universitetene omtales ofte med teleskopordet Oxbridge). Cambridge inntar førsteplassen globalt på Times' liste over verdens beste universiteter.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:staff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">3142</dbpprop:staff>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">University of Cambridge</foaf:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ケンブリッジ大学"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">6371</dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">L’université de Cambridge est la deuxième plus ancienne institution académique du monde anglophone (la première étant l'université d'Oxford). Elle fait partie des Ancient universities. C'est l'une des plus prestigieuses universités du monde. Elle forme, avec son éternelle rivale l'université d'Oxford la quasi-totalité des élites politiques et intellectuelles du Royaume-Uni depuis des centaines d'années et représente la quintessence, avec Oxford, du système universitaire élitiste anglais.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:staff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">3142</dbpedia-owl:staff>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L’université de Cambridge est la deuxième plus ancienne institution académique du monde anglophone (la première étant l'université d'Oxford). Elle fait partie des Ancient universities. C'est l'une des plus prestigieuses universités du monde. Elle forme, avec son éternelle rivale l'université d'Oxford la quasi-totalité des élites politiques et intellectuelles du Royaume-Uni depuis des centaines d'années et représente la quintessence, avec Oxford, du système universitaire élitiste anglais.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Exempt_charities"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/poundSterling">4.3E9</dbpedia-owl:endowment>
    <dbpprop:undergrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">12077</dbpprop:undergrad>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:students rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">18448</dbpprop:students>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.gradunion.cam.ac.uk/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.cam.ac.uk/map/v3/drawmap.cgi?mp=city"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">L'Università di Cambridge è la seconda per anzianità delle università anglosassoni, dopo l'Università di Oxford, e la quarta in Europa. È considerata fra i migliori centri universitari britannici e mondiali; ospita quasi 20000 studenti e più di 5000 fra ricercatori e professori.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
