<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Pennsylvania">
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:National_Association_of_Independent_Colleges_and_Universities_members"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Pennsylvanian yliopisto (University of Pennsylvania; Penn on usein käytetty lyhenne; UPenn on myös oikein, mutta harvinaisempi) on yksityinen yliopisto Philadelphiassa, Pennsylvaniassa. Yliopiston mukaan se on neljänneksi vanhin korkeakoulu Yhdysvalloissa ja "Amerikan ensimmäinen yliopisto". Se on myös jäsen eliittiyliopistojen ryhmässä Ivy League. Yliopisto järjestää maailman vanhimman ja suurimman viestijuoksutapahtuman Penn Relaysin. Yliopiston perustaja on Benjamin Franklin.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">A Universidade de Pensilvânia (também conhecida como Penn) é uma instituição de ensino superior particular localizada na cidade da Filadélfia, Pensilvânia, nos Estados Unidos da América. Fundada por Benjamin Franklin, em 1740 como faculdade, em 1765 se transformou na primeira universidade dos Estados Unidos da América. Além disso, é uma das oito universidades integrantes da Ivy League e também um dos Colonial Colleges. O U.S. News &amp; World Report classificou a Universidade da Pensilvânia em quinto lugar entre entre as instituições de graduação nos Estados Unidos para o ano escolar de 2008, atrás de Princeton, Harvard, Stanford e Yale. Nos anos de 2005 e 2006, a Penn foi classificada em quarto lugar. Referências</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Pennsylvania?oldid=495204419"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">펜실베이니아 대학교(University of Pennsylvania)는 흔히 유펜(UPenn)으로도 불리며 미국 펜실베이니아 주 필라델피아에 있는 연구 중심의 종합 사립대학이다. 1740년 설립된 이 학교는 미국에서 네 번째로 오래된 고등교육기관이며 아이비 리그(Ivy League)에 일원인 최상위권 명문대학이다. 조지프 와튼이 설립한 이 대학의 와튼 비즈니스 스쿨(Wharton Business School)은 미국에서 제일 오래되고 우수한 비즈니스 스쿨이다. 비즈니스 스쿨 외에도 마케팅, 경영학, 회계학, 재정학, 노동산업학, 경제학 등이 우수하다. 언어학과 인류학, 생의공학 분야도 뛰어나다. 펜실베이니아대학은 여러 종류의 이중학위 과정을 제공하고 있으며 엔지니어링을 전공하는 학생수도 많다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/92/UPenn_shield_with_banner.svg/200px-UPenn_shield_with_banner.svg.png"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">11028</dbpedia-owl:numberOfPostgraduateStudents>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EduCAtionalInstitutionsEstablishedInThe1740s"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ivy_League"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/UniversitiesAndCollegesInPhiladelphia,Pennsylvania"/>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-75.193 39.9539)</geo:geometry>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_university"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/EducationalInstitution"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Amy_Gutmann"/>
    <dbpprop:align xml:lang="en">right</dbpprop:align>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Division_I_(NCAA)"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Philadelphia_Big_5"/>
    <dbpprop:endowment xml:lang="en">US$6.58  billion</dbpprop:endowment>
    <dbpprop:alt xml:lang="en">Current Seal of the Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania</dbpprop:alt>
    <dbpprop:width xml:lang="en">(100 * 305 / 299) round 0</dbpprop:width>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Die University of Pennsylvania (Penn) ist eine private Forschungsuniversität in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Die Penn ist eine der renommiertesten und ältesten Universitäten der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika. Sie ist Mitglied in der Association of American Universities und einer Sportliga acht amerikanischer Elite-Unis, der Ivy League. Penn ist mit rund 13.240 Angestellten der größte private Arbeitgeber in Philadelphia. Mit jährlichen Forschungsausgaben in Höhe von $ 814 Millionen (2011) zählt die Universität zu den größten Forschungszentren in den USA. Das jährliche Budget der Universität in Höhe von ca. $ 6 Milliarden (Fiskaljahr 2011; rund $ 2,5 Milliarden davon sind Löhne und Gehälter) ist das Größte aller Ivy League Universitäten. Das Stiftungsvermögen von Penn ist mit $ 6,44 Milliarden (2007) allerdings kleiner als das der Stiftungen der Harvard University, der Princeton University und der Yale University. Die Wharton School of Business, die Law School und die School of Medicine genießen ein besonders hohes Ansehen.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:wamoNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">21</dbpprop:wamoNu>
    <dbpprop:thesW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">16</dbpprop:thesW>
    <dbpprop:title xml:lang="en">Links to related articles</dbpprop:title>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:logo>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Colonial_Colleges"/>
    <dbpprop:latinName xml:lang="en">Universitas Pennsylvaniensis</dbpprop:latinName>
    <dbpprop:colors xml:lang="en">Red and blue</dbpprop:colors>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:University_of_Pennsylvania"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Пенсильванский_университет"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ペンシルベニア大学"/>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Arms of the University of Pennsylvania</dbpprop:caption>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">University of Pennsylvania (Penn) er et privat universitet i Philadelphia, staten Pennsylvania i USA. Det ble grunnlagt i 1740 av Benjamin Franklin, og inngår i sammenslutningen av fremragende amerikanske universiteter – Ivy League. Wharton School er handelshøyskolen ved universitetet, og det er også egne skoler for medisin, veterinærmedisin, jus og kommunikasjon. Alle skolene er lokalisert på samme campus.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">A Universidade de Pensilvânia (também conhecida como Penn) é uma instituição de ensino superior particular localizada na cidade da Filadélfia, Pensilvânia, nos Estados Unidos da América. Fundada por Benjamin Franklin, em 1740 como faculdade, em 1765 se transformou na primeira universidade dos Estados Unidos da América. Além disso, é uma das oito universidades integrantes da Ivy League e também um dos Colonial Colleges. O U.S.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/9/92/UPenn_shield_with_banner.svg"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Пенсильванский университет — частный исследовательский университет США, расположенный в Филадельфии, штат Пенсильвания. Основан в 1740 году Бенджамином Франклином. Пенсильванский университет — одно из старейших высших учебных заведений и первый университет в США, а также один из 9-и колониальных колледжей, основанных до подписания декларации независимости. Несмотря на название, университет является частным и его иногда путают с общественным университетом штата Пенсильвания (Pennsylvania State University), расположенным в городе Стейт Колледж. В 2006 году университет принял 17,7 % абитуриентов, подавших документы на бакалавриат. Это был рекордно низкий процент принятых на первый курс студентов за всю историю существования университета. Бенджамин Франклин, основатель университета, пропагандировал образовательную программу, которая бы фокусировалась на практически полезном образовании для торговли и общественной службы, будучи в то же время сфокусированным на классике. Школа бизнеса Уортона, одна из самых престижных и известных бизнес школ мира, является частью Пенсильванского университета. При университете с конца XIX века существует Музей археологии и антропологии Пенсильванского университета.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">10301</dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Consortium_on_Financing_Higher_Education"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">University of Pennsylvania (vanligtvis kallat Penn eller UPenn), är ett universitet i Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Universities_and_colleges_in_Philadelphia,_Pennsylvania"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">常に米国大学ランキングでトップ3またはトップ5にランクインし、世界大学ランキングではトップ10に入り、米国を代表する名門大学として不動の地位を保っている。アイビーリーグに属し、大学の愛称はPennまたはUPenn、日本人の間ではユーペン、ペン大と略称される。モットーは Laws Without Morals are Useless（良識のない法は無益である: Leges Sine Moribus Vanae）。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Université_de_Pennsylvanie"/>
    <dbpprop:width xml:lang="en">(150 * 1331 / 881) round 0</dbpprop:width>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:administrativeStaff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2347</dbpprop:administrativeStaff>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CollegeOrUniversity"/>
    <dbpprop:alt xml:lang="en">Hamilton Walk and the John Morgan Building at the Perelman School of Medicine</dbpprop:alt>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/University_City,_Philadelphia,_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Pennsilvània, és una de les institucions educatives més prestigioses dels Estats Units d'Amèrica. La universitat és localitzada en Filadèlfia en l'estat de Pennsilvània, Estats Units, és una universitat membre de la Ivy League. La Universitat de Pennsilvània és una universitat privada.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:width xml:lang="en">(100 * 385 / 390) round 0</dbpprop:width>
    <dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour xml:lang="en">Red and blue</dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour>
    <dbpedia-owl:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Collegiate_Athletic_Association"/>
    <dbpprop:qsW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">9</dbpprop:qsW>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">La Universitat de Pennsilvània, és una de les institucions educatives més prestigioses dels Estats Units d'Amèrica. La universitat és localitzada en Filadèlfia en l'estat de Pennsilvània, Estats Units, és una universitat membre de la Ivy League. La Universitat de Pennsilvània és una universitat privada.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:imageName xml:lang="en">UPenn_shield_with_banner.svg</dbpprop:imageName>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Leges sine moribus vanae</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Universitat de Pennsilvània</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">De Universiteit van Pennsylvania (University of Pennsylvania), ook wel bekend als UPenn of Penn, is een universiteit in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. De universiteit behoort tot de Ivy League en geldt als een elite-universiteit. Een van de meest toonaangevende onderdelen van de universiteit is de Wharton School, een businessschool. De Universiteit van Pennsylvania is een private university, niet te verwarren met de staatsuniversiteit Pennsylvania State University.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/ColonialColleges"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">宾夕法尼亚大学（University of Pennsylvania），位于美國賓夕法尼亞州的費城，是一所著名的私立研究型大學，八所常春藤盟校之一。学校创建于1740年，是美國第四古老的高等教育機構，也是美国第一所从事科学技术和人文教育的现代高等学校。美国《独立宣言》的9位签字者和《美国宪法》的11位签字者和该校有关。本杰明·富兰克林是学校的创建人。 宾夕法尼亚大学在艺术、人文、社会科学、商学、建筑与工程教育上处于领先地位，其中尤为知名的学科是商業学、法学与医学。学校拥有约4,500名教授，近10,000名全日制大學生与10,000多名研究生。2006年学校获得的科研经费达到6千6百多万美元，从事研究的人员包括约4,200名教职工，870名博士后，3,800名研究生与5,400多名技术人员。同时，学校每年的建设投入达到4亿美元以上，在常春藤盟校中名列前茅。 宾夕法尼亚大学还是美国大学联合会的14所创始校之一。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:established rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1740</dbpprop:established>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Philadelphia"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">University of Pennsylvania (Penn) er et privat universitet i Philadelphia, staten Pennsylvania i USA. Det ble grunnlagt i 1740 av Benjamin Franklin, og inngår i sammenslutningen av fremragende amerikanske universiteter – Ivy League. Wharton School er handelshøyskolen ved universitetet, og det er også egne skoler for medisin, veterinærmedisin, jus og kommunikasjon. Alle skolene er lokalisert på samme campus.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">The University of Pennsylvania (commonly referred to as Penn or UPenn) is a private, Ivy League university, located in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States. Penn considers itself the fourth-oldest institution of higher education in the United States, as well as the first university in the United States with both undergraduate and graduate studies. It is also one of the Colonial Colleges.</rdfs:comment>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.upenn.edu/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">펜실베이니아 대학교(University of Pennsylvania)는 흔히 유펜(UPenn)으로도 불리며 미국 펜실베이니아 주 필라델피아에 있는 연구 중심의 종합 사립대학이다. 1740년 설립된 이 학교는 미국에서 네 번째로 오래된 고등교육기관이며 아이비 리그(Ivy League)에 일원인 최상위권 명문대학이다. 조지프 와튼이 설립한 이 대학의 와튼 비즈니스 스쿨(Wharton Business School)은 미국에서 제일 오래되고 우수한 비즈니스 스쿨이다. 비즈니스 스쿨 외에도 마케팅, 경영학, 회계학, 재정학, 노동산업학, 경제학 등이 우수하다. 언어학과 인류학, 생의공학 분야도 뛰어나다. 펜실베이니아대학은 여러 종류의 이중학위 과정을 제공하고 있으며 엔지니어링을 전공하는 학생수도 많다. 와튼 비즈니스 스쿨과 엔지니어링 스쿨이 제공하는 경영학과 공학(Management and Technology)의 이중학위 과정은 엔지니어링과 비즈니스 분야를 둘 다 공부하고 싶어하는 학생들에게 유용하다. 대학 외에도 일반대학원과 의학, 간호, 법학, 사회복지, 디자인, 커뮤니케이션, 건축 등의 전문대학원이 있어 훌륭한 종합대학을 이루고 있다. 이들 각각의 (전문)대학원들은 미국 내 뿐만 아니라 세계적으로 최상위권에 속하며, 전 세계에서 매우 우수한 인재들이 입학을 하고 있다. 펜실베이니아대는 9,600명이 넘는 학부학생들과 10,100여명이 되는 대학원 학생들로 총 1만9,800여명이 공부하고 있다. 캠퍼스안에 120 여개가 넘는 빌딩들은 오래된 벽돌집에서부터 현대식 건물까지 섞여져 있다. 특히 푸른 가로수가 줄지어 있는 거리(Locust Walk)는 인상적이다. 펜실베이니아대학은 필라델피아의 중심에 위치해 있는데 캠퍼스와 시가지와의 경계선이 없어서 도시 자체가 대학같은 분위기를 풍긴다. 주말에는 필라델피아 시내를 중심으로 캠퍼스를 빠져나온 학생들로 인산 인해를 이룬다. 학생 및 교수을 포함해서 지금까지 총 26명의 노벨상 수상자들이 이 대학을 거쳐갔으며, 총 18명의 로즈 장학생을 배출했다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">宾夕法尼亚大学（University of Pennsylvania），位于美國賓夕法尼亞州的費城，是一所著名的私立研究型大學，八所常春藤盟校之一。学校创建于1740年，是美國第四古老的高等教育機構，也是美国第一所从事科学技术和人文教育的现代高等学校。美国《独立宣言》的9位签字者和《美国宪法》的11位签字者和该校有关。本杰明·富兰克林是学校的创建人。 宾夕法尼亚大学在艺术、人文、社会科学、商学、建筑与工程教育上处于领先地位，其中尤为知名的学科是商業学、法学与医学。学校拥有约4,500名教授，近10,000名全日制大學生与10,000多名研究生。2006年学校获得的科研经费达到6千6百多万美元，从事研究的人员包括约4,200名教职工，870名博士后，3,800名研究生与5,400多名技术人员。同时，学校每年的建设投入达到4亿美元以上，在常春藤盟校中名列前茅。 宾夕法尼亚大学还是美国大学联合会的14所创始校之一。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:country xml:lang="en">USA</dbpprop:country>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:motto xml:lang="en">Laws without morals are in vain</dbpedia-owl:motto>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">No se debe confundir esta universidad con la Universidad Estatal de Pensilvania, ubicada en State College University of Pennsylvania Universidad de Pensilvania220px Acrónimo Penn Alias Cuáqueros Lema «Leges sine moribus vanae»Latín«La Ley sin moral es vana» Tipo Universidad privada Fundación 1740 como Church and Charity School of Philadelphia Fundador Benjamin Franklin Localización Dirección &lt;/span&gt; Filadelfia, 20px Pensilvania, Bandera de los Estados Unidos Estados Unidos&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Academia&lt;/tr&gt; Estudiantes 19.265&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;  • Pregrado 10.047&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;  • Postgrado 9.218&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Colores académicos      Azul Pantone 288      Rojo Pantone 201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Colores deportivos      Azul Pantone 288      Rojo Pantone 201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Administración&lt;/tr&gt; Rector Amy Gutmann&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Afiliaciones Ivy League&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; http://www. </rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1740_establishments"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Đại học Pennsylvania</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:arwuW rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">14</dbpprop:arwuW>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpprop:image xml:lang="en">U_Pennsylvania_Seal.gif</dbpprop:image>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Morris_Arboretum"/>
    <dbpprop:arwuN rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">12</dbpprop:arwuN>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">University of Pennsylvania, známá také jenom jako Penn je jednou z nejslavnějších a nejrespektovanějších amerických soukromých univerzit, která sídlí ve městě Philadelphia ve státě Pensylvánie. Penn je členem Ivy League.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:campus xml:lang="en">Urban,  total: , University City campus; , New Bolton Center; , Morris Arboretum</dbpprop:campus>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:state xml:lang="en">autocollapse</dbpprop:state>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Pennsylvanian yliopisto (University of Pennsylvania; Penn on usein käytetty lyhenne; UPenn on myös oikein, mutta harvinaisempi) on yksityinen yliopisto Philadelphiassa, Pennsylvaniassa. Yliopiston mukaan se on neljänneksi vanhin korkeakoulu Yhdysvalloissa ja "Amerikan ensimmäinen yliopisto". Se on myös jäsen eliittiyliopistojen ryhmässä Ivy League. Yliopisto järjestää maailman vanhimman ja suurimman viestijuoksutapahtuman Penn Relaysin. Yliopiston perustaja on Benjamin Franklin. Yliopiston arvostetuimpia aloja ovat humanistiset tieteet, sosiaalitieteet, arkkitehtuuri ja kasvatustieteet. Lisäksi yliopisto on saanut tunnustusta lääketieteen, oikeustieteen ja kauppatieteen tiedekunnista. Lisäksi yliopistossa voi opiskella muun muassa eläinlääketiedettä, muotoilua ja teknillisiä tieteitä. Vuonna 2011 yliopisto arvioitiin Yhdysvaltojen 5th parhaaksi yliopistoksi. Aikaisimpina vuosina 2005-2006 yliopisto arvioitiin Yhdysvaltojen 4th parhaaksi yliopistoksi. Yliopiston kauppatieteellinen tiedekunta arvioitiin Yhdysvaltojen parhaaksi kauppatieteelliseksi tiedekunnaksi vuonna 2007. Yliopiston pääaineista muun muassa tietojenkäsittely, psykologia, espanjan kieli, biologia, taidehistoria, antropologia ja historia ovat erittäin tunnettuja ja arvostettuja. Vuonna 2011 yliopisto hyväksyi 12.3 % hakijoista. Hakijoita oli 31 659. Vuoden 2011 valinnat olivat tiukimmat sitten yliopiston historian. Edellisinä vuosina yliopistoon on päässyt noin 15-20 prosenttia hakijoista. Kaikista tarkimmin yliopisto valitsee oppilaat oikeustieteelliseen, lääketieteelliseen ja kauppatieteelliseen tiedekuntaan. Yliopiston opiskelijoista noin 51,3 % on naisia. Yliopistoon hakee vuosittain noin 2500 ulkomaalaista opiskelijaa, joista noin 20 % hyväksytään. Suurin osa ulkomaalaisista opiskelijoista, noin 50 prosenttia, tulee Aasiasta ja noin 14 % tulee Europasta. Yliopistosta ovat valmistuneet muun muassa William Henry Harrison, Donald Trump, Warren Buffet, Noam Chomsky, ja Safra Catz.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">University of Pennsylvania</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/University_of_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpprop:undergrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">10301</dbpprop:undergrad>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidade_da_Pensilvânia"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Philadelphia"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.07tds"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">L'Università della Pennsylvania (comunemente denominata Penn o UPenn), situata a Filadelfia, Pennsylvania, è una delle più antiche ed importanti università negli Stati Uniti. Insieme ad Harvard, Yale, Columbia, Princeton, Brown, Dartmouth College e Cornell forma la Ivy League, titolo che identifica i più prestigiosi atenei statunitensi. L'attuale rettore dell'Università della Pennsylvania è la professoressa Amy Gutmann.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:image rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1757</dbpprop:image>
    <dbpprop:titlestyle xml:lang="en">background:#990000;color:white;border:1px solid #011F5B;</dbpprop:titlestyle>
    <dbpprop:almaMater rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Hail,_Pennsylvania!"/>
    <dbpprop:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Amy_Gutmann"/>
    <dbpprop:forbes rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">52</dbpprop:forbes>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">The University of Pennsylvania (commonly referred to as Penn or UPenn) is a private, Ivy League university, located in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, United States. Penn considers itself the fourth-oldest institution of higher education in the United States, as well as the first university in the United States with both undergraduate and graduate studies. It is also one of the Colonial Colleges. Incorporated as The Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania, Penn is one of 14 founding members of the Association of American Universities. Benjamin Franklin, Penn's founder, advocated an educational program that focused as much on practical education for commerce and public service as on the classics and theology. Penn was one of the first academic institutions to follow a multidisciplinary model pioneered by several European universities, concentrating multiple "faculties" into one institution. It was also home to many other educational innovations. The first school of medicine in North America, the first collegiate business school and the first student union, were all born at Penn. Penn offers a broad range of academic departments, an extensive research enterprise and a number of community outreach and public service programs. It is particularly well known for its medical school, dental school, school of business, law school, communications school, nursing school, veterinary school, its social sciences and humanities programs, as well as its biomedical teaching and research capabilities. Its undergraduate programs are also among the most selective in the country (12.3% acceptance rate). One of Penn's most well known academic qualities is its emphasis on interdisciplinary education, which it promotes through numerous joint degree programs, research centers and professorships, a unified campus, and the ability for students to take classes from any of Penn's schools (the "One University Policy"). All of Penn's schools, alone or jointly, exhibit very high research activity. Penn is consistently included among the top five research universities in the US, and among the top research universities in the world, both in terms of quality and quantity of research. In fiscal year 2011, Penn topped the Ivy League in academic research spending with a $814 million budget, involving some 4,000 faculty, 1,100 postdoctoral fellows and 5,400 support staff/graduate assistants. As one of the most active and prolific research institutions, Penn is associated with several important innovations and discoveries in many fields of science and the humanities. Among them are the first general purpose electronic computer, the Rubella and Hepatitis B vaccines, Retin-A, cognitive therapy, conjoint analysis and others. Penn's academic and research programs are led by a large and highly productive faculty. In the last ten years alone 9 Penn faculty members or graduates have won a Nobel Prize. Over its long history the university has also produced a large volume of distinguished alumni. These include 12 heads of state (including one U.S. President), 3 United States Supreme Court justices, and supreme court justices of other states, founders of technology companies, international law firms, and global financial institutions, university presidents and 18 living billionaires.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:budget xml:lang="en">US$6.007 billion</dbpprop:budget>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_US_university_ranking"/>
    <dbpprop:image xml:lang="en">Hamilton Walk at the Perelman School of Medicine.jpg</dbpprop:image>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Multiple_image"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_university"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Uniwersytet Pensylwanii (ang. University of Pennsylvania, potocznie Penn lub UPenn) – prywatny uniwersytet w Stanach Zjednoczonych, działający w Filadelfii, w stanie Pensylwania, należący do tzw. Ligi Bluszczowej (Ivy League). Jest jednym z niewielu prywatnych uniwersytetów nazwanych imieniem stanu w którym się znajdują. Z tego powodu często jest mylony ze stanowym Uniwersytetem Stanu Pensylwania (potocznie Penn State).</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-university-noun-2"/>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ivy_League"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Education_in_Philadelphia,_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpprop:alt xml:lang="en">University of Pennsylvania Dental School</dbpprop:alt>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_Bolton_Center"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Middle_States_Association_of_Colleges_and_Schools"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/usDollar">6.58</dbpedia-owl:endowment>
    <dbpprop:usnwrNu rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">5</dbpprop:usnwrNu>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Пенсильванський університет або Університет Пенсильванії (англ. University of Pennsylvania) — університет в місті Філадельфія, штат Пенсильванія, заснований в 1740 Бенджаміном Франкліном. Пенсильванський університет — четвертий найстаріший вищий навчальний заклад у США, один з восьми членів асоціації найстаріших вузів країни Л́іга плющ́а. Народна назва унівеситету — Penn(Пенн) або UPenn.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:postgrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">11028</dbpprop:postgrad>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/펜실베이니아_대학교"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">University of Pennsylvania, známá také jenom jako Penn je jednou z nejslavnějších a nejrespektovanějších amerických soukromých univerzit, která sídlí ve městě Philadelphia ve státě Pensylvánie. Penn je členem Ivy League.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">University of Pennsylvania Dental School</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">常に米国大学ランキングでトップ3またはトップ5にランクインし、世界大学ランキングではトップ10に入り、米国を代表する名門大学として不動の地位を保っている。アイビーリーグに属し、大学の愛称はPennまたはUPenn、日本人の間ではユーペン、ペン大と略称される。モットーは Laws Without Morals are Useless（良識のない法は無益である: Leges Sine Moribus Vanae）。</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">University of Pennsylvania</rdfs:label>
    <foaf:nick xml:lang="en">Quakers</foaf:nick>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">21329</dbpedia-owl:numberOfStudents>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Università_della_Pennsylvania"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://el.dbpedia.org/resource/Πανεπιστήμιο_της_Πενσυλβάνια"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">宾夕法尼亚大学</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">De Universiteit van Pennsylvania (University of Pennsylvania), ook wel bekend als UPenn of Penn, is een universiteit in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. De universiteit behoort tot de Ivy League en geldt als een elite-universiteit. Een van de meest toonaangevende onderdelen van de universiteit is de Wharton School, een businessschool. De Universiteit van Pennsylvania is een private university, niet te verwarren met de staatsuniversiteit Pennsylvania State University.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_university"/>
    <dbpprop:image xml:lang="en">PennDentalSchool.jpg</dbpprop:image>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Die University of Pennsylvania (Penn) ist eine private Forschungsuniversität in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania. Die Penn ist eine der renommiertesten und ältesten Universitäten der Vereinigten Staaten von Amerika. Sie ist Mitglied in der Association of American Universities und einer Sportliga acht amerikanischer Elite-Unis, der Ivy League. Penn ist mit rund 13.240 Angestellten der größte private Arbeitgeber in Philadelphia.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:academicStaff rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">4246</dbpprop:academicStaff>
    <dbpprop:provost xml:lang="en">Vincent Price</dbpprop:provost>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Eastern_Pennsylvania_Rugby_Union"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/University_of_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpprop:imageAlt xml:lang="en">Arms of the University of Pennsylvania</dbpprop:imageAlt>
    <dbpprop:width xml:lang="en">(150 * 2039 / 1138) round 0</dbpprop:width>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">39.953885 -75.193048</grs:point>
    <dbpprop:caption rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1757</dbpprop:caption>
    <dbpprop:state rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pennsylvania"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Universitas Pennsylvaniensis</foaf:name>
    <dbpprop:mottoeng xml:lang="en">Laws without morals are in vain</dbpprop:mottoeng>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/University108286163"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.upenn.edu/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:state rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Viện Đại học Pennsylvania (tên gọi tắt là Penn hoặc UPenn) là viện đại học tư thục nằm tại thành phố Philadelphia, thuộc bang Pennsylvania, Hoa Kỳ. Penn là một thành viên của Ivy League với thế mạnh về các ngành khoa học cơ bản, nhân chủng học, luật học, y dược, giáo dục học, kỹ thuật và kinh doanh. Chín người ký tên Tuyên ngôn Độc lập Hoa Kỳ và mười một người ký vào Hiến pháp Hoa Kỳ có liên hệ với viện đại học này. Benjamin Franklin, người sáng lập Penn, ủng hộ một chương trình giáo dục tập trung nhiều vào các giáo dục thực tiễn cho thương mại và quản lý nhà nước cũng như các ngành kinh điển và thần học. Penn là một trong những học viện đầu tiên đi theo một khuôn mẫu đa ngành được phát triển bởi các viện đại học châu Âu, tập trung nhiều "trường" (faculty) dưới cùng một viện đại học.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Universidad_de_Pensilvania"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">University of Pennsylvania</foaf:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Universities_and_colleges_in_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpprop:caption rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1933</dbpprop:caption>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Пенсильванский университет — частный исследовательский университет США, расположенный в Филадельфии, штат Пенсильвания. Основан в 1740 году Бенджамином Франклином. Пенсильванский университет — одно из старейших высших учебных заведений и первый университет в США, а также один из 9-и колониальных колледжей, основанных до подписания декларации независимости.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:imageSize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">200</dbpprop:imageSize>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">No se debe confundir esta universidad con la Universidad Estatal de Pensilvania, ubicada en State College University of Pennsylvania Universidad de Pensilvania220px Acrónimo Penn Alias Cuáqueros Lema «Leges sine moribus vanae»Latín«La Ley sin moral es vana» Tipo Universidad privada Fundación 1740 como Church and Charity School of Philadelphia Fundador Benjamin Franklin Localización Dirección &lt;/span&gt; Filadelfia, 20px Pensilvania, Bandera de los Estados Unidos Estados Unidos&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Academia&lt;/tr&gt; Estudiantes 19.265&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;  • Pregrado 10.047&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;  • Postgrado 9.218&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Colores académicos      Azul Pantone 288      Rojo Pantone 201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Colores deportivos      Azul Pantone 288      Rojo Pantone 201&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Administración&lt;/tr&gt; Rector Amy Gutmann&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; Afiliaciones Ivy League&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt; http://www. upenn. edu&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt; La Universidad de Pensilvania (University of Pennsylvania), comúnmente llamada Penn o UPenn, ubicada en Filadelfia, Pensilvania, Estados Unidos es una de las universidades más prestigiosas del mundo. Es una de las ocho universidades pertenecientes a la Ivy League y también forma parte de las Universidades Coloniales de Estados Unidos. Fue fundada en 1740 por Benjamin Franklin como Iglesia y Colegio Caritativo de Filadelfia (Church and Charity School of Philadelphia). La universidad, una entidad privada sin fines de lucro, es sede de la prestigiosa Wharton Business School y de la primera escuela de medicina de los Estados Unidos. Por ser la primera institución americana en tener más de una facultad, y por haber sido la primera en obtener reconocimiento oficial como universidad, es considerada técnicamente la primera universidad de los Estados Unidos.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/University"/>
    <dbpprop:motto xml:lang="en">Leges sine moribus vanae</dbpprop:motto>
    <dbpprop:athletics rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/National_Collegiate_Athletic_Association"/>
    <dbpprop:students rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">21329</dbpprop:students>
    <dbpprop:affiliations rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Association_of_American_Universities"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Navboxes"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Gothic_Revival_architecture_in_Pennsylvania"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/University_of_Pennsylvania"/>
    <dbpprop:alt rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1757</dbpprop:alt>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.upenn.edu/"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">University of Pennsylvania</dbpprop:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Educational_institutions_established_in_the_1740s"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:affiliation rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Consortium_on_Financing_Higher_Education"/>
    <dbpprop:nickname rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Penn_Quakers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">L'université de Pennsylvanie (en anglais, University of Pennsylvania, souvent abrégée en Penn ou UPenn) est une université privée américaine dont le siège est à Philadelphie. Elle fait partie de la Ivy League, association informelle regroupant les huit universités les plus anciennes et les plus célèbres des États-Unis. C'est en particulier là-bas qu'a été créé l'ENIAC, le premier ordinateur. Penn est l'une des universités fondatrices de l'Association des universités américaines.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">University of Pennsylvania (vanligtvis kallat Penn eller UPenn), är ett universitet i Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, USA.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Пенсильванський університет</rdfs:label>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">39.9539</geo:lat>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">L'Università della Pennsylvania (comunemente denominata Penn o UPenn), situata a Filadelfia, Pennsylvania, è una delle più antiche ed importanti università negli Stati Uniti. Insieme ad Harvard, Yale, Columbia, Princeton, Brown, Dartmouth College e Cornell forma la Ivy League, titolo che identifica i più prestigiosi atenei statunitensi. L'attuale rettore dell'Università della Pennsylvania è la professoressa Amy Gutmann.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sws.geonames.org/4561872/"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Пенсильванський університет або Університет Пенсильванії (англ. University of Pennsylvania) — університет в місті Філадельфія, штат Пенсильванія, заснований в 1740 Бенджаміном Франкліном. Пенсильванський університет — четвертий найстаріший вищий навчальний заклад у США, один з восьми членів асоціації найстаріших вузів країни Л́іга плющ́а. Народна назва унівеситету — Penn(Пенн) або UPenn. Незважаючи на назву, університет є приватним і його іноді плутають з Державним університетом штату Пенсильванія (Pennsylvania State University), розташованим у місті Стейт Коледж або з Філадельфійським університетом (Philadelphia University). Бенджамін Франклін, засновник Penn, виступав за впровадження освітніх програми, які були б більше зосереджені на практичному навчанні у сферах розвитку торгівлі та державної служби, і які б стали новим стандартом освіти. Пенсильванський університет був одних з перших наукових закладів, що запровадив міждисциплінарну модель, що вже була прийнята передовими європейськими університетами, зосередивши декілька «факультетів» (теологічний, класичний, медичний) в одній установі. Нині Penn пропонує широкий спектр наукових відділень, багатосторонні дослідження підприємництва, низку державних програм допомоги та загальнодоступних програм обслуговування. Пенсильванський університет особливо добре відомий завдяки своїм медичній, стоматологічній, юридичній школам, бізнес-школі, школі медсестер, ветеринарній школі, своїми соціальними науками, гуманітарними програмами, біомедичним викладанням та науково-дослідницьким потенціалом. Університет є одним з вузів країни, програми бакалаврату якого абітурієнти вибирають найчастіше. Школа бізнесу Уортона (англ. Wharton School), одна з найпрестижніших і найвідоміших бізнес-шкіл світу, є частиною Пенсильванського університету. При університеті з кінця XIX століття існує Музей археології та антропології Пенсильванського університету.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:caption xml:lang="en">Perelman School of Medicine</dbpprop:caption>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-75.193</geo:long>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">L'université de Pennsylvanie (en anglais, University of Pennsylvania, souvent abrégée en Penn ou UPenn) est une université privée américaine dont le siège est à Philadelphie. Elle fait partie de la Ivy League, association informelle regroupant les huit universités les plus anciennes et les plus célèbres des États-Unis. C'est en particulier là-bas qu'a été créé l'ENIAC, le premier ordinateur. Penn est l'une des universités fondatrices de l'Association des universités américaines.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:align xml:lang="en">left</dbpprop:align>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Viện Đại học Pennsylvania (tên gọi tắt là Penn hoặc UPenn) là viện đại học tư thục nằm tại thành phố Philadelphia, thuộc bang Pennsylvania, Hoa Kỳ. Penn là một thành viên của Ivy League với thế mạnh về các ngành khoa học cơ bản, nhân chủng học, luật học, y dược, giáo dục học, kỹ thuật và kinh doanh. Chín người ký tên Tuyên ngôn Độc lập Hoa Kỳ và mười một người ký vào Hiến pháp Hoa Kỳ có liên hệ với viện đại học này.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Uniwersytet Pensylwanii (ang. University of Pennsylvania, potocznie Penn lub UPenn) – prywatny uniwersytet w Stanach Zjednoczonych, działający w Filadelfii, w stanie Pensylwania, należący do tzw. Ligi Bluszczowej (Ivy League). Jest jednym z niewielu prywatnych uniwersytetów nazwanych imieniem stanu w którym się znajdują. Z tego powodu często jest mylony ze stanowym Uniwersytetem Stanu Pensylwania (potocznie Penn State). University of Pennsylvania utrzymuje współpracę zagraniczną w dziedzinie wymiany naukowej i studentów z wieloma ośrodkami akademickimi na świecie, w tym także z Polską.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">University of Pennsylvania</rdfs:label>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
