<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
   xmlns:grs="http://www.georss.org/georss/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Vassar_College">
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/EducationalOrganization"/>
    <dbpprop:imageSize rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">150</dbpprop:imageSize>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Vassar College</rdfs:label>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:National_Association_of_Independent_Colleges_and_Universities_members"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#integer">2450</dbpedia-owl:numberOfUndergraduateStudents>
    <dbpedia-owl:mascot xml:lang="en">Brewer</dbpedia-owl:mascot>
    <foaf:homepage rdf:resource="http://www.vassar.edu"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/UniversitiesAndCollegesInNewYork"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Vassar College</dbpprop:name>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-university-noun-2"/>
    <dbpprop:website rdf:resource="http://www.vassar.edu"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/b8/Vassar_College_Seal.png/200px-Vassar_College_Seal.png"/>
    <grs:point xml:lang="en">41.68686666666667 -73.8951888888889</grs:point>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vassar_College?oldid=494259890"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Suburb"/>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_school"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Organisation"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Vassar College je známá americká elitní vyšší škola ve městě Poughkeepsie, které se nachází 100 km severně od New Yorku. Vassar býval vždy jedním ze symbolů tzv. bílé anglosaské protestantské elity USA (tzv. WASP). Škola byla založena v roce 1861 Matthewem Vassarem jako škola pro dívky, ale od roku 1969 se v rámci snah o společné (koedukované) vzdělávání na soukromých vyšších školách stal jednou z vedoucích škol poskytujících společné vzdělávání pro obě pohlaví.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Educational_institutions_established_in_1861"/>
    <geo:long rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">-73.8952</geo:long>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Das Vassar College ist eine US-amerikanische Elitehochschule in Poughkeepsie, 100 km nördlich von New York City. Vassar war immer eines der Symbole der sogenannten weißen angelsächsischen protestantischen Elite der USA, auch bekannt als WASP. Das College wurde in diesem Sinn in einem Atemzug mit Harvard, Princeton und Yale genannt.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/University108286163"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.madsvassarblog.com/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Vassar_College"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Former_women's_universities_and_colleges_in_the_United_States"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.opengis.net/gml/_Feature"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Vassar_College"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Middle_States_Association_of_Colleges_and_Schools"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour xml:lang="en">Rose and Gray</dbpedia-owl:officialSchoolColour>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Vassar_College"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Vassar_College"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Das Vassar College ist eine US-amerikanische Elitehochschule in Poughkeepsie, 100 km nördlich von New York City. Vassar war immer eines der Symbole der sogenannten weißen angelsächsischen protestantischen Elite der USA, auch bekannt als WASP. Das College wurde in diesem Sinn in einem Atemzug mit Harvard, Princeton und Yale genannt. Es wurde 1861 von Matthew Vassar als College für Frauen gegründet, 1969 jedoch im Rahmen der Koedukationsbestrebungen an privaten Hochschulen Vorreiter bei der gemeinsamen Ausbildung von Männern und Frauen. Das Vassar College gehört mit sechs anderen Colleges für Frauen zu den „Seven Sisters“-Colleges. Der Campus des Vassar Colleges ist ein 4 km² großes Areal, auf dem auch die Mehrheit der etwa 2400 Studenten lebt. Die dortige Bibliothek ist bekannt für ihre Sammlung von Quellen Albert Einsteins und Elizabeth Bishops.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catharine_Bond_Hill"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Vassar College is a private, coeducational liberal arts college in the town of Poughkeepsie, New York, in the United States. The Vassar campus comprises over 1,000 acres (4.0 km) and more than 100 buildings, including four National Historic Landmarks, ranging in style from Collegiate Gothic to International, designed over the course of the college’s history by a range of prominent architects, including James Renwick Jr. , Eero Saarinen, Marcel Breuer, and Cesar Pelli.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:mascot xml:lang="en">Brewer</dbpprop:mascot>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/b8/Vassar_College_Seal.png"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">リベラル・アーツ・カレッジ。著名女子大学群であるセブンシスターズの一校として設立、1969年に男女共学化を実施。各誌の大学ランキングにおいて、最難関校またリベラル・アーツ教育のトップ大学のひとつとして数えられる。</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Seven_Sister_Colleges"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/University"/>
    <geo:lat rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#float">41.6869</geo:lat>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Members_of_the_Annapolis_Group"/>
    <dbpprop:campus xml:lang="en">Urban, suburban, park; 1,250 acres</dbpprop:campus>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://athletics.vassar.edu/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Vassar College est une université privée mixte, située à Poughkeepsie, dans l'État de New York. Bien qu'à l'origine université féminine, elle est aujourd’hui la seule des universités mixtes faisant partie des Sept Sœurs. L'université a été fondée en 1861 par Matthew Vassar, dans la vallée de Hudson, à environ 100 kilomètres au nord de New York. La première personne qui fit officiellement partie du corps enseignant fut l'astronome Maria Mitchell, en 1865.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/CollegeOrUniversity"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Vassar_College"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_university"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Park"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Vassar College</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:undergrad rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">2450</dbpprop:undergrad>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Vassar College</foaf:name>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Vassar College</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FormerWomen'sUniversitiesAndCollegesInTheUnitedStates"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Vassar College je známá americká elitní vyšší škola ve městě Poughkeepsie, které se nachází 100 km severně od New Yorku. Vassar býval vždy jedním ze symbolů tzv. bílé anglosaské protestantské elity USA (tzv. WASP). Škola byla založena v roce 1861 Matthewem Vassarem jako škola pro dívky, ale od roku 1969 se v rámci snah o společné (koedukované) vzdělávání na soukromých vyšších školách stal jednou z vedoucích škol poskytujících společné vzdělávání pro obě pohlaví. Vassar College patří k dalším šesti vyšším školám pro ženy, tzv.. Na škole studuje přes 2400 studentů.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Mixed-sex_education"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Vassar College est une université privée mixte, située à Poughkeepsie, dans l'État de New York. Bien qu'à l'origine université féminine, elle est aujourd’hui la seule des universités mixtes faisant partie des Sept Sœurs. L'université a été fondée en 1861 par Matthew Vassar, dans la vallée de Hudson, à environ 100 kilomètres au nord de New York. La première personne qui fit officiellement partie du corps enseignant fut l'astronome Maria Mitchell, en 1865. L'université est souvent prisée pour la beauté de son campus, un espace de 40 hectares de terrain, et possède en outre un jardin botanique. La grande majorité des étudiants vivent sur le campus. Bien qu'à l'origine établissement de filles, l'université devient mixte en 1969, après le refus d'une proposition de fusion de l'établissement avec celui de Yale. L'établissement a cependant gardé son statut d'université privée d'art prestigieuse, et sa réputation concernant l'ambiance sociale qui y règne. La bibliothèque rénovée est exceptionnellement fournie et riche par rapport à la taille de l'université. Y figurent des collections spéciales d'Albert Einstein et Elizabeth Bishop. Sur le campus, se trouve le musée Frances Lehman Loeb Art Center. Les différentes œuvres exposées datent de l'Antiquité à nos jours. Parmi les Européens représentés, il y a des tableaux de Pablo Picasso, Paul Cézanne, Balthus et Gustave Doré. L’entrée est gratuite. Vassar College est classé comme l'une des meilleures universités d'art par le magazine américain U.S. News &amp; World Report.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Vassar College is a private, coeducational liberal arts college in the town of Poughkeepsie, New York, in the United States. The Vassar campus comprises over 1,000 acres (4.0 km) and more than 100 buildings, including four National Historic Landmarks, ranging in style from Collegiate Gothic to International, designed over the course of the college’s history by a range of prominent architects, including James Renwick Jr. , Eero Saarinen, Marcel Breuer, and Cesar Pelli. In a designated arboretum, the campus features more than 200 species of trees, a native plant preserve, and a 400-acre (1.6 km) ecological preserve.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:country rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Private_school"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/University"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Vassar_College"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Universities_and_colleges_in_New_York"/>
    <dbpprop:colors xml:lang="en">Rose and Gray</dbpprop:colors>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Vassar College es una universidad privada situada en el pueblo neoyorquino de Poughkeepsie en los Estados Unidos. Fue fundada por el cervecero Matthew Vassar en 1861 como una universidad solo para mujeres, convirtiéndose en la primera institución de las Siete Escuelas Hermanas en ser titulada, siendo estas contrapartes históricas a las universidades Ivy League para hombres. Esta condición cambió cuando el cuerpo estudiantil pasó a ser de sexo mixto en 1969, año en que Vassar rechazó la oferta de la Universidad de Yale (su institución hermana) de fusionarse. Todavía retiene su estatus como miembra de las Siete Escuelas Hermanas.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:imageName xml:lang="en">Vassar College Seal.png</dbpprop:imageName>
    <dbpprop:established rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">1861</dbpprop:established>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Vassar College er en privat, eliteskole på høgskolenivå som ligger i Poughkeepsie, New York, i USA. Vassar ble grunnlagt som en skole bare for kvinner i 1861, men begynte å ta imot mannlige studenter i 1969. Over 2400 studenter studerer ved Vassar College hvert år. Omtrent 60% av disse kommer fra offentlige videregående skoler, og de resterende 40% av studentene kommer fra private skoler. Skolen består av over hundre bygninger. Frances D. Fergusson satt som direktør for Vassar College i to tiår, før hun pensjonerte seg våren 2006, og ble etterfulgt av Catharine Bond Hill, tidligere prost ved Williams College.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ヴァッサー大学"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:president rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Catharine_Bond_Hill"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.google.com/books?vid=ISBN0870238698&amp;id=Z3qWLyDZ8PsC&amp;pg=PP1&amp;lpg=PP1&amp;ots=xMmu_yuuHV&amp;dq=alma+mater&amp;sig=N7RcPpZKbQvPM1m5ohSuIcu_KxU#PPP1,M1"/>
    <dbpprop:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poughkeepsie_(town),_New_York"/>
    <dbpprop:state rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://vassarmedia.blogspot.com/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Vassar College é uma das mais antigas, tradicionais e renomadas instituições privadas mista de ensino e de artes, de alto nível dos Estados Unidos. É situada em Poughkeepsie, cem quilômetros ao norte da cidade de Nova Iorque, Estados Unidos. Fundado em 1861 por Matthew Vassar como faculdade exclusivamente para mulheres. Foi a primeira universidade para mulheres nos Estados Unidos que não foi de religião.</rdfs:comment>
    <geo:geometry rdf:datatype="http://www.openlinksw.com/schemas/virtrdf#Geometry">POINT(-73.8952 41.6869)</geo:geometry>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vassar_College"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Universities_and_colleges_in_Dutchess_County,_New_York"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Vassar College é uma das mais antigas, tradicionais e renomadas instituições privadas mista de ensino e de artes, de alto nível dos Estados Unidos. É situada em Poughkeepsie, cem quilômetros ao norte da cidade de Nova Iorque, Estados Unidos. Fundado em 1861 por Matthew Vassar como faculdade exclusivamente para mulheres. Foi a primeira universidade para mulheres nos Estados Unidos que não foi de religião.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:city rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Poughkeepsie_(town),_New_York"/>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Vassar_College"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:country rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/United_States"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Organization"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/SevenSisterColleges"/>
    <dbpprop:logo rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">150</dbpprop:logo>
    <dbpprop:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/usDollar">8.15E8</dbpprop:endowment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:endowment rdf:datatype="http://dbpedia.org/datatype/usDollar">8.15E8</dbpedia-owl:endowment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.vassar.edu"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">リベラル・アーツ・カレッジ。著名女子大学群であるセブンシスターズの一校として設立、1969年に男女共学化を実施。各誌の大学ランキングにおいて、最難関校またリベラル・アーツ教育のトップ大学のひとつとして数えられる。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.01ljpm"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/EduCAtionalInstitutionsEstablishedIn1861"/>
    <dbpprop:faculty rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">270</dbpprop:faculty>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/EducationalInstitution"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:campus rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Urban_area"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.vassar.edu/"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rwHJyepwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://vcencyclopedia.vassar.edu/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Vassar College er en privat, eliteskole på høgskolenivå som ligger i Poughkeepsie, New York, i USA. Vassar ble grunnlagt som en skole bare for kvinner i 1861, men begynte å ta imot mannlige studenter i 1969. Over 2400 studenter studerer ved Vassar College hvert år. Omtrent 60% av disse kommer fra offentlige videregående skoler, og de resterende 40% av studentene kommer fra private skoler. Skolen består av over hundre bygninger. Frances D.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:state rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/New_York"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Vassar College es una universidad privada situada en el pueblo neoyorquino de Poughkeepsie en los Estados Unidos. Fue fundada por el cervecero Matthew Vassar en 1861 como una universidad solo para mujeres, convirtiéndose en la primera institución de las Siete Escuelas Hermanas en ser titulada, siendo estas contrapartes históricas a las universidades Ivy League para hombres.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
