<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns7="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Wilson_Harris">
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Sir Theodore Wilson Harris est un écrivain, essayiste et poète guyanien, né le 24 mars 1921. Il a écrit Le Palais du paon. Il a été fait Chevalier le 12 juin 2010, pour services rendus à la littérature.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.postcolonialweb.org/caribbean/harris/harrisov.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1921-03-24</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fellows_of_the_Royal_Society_of_Literature"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Knights_Bachelor"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Sir Theodore Wilson Harris (born 24 March 1921) is a Guyanese writer. He initially wrote poetry, but has since become a well-known novelist and essayist. His writing style is often said to be abstract and densely metaphorical, and his subject matter wide-ranging. Wilson Harris was born in New Amsterdam in what was then called British Guiana.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfQuEEn'sCollege,Guyana"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Sir Theodore Wilson Harris (born 24 March 1921) is a Guyanese writer. He initially wrote poetry, but has since become a well-known novelist and essayist. His writing style is often said to be abstract and densely metaphorical, and his subject matter wide-ranging. Wilson Harris was born in New Amsterdam in what was then called British Guiana. After studying at Queen's College in the capital of Guyana, Georgetown, Harris became a government surveyor, before taking up a career as lecturer and writer. The knowledge of the savannas and rain forests he gained during his time as a surveyor formed the setting for many of his books, with the Guyanese landscape dominating his fiction. Harris came to England in 1959 and published his first novel Palace of the Peacock in 1960. This became the first of a quartet of novels, The Guyana Quartet, which includes The Far Journey of Oudin (1961), The Whole Armour (1962), and The Secret Ladder (1963). He subsequently wrote the Carnival trilogy: Carnival (1985), The Infinite Rehearsal (1987), and The Four Banks of the River of Space (1990). His most recent novels include Jonestown (1996), which tells of the mass-suicide of followers of cult leader Jim Jones, The Dark Jester (2001), his latest semi-autobiographical novel, The Mask of the Beggar (2003), and The Ghost of Memory (2006). Harris also writes non-fiction and critical essays and has been awarded honorary doctorates by several universities, including the University of the West Indies (1984) and the University of Liège (2001). He has twice won the Guyana Prize for Literature. Harris was knighted in the 2010 Birthday Honours.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Harris</foaf:surname>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Wilson Harris ist ein guyanischer Schriftsteller, der vor allem für seine Romane bekannt ist. Daneben publiziert er auch Lyrik und Essays.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Wilson</foaf:givenName>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Living_people"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Wilson Harris</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://caribbeanreviewofbooks.com/subject/wilson-harris/"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Wilson Harris on guyanalainen kirjailija. Hän aloitti runoilijana, mutta on sittemmin saanut mainetta romaaneillaan ja esseistinä. Hän on lisäksi julkaissut novelleja. Harris syntyi New Amsterdamissa. Hän opiskeli Queen's Collegessa maansa pääkaupungissa Georgetownissa. Hän saapui Englantiin vuonna 1959 ja julkaisi ensimmäisen romaaninsa Palace of the Peacockin vuonna 1960. Hänen myöhempiin romaaneihinsa kuuluvat mm.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Wilson Harris</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.hrc.utexas.edu/research/fa/harris.wilson.html"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Wilson Harris</foaf:name>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Wilson_Harris"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.09n_v2"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Wilson_Harris"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.L3.ulg.ac.be/harris"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">119132478</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">24</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Sir Theodore Wilson Harris est un écrivain, essayiste et poète guyanien, né le 24 mars 1921. Il a écrit Le Palais du paon. Il a été fait Chevalier le 12 juin 2010, pour services rendus à la littérature.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/GuyaneseWriters"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Wilson Harris on guyanalainen kirjailija. Hän aloitti runoilijana, mutta on sittemmin saanut mainetta romaaneillaan ja esseistinä. Hän on lisäksi julkaissut novelleja. Harris syntyi New Amsterdamissa. Hän opiskeli Queen's Collegessa maansa pääkaupungissa Georgetownissa. Hän saapui Englantiin vuonna 1959 ja julkaisi ensimmäisen romaaninsa Palace of the Peacockin vuonna 1960. Hänen myöhempiin romaaneihinsa kuuluvat mm. The Eye of the Scarecrow sekä Jim Jonesin johtamaan joukkoitsemurhaan pohjautuva Jonestown. Harris nimettiin vuonna 1984 Länsi-Intian yliopiston ja vuonna 2001 Liègen yliopiston kunniatohtoriksi.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1921_births"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Guyanese_writers"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Harris, Wilson</dbpprop:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/LivingPeople"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FellowsOfTheRoyalSocietyOfLiterature"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Wilson Harris ist ein guyanischer Schriftsteller, der vor allem für seine Romane bekannt ist. Daneben publiziert er auch Lyrik und Essays.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Wilson_Harris"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_Queen's_College,_Guyana"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://books.guardian.co.uk/review/story/0,,1972887,00.html"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilson_Harris"/>
    <ns7:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wilson_Harris?oldid=494321875"/>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
