<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rdf:RDF
   xmlns:dbpedia-owl="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/"
   xmlns:dbpprop="http://dbpedia.org/property/"
   xmlns:dcterms="http://purl.org/dc/terms/"
   xmlns:foaf="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/"
   xmlns:ns8="http://www.w3.org/ns/prov#"
   xmlns:owl="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#"
   xmlns:rdf="http://www.w3.org/1999/02/22-rdf-syntax-ns#"
   xmlns:rdfs="http://www.w3.org/2000/01/rdf-schema#"
   xmlns:skos="http://www.w3.org/2004/02/skos/core#"
>
  <rdf:Description rdf:about="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka">
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="en">Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka (born 13 July 1934) is a Nigerian writer, notable especially as a playwright and poet; he was awarded the 1986 Nobel Prize in Literature, the first African in Africa and the diaspora to be so honoured. Soyinka was born into a Yoruba family in Abeokuta. After study in Nigeria and the UK, he worked with the Royal Court Theatre in London. He went on to write plays that were produced in both countries, in theatres and on radio. He took an active role in Nigeria's political history and its struggle for independence from Great Britain. In 1965, he seized the Western Nigeria Broadcasting Service studio and broadcast a demand for the cancellation of the Western Nigeria Regional Elections. In 1967 during the Nigerian Civil War, he was arrested by the federal government of General Yakubu Gowon and put in solitary confinement for two years. Soyinka has strongly criticized many Nigerian military dictators, as well as other political tyrannies, including the Mugabe regime in Zimbabwe. Much of his writing has been concerned with "the oppressive boot and the irrelevance of the colour of the foot that wears it". During the regime of General Sani Abacha (1993–1998), Soyinka escaped from Nigeria via the "Nadeco Route" on motorcycle. Living abroad, mainly in the United States, he was a professor first at Cornell University and then at Emory University in Atlanta, where in 1996 he was appointed Robert W. Woodruff Professor of the Arts. Abacha proclaimed a death sentence against him "in absentia". With civilian rule restored to Nigeria in 1999, Soyinka returned to his nation. He has also taught at Oxford, Harvard and Yale. From 1975 to 1999, he was a Professor of Comparative Literature at the Obafemi Awolowo University, then called the University of Ife. With civilian rule restored in 1999, he was made professor emeritus. Soyinka has been a Professor of Creative Writing at the University of Nevada, Las Vegas. In the fall of 2007 he was appointed Professor in Residence at Loyola Marymount University in Los Angeles, California, US.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_dramatists_and_playwrights"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/africabeyond/africanarts/18991.shtml"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pt">Wole Soyinka é um escritor nigeriano. Foi agraciado com o Nobel de Literatura de 1986. Muitos o consideram o dramaturgo mais notável da África. Soyinka nasceu em uma família humilde de origem iorubá em Abeokuta, Nigéria. Ele fez o primário escolar em Abeokuta e o secundário no Government College, em Ibadan. Soyinka fez faculdade na University College, em Ibadan, e na University of Leeds (1954-1957), na Inglaterra, onde ele se formou com menção honrosa em Literatura inglesa. Ele trabalhou no Teatro da corte real (Royal Court Theater) em Londres antes de retornar a Nigéria para se dedicar ao estudo da dramaturgia africana. Soyinka lecionou nas universidade de Lagos e Ife (tornando-se professor de Literatura comparada nesta instituição de ensino em 1975). Soyinka participou ativamente na história política da Nigéria. Em 1967, durante a Guerra civil nigeriana, ele foi preso pelo Governo federal mantido em confinamento solitário na prisão por suas tentativas de mediar a paz entre os partidos em guerra. Na prisão ele escreveu poemas que mais tarde viriam a ser publicados em uma coleção sob o título Poems from Prison. Soyinka foi liberado vinte e dois meses mais tarde após haver se formado uma conscientização internacional sobre a sua situação. Mais tarde ele recontou a sua experiência no confinamento em um livro: The Man Died: Prison Notes. Soyinka tem criticado abertamente as administrações da Nigéria e de tiranias políticas mundo afora, inclusive fez denúncias contra o regime de Mugabe de Zimbabwe. Muitos de seus escritos tratam do que ele chama de "the oppressive boot and the irrelevance of the colour of the foot that wears it", ou seja, parafraseando: o coturno opressivo e a irrelevância da cor do pé que a calça. Essas formas de pensar e de se expressar tem causado grande risco de morte ao autor, especialmente durante o governo do ditador nigeriano Sani Abacha. Durante a ditadura do General Abacha, Soyinka se retirou de seu país de origem em exílio voluntário (passando a maioria desse tempo nos Estados Unidos onde lecionou na University of Emory, na cidade de Atlanta. Quando do retorno do governo civil na Nigéria, em 1999, Soyinka aceitou emérito da Ife (agora Obafemi Awolowo University, mas somente com a condição de que nenhum dos ex generais do regime prévio jamais fossem designados como chanceller da universidade no futuro. Após algum tempo na África, ele passou a ocupar a cadeira Elias Ghanem Professor of Creative Writing no Departamento de inglês da University of Nevada, na cidade de Las Vegas, Estados Unidos.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="cs">Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka je anglicky píšící nigerijský spisovatel, nositel Nobelovy ceny za literaturu z roku 1986.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://fr.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Loyola_Marymount_University"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:influencedBy rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Yor%C3%B9b%C3%A1_religion"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="vi">Wole Soyinka (tên thật là Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka; sinh ngày 13 tháng 7 năm 1934) là nhà văn, nhà thơ, nhà viết kịch người Nigeria đoạt giải Nobel Văn học năm 1986.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <skos:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Comparative_literature"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="ca">Wole Soyinka</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="hu">Wole Soyinka joruba származású, főleg angol nyelven publikáló Nobel-díjas nigériai regényíró. Emellett Nigériában és Angliában is elismert színházi személyiség.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd xml:lang="de">118615807</dbpedia-owl:individualisedPnd>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ko">아킨완데 올루월레 "월레" 소잉카는 나이지리아의 소설가, 시인, 극작가이다. 1986년 〈해설자〉라는 소설로 아프리카 출신으로서는 처음으로 노벨 문학상을 수상했다. 소앙카는 요루바 족 출신으로 오군 주의 아베오쿠타에서 태어났다. 영어로 글을 쓰면서, 요루바 족의 종교, 철학, 언어를 소개시켰다. 1965년 식민지주의, 인간의 책임과 관련된 〈길〉이라는 연극을 만들었는 데, 이 작품은 하류층과 중류층 간의 관계, 요루바 족의 전통적 신앙과 기독교 간의 관계를 다루는 이야기이다. 유럽의 식민지주의를 보여주는 〈콩기의 추수〉와 〈거인들의 연극〉 등의 연극을 만들기도 했다. 이 극작들에서 주목할 점은 독재정치를 인정하는 아프리카 사회 안의 힘을 보여준다는 것이다. 1967년 나이지리아 정부는 소잉카가 나라 안의 내전을 막으려한다는 이유로 그를 체포하였다. 징역 2년을 보낸 후, 〈사람이 죽다:소잉카의 교도소 기록〉을 썼는 데, 이 책은 그가 어떻게 징역살이를 견디어낼 수 있었는가를 보여준다. 소잉카는 나이지리아의 사회, 정치적인 문제를 분석한 것으로도 유명했다.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.guardian.co.uk/books/2002/nov/02/theatre.artsfeatures"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="pl">Wole Soyinka – dramaturg, prozaik i poeta nigeryjski, piszący w języku angielskim. Został laureatem NagrodyNobla]] w dziedzinie literatury za rok 1986.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_writers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/YoruBANovelists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="en">Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka (born 13 July 1934) is a Nigerian writer, notable especially as a playwright and poet; he was awarded the 1986 Nobel Prize in Literature, the first African in Africa and the diaspora to be so honoured. Soyinka was born into a Yoruba family in Abeokuta. After study in Nigeria and the UK, he worked with the Royal Court Theatre in London. He went on to write plays that were produced in both countries, in theatres and on radio.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="it">Ha compiuto gli studi universitari a Ibadan e a Leeds, in Inghilterra, dove ha conseguito il Ph.D. nel 1973. Dopo due anni al Royal Court Theatre di Londra come drammaturgo, nel 1960 è rientrato in Nigeria, dove ha iniziato ad insegnare letteratura e teatro in diverse università e ha fondato il gruppo teatrale "Le maschere 1960". Nel 1964 ha creato la compagnia "Teatro Orisun" con la quale ha messo in scena anche le proprie opere. Nel 1965 ha pubblicato il primo romanzo, scritto in inglese, Gli interpreti. Nel corso della guerra civile nigeriana, viene incarcerato dal 1967 al 1969 per un articolo in cui chiedeva un cessate il fuoco. La sua esperienza in cella di isolamento è narrata in L'uomo è morto. Ancor più che per la narrativa e la saggistica, Wole Soyinka si è affermato in Africa e in Occidente attraverso il teatro e la poesia. In particolare, è noto per aver rivalutato il teatro della tradizione nigeriana e la "folk opera Yoruba". Ha scritto oltre venti drammi e commedie e ha adattato in un contesto africano Le Baccanti di Euripide, L'Opera da tre soldi di Brecht, I negri di Genet. Fra i suoi lavori teatrali figurano: Il leone e la perla, Pazzi e specialisti, La morte e il cavaliere del Re, Danza della foresta, La strada, Il raccolto di Kongi. Fra le sue raccolte poetiche: Idanre and Other Poems; A Shuttle in the Crypt; Ogun Abibiman; Mandela's Earth and Other Poems. Ha insegnato in numerose università, fra cui Yale, Cornell, Harvard, Sheffield e Cambridge, ed è membro delle più prestigiose associazioni letterarie internazionali. Ha ricevuto diversi riconoscimenti in tutto il mondo e il premio Nobel per la Letteratura nel 1986. Perseguitato e condannato a morte dal dittatore nigeriano Sani Abacha, Soyinka vive ora negli Stati Uniti.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ca">Wole Soyinka FRSL és un novel·lista, dramaturg i poeta nigerià en llengua anglesa, el primer africà en ser guardonat amb el Premi Nobel de Literatura l'any 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.motherjones.com/arts/qa/2006/07/running_to_stand_still.html"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="uk">Акінванде Воле Бабатунде Шоїнка — нігерійський драматург, письменник, поет і публіцист. Лауреат Нобелівської премії з літератури.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="es">Wole Soyinka es un escritor nigeriano en idioma inglés, el primer africano en conseguir el en 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.nobelprize.org/nobel_prizes/literature/laureates/1986/soyinka-bio.html"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Yoruba_writers"/>
    <dbpprop:dateOfBirth rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">13</dbpprop:dateOfBirth>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Abeokuta"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="no">Wole Soyinka er en nigeriansk forfatter som fikk Nobelprisen i litteratur i 1986. Han er først og fremst dramatiker og teaterinstruktør, men har skrevet i mange sjangre. Han har sittet i husarrest i hjemlandet.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:thumbnail rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3d/Soyinka,_Wole_(1934).jpg/200px-Soyinka,_Wole_(1934).jpg"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="sv">Wole Soyinka, eg. Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka, är en nigeriansk författare född 13 juli 1934 i Abeokuta. Soyinka var den förste afrikan som tilldelades Nobelpriset i litteratur, år 1986. Soyinka studerade teater i England och har varit både skådespelare och teaterledare i Nigeria. Han skildrar nutida människor, men tar även med de gamla afrikanska gudarna i berättelserna.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://de.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fellows_of_Churchill_College,_Cambridge"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="zh">渥雷·索因卡（Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka，又译作握雷·索因卡或沃萊·索因卡，1934年7月13日－），尼日利亚作家、诗人和剧作家。他尤其在戏剧创作上取得很大的成就，并在1986年获得了诺贝尔文学奖，成为第一个获得该奖的非洲人。 1934年，索因卡出生于尼日利亚约鲁巴族（Yoruba）埃格巴部落（Egba）的一个贫穷家庭，出生地为阿贝奥库塔。他首先在阿贝奥库塔接受了小学教育，又在伊巴丹的政府学院接受了中学教育。最后进入伊巴丹的大学学院（1953年-1954年）并在英国列斯大學取得了英国文学学士学位。毕业后他首先任职于伦敦的皇家宫廷剧场，成为一名剧本校对员，后又返回了尼日利亚研究非洲戏剧。他先后任教于拉多斯大学（University of Lagos）、伊巴丹大学（University of Ibadan）和伊费大学（University of Ife）。（1975年又成为比较文学专业的教授。） 索因卡一直在尼日利亚政坛较为活跃，1967年，在尼日利亚内战期间，因被指责为破坏交战双方的和平，他被雅库布·戈文（Yakubu Gowon）领导的联邦政府逮捕入狱，单独囚禁。在狱中，他创作了许多诗歌，后来全部收录在《狱中诗抄》（Poems from Prison）中出版。后因国际社会的关注和施压，在被关押22个月后得以释放。他在狱中的经历最后写进了《此人已死：狱中笔记》（The Man Died: Prison Notes）。 此外，索因卡也一贯以大胆直言著称，他经常批评尼日利亚的行政部门，也反对全世界其他国家的暴政，包括津巴布韦的罗伯特·穆加贝政权、中国政府1989年的六四事件等。他的许多著作都有明显的反对独裁反对专政的论调，这些激进言论经常使他身处险境，但同样也令他的名声大增。尼日利亚独裁者萨尼·阿巴察（Sani Abacha）的统治期间（1993年-1998年），索因卡因被迫离开尼日利亚，流落异乡，常年在国外居住，后成为美国亚特兰大艾默里大学（Emory University）的教授，主要居住在美国。独裁政权倒台后，1999年他接受了原伊费大学（现在的奥巴费米亚沃洛沃大学,Obafemi Awolowo）名誉教授的头衔，但开出的条件是，这个大学必须禁止招收政府高级官员中的军官。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ogun_State"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/YoruBADramatistsAndPlaywrights"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://schema.org/Person"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NigerianWriters"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://cs.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:University_of_Nevada,_Las_Vegas_faculty"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://it.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Yoruba_novelists"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pl">Wole Soyinka – dramaturg, prozaik i poeta nigeryjski, piszący w języku angielskim. Został laureatem NagrodyNobla]] w dziedzinie literatury za rok 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.wsu.edu/~brians/anglophone/soyinka.html"/>
    <foaf:name xml:lang="en">Wole Soyinka</foaf:name>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Person"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="zh">渥雷·索因卡（Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka，又译作握雷·索因卡或沃萊·索因卡，1934年7月13日－），尼日利亚作家、诗人和剧作家。他尤其在戏剧创作上取得很大的成就，并在1986年获得了诺贝尔文学奖，成为第一个获得该奖的非洲人。 1934年，索因卡出生于尼日利亚约鲁巴族（Yoruba）埃格巴部落（Egba）的一个贫穷家庭，出生地为阿贝奥库塔。他首先在阿贝奥库塔接受了小学教育，又在伊巴丹的政府学院接受了中学教育。最后进入伊巴丹的大学学院（1953年-1954年）并在英国列斯大學取得了英国文学学士学位。毕业后他首先任职于伦敦的皇家宫廷剧场，成为一名剧本校对员，后又返回了尼日利亚研究非洲戏剧。他先后任教于拉多斯大学（University of Lagos）、伊巴丹大学（University of Ibadan）和伊费大学（University of Ife）。（1975年又成为比较文学专业的教授。） 索因卡一直在尼日利亚政坛较为活跃，1967年，在尼日利亚内战期间，因被指责为破坏交战双方的和平，他被雅库布·戈文（Yakubu Gowon）领导的联邦政府逮捕入狱，单独囚禁。在狱中，他创作了许多诗歌，后来全部收录在《狱中诗抄》（Poems from Prison）中出版。后因国际社会的关注和施压，在被关押22个月后得以释放。他在狱中的经历最后写进了《此人已死：狱中笔记》（The Man Died: Prison Notes）。 此外，索因卡也一贯以大胆直言著称，他经常批评尼日利亚的行政部门，也反对全世界其他国家的暴政，包括津巴布韦的罗伯特·穆加贝政权、中国政府1989年的六四事件等。他的许多著作都有明显的反对独裁反对专政的论调，这些激进言论经常使他身处险境，但同样也令他的名声大增。尼日利亚独裁者萨尼·阿巴察（Sani Abacha）的统治期间（1993年-1998年），索因卡因被迫离开尼日利亚，流落异乡，常年在国外居住，后成为美国亚特兰大艾默里大学（Emory University）的教授，主要居住在美国。独裁政权倒台后，1999年他接受了原伊费大学（现在的奥巴费米亚沃洛沃大学,Obafemi Awolowo）名誉教授的头衔，但开出的条件是，这个大学必须禁止招收政府高级官员中的军官。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Authority_control"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ogun_State"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="zh">渥雷·索因卡</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NobelLaureatesInLiterature"/>
    <dbpprop:genre xml:lang="en">Drama, poetry</dbpprop:genre>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ru.dbpedia.org/resource/Шойинка,_Воле"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="uk">Акінванде Воле Бабатунде Шоїнка — нігерійський драматург, письменник, поет і публіцист. Лауреат Нобелівської премії з літератури.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:wordnet_type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2006/03/wn/wn20/instances/synset-writer-noun-1"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_poets"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="cs">Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka je anglicky píšící nigerijský spisovatel, nositel Nobelovy ceny za literaturu z roku 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nigeria"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="no">Wole Soyinka er en nigeriansk forfatter som fikk Nobelprisen i litteratur i 1986. Han er først og fremst dramatiker og teaterinstruktør, men har skrevet i mange sjangre. Han har sittet i husarrest i hjemlandet.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ko.dbpedia.org/resource/월레_소잉카"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Emory_University_faculty"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Persondata"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ca">Wole Soyinka FRSL és un novel·lista, dramaturg i poeta nigerià en llengua anglesa, el primer africà en ser guardonat amb el Premi Nobel de Literatura l'any 1986.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NigerianNobelLaureates"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Writer"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="hu">Wole Soyinka joruba származású, főleg angol nyelven publikáló Nobel-díjas nigériai regényíró. Emellett Nigériában és Angliában is elismert színházi személyiség.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="pt">Wole Soyinka é um escritor nigeriano. Foi agraciado com o Nobel de Literatura de 1986. Muitos o consideram o dramaturgo mais notável da África. Soyinka nasceu em uma família humilde de origem iorubá em Abeokuta, Nigéria. Ele fez o primário escolar em Abeokuta e o secundário no Government College, em Ibadan. Soyinka fez faculdade na University College, em Ibadan, e na University of Leeds (1954-1957), na Inglaterra, onde ele se formou com menção honrosa em Literatura inglesa.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:hasPhotoCollection rdf:resource="http://www4.wiwiss.fu-berlin.de/flickrwrappr/photos/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="vi">Wole Soyinka (tên thật là Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka; sinh ngày 13 tháng 7 năm 1934) là nhà văn, nhà thơ, nhà viết kịch người Nigeria đoạt giải Nobel Văn học năm 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:People_from_Abeokuta"/>
    <dbpprop:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1934-07-13</dbpprop:birthDate>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Fellows_of_the_Royal_Society_of_Literature"/>
    <dbpprop:twitter xml:lang="en">@WoleSoyinka</dbpprop:twitter>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://sw.cyc.com/concept/Mx4rvcP31ZwpEbGdrcN5Y29ycA"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fr">Wole Soyinka est un écrivain nigérian né à Abeokuta le 13 juillet 1934. Il est le premier auteur africain et le premier auteur noir lauréat du prix Nobel de littérature, qu'il obtient en 1986.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://ja.dbpedia.org/resource/ウォーレ・ショインカ"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Alumni_of_the_University_of_Leeds"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="fi">Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka on nigerialainen kirjailija, joka sai ensimmäisenä afrikkalaisena Nobelin kirjallisuuspalkinnon vuonna 1986. Hän on Nigerian huomattavin näytelmäkirjailija. Hän kirjoittaa englanniksi. Soyinka kävi koulunsa Nigeriassa ja opiskeli Leedsin yliopistossa, Englannissa englantilaista kirjallisuutta. Hän työskenteli Royal Court Theatressa Lontoossa ennen paluutaan Nigeriaan tutkimaan afrikkalaista draamaa.</rdfs:comment>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://es.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AlumniOfTheUniversityOfLeeds"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="cs">Wole Soyinka</rdfs:label>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PeopleFromAbeokuta"/>
    <dbpprop:occupation xml:lang="en">Author, poet, playwright</dbpprop:occupation>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:1934_births"/>
    <dbpprop:lccn xml:lang="en">n/80/38437</dbpprop:lccn>
    <foaf:surname xml:lang="en">Soyinka</foaf:surname>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/YoruBAWriters"/>
    <dbpprop:birthName xml:lang="en">Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka</dbpprop:birthName>
    <dbpprop:nationality xml:lang="en">Nigerian</dbpprop:nationality>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Writer"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/AfricanPhilosophers"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://www.w3.org/2002/07/owl#Thing"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="de">Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka ist ein nigerianischer Schriftsteller. Ihm wurde am 16. Oktober 1986 mit der Begründung, er gestalte „in breiter kultureller Perspektive und mit poetischen Obertönen das Drama des menschlichen Seins“ als erstem Vertreter afrikanischer Literatur der Nobelpreis für Literatur zuerkannt. Seit 1994 ist Soyinka Goodwill-Botschafter der UNESCO.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://xmlns.com/foaf/0.1/Person"/>
    <dbpprop:wikiPageUsesTemplate rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Template:Infobox_writer"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Artist"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ja">ウォーレ・ショインカ（Wọlé Sóyinká, 1934年7月13日 - ）は、ナイジェリアの詩人、劇作家。1959年発表の『ライオンと宝石』が処女作。アフリカ人としては初のノーベル文学賞受賞者（1986年）。『死と王の先導者』が代表作。 他に、小説、評論、演出、映画などのジャンルでも才能を発揮している。 何度か来日もしており、1995年11月13日には福岡市内のフォーラムで大江健三郎とも対談をしている。現在、ユネスコ親善大使に就任している。</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthName xml:lang="en">Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka</dbpedia-owl:birthName>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://umbel.org/umbel/rc/Artist"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Prisoners_and_detainees_of_Nigeria"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Duke_University_faculty"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Abeokuta"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="es">Wole Soyinka es un escritor nigeriano en idioma inglés, el primer africano en conseguir el en 1986.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NigerianPoets"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_prisoners_and_detainees"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/Person100007846"/>
    <foaf:isPrimaryTopicOf rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="nl">Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka is een Nigeriaanse schrijver, dichter en toneelschrijver van Yoruba afkomst. Hij wordt beschouwd als de belangrijkste toneelschrijver van Afrika, en verkreeg als eerste Afrikaan ooit in 1986 de Nobelprijs voor de Literatuur.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nobel_laureates_in_Literature"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pl.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <ns8:wasDerivedFrom rdf:resource="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wole_Soyinka?oldid=492614200"/>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://pt.dbpedia.org/resource/Wole_Soyinka"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="de">Wole Soyinka</rdfs:label>
    <dbpprop:viaf rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">105939176</dbpprop:viaf>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:University_of_Ibadan_alumni"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/PrisonersAndDetaineesOfNigeria"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.bbc.co.uk/radio4/reith2004/lectures.shtml"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="uk">Воле Шоїнка</rdfs:label>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="en">Wole Soyinka</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="ru">Акинванде Воле Бабатунде Шойинка — нигерийский драматург, писатель, поэт. Стихи пишет на йоруба, прозу и драмы — на английском языке. Лауреат Нобелевской премии по литературе 1986 года «За создание театра огромной культурной перспективы и поэзии».</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NigerianNovelists"/>
    <dbpprop:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Comparative_literature"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/ontology/Agent"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Abeokuta"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ru">Акинванде Воле Бабатунде Шойинка — нигерийский драматург, писатель, поэт. Стихи пишет на йоруба, прозу и драмы — на английском языке. Лауреат Нобелевской премии по литературе 1986 года «За создание театра огромной культурной перспективы и поэзии».</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:placeOfBirth rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nigeria"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.democracynow.org/article.pl?sid=06/04/19/1312253"/>
    <foaf:givenName xml:lang="en">Wole</foaf:givenName>
    <owl:sameAs rdf:resource="http://rdf.freebase.com/ns/m.0858l"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NigerianPrisonersAndDetainees"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ja">ウォーレ・ショインカ（Wọlé Sóyinká, 1934年7月13日 - ）は、ナイジェリアの詩人、劇作家。1959年発表の『ライオンと宝石』が処女作。アフリカ人としては初のノーベル文学賞受賞者（1986年）。『死と王の先導者』が代表作。 他に、小説、評論、演出、映画などのジャンルでも才能を発揮している。 何度か来日もしており、1995年11月13日には福岡市内のフォーラムで大江健三郎とも対談をしている。現在、ユネスコ親善大使に就任している。</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="sv">Wole Soyinka, eg. Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka, är en nigeriansk författare född 13 juli 1934 i Abeokuta. Soyinka var den förste afrikan som tilldelades Nobelpriset i litteratur, år 1986. Soyinka studerade teater i England och har varit både skådespelare och teaterledare i Nigeria. Han skildrar nutida människor, men tar även med de gamla afrikanska gudarna i berättelserna. Strax innan inbördeskriget i Biafra fängslades Soyinka, eftersom den nigerianska regeringen uppfattade hans vädjanden om en fredlig lösning som ett ensidigt stöd för Biafra. Efter frigivningen 1972 skrev han boken The man died om tiden i fängelset.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/NigerianDramatistsAndPlaywrights"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/LivingPeople"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="ko">아킨완데 올루월레 "월레" 소잉카는 나이지리아의 소설가, 시인, 극작가이다. 1986년 〈해설자〉라는 소설로 아프리카 출신으로서는 처음으로 노벨 문학상을 수상했다. 소앙카는 요루바 족 출신으로 오군 주의 아베오쿠타에서 태어났다. 영어로 글을 쓰면서, 요루바 족의 종교, 철학, 언어를 소개시켰다. 1965년 식민지주의, 인간의 책임과 관련된 〈길〉이라는 연극을 만들었는 데, 이 작품은 하류층과 중류층 간의 관계, 요루바 족의 전통적 신앙과 기독교 간의 관계를 다루는 이야기이다. 유럽의 식민지주의를 보여주는 〈콩기의 추수〉와 〈거인들의 연극〉 등의 연극을 만들기도 했다. 이 극작들에서 주목할 점은 독재정치를 인정하는 아프리카 사회 안의 힘을 보여준다는 것이다. 1967년 나이지리아 정부는 소잉카가 나라 안의 내전을 막으려한다는 이유로 그를 체포하였다.</rdfs:comment>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Living_people"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/YoruBAPoets"/>
    <dbpprop:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Nigeria"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="nl">Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka is een Nigeriaanse schrijver, dichter en toneelschrijver van Yoruba afkomst. Hij wordt beschouwd als de belangrijkste toneelschrijver van Afrika, en verkreeg als eerste Afrikaan ooit in 1986 de Nobelprijs voor de Literatuur.</rdfs:comment>
    <dbpprop:name xml:lang="en">Soyinka, Wole</dbpprop:name>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_philosophers"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.democracynow.org/article.pl?sid=06/04/18/1358206"/>
    <rdf:type rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/class/yago/FellowsOfTheRoyalSocietyOfLiterature"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthPlace rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Ogun_State"/>
    <dbpprop:selibr rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">226683</dbpprop:selibr>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_novelists"/>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Yoruba_poets"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://prelectur.stanford.edu/lecturers/soyinka/"/>
    <dbpprop:influences rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Yor%C3%B9b%C3%A1_religion"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:wikiPageExternalLink rdf:resource="http://www.enotes.com/contemporary-literary-criticism/soyinka-wole-vol-179"/>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fi">Akinwande Oluwole "Wole" Soyinka on nigerialainen kirjailija, joka sai ensimmäisenä afrikkalaisena Nobelin kirjallisuuspalkinnon vuonna 1986. Hän on Nigerian huomattavin näytelmäkirjailija. Hän kirjoittaa englanniksi. Soyinka kävi koulunsa Nigeriassa ja opiskeli Leedsin yliopistossa, Englannissa englantilaista kirjallisuutta. Hän työskenteli Royal Court Theatressa Lontoossa ennen paluutaan Nigeriaan tutkimaan afrikkalaista draamaa. Afrikassa asuessaan Soyinka on opettanut Lagosin, Ibadanin ja Ifan yliopistoissa, maanpakoon lähdettyään Atlantan yliopistossa Yhdysvalloissa. Soyinkalla on ollut aktiivinen rooli Nigerian politiikassa, vuonna 1967 Nigerian sisällissodan aikana hänet vangittiin, koska hän oli yrittänyt omin päin neuvotella osapuolten välille rauhaa. Hänet vapautettiin lähes kahden vuoden jälkeen, kun kansainvälinen huomio kohdistui vangittuun kirjailijaan. Soyinka on arvostellut avoimesti maailman hirmuhallitsijoita. Iso osa hänen tuotannostaan käsittelee "kansan oikeuksia tallovaa saapasta ja sen saappaan sisällä olevan jalan värin yhdentekevyyttä". Nigerian ollessa diktaattori Sani Abachan vallassa 1993–1998 Soyinka pakeni maasta. Hän on nykyisin UNESCOn hyvän tahdon lähettiläs. Etniseltä taustaltaan Soyinka on joruba.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dbpedia-owl:birthDate rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#date">1934-07-13</dbpedia-owl:birthDate>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Yoruba_dramatists_and_playwrights"/>
    <dbpprop:pnd rdf:datatype="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema#int">118615807</dbpprop:pnd>
    <foaf:depiction rdf:resource="http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/3d/Soyinka,_Wole_(1934).jpg"/>
    <rdfs:label xml:lang="vi">Wole Soyinka</rdfs:label>
    <dbpedia-owl:abstract xml:lang="fr">Wole Soyinka est un écrivain nigérian né à Abeokuta le 13 juillet 1934. Il est le premier auteur africain et le premier auteur noir lauréat du prix Nobel de littérature, qu'il obtient en 1986.</dbpedia-owl:abstract>
    <dcterms:subject rdf:resource="http://dbpedia.org/resource/Category:Nigerian_Nobel_laureates"/>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="it">Ha compiuto gli studi universitari a Ibadan e a Leeds, in Inghilterra, dove ha conseguito il Ph.D. nel 1973. Dopo due anni al Royal Court Theatre di Londra come drammaturgo, nel 1960 è rientrato in Nigeria, dove ha iniziato ad insegnare letteratura e teatro in diverse università e ha fondato il gruppo teatrale "Le maschere 1960". Nel 1964 ha creato la compagnia "Teatro Orisun" con la quale ha messo in scena anche le proprie opere.</rdfs:comment>
    <rdfs:comment xml:lang="de">Akinwande Oluwole Soyinka ist ein nigerianischer Schriftsteller. Ihm wurde am 16. Oktober 1986 mit der Begründung, er gestalte „in breiter kultureller Perspektive und mit poetischen Obertönen das Drama des menschlichen Seins“ als erstem Vertreter afrikanischer Literatur der Nobelpreis für Literatur zuerkannt. Seit 1994 ist Soyinka Goodwill-Botschafter der UNESCO.</rdfs:comment>
  </rdf:Description>
</rdf:RDF>
